[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "Who wrote the title page of The Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "Mormon",
    "options": ["Joseph Smith", "Mormon", "Moroni"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "The abridgment of the record is written to the Jew and Gentile.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "The record is written by way of commandment, and also by the spirit of ____ and of revelation.",
    "answer": "prophecy"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "The record was written and sealed up, and hid up unto the Lord, that they may not be destroyed",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "Where in the Book of Mormon is the word Lamanites first mentioned?",
    "answer": "Title Page"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "The word “Jaredites” first appears to in the Title page of the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "An abridgment is taken from the Book of ____, which is a record of the people of Jared.",
    "answer": "ether"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "The people of Jared were scattered at the time the Lord confounded their language.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "At time the Lord confounded the language of the Jaredites, they were trying to build a ____ to get to heaven.",
    "answer": "tower"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "The Lord has done many great things unto the remnant of the House of ____.",
    "answer": "Israel"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "The Lord wants to show the remnant House of Israel the many great things that he has done for their fathers.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "The Lord wants the House of Israel to know the ____ he has made with them and not be cast-off forever.",
    "answer": "Covenants",
    "options": ["Bible", "Articles of Faith", "Covenants"]
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "The Lord wants to convince Jews and Gentiles that Jesus is the ____.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "Jesus is the Christ, the Eternal God, manifesting himself unto all nations.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "Mormon states that if there are faults in the record, they are the ____ of Men.",
    "answer": "Mistakes"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "Mormon writes, condemn not the things of God?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "Mormon wants us to be found spotless at the _____ seat of Christ",
    "answer": "Judgment"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "Who translated the title page of the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "Joseph Smith",
    "options": ["Moroni", "Mormon", "Joseph Smith"]
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Brief Analysis",
    "question": "In the brief analysis of the Book of Mormon we are told that there are namely three classes of record plates.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Brief Analysis",
    "question": "The Brass Plates of Laban are mentioned frequently in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Brief Analysis",
    "question": "The body of the Book of Mormon, from Mosiah to Mormon, chapter #7, inclusive, is the translation of whose ____ abridgment of the Plates of Nephi.",
    "answer": "Mormon"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Brief Analysis",
    "question": "The period covered in the Book of Mormon extends from B.C. 600 to A.D. 421.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Brief Analysis",
    "question": "Who was the last of the Nephite historians?",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Brief Analysis",
    "question": "Moroni was the last of the Nephite historians that sealed the sacred record, and hid up unto the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Brief Analysis",
    "question": "In the Brief Analysis of the Book of Mormon, Joseph Smith mentions the hill Cumorah by name.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Ether 15:11",
    "question": "The hill Cumorah was referred as the hill Ramah by the Jaredites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mor 1:3, 4:23",
    "question": "The hill Cumorah was referred as the hill Shim by the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Look at Book of Mormon",
    "question": "In what beautiful state, is the hill Cumorah located.",
    "answer": "New York"
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "On the night of September 21, 1823, who appeared to Joseph Smith Junior ____?",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "When Moroni first appeared to Joseph Smith he referred to him as a personage.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "When Joseph sought the Lord in fervent prayer, he discovered a_____ appearing in his room.",
    "answer": "light"
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The light that appeared to Joseph, was lighter than noon-day.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The personage that appeared to Joseph Smith was ____, and he was standing in the air.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "When Moroni appeared to Joseph Smith, he was standing in the air.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Moroni’s robe was of the most exquisite ____.",
    "answer": "whiteness",
    "options": ["Color", "Whiteness", "Design"]
  },
  {
    "id": 36,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph Smith writes: That he believed that anything earthly could be made to appear so exceedingly white or brilliant.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph Smith said that he could see Moroni’s hands were naked and his arms also, a little above the wrists.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Moroni’s ____ and neck were also bare, when he appeared to Joseph Smith.",
    "answer": "Head"
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph Smith could see that Moroni was wearing clothing that is worn by worthy temple workers.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 40,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Because Moroni’s head and neck were bare, Joseph Smith could see into Moroni’s ____.",
    "answer": "bosom"
  },
  {
    "id": 41,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Not only was Moroni’s robe exceedingly white, his whole person was glorious beyond description.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 42,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph Smith states that ____ countenance was truly like lightning.",
    "answer": "moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 43,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Moroni’s countenance was truly like lightning, when he appeared to Joseph Smith.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 44,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The light that surrounded ____ was brighter than the light of the room.",
    "answer": "moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 45,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "When Joseph Smith first saw Moroni, he was afraid.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Who was afraid of Moroni, when he first appeared in his room?",
    "answer": "Joseph Smith"
  },
  {
    "id": 47,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "It took a very long time for Joseph Smith to get over of being afraid of Moroni.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 48,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "At first, Joseph Smith was afraid of Moroni, but soon the ____ left him.",
    "answer": "Fear",
    "options": ["Fear", "Sadness", "Glory"]
  },
  {
    "id": 49,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The messenger called Joseph Smith by name.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 50,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The messenger told Joseph Smith, that his name would be had for good and ____.",
    "answer": "evil"
  },
  {
    "id": 51,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The messenger to Joseph that all nation’s, kindreds, and ____, would speak evil of his name.",
    "answer": "tongues"
  },
  {
    "id": 52,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The messenger to Joseph that all nation’s, kindreds, and tongues would speak evil of his name.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 53,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Moroni said that there was a_____ deposited in the ground, written upon gold plates.",
    "answer": "Book",
    "options": ["Manuscript", "Book", "Tablet"]
  },
  {
    "id": 54,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The book that was deposited in the ground was written on what type of metal?",
    "answer": "Gold",
    "options": ["Silver", "Brass", "Gold"]
  },
  {
    "id": 55,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The book gave an account of the former ____ of the continent.",
    "answer": "Inhabitants",
    "options": ["Inhabitants", "Dinosaurs", "Birds"]
  },
  {
    "id": 56,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Ask someone that knows",
    "question": "What is the name of continent in which the book was deposited and in which we in the united states live?",
    "answer": "North America"
  },
  {
    "id": 57,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The book gives an account of the former inhabitants of this continent, and the source from whence they sprang.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 58,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The ____ of the everlasting Gospel was contained in the book; that was deposited in the earth.",
    "answer": "fulness"
  },
  {
    "id": 59,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The fulness of the everlasting Gospel is contained in the Book.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 60,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The fulness of the everlasting Gospel was delivered by the ____, to the former ancient inhabitants.",
    "answer": ["savior", "lord"]
  },
  {
    "id": 61,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "What shade of color were the two stones in the bow?",
    "answer": "Silver",
    "options": ["Metallic", "Gold", "Silver"]
  },
  {
    "id": 62,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The two stones in silver bows were fastened to a breastplate.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 63,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Another name that is given to the two stones and breastplate is the ____.",
    "answer": "Urim and Thummim"
  },
  {
    "id": 64,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The Urim and Thummim is what constitutes the two stones and the breastplate.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 65,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "No ref because they are not.",
    "question": "The Urim and Thummim are mentioned by name in the text of Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 66,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The possession and the use of these stones were what constituted what word?",
    "answer": "Seers"
  },
  {
    "id": 67,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The Seers were not used in ancientformer times.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 68,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The Seers were madeprepared by whom?",
    "answer": ["god", "lord"]
  },
  {
    "id": 69,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The Seers were prepared by God; for the purpose of translating the book, of which is now known as the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 70,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "With the possession and use of the Seers, people cancould translate ancient writings.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 71,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Angel Moroni told Joseph Smith to show the plates to anyone that he pleased.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 72,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph was told not to show the plates to anyone, unless he was ____ to do so.",
    "answer": "Commanded"
  },
  {
    "id": 73,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph was commanded by Moroni, to show only the breastplate and not the Urim and Thummim.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 74,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Unless Joseph was commanded; Moroni said that he must not show the plates and Urim and Thummin to anyonehe would be destroyed.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 75,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "While Joseph was conversing with Moroni about the plates, he had a ____.",
    "answer": "Vision",
    "options": ["Vision", "Seizure", "Migraine Headache"]
  },
  {
    "id": 76,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "In his vision, Joseph Smith could see the place where the plates were deposited.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 77,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The vision was so clear and distinct, that Joseph knew where the place was when he visited it.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 78,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "After the communication, Joseph saw the light in the room begin to gather around this person.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 79,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Except around Moroni, the room began to get dark again.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 80,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "A conduit opened right up into ____, and Moroni ascended until he entirely disappeared.",
    "answer": "heaven"
  },
  {
    "id": 81,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph states and refers to the light in his room as being heavenly.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 82,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "After the messenger and the light left, Joseph fell asleep.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 83,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph lay in bed and was overwhelmed with astonishment at what he had both ____, and heard.",
    "answer": "seen"
  },
  {
    "id": 84,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The second time the messenger appeared to Joseph, he repeated the same words as the first time, without variation.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 85,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Moroni told Joseph ____ would try to tempt him.",
    "answer": "satan"
  },
  {
    "id": 86,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Moroni informed Joseph of great judgments which were coming upon the ____.",
    "answer": "Earth",
    "options": ["People", "Heavens", "Earth"]
  },
  {
    "id": 87,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Moroni said that great judgments were coming upon the earth such as; desolations by famine, sword, and ____.",
    "answer": "Pestilence"
  },
  {
    "id": 88,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "At what time did Moroni say that the judgements were coming to the earth?",
    "answer": "This generation",
    "options": ["Noah's time", "This generation", "The generation to come"]
  },
  {
    "id": 89,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph writes that he and his father’s family were indigent.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 90,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Moroni told Joseph that he must have no other object in view in getting the plates but glorify ____.",
    "answer": "god"
  },
  {
    "id": 91,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Moroni told Joseph Smith that he must not be influenced by any other motive than that of building the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 92,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "How many times did the angel Moroni visit Joseph Smith in one single night?",
    "answer": "Three",
    "options": ["One", "Two", "Three"]
  },
  {
    "id": 93,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Angel Moroni visited Joseph Smith three times in September of 1823.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 94,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "After Moroni’s third visit, as he ascended into heaven; What kind of fowl did Joseph hear crowed.",
    "answer": "Rooster",
    "options": ["Swan", "Rooster", "Turkey"]
  },
  {
    "id": 95,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Moroni left, and Joseph realized that their interviews must of have taken all night because the day had approach.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 96,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph attempted to work as other times, but found that his strength was ____.",
    "answer": "Exhausted",
    "options": ["Exhausted", "Gone", "Stronger"]
  },
  {
    "id": 97,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Because of his exhausted strength, Joseph’s father told him to go home.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 98,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "While attempting to cross the _____ out of the field, Joseph's strength left him and he fell to the ground.",
    "answer": "Fence",
    "options": ["River", "Highway", "Fence"]
  },
  {
    "id": 99,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph fell to the ground and was unconscious for three days.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 100,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "In the Origin of the Book of Mormon: It does not sayhow long Joseph exactly lay unconscious.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 101,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Who appeared to Joseph Smith when he arose from his unconsciousness?",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 102,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph was ____ by Moroni to tell his father, of the vision and commandments he had received.",
    "answer": "Commanded",
    "options": ["Told", "Exhorted", "Commanded"]
  },
  {
    "id": 103,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph obeyed Moroni, and returned to his father in the field, and rehearsed the whole matter to him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 104,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph left out some important details, when he rehearsed the story to his father.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 105,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph’s father told him to go to the place where the Messenger had told him to go.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 106,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph new the place where the plates were deposited because of the dream that he had.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 107,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Because of his_____, Joseph knew the place where the plates were buried.",
    "answer": "Vision",
    "options": ["Hindsight", "Vision", "Foresight"]
  },
  {
    "id": 108,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The hill where the plates were deposited was more elevated than the other surrounding hills.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 109,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Convenient to what village is the Hill Cumorah located?",
    "answer": "Manchester"
  },
  {
    "id": 110,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "What person is represented by statue, atop the Hill Cumorah?",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 111,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph Smith tells us the plates were hidden under a considerable size stone and facing what direction?",
    "answer": "West",
    "options": ["North", "South", "West"]
  },
  {
    "id": 112,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "When Joseph Smith removed the earth that was fixed under the stone, he had a difficult time.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 113,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "When Joseph Smith looked into the stone box; it contained the plates, the ____, and the breastplate.",
    "answer": "Urim and Thummim"
  },
  {
    "id": 114,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph Smith made an attempt to get the things out of the box, but was forbidden by whom?",
    "answer": ["messanger", "moroni"]
  },
  {
    "id": 115,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The messenger told Joseph Smith that the time had not come yet to get the things out of the box.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 116,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "How many years would pass before Joseph Smith could get the things out of the box?",
    "answer": "Four",
    "options": ["Two", "Three", "Four"]
  },
  {
    "id": 117,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Moroni told Joseph Smith to come precisely one year from the time that he first saw him and that he would meet with him again.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 118,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph Smith did as he was ____, and he went at the end of each year and at each time, he found the same messenger there waiting for him.",
    "answer": "Commanded",
    "options": ["Forbidden", "Commanded", "Instructed"]
  },
  {
    "id": 119,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph Smith received instructions and ____, from the messenger, at each of their interviews.",
    "answer": "Intelligence",
    "options": ["Gold", "Money", "Intelligence"]
  },
  {
    "id": 120,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The messenger told Joseph what the Lord was going to do, and how and what manner His kingdom was to be conducted in the last days.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 121,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The messenger delivered the plates to Joseph and told him that he was to be responsible for them and if he would let them go carelessly, he would not be cut off.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 122,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The messenger told Joseph that he should use all of his endeavors to preserve the ____.",
    "answer": "Plates",
    "options": ["Hill Cumorah", "Plates", "House of his Father"]
  },
  {
    "id": 123,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph Smith was told by the messenger what would be required of him to do by his hand.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 124,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph was told by the messenger: That the ____ would be protected until he should call for them again.",
    "answer": "Plates"
  },
  {
    "id": 125,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "As soon as it was found out that he had the plates, multitudes of people were out to get them away from them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 126,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Who do you think told people that Joseph Smith had a book written upon gold plates?",
    "answer": ["adversary", "satan"]
  },
  {
    "id": 127,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Joseph Smith said that every_____ that could be invented was resorted to take away the plates from him.",
    "answer": "Stratagem",
    "options": ["Stratagem", "Device", "Intelligence"]
  },
  {
    "id": 128,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "When the messenger called for the plates, Joseph Smith did not deliver them unto him until he was commanded.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 129,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "According to Joseph Smith, Who has the platesis in charge of them to this day?",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 130,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The Book of Mormon was translated into modern speech by the gift and power of_____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 131,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "As attested by Divine affirmation, the ancient record has been brought forth from the earth.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 132,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Origin of Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The Book of Mormon was first published to the world in what year of our Lord?",
    "answer": "1830",
    "options": ["1821", "1823", "1830"]
  },
  {
    "id": 133,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Look at Book of Mormon",
    "question": "What is the name of the artist who painted most of the Book of Mormon paintings?",
    "answer": ["Arnold", "Friberg"]
  },
  {
    "id": 134,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Testimony of Three Witnesses",
    "question": "Who were the Three Witnesses of the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "Oliver Cowdery, David Whitmer and Martin Harris",
    "options": [
      "Oliver Cowdery, David Whitmer and Lorenzo Snow",
      "Joseph Smith Sr, Brigham Young and Nephi",
      "Oliver Cowdery, David Whitmer and Martin Harris"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 135,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Testimony of the Eight Witnesses",
    "question": "In the testimony of the Eight Witnesses, they describe the plates of having the appearance of ancient work, and of curious workmanship.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 136,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Testimony of the Eight Witnesses",
    "question": "In the testimony of the Eight Witnesses, they state that they gave their names to the world, to witness unto the world that, that they handled the plates with their hands and saw the engraving thereon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 137,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Testimony of the Eight Witnesses",
    "question": "The Eight Witnesses state that they “lie not” and bear witness unto whom?",
    "answer": "god"
  },
  {
    "id": 138,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon",
    "question": "What is the title of the first book in the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 139,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon",
    "question": "What is the title of the last book in the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 140,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The longest book in the Book of Mormon is the Book of Mosiah?",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 141,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon",
    "question": "What is the longest book in the Book of Mormon",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 142,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon",
    "question": "What Book of Mormon book has the least verses",
    "answer": "Jarom"
  },
  {
    "id": 143,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon",
    "question": "What is the name of the book that has the second least amount of verses",
    "answer": "The Words Of Mormon"
  },
  {
    "id": 144,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The words: “was the son of “are used how many times in the Book of Ether.",
    "answer": "21",
    "options": ["15", "20", "21"]
  },
  {
    "id": 145,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Book of Omni",
    "question": "What Book of Mormon author wrote the least amount of words in the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "Chemish"
  },
  {
    "id": 146,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Book of Omni",
    "question": "This Book of Mormon author only wrote one verse.",
    "answer": "Chemish"
  },
  {
    "id": 147,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep10:4",
    "question": "A prophet would the Lord God raise up among the Jews-even a _____, or, in other words, a Savior of the world.",
    "answer": "Messiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 148,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Abish-Alma19:16, Eve-1Nep5:11, Isabel-Alma39:3, Mary-Mos3:8, Sariah-1Nep2:5",
    "question": "There are only three women mentioned by name in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 149,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep:1",
    "question": "Nephi was born of _____ parents.",
    "answer": "Goodly",
    "options": ["Bad", "Naughty", "Goodly"]
  },
  {
    "id": 150,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:1",
    "question": "Nephi was taught somewhat in all the learning of his father.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 151,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep1:1",
    "question": "Nephi saw many_____ in the course of his days.",
    "answer": "afflictions",
    "options": ["bad things", "afflictions", "parties"]
  },
  {
    "id": 152,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:13, Alma 12:221, 42:2-3",
    "question": "What modern day weapon has been around since the beginning of man?",
    "answer": "Sword"
  },
  {
    "id": 153,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:1",
    "question": "Nephi was highly favored of the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 154,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:1",
    "question": "What Book of Mormon historian was highly favored of the Lord?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 155,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep1:1",
    "question": "How many days was, Nephi highly favored of the Lord?  c-(B)",
    "answer": "all",
    "options": ["half", "all", "neither half nor all"]
  },
  {
    "id": 156,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:1",
    "question": "Nephi had_____ knowledge of the goodness and the mysteries of God.",
    "answer": "Great"
  },
  {
    "id": 157,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:1",
    "question": "Nephi was not a very smart prophet.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 158,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:1",
    "question": "Nephi said: “I make a record of my proceedings in my days”.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 159,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon",
    "question": "The record that Nephi made about his reign and ministry is known to us as the: “First Book Of _____”.",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 160,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:2",
    "question": "Nephi made a record in the _____ of his father.",
    "answer": "Language"
  },
  {
    "id": 161,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep1:1",
    "question": "Nephi’s writing’s consists of the learning of what tribe of people?",
    "answer": "Jews",
    "options": ["Jews", "Egyptians", "Mongols"]
  },
  {
    "id": 162,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep1:2 & Mosiah1:4",
    "question": "Nephi was taught by his father in the language of the _____",
    "answer": "Egyptians",
    "options": ["Israelites", "Egyptians", "Mongols"]
  },
  {
    "id": 163,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:2",
    "question": "Nephi taught Lehi the language of the Egyptians.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 164,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:3",
    "question": "Nephi said that his record is somewhat true as far as he can remember.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 165,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:3",
    "question": "Nephi wrote that: The record which I make is true; and I make it with mine own hand”.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 166,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep1:3",
    "question": "Nephi made the record according to his_____.  (a) -(C)",
    "answer": "knowledge",
    "options": ["memory", "will", "knowledge"]
  },
  {
    "id": 167,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4",
    "question": "It came to pass in the commencement of the_____ year of the reign Zedekiah. ",
    "answer": "1st",
    "options": ["1st", "2nd", "3rd"]
  },
  {
    "id": 168,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4",
    "question": "Who was the king of Judah at the time that Nephi wrote the book of Nephi?",
    "answer": "Zedekiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 169,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4",
    "question": "What body of land did king Zedekiah reign over.",
    "answer": "Judah",
    "options": ["Egypt", "Israel", "Judah"]
  },
  {
    "id": 170,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4",
    "question": "What important city was located in the land of Judah?",
    "answer": "Jerusalem"
  },
  {
    "id": 171,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4",
    "question": "In the beginning of the Book of Nephi: He writes that Lehi lived in Jerusalem all his days.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 172,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4",
    "question": "Lehi was Nephi's uncle.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 173,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4",
    "question": "Lehi was the father of Nephi."
  },
  {
    "id": 174,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4",
    "question": "What kind of people came to Jerusalem at the same year of the commencement of the reign of King Zedekiah?",
    "answer": "Prophets",
    "options": ["Jews", "Prophets", "Hebrews"]
  },
  {
    "id": 175,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4",
    "question": "Many prophets came to the city of Jerusalem and prophesied that if the people did not repent, the city would be destroyed.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 176,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4",
    "question": "What city in the land of Judah would be destroyed if the people did not repent?",
    "answer": "Jerusalem"
  },
  {
    "id": 177,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4",
    "question": "The city of Jerusalem; was a great city according to Nephi.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 178,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep1:5",
    "question": "Lehi prayed on behalf of his_____.",
    "answer": "People",
    "options": ["Wives", "Pets", "People"]
  },
  {
    "id": 179,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:5",
    "question": "Who did Lehi pray to and asked that the city would not be destroyed?",
    "answer": ["god", "lord"]
  },
  {
    "id": 180,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:5",
    "question": "Lehi prayed to the Lord with all his heart.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 181,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:6",
    "question": "As Lehi prayed unto the Lord, there came a pillar of_____.",
    "answer": "Fire"
  },
  {
    "id": 182,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:6",
    "question": "When Lehi was praying unto the Lord, a pillar of fire appeared.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 183,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:6",
    "question": "The pillar of fire did not dwell upon a rock; instead it flew over Lehi’s head.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 184,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:6",
    "question": "Because of the pillar of fire, Lehi saw and heard much.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 185,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep1:6",
    "question": "Because of the things Lehi saw and heard he did quake and_____ exceedingly.",
    "answer": "Tremble",
    "options": ["Danced The Macarena", "Did The Twist", "Tremble"]
  },
  {
    "id": 186,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep1:7",
    "question": "Lehi cast himself upon his bed, being overcome by the_____.",
    "answer": "Spirit",
    "options": ["Heat", "Spirit", "Devil"]
  },
  {
    "id": 187,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:7",
    "question": "Lehi cast himself to bed because he was overcome by the Spirit.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 188,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:8",
    "question": "And being thus overcome with the Spirit, Lehi was carried away in a_____.",
    "answer": "Vision"
  },
  {
    "id": 189,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep1:8",
    "question": "Lehi saw in his vision the_____ opened.",
    "answer": "Heavens",
    "options": ["Earth", "Heavens", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 190,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:8",
    "question": "In his vision, who did Lehi see sitting upon his throne?",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 191,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:8",
    "question": "Lehi saw God sitting upon his_____.",
    "answer": "Throne"
  },
  {
    "id": 192,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:8",
    "question": "In his vision Lehi saw the Devil being cast out of heaven.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 193,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:8",
    "question": "_____was sitting upon his throne, surrounded with numberless concourses of angels.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 194,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:8",
    "question": "God sat on his throne, and was surrounded by one million angels.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 195,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:8",
    "question": "As God sat on his throne, angels were singing and praising their God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 196,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:8",
    "question": "In his vision, Lehi saw____ singing and praising their God.",
    "answer": "Angels"
  },
  {
    "id": 197,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:9",
    "question": "Lehi saw one/person descending out of the midst of_____.",
    "answer": "Heaven"
  },
  {
    "id": 198,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:9",
    "question": "The person’s luster that Lehi saw descending out of heaven was above that of the sun at noon-day.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 199,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:9",
    "question": "The word “noon-day” only appears once in the text of the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 200,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep1:9",
    "question": "How many times does the word “noon-day” appear in the text of the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "1",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": 201,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep1:10",
    "question": "How many persons followed the first person that Lehi saw in his vision?",
    "answer": "12",
    "options": ["3", "Six", "12"]
  },
  {
    "id": 202,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:10",
    "question": "Twelve others followed the first person that Lehi saw in his vision.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 203,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:10",
    "question": "The brightness of the twelve people that Lehi saw in his vision exceeded that of the stars in the firmament.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 204,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep1:10",
    "question": "Whose brightness exceeded that of the stars in the firmament?",
    "answer": "The Twelve",
    "options": ["The Devil", "The Twelve", "Laman’s"]
  },
  {
    "id": 205,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:11",
    "question": "The first person that Lehi saw descending out of heaven and the twelve others that followed him; came down and went forth upon the face of the earth.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 206,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:11",
    "question": "All the people that Lehi saw descending out of heaven came down and went forth upon the face of the_____.",
    "answer": "Earth"
  },
  {
    "id": 207,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep1:11",
    "question": "What person stood before Lehi and gave him a book and bade him to read it.",
    "answer": "1st Person",
    "options": ["1st Person", "2nd Person", "The 3rd"]
  },
  {
    "id": 208,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:11",
    "question": "Lehi choose not to read the book that the first person gave him to read.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 209,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:12",
    "question": "When Lehi read the book that he was given; he was filled with the____ of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },
  {
    "id": 210,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:12",
    "question": "Lehi did not pray before he read the book that he was given and consequently, did not feel the Spirit of the Lord.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 211,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:13",
    "question": "In the book that he was given Lehi saw the abominations of what city in the land of Judah?",
    "answer": "Jerusalem"
  },
  {
    "id": 212,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:13",
    "question": "Lehi said: “Woe, woe, unto_____, for I have seen thine abominations!”",
    "answer": "Jereusalem"
  },
  {
    "id": 213,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:13",
    "question": "Lehi saw and read many things concerning the city of Jerusalem.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 214,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:13",
    "question": "Lehi saw and read that the city of Jerusalem would be destroyed and also it's inhabitants.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 215,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep1:13",
    "question": "Many of the people of Jerusalem would perish by the_____ and be carried away captive.",
    "answer": "Sword",
    "options": ["Knife", "Sword", "Famine"]
  },
  {
    "id": 216,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:13",
    "question": "Only those that were unrighteous would perish by the sword and be carried into captivity.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 217,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:13",
    "question": "Lehi saw the people of Jerusalem perish and be carried away captive to_____.",
    "answer": "Babylon"
  },
  {
    "id": 218,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep1:14",
    "question": "Lehi read and saw many_____ and marvelous things and exclaimed many things unto the Lord.",
    "answer": "Great",
    "options": ["Bad", "Good", "Great"]
  },
  {
    "id": 219,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep1:14",
    "question": "Lehi said “great and marvelous are thy works, O Lord God_____",
    "answer": "Almighty",
    "options": ["Almighty", "Gosh Darn It", "Its All Good"]
  },
  {
    "id": 220,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep1:14",
    "question": "According to Lehi, where is the throne of God located?",
    "answer": "The Heavens",
    "options": ["Close To The Moon", "The Heavens", "Underneath The Stars"]
  },
  {
    "id": 221,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:14",
    "question": "Lehi said the throne of God is located in the heavens.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 222,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep1:14",
    "question": "Lehi said that God’s power, goodness, and mercy are over all the_____ of the earth.",
    "answer": "Inhabitants",
    "options": ["People", "Inhabitants", "Unrighteous"]
  },
  {
    "id": 223,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:14",
    "question": "Lehi said that God is merciful.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 224,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:14",
    "question": "Lehi saw and read that God was not very merciful to the inhabitants of Jerusalem.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 225,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:14",
    "question": "Because God is _____, he will not suffer those that come unto him to perish.",
    "answer": "Merciful"
  },
  {
    "id": 226,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:15",
    "question": "Lehi did not praise God because of the things he had seen.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 227,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:15",
    "question": "Because of the things Lehi saw his soul did rejoice.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 228,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:15",
    "question": "Lehi’s soul did rejoice, and his_____ was filled because of the things he saw.",
    "answer": "Heart"
  },
  {
    "id": 229,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:16",
    "question": "Nephi made a full account of the thing which his father wrote.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 230,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:16",
    "question": "Lehi wrote many things which he saw in visions and in_____.",
    "answer": "Dreams"
  },
  {
    "id": 231,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep1:16",
    "question": "Nephi said that Lehi had written many things which he prophesied and spoke unto his_____.",
    "answer": "Children",
    "options": ["Daughters", "Uncles", "Children"]
  },
  {
    "id": 232,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:17",
    "question": "Nephi made an account of his proceedings.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 233,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:17",
    "question": "Who made an abridgement of the record of his father?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 234,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:17",
    "question": "The plates that Nephi made for the record, were made by his_____.",
    "answer": "Hand"
  },
  {
    "id": 235,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:17",
    "question": "Nephi first made an abridgment of the record of Lehi then he made an account of his life.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 236,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:18",
    "question": "Lehi prophesied and declared to the people of Jerusalem the marvelous things which he had seen and heard.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 237,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:19",
    "question": "The Jews did_____, Lehi because of the things he testified of them.",
    "answer": "Mock"
  },
  {
    "id": 238,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:19",
    "question": "Lehi testified to the Jews of things which he saw and heard, and also of the things which he read in a book.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 239,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:19",
    "question": "The book which Lehi read; manifested plainly of the coming of the_____.",
    "answer": "Messiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 240,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:20",
    "question": "The Jews were angry with Lehi even as with the prophets of old.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 241,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:20",
    "question": "Because of the things that he had said, the Jews sought to kill_____.",
    "answer": "Lehi"
  },
  {
    "id": 242,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:20",
    "question": "The Jews: _____out, and stoned, and slain, the prophets of old in the city of Jerusalem.",
    "answer": "Cast"
  },
  {
    "id": 243,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:20",
    "question": "Nephi wrote that he would show unto us that the tender mercies of the Lord are over all those whom he hath chosen.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 244,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep1:20",
    "question": "Because of their_____, the Lord will make those that he has chosen mighty even unto the power of deliverance.",
    "answer": "Faith",
    "options": ["Riches", "Pride", "Faith"]
  },
  {
    "id": 245,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep1:19-20",
    "question": "The Jews were angry with Lehi because he testified of their wickedness and abominations.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 246,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep2:1",
    "question": "The Lord spoke to Lehi in a dream and told him he was blessed for things that he had done.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 247,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:1",
    "question": "Lehi was faithful and declared unto the people the things which the_____ had commanded him to say.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 248,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep2:1",
    "question": "The people in Jerusalem sough to take away Lehi’s life.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 249,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:2",
    "question": "The ____ came to Lehi in a dream and commanded him to depart into the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 250,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep2:3",
    "question": "Lehi did not obey the word of the Lord, and did not depart until he was ready.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 251,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:5",
    "question": "By what borders and shore of a sea did Lehi and his family travel to?",
    "answer": "Red Sea"
  },
  {
    "id": 252,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:5",
    "question": "What was Nephi’s mother’s name?",
    "answer": "Sariah"
  },
  {
    "id": 253,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep2:6",
    "question": "How many days did Lehi and his family travel before pitching their tents for the first time?",
    "answer": "3",
    "options": ["2", "3", "4"]
  },
  {
    "id": 254,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep2:7",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Lehi built an altar of_____.",
    "answer": "Stones",
    "options": ["Rocks", "Clay", "Stones"]
  },
  {
    "id": 255,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep2:7",
    "question": "Nephi made an offering unto the Lord and gave thanks unto the Lord.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 256,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep2:8",
    "question": "Which son die Lehi name a river after; that emptied into the Red Sea?",
    "answer": "Laman",
    "options": ["Nephi", "Sam,", "Laman"]
  },
  {
    "id": 257,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep2:8",
    "question": "The name of the river that emptied into the Red Sea was called_____.",
    "answer": "Laman",
    "options": ["The Snake,", "The Mississippi,", "Laman"]
  },
  {
    "id": 258,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep2:8",
    "question": "Lehi named a river after one of his sons",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 259,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:9",
    "question": "Which one of his son’s was Lehi speaking to when he said” O that thou mightest be like unto this river, continually running into the fountain of all righteousness!",
    "answer": "Laman"
  },
  {
    "id": 260,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep2:10",
    "question": "Lehi was referring to Lemuel when he said “O that thou might be like unto this valley, firm and stead-fest, and immovable in keeping the commandments of the Lord!”",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 261,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep2:11",
    "question": "Lehi spoke encouraging words to Laman and Lemuel because of their_____.",
    "answer": "Stiffneckedness",
    "options": ["Looks", "Stiffneckedness", "Clothes"]
  },
  {
    "id": 262,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep2:11",
    "question": "For behold Laman and Lemuel did murmur in many things against Lehi.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 263,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep2:11",
    "question": "Lehi was a visionary man.",
    "answer": "t"
  },
  {
    "id": 264,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:11",
    "question": "Nephi’s brothers murmured because Lehi had led them out of Jerusalem, to leave the land of their inheritance, and their gold and_____.",
    "answer": "Silver"
  },
  {
    "id": 265,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep2:11",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel left behind their precious things and thought they were going to perish in the wilderness.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 266,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep2:11",
    "question": "Nephi’s brothers said that Lehi had led them into the wilderness because of the foolish imaginations of his_____.",
    "answer": "Heart",
    "options": ["Heart", "Head", "Mind"]
  },
  {
    "id": 267,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:12",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel murmured because they did not know the dealings of that_____, who had created them.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 268,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep2:13",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel did not believe that what great city could be destroyed.",
    "answer": "Jerusalem",
    "options": ["Salt Lake City,", "Sugar City,", "Jerusalem"]
  },
  {
    "id": 269,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep2:13",
    "question": "Nephi’s two older brothers did not believe that Jerusalem could be destroyed according to the words of the_____.",
    "answer": "Prophets",
    "options": ["3 Wise Men", "Prophets", "Holy Men"]
  },
  {
    "id": 270,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep2:13",
    "question": "Nephi writes that his older brothers were like the Jews who sought to take away the life of his father.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 271,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:14",
    "question": "Lehi spoke to Laman and Lemuel in the valley of_____, with great power.",
    "answer": "Lemuel"
  },
  {
    "id": 272,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:14",
    "question": "Lehi spoke to his eldest sons with great power because he was filled with the____ of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },
  {
    "id": 273,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep2:14",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel’s frame_____ because of the spirit of the Lord in Lehi.",
    "answer": "Shook",
    "options": ["Rocked", "Rolled", "Shook"]
  },
  {
    "id": 274,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep2:14",
    "question": "The words that Lehi spoke confounded Laman and Lemuel.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 275,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep2:15",
    "question": "Nephi writes that Lehi lived in a pretty nice house.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 276,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep2:14",
    "question": "Because of the words Lehi spoke to Laman and Lemuel they did not utter a word against him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 277,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:16",
    "question": "Who was exceedingly young and large in stature?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 278,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep2:16",
    "question": "Nephi did not have a great desire to know of the mysteries of God.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 279,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:16",
    "question": "Nephi cried unto God so that he could know of his_____.",
    "answer": "Mysteries"
  },
  {
    "id": 280,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep2:16",
    "question": "Nephi’s heart was softened when he cried unto the Lord. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 281,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep2:16",
    "question": "Who did the Lord visit when he cried unto him?",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["Laman", "Lamuel", "Nephi"]
  },
  {
    "id": 282,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:16",
    "question": "Because his heart was softened: Nephi, believed all the_____ which had been spoken by his father.",
    "answer": "Words"
  },
  {
    "id": 283,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep2:17",
    "question": "Sam the brother of Nephi; did not believe in the words that Nephi had spoken to him. ",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 284,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep2:17",
    "question": "What brother believed Nephi’s words when he spoke to them concerning the things which the Lord had manifested unto him?",
    "answer": "Sam",
    "options": ["Laman,", "Lemuel", "Sam"]
  },
  {
    "id": 285,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:18",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel would not _____ unto the words that Nephi said to them.",
    "answer": "Hearken"
  },
  {
    "id": 286,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep2:18",
    "question": "Nephi cried unto the Lord because of the _____ of the hearts of his two older brothers.",
    "answer": "Hardness",
    "options": ["Heads", "Hardness", "Softness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 287,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep2:18",
    "question": "Nephi was grieved because of the hardness of the hearts of his two older brothers. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 288,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:19",
    "question": "Who did the Lord visit because of his faith and his lowliness of heart?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 289,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep2:19",
    "question": "Because of his faith, Nephi diligently sought the Lord. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 290,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep2:20 & 1Nep18:22-23",
    "question": "Who did the Lord say that he would lead to a promise land?",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["Nephi", "Lehi", "Laman"]
  },
  {
    "id": 291,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:19-20",
    "question": "Who is the first person the Lord said these words to “in as-much as ye shall keep my commandments, ye shall prosper”.",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 292,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep2:20",
    "question": "The Lord did not prepare a choice land that was above all other lands for Nephi. ",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 293,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep2:20",
    "question": "In as much as Laman and Lemuel rebel against_____; they shall be cut off from the presence of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Lehi",
    "options": ["Lehi", "Neph"]
  },
  {
    "id": 294,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:22",
    "question": "Who did the Lord say needed to keep his commandments and he would be made a teacher and ruler over his older brothers? ",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 295,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:22",
    "question": "Who was chosen to be a ruler and a teacher over his brothers?_____",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 296,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep2:23",
    "question": "In the day that Laman and Lemuel rebel against the Lord, he would curse them with a sore curse.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 297,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:23",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel’s seed shall have no power over the seed of Nephi unless they_____ against the Lord also. ",
    "answer": "Rebel"
  },
  {
    "id": 298,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep3:1",
    "question": "Nephi returned to his____ after he had spoken to the Lord.",
    "answer": "Tent",
    "options": ["House", "Tent", "Sanctuary"]
  },
  {
    "id": 299,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep3:2",
    "question": "In a dream, Lehi was_____ by the Lord to send Nephi and his older brothers back to Jerusalem.",
    "answer": "Commanded",
    "options": ["Told", "Commanded", "Asked"]
  },
  {
    "id": 300,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep3:3",
    "question": "Who had a record of the Jews and also a genealogy of Lehi’s forefathers?",
    "answer": "Laban"
  },
  {
    "id": 301,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep3:3",
    "question": "What type of metal plates was the record of the Jews engraved on?",
    "answer": "Brass",
    "options": ["Gold", "Silver", "Brass"]
  },
  {
    "id": 302,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep3:4",
    "question": "Lehi required that Nephi and his brothers get the record from Laban.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 303,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep3:4",
    "question": "Nephi and his brothers did not go the house of Laban, instead they went to work. ",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 304,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep3:5",
    "question": "Who did Laman and Lemuel murmur against, saying it was a hard thing that the Lord had required of them.",
    "answer": "Lehi",
    "options": ["Lehi", "God", "Nephi"]
  },
  {
    "id": 305,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep3:5",
    "question": "Nephi and his older brothers were required and not commanded to go to the house of Laban by the Lord. ",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 306,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep3:6",
    "question": "Who was favored of the Lord because he did not murmur of the thing that the Lord had commanded of him? ",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 307,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep3:7",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Nephi did as he was commanded. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 308,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep3:7",
    "question": "Nephi said, “I know that the Lord gives no_____ unto the children of men unless he shall prepare a way for them that they may accomplish the thing which he commands them”. ",
    "answer": "Commandments"
  },
  {
    "id": 309,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep3:8",
    "question": "Lehi was pleased because of the words Nephi had said, concerning the commandments of the Lord. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 310,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep3:9",
    "question": "Nephi and his brothers went up to what city to get the plates?",
    "answer": "Jerusalem"
  },
  {
    "id": 311,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep3:10",
    "question": "Nephi and his brothers did not consult with one another when they got to Jerusalem for the plates. ",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 312,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep3:11",
    "question": "How did Nephi and his brothers do to decide which one of them would go to the house of Laban to get the plates?",
    "answer": "Cast Lots",
    "options": ["Draw Straws", "Cast Lots", "Played Paper, Rock, Scissors."]
  },
  {
    "id": 313,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep3:11",
    "question": "Who was the first person decided upon to go to the house of Laban to get the brass plates?_____",
    "answer": "Laman"
  },
  {
    "id": 314,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep3:11",
    "question": "Concerning the plates, Laman talked with Laban in his_____.",
    "answer": "House",
    "options": ["House", "Tent", "Treasury"]
  },
  {
    "id": 315,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep3:12",
    "question": "Laman desired of Laban the records which were engraved upon the plates of brass. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 316,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep3:12",
    "question": "The plates of brass contained the_____ of Nephi’s father. ",
    "answer": "Genealogy"
  },
  {
    "id": 317,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep3:13",
    "question": "Laban welcomed Laman with open arms and hugs when he arrived to his house. ",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 318,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep3:13",
    "question": "Laban did not want to give the brass plates to Laman. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 319,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep3:13",
    "question": "Laban accused Laman of being a _____.",
    "answer": "Robber",
    "options": ["Thief", "Robber", "Swindler."]
  },
  {
    "id": 320,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep3:14",
    "question": "Who fled out of the presence of Laban and told Nephi and his brothers what Laban had done? ",
    "answer": "Laman"
  },
  {
    "id": 321,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep3:14",
    "question": "Nephi and his brothers began to be exceedingly_____ because of the things Laban had done.",
    "answer": "Sorrowful",
    "options": ["Sorrowful", "Angry", "Crazy"]
  },
  {
    "id": 322,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep3:14",
    "question": "Nephi’s brothers were about to return to their father in the wilderness because of what Laban had done. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 323,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep3:15",
    "question": "Who said: “As the Lord lives, and as we live, we will not go down unto our father until we have accomplished the things he has commanded”. ",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 324,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep3:16",
    "question": "Wherefore, let us be faithful in keeping the_____ of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Commandments",
    "options": ["Statues", "Laws", "Commandments"]
  },
  {
    "id": 325,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep3:16",
    "question": "Lehi left behind all his gold, silver, and all manner of riches when he left Jerusalem.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 326,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep3:17",
    "question": "Lehi knew that Jerusalem must be destroyed because of the _____ of the people.",
    "answer": "Wickedness",
    "options": ["Filthiness", "Lawlessness", "Wickedness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 327,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep3:18",
    "question": "The _____ of Jerusalem rejected the words of the prophets. ",
    "answer": "Jews"
  },
  {
    "id": 328,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep3:19",
    "question": "Nephi said: 'it is the wisdom in God that we should obtain these records'. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 329,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep3:19",
    "question": "And behold, it is wisdom in God that we should obtain these records that we may preserve the_____ of our fathers. ",
    "answer": "Language"
  },
  {
    "id": 330,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep3:20",
    "question": "Nephi wanted to preserve the words that had been spoken by the holy prophets unto his children. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 331,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep3:20",
    "question": "The words of the holy prophets have been delivered to them by the Spirit and _____ of God, since the world began, even down to the present time. ",
    "answer": "Power"
  },
  {
    "id": 332,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep3:21",
    "question": "Nephi wanted to persuade Laman and Lemuel to _____",
    "answer": "Be Faithful In Keeping The Commandments Of God.",
    "options": [
      "Slay Laban",
      "Bribe Laban",
      "Be Faithful In Keeping The Commandments Of God."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 333,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep3:22",
    "question": "Nephi and his brothers went down to the land of their inheritance and gathered their gold, silver, and their_____ things. ",
    "answer": "Precious"
  },
  {
    "id": 334,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep3:24",
    "question": "Nephi and his brothers wanted to trade their gold, silver and their precious things for the brass plates. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 335,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep3:25",
    "question": "When Laban saw the property of Nephi and his brothers and that it was exceedingly great, he did_____ after it.",
    "answer": "Lust",
    "options": ["Desire", "Seek", "Lust"]
  },
  {
    "id": 336,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep3:26",
    "question": "Nephi and his brothers fled from Laban and had to leave their property behind which fell into the hands of Zoram. ",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 337,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep3:26-27",
    "question": "Who did Laban send to slay Nephi and his brothers?",
    "answer": "His Servants",
    "options": ["His Bodyguards", "His Servants", "His Army"]
  },
  {
    "id": 338,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep3:27",
    "question": "Where did Nephi and his brothers hide that the servants of Laban could not overtake them?",
    "answer": "Cavity Of A Rock",
    "options": ["Shed", "Forest", "Cavity Of A Rock"]
  },
  {
    "id": 339,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep3:28",
    "question": "Who was angry with Nephi, Lehi and Lemuel? ",
    "answer": "Laman"
  },
  {
    "id": 340,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep3:28",
    "question": "Lemuel would not hearken unto Nephi, but hearkened unto_____. ",
    "answer": "Laman"
  },
  {
    "id": 341,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep3:28-29",
    "question": "An angel appeared to Laman and Lemuel as they hit Nephi and his younger brother with a rod.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 342,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep3:29",
    "question": "The angel told Laman and Lemuel that the Lord had chosen Nephi to be a ruler over them. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 343,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep3:29",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel were told by the angel that the Lord had chosen Nephi to be ruler over them because of their_____.",
    "answer": "Iniquities",
    "options": ["Partying", "Slothfulness", "Iniquities"]
  },
  {
    "id": 344,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep3:29",
    "question": "The angel told the sons of Lehi that the_____ would deliver Laban into their hands.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 345,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep3:31",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel began to_____ when the angel departed.",
    "answer": "Murmur"
  },
  {
    "id": 346,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep3:31",
    "question": "How many men did Laman and Lemuel say that Laban can command to slay them?",
    "answer": "50",
    "options": ["30", "40", "50"]
  },
  {
    "id": 347,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep4:1",
    "question": "Who is mightier than Laban and his fifty?",
    "answer": "The Lord",
    "options": ["Nephi,", "Laman,", "The Lord"]
  },
  {
    "id": 348,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep4:2",
    "question": "Who spoke to the waters of the Red Sea and they divided?",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },
  {
    "id": 349,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep4:2",
    "question": "When Moses and Nephi’s forefathers came through the Red Sea it had not yet dried. ",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 350,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep4:2",
    "question": "The armies of the_____ followed Moses and the Israelites and were drowned in the waters of the Red Sea.",
    "answer": "Pharaoh"
  },
  {
    "id": 351,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep4:3",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel knew that the things concerning Moses were not true. ",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 352,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep4:3",
    "question": "Nephi told his brothers that they knew that an angel of the Lord had spoken to them and they should not doubt. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 353,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep4:4",
    "question": "Nephi said the Lord can deliver them even as their fathers, and to destroy Laban, even as he did to the_____.",
    "answer": "Egyptians"
  },
  {
    "id": 354,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep4:5",
    "question": "Nephi went to Laban's house during a sunny afternoon. ",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 355,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep4:6",
    "question": "Nephi was led to the house of Laban by the_____ even though he did not know what to do.",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },
  {
    "id": 356,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep4:7",
    "question": "What in the name of the man that Nephi saw and had fallen to the earth because he had too much wine?",
    "answer": "Laban"
  },
  {
    "id": 357,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep4:9",
    "question": "The hilt of Laban’s sword was made of pure gold and the blade of precious steel.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 358,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep4:10",
    "question": "Who told Nephi to slay Laban?",
    "answer": "The Spirit",
    "options": ["The Spirit", "Laman", "Lemuel"]
  },
  {
    "id": 359,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep4:10",
    "question": "How many times had Nephi killed before he took Laban’s life?",
    "answer": "Never",
    "options": ["1", "2", "Never"]
  },
  {
    "id": 360,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep4:10-12",
    "question": "The Spirit told Nephi _____ times to slay Laban.",
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "id": 361,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep4:13",
    "question": "The Lord slays the _____ to bring to forth his righteous purposes.",
    "answer": "Wicked",
    "options": ["Ugly", "Rich", "Wicked"]
  },
  {
    "id": 362,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep4:13",
    "question": "Who said “it is better that one man should perish than that a nation should dwindle and perish in unbelief”",
    "answer": "The Lord",
    "options": ["Nephi", "Lehi", "The Lord"]
  },
  {
    "id": 363,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep4:15-16",
    "question": "The lawords of Mosmones was engraved upon the",
    "answer": "Brass Plates",
    "options": ["Gold Plates", "Brass Plates", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": 364,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep4:17",
    "question": "Nephi did not know that the Lord had delivered Laban into his hands. ",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 365,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep4:17",
    "question": "Who commanded Nephi to get the records from Laban?",
    "answer": "The Lord",
    "options": ["Laman", "Lehi", "The Lord"]
  },
  {
    "id": 366,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep4:18",
    "question": "Nephi did not obey the Spirit, and decided not to slay Laban. ",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 367,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep4:18",
    "question": "Nephi slew_____ by grabbing his hair and cutting of his head with his own sword.",
    "answer": "Laban"
  },
  {
    "id": 368,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep4:19",
    "question": "Nephi put on Laban’s garments and armor about his loins so that he could fool his servant. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 369,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep4:20",
    "question": "Where did Laban store the brass plates?",
    "answer": "His Treasury",
    "options": ["His House", "His Treasury", "Safe Deposit Box"]
  },
  {
    "id": 370,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep4:20",
    "question": "Nephi commanded Laban’s servant with the voice of Laban that he should go with him to the treasury.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 371,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep4:20,35",
    "question": "What servant of Laban had the keys to the treasury?",
    "answer": "Zoram"
  },
  {
    "id": 372,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep4:21",
    "question": "The servant thought that Nephi was _____ because he had his garments and the sword girded about his loins.",
    "answer": "Laban"
  },
  {
    "id": 373,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep4:22",
    "question": "Laban had been out with the elders of the Jews before he was slain.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 374,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep4:24,4:38,5:14",
    "question": "The things we call the “Brass Plates” are never referred as such in the Book of Mormon. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 375,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep13:13,19:21,22:30",
    "question": "The things we call the “Brass Plates” are only referred to as the Plates of_____ in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "Brass"
  },
  {
    "id": 376,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep4:28",
    "question": "Nephi’s brothers thought that Nephi was Laban and were exceedingly frightened. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 377,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep4:32-33",
    "question": "Nephi made a covenant with Zoram that he would not harm him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 378,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep4:33",
    "question": "Nephi told Zoram if he would follow him and his brothers that he would be a _____ like them.",
    "answer": "Free",
    "options": ["Free", "Happy Guy", "Virtuous Man"]
  },
  {
    "id": 379,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep4:34",
    "question": "Nephi said unto Zoram “Surely the Lord hath commanded us to do this thing”. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 380,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep4:35",
    "question": "Zoram promised Nephi and his brothers that he would go down to the _____ and tarry with them from that time forth.",
    "answer": "Wilderness"
  },
  {
    "id": 381,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep4:37",
    "question": "When_____ made an oath to Nephi and his brothers their fears concerning him ceased.",
    "answer": "Zoram"
  },
  {
    "id": 382,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep5:1",
    "question": "Nephi’s mothers’ name was",
    "answer": "Sariah",
    "options": ["Sarah", "Akish", "Sariah"]
  },
  {
    "id": 383,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep5:1",
    "question": "Sariah had truly mourned because of her_____.",
    "answer": "Sons",
    "options": ["Aches", "Husband", "Sons"]
  },
  {
    "id": 384,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep5:2",
    "question": "Sariah complained to Lehi about leaving the land of their inheritance.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 385,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep5:2",
    "question": "Sariah said that Lehi was a “visionary man”",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 386,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep5:4",
    "question": "Lehi said that if he had not seen the things of God in a vision he would not have known the_____ of God, and perished with his brethren.",
    "answer": "Goodness"
  },
  {
    "id": 387,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep5:5",
    "question": "Lehi told Sariah that he had obtained a land or promise and knew that the Lord would deliver his sons out of the hands of _____.",
    "answer": "Laban"
  },
  {
    "id": 388,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep5:6",
    "question": "Sariah was comforted by the words that Lehi said concerning the land of promise and their sons. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 389,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep5:7,8",
    "question": "When her sons returned from the wilderness, Sariah said that now she knew that the Lord had commanded Lehi and delivered her sons from Laban. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 390,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep5:8",
    "question": "Who commanded Lehi to flee into the wilderness?",
    "answer": "The Lord",
    "options": ["Elders Of The Jews", "The Lord", "Moses"]
  },
  {
    "id": 391,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep5:9",
    "question": "And it came to pass, that they did rejoice exceedingly, and did offer_____ and burnt offerings unto the Lord.",
    "answer": "Sacrifice",
    "options": ["Gold", "Sacrifice", "Silver"]
  },
  {
    "id": 392,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep5:10",
    "question": "Lehi searched the brass plateds diligently.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 393,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep5:11",
    "question": "Lehi beheld that the plates of brass contained the 6 books of Moses",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 394,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep5:11",
    "question": "The five books of Moses gave an account of the creation of the world and also of _____, who were our first parents.",
    "answer": "Adam and Eve"
  },
  {
    "id": 395,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep5:12",
    "question": "The five books of Moses also gave a record of the Jews from the beginning; even down to the commencement of the reign of king _____.",
    "answer": "Zedekiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 396,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep5:12",
    "question": "The five books of Moses also contained the prophecies of the holy prophets from the beginning, even down the commencement of the reign of Zedekiah. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  { "id": 397, "type": "fill", "ref": "", "question": "", "answer": "Israel" },
  {
    "id": 398,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep5:12",
    "question": "Moses’ books also contained the prophecies spoken by the mouth of what prophet? Who was arrested during the reign of Zedekiah on suspicion of desertion.",
    "answer": "Jeremiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 399,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep5:13",
    "question": "The record that Lehi beheld contained many prophecies which have been spoken by the mouth of Jeremiah the prophet. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 400,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep5:14",
    "question": "Joseph was the son of _____, who was sold into Egypt.",
    "answer": "Jacob"
  },
  {
    "id": 401,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep5:16",
    "question": "The reason Laban had the brass plates was that, he also was a descendant of Joseph who was sold into Egypt",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 402,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep5:19",
    "question": "Lehi said that the plates of brass should never perish, nor be dimmed any more by time",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 403,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep5:21",
    "question": "Nephi said that they had obtained the records and searched them and found that they were of great_____ unto them.",
    "answer": "Worth",
    "options": ["Calamities", "Worth", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 404,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep5:22",
    "question": "Lehi said it is wisdom in him, that they should carry the plates of brass into the wilderness",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 405,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep6:1",
    "question": "Nephi did not give the genealogy of his fathers because they had already been given in the record that Lehi had. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 406,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep6:3",
    "question": "Nephi desired to save room in the plates so he could write the things of _____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 407,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep6:5",
    "question": "Nephi wrote things which were pleasing unto the world",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 408,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep6:6",
    "question": "Nephi gave a commandment unto his seed to write only things which were of great worth unto the children of men",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 409,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep7:1",
    "question": "Who commanded Lehi’s sons to take the daughters of Ismael to wife; to raise up seed unto the Lord in the land of promise?",
    "answer": ["God", "Lord"]
  },
  {
    "id": 410,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep7:2",
    "question": "Nephi and his brethren were commanded by the Lord to return to Jerusalem and get _____ and his family, into the wilderness with them.",
    "answer": "Ishmael"
  },
  {
    "id": 411,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep7:5",
    "question": "The Lord softened the heart of Ishmael and his household.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 412,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep7:6-7",
    "question": "Some of Ishmeal’s sons and daughters desired to return to the land of Jerusalem",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 413,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep7:10",
    "question": "Nephi asked his older brothers- “How is it that ye have forgotten that ye have seen an angel of the Lord?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 414,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep7:12",
    "question": "What must we do for the Lord to do all things according to his will?",
    "answer": "Exercise Faith In Him",
    "options": [
      "Exercise Faith In Him",
      "Obey His Commandments",
      "Obey Our Parents"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 415,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep7:14",
    "question": "The people of Jerusalem rejected the prophets and cast the prophet_____ into prison.",
    "answer": "Jeremiah",
    "options": ["Zedekiah", "Samuel The Lamanite", "Jeremiah"]
  },
  {
    "id": 416,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep7:14",
    "question": "The Spirit of the Lord ceased to strive in the people of Jerusalem because they had cast out the prophets. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 417,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep7:15",
    "question": "Who told Nephi to tell Laman and Lemuel not to go back to Jerusalem or they would perish also?",
    "answer": ["God", "Lord"]
  },
  {
    "id": 418,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep7:16",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel became angry with Nephi and bound him with cords and sought to take away his life",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 419,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep7:17-18",
    "question": "How did Nephi loosen the cords that he was bound with?",
    "answer": "Prayed Unto The Lord For Strength",
    "options": [
      "Butter Knife",
      "Sharp Steak Knife",
      "Prayed Unto The Lord For Strength"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 420,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Neph17:18",
    "question": "Who witnessed the power of God when Nephi's bonds were released?",
    "answer": "Laman",
    "options": ["Joseph", "Sam", "Laman"]
  },
  {
    "id": 421,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep7:19",
    "question": "Because of the words of Ismael’s son and others, the hearts of Laman and Lemuel were softened and they did not desire to take away the life of Nephi for a second time. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 422,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep7:19",
    "question": "The wife of_____defended Nephi with her daughter against Laman and Lemuel.",
    "answer": "Ishmael"
  },
  {
    "id": 423,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep7:20",
    "question": "Nephi’s brothers bowed down before him and pleaded for forgiveness for what they had done to him",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 424,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep7:21",
    "question": "Nephi forgave his brothers for all that they had done to him and exhorted them that they should pray unto the Lord their ____ for forgiveness.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 425,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep8:1",
    "question": "Lehi and his family gathered together all manner of _____ of every kind.",
    "answer": "Seeds",
    "options": ["Animals", "Seeds", "Wild Beasts"]
  },
  {
    "id": 426,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep8:2",
    "question": "While Lehi tarried in the wilderness he spoke to his sons and said he had a dream; or, in other words, I have seen a _____.",
    "answer": "Vision"
  },
  {
    "id": 427,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep8:3",
    "question": "Because of the things that he saw in his vision, Lehi had a reason to rejoice in his sons Nephi and _____.",
    "answer": "Sam"
  },
  {
    "id": 428,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep8:3",
    "question": "In Lehi’s vision, he saw that many of the seed of Nephi and Sam would be saved. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 429,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep8:4",
    "question": "Because of his vision Lehi feared exceedingly for____ and Lamuel.",
    "answer": "Laman"
  },
  {
    "id": 430,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep8:5",
    "question": "Lehi saw in his vision a man dressed in a white_____, and he came and stood before him.",
    "answer": "Robe",
    "options": ["Shirt", "Long Coat", "Robe"]
  },
  {
    "id": 431,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep8:6",
    "question": "The man dressed in a white robe asked Lehi to follow him. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 432,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep8:8",
    "question": "Lehi traveled for many hours in darkness and began to pray to the Lord to have_____ on him.",
    "answer": "Mercy",
    "options": ["Pity", "Mercy", "Sympathy"]
  },
  {
    "id": 433,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep8:9",
    "question": "And it came to pass after Lehi prayed unto the Lord he beheld a large and_____ field.",
    "answer": "Spacious"
  },
  {
    "id": 434,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep8:10",
    "question": "Lehi saw a vision of a tree whose fruit was desirable to make one happy.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 435,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep8:11",
    "question": "As Lehi partook of the fruit of the tree he beheld that it was most sweet and white to exceed all the whiteness that he had ever seen.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 436,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep8:12",
    "question": "When Lehi partook of the fruit thereof it filled his _____ with exceeding great joy.",
    "answer": "Soul",
    "options": ["Head", "Soul", "Body"]
  },
  {
    "id": 437,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep8:12",
    "question": "Lehi desired that his family would partake of the fruit also, because he knew that it was desirable above all other fruit. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 438,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep8:13",
    "question": "Lehi beheld that a river of water that ran along and near the tree of the fruit that he was partaking of.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 439,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep8:14-16",
    "question": "Lehi and part of his family realized that the fruit of the tree was most desirable above all other fruit.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 440,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep8:14,16",
    "question": "Lehi saw in his vision that Nephi, Sam, and_____, partook of the fruit of the tree.",
    "answer": "Sariah"
  },
  {
    "id": 441,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep8:17-18",
    "question": "Laman and Lamuel did not partake of the fruit of the tree.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 442,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep8:19",
    "question": "The _____ of iron extended along the bank of the river and led to the tree of life.",
    "answer": "Rod",
    "options": ["Shaft", "Pipe", "Rod"]
  },
  {
    "id": 443,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep8:20",
    "question": "Lehi beheld a straight and_____ path, which came along the rod of iron. ",
    "answer": "Narrow"
  },
  {
    "id": 444,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep8:20",
    "question": "The straight and narrow path also led unto the large and spacious field. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 445,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep8:20",
    "question": "Lehi referred to the large and spacious field as if had been a world. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 446,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep8:21",
    "question": "Lehi saw numberless_____ of people who were pressing forward that they might obtain the path that led to the tree. ",
    "answer": "Concourses"
  },
  {
    "id": 447,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep8:23",
    "question": "And it came to pass that a great_____ of darkness arose. ",
    "answer": "Mist"
  },
  {
    "id": 448,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep8:23",
    "question": "The mist of darkness caused a lot of people to wander off and lose their way to the tree of life.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 449,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep8:24",
    "question": "Lehi beheld others pressing forward and_____ to the rod of iron and partake of the fruit of the tree.",
    "answer": "Clinging",
    "options": ["Holding", "Hanging", "Clinging"]
  },
  {
    "id": 450,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep8:25",
    "question": "After they had partaken of the fruit of the tree, the people cast their eyes about as if they were ashamed. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 451,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep8:26",
    "question": "Lehi cast his eyes round about, and beheld, on the other side of the river of water, a_____ and spacious building. ",
    "answer": "Great"
  },
  {
    "id": 452,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep8:26",
    "question": "The great and spacious building stood as if it were in the air and high above the earth.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 453,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep8:27",
    "question": "The great and spacious building was filled with people, both old and young, both_____ and female. ",
    "answer": "Male"
  },
  {
    "id": 454,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep8:27",
    "question": "The people in the great and spacious building were dress exceedingly _____.",
    "answer": "Fine",
    "options": ["Ugly", "Terrible", "Fine"]
  },
  {
    "id": 455,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep8:27",
    "question": "The people in the great and spacious building pointed their _____ and made fun of Nephi and all of those that partook of the fruit of the tree.",
    "answer": "Fingers",
    "options": ["Guns", "Spears", "Fingers"]
  },
  {
    "id": 456,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep8:28",
    "question": "And after they had tasted of the fruit they were ashamed, because of those that were scoffing at them, and they fell away into forbidden paths and were lost. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 457,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep8:29",
    "question": "Nephi spoke of all the words of his father; concerning the vision that he had. ",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 458,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep8:30",
    "question": "Lehi saw other multitudes pressing forward, continually holding fast to the rod of iron. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 459,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep8:31",
    "question": "Lehi saw other multitudes_____ their way towards the great and spacious building.",
    "answer": "Feeling",
    "options": ["Holding", "Feeling", "Clinging"]
  },
  {
    "id": 460,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep8:32",
    "question": "Lehi saw many drowned in the depths of the fountain and were lost from his view. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 461,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep8:32",
    "question": "Lehi also saw in his vision that many were wandering in strange_____.",
    "answer": "Roads",
    "options": ["Roads", "Paths", "Highways"]
  },
  {
    "id": 462,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep8:33",
    "question": "In Lehi’s vision great was the multitude that_____.",
    "answer": "Entered Into That Strange Building",
    "options": [
      "Took Of The Rod Of Iron",
      "Entered Into That Strange Building",
      "Entered Into The Straight And Narrow Path"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 463,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep8:33",
    "question": "After they had entered into the strange building, they pointed their fingers to Nephi and scorned at him and those that had partaken of the fruit. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 464,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep8:35",
    "question": "Laman and____ did not partake of the fruit according to Lehi. ",
    "answer": "Lemuel"
  },
  {
    "id": 465,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep8:36",
    "question": "Lehi feared exceedingly for Laman and Lemuel lest they should be cast off from the presence of the_____. ",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 466,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep8:37",
    "question": "Lehi exhorted Laman and Lemuel with all the feeling of a _____ parent.",
    "answer": "Tender",
    "options": ["Tender", "Grateful", "Kind"]
  },
  {
    "id": 467,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep8:38",
    "question": "After Lehi preached unto Laman and Lemuel, he prophesied unto them many things and bade them to keep the_____. ",
    "answer": "Commandments"
  },
  {
    "id": 468,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep9:1",
    "question": "And all these things did my father see, and hear, and_____, as he dwelt in a tent, in the valley of Lemuel.",
    "answer": "Speak"
  },
  {
    "id": 469,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep9:1",
    "question": "What is the name of the valley where Lehi saw, heard, and spoke of many great things?",
    "answer": "Lemuel",
    "options": ["Death Valley", "Lemuel", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 470,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep9:1",
    "question": "Lehi saw, heard, and spoke of many great things that cannot be written upon the plates of Nephi. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 471,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep9:2",
    "question": "The plates of Nephi are given that name because they contain a full account of the history of the people of _____.",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["Christ", "Nephi", "Lehi"]
  },
  {
    "id": 472,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep9:4",
    "question": "Nephi knew that in the future, there would be a reign of kings among his people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 473,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep9:4",
    "question": "The plates of Nephi are written mostly of his ministry.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 474,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep9:4",
    "question": "The other plates that are written are for the more part of the reign of_____ and the wars and contentions of the people of Nephi. ",
    "answer": "Kings"
  },
  {
    "id": 475,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep9:5",
    "question": "Nephi made another set of plates that he did not know for what purpose.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 476,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep9:6",
    "question": "Nephi said the “Lord knows all things from the beginning; wherefore, he prepares a way to accomplish all his works among the children of men”.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 477,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep10:2",
    "question": "Lehi exhorted his sons with all diligence and also spoke to them concerning the_____ at Jerusalem. ",
    "answer": "Jews"
  },
  {
    "id": 478,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep10:3",
    "question": "Lehi said that Jerusalem would be destroyed and many would be carried away captive to _____. ",
    "answer": "Babylon"
  },
  {
    "id": 479,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep10:3",
    "question": "Lehi said that the Jews would be brought back out of captivity and possess again the land of their inheritance, in the Lords’ own due time. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 480,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep10:4",
    "question": "The Lord God would rise up a _____ 600 years after Lehi left Jerusalem.-Messiah",
    "answer": "Savior"
  },
  {
    "id": 481,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep10:4",
    "question": "Lehi said that the Messiah would only be a savior to the most righteous people of the world.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 482,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep10:5",
    "question": "Lehi also spoke concerning the prophets and how great a number had testified concerning the_____. ",
    "answer": "Messiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 483,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep10:5",
    "question": "Nephi also referred to the Savior as the_____ of the world. ",
    "answer": "Redeemer"
  },
  {
    "id": 484,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep10:6",
    "question": "“Wherefore, all mankind were in a lost and in a_____ state, and ever would be save they should rely on this redeemer”. ",
    "answer": "Fallen"
  },
  {
    "id": 485,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep10:7",
    "question": "Lehi also spoke of a_____ who should come before the Messiah, to prepare the way of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Prophet",
    "options": ["Person", "Man", "Prophet"]
  },
  {
    "id": 486,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep10:7-10, 1Nep11:27, 2Nep31:4",
    "question": "The Book of Mormon never mentions John the Baptist by name.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 487,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep10:7-10, 1Nep11:27, 2Nep31:4",
    "question": "The Book of Mormon only references John the Baptist three times and never by name, but only as a prophet. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 488,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep10:7-11",
    "question": "Who predicted the birth, baptism, death, and resurrection of the Messiah?_____.",
    "answer": "Lehi",
    "options": ["Lehi", "Laban)", "Zoram"]
  },
  { "id": 489, "type": "fill", "ref": "", "question": "", "answer": "" },
  {
    "id": 490,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep10:8",
    "question": "This prophet of the Lord would go forth and cry in the wilderness:”Prepare ye the way of the Lord, and make his paths straight”. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 491,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep10:8",
    "question": "For there stands one among you whom ye know not, whose____ latchet I am not worthy to unloose.",
    "answer": "shoe"
  },
  {
    "id": 492,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep10:8",
    "question": "The prophet of the Lord said that there was one among them that was mightier than him. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 493,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "INep10:9",
    "question": "What is the name of the place where Lehi said that the Messiah would be baptized?",
    "answer": "Bethabara"
  },
  {
    "id": 494,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "INep10:9",
    "question": "Lehi said that Bethabara was located by_____.",
    "answer": "Beyond Jordan",
    "options": ["Utah", "Iowa", "Beyond Jordan"]
  },
  {
    "id": 495,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep10:9",
    "question": "Who would baptize the Messiah with water?",
    "answer": "A Prophet",
    "options": ["Alma", "A Prophet", "Mosiah"]
  },
  {
    "id": 496,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep10:10",
    "question": "Lehi said that the prophet that would baptize the Lamb of God should behold and bear record that he was the Messiah, and should take away the sins of the world. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 497,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep10:10",
    "question": "Who would bear record that he baptized the Lamb of God?",
    "answer": "A Prophet",
    "options": ["Nephi", "Laman", "A Prophet"]
  },
  {
    "id": 498,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep10:11",
    "question": "Lehi spoke to Nephi’s brothers concerning the gospel which should be preached among the Jews and their dwindling in unbelief. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 499,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep10:11",
    "question": "Who did Lehi say would slay the Messiah?",
    "answer": "jews"
  },
  {
    "id": 500,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep10:11",
    "question": "Lehi said that the Messiah would rise from the dead and make himself manifest by the _____ unto the Gentiles.",
    "answer": "Holy Ghost"
  },
  {
    "id": 501,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep10:12",
    "question": "The Gentiles and the house of Israel would be compared like unto an olive-tree and should be scattered upon the face of the earth.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 502,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep10:13",
    "question": "Lehi said that they should be led with one accord into the land of_____ unto the fulfilling of the word of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Promise"
  },
  {
    "id": 503,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep10:16",
    "question": "When Lehi prophesied about the Gentiles and the house of Israel he dwelt in a tent, in the valley of _____.",
    "answer": "Lemuel",
    "options": ["Gideon", "Lemuel", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": 504,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep10:17",
    "question": "Nephi heard all the words of his father, concerning the things which he saw in a vision. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 505,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep10:17",
    "question": "By what power did Lehi prophesy the things concerning the Gentiles and the house of Israel?",
    "answer": "Holy Ghost"
  },
  {
    "id": 506,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep10:17",
    "question": "What is the gift given to all those who diligently seek God?",
    "answer": "Holy Ghost",
    "options": ["Eternal Life", "Holy Ghost", "Eternal Happiness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 507,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep10:17",
    "question": "We receive the power of the Holy Ghost by having_____ in the Son of God.",
    "answer": "Faith",
    "options": ["Faith", "Diligence", "Contrite Spirit"]
  },
  {
    "id": 508,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep10:18",
    "question": "The way is prepared for all men from the foundation of the world, if it so be that they repent and come unto him. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 509,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep10:19",
    "question": "By the power of the Holy Ghost the _____ of God are revealed to those that diligently seek him.",
    "answer": "Mysteries",
    "options": ["Things", "Mysteries", "Secrets"]
  },
  {
    "id": 510,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep10:21",
    "question": "Wherefore, if ye have sought to do wickedly in the days of your_____, then ye are found unclean before the judgment-seat of God.",
    "answer": "Probation"
  },
  {
    "id": 511,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep10:21",
    "question": "If you are unclean and repent you can still enter the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 512,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep10:22",
    "question": "Who gave authority to Nephi to speak and write the things he did and not deny them?",
    "answer": "Holy Ghost",
    "options": ["Jesus Christ", "Holy Ghost", "God"]
  },
  {
    "id": 513,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep10:23",
    "question": "We are free to act for ourselves-to choose the way of everlasting death or the way of eternal life.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 514,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep11:1",
    "question": "Nephi desired to know the things which his father had seen.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 515,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep11:1",
    "question": "Nephi was carried away in the _____ of the Lord into an exceedingly high mountain.",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },
  {
    "id": 516,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep11:1",
    "question": "The name of the mountain that Nephi was carried away is named.",
    "answer": "We Don’t Know",
    "options": ["Sinai", "Hoeb", "We Don’t Know"]
  },
  {
    "id": 517,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep11:7",
    "question": "Nephi was to witness and bear record that the man he saw descending out of heaven, was the Son of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 518,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep11:8",
    "question": "Nephi beheld that the tree the Spirit of Lord showed him, exceeded the whiteness of the driven snow.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 519,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep11:9",
    "question": "The tree that Nephi was shown by the Spirit was precious above all things.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 520,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep11:13",
    "question": "Nephi beheld in his vision, the city of Nazareth.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 521,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep11:13",
    "question": "Nephi saw in his vision a _____ who was exceedingly fair and white.",
    "answer": "Virgin"
  },
  {
    "id": 522,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep11:1",
    "question": "Who did Nephi see that was the mother of the Son of God, after the manner of the flesh?",
    "answer": "Virgin"
  },
  {
    "id": 523,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:8, Alma7:",
    "question": "What is the name of the Savior's mother?",
    "answer": "Mary"
  },
  {
    "id": 524,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep11:19-20",
    "question": "When Nephi beheld the virgin the second time, she was bearing a child in her arms.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 525,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep11:16",
    "question": "The Spirit of the Lord asked Nephi if he knew the condescension of God.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 526,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep11:21",
    "question": "Other names for the Savior are_____of God and Son of the Eternal Father.",
    "answer": "Lamb"
  },
  {
    "id": 527,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1 Nep11:23",
    "question": "The angel said that the love of God is the most joyous to the soul.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 528,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep11:25",
    "question": "What did the Rod of Iron represent in Lehi’s vision?",
    "answer": "Word"
  },
  {
    "id": 529,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep11:27",
    "question": "The Holy Ghost appeared in the form of a_____ after Jesus Christ was baptized.",
    "answer": "Dove"
  },
  {
    "id": 530,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep11:33",
    "question": "Who was gathered together to fight against the apostles of the Lamb of God.",
    "answer": "People Of The Earth",
    "options": ["Israel", "People Of The Earth", "Lamanites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 531,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep11:36",
    "question": "Nephi saw in his vision the great and spacious building fall.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 532,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep12:9",
    "question": "Who is to judge the twelve tribes of Israel?",
    "answer": "12 Apostles Of The Lamb Of God",
    "options": ["God", "Jesus Christ", "12 Apostles Of The Lamb Of God"]
  },
  {
    "id": 533,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep12:1-2",
    "question": "Nephi beheld his seed and the seed of his brothers gathered together to do battle one with another. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 534,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep12:1",
    "question": "Nephi saw the land of promise in his vision.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 535,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep12:6, 2Nep26:1,9",
    "question": "Nephi saw the heavens open and Jesus Christ descending out of heaven and appearing to the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 536,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep12:11",
    "question": "Because of the _____ in the Lamb of God the garments of the twelve disciples are made white in his blood.",
    "answer": "Faith",
    "options": ["Faith", "Greatness", "The Ivory Soap"]
  },
  {
    "id": 537,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep12:11",
    "question": "Because of their faith, _____generations passed away in righteousness and their garments were made white, even like unto the Lamb of God.",
    "answer": "3",
    "options": ["2", "12", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": 538,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep12:16",
    "question": "Another name that can describe the fountain of filthy water and the depths thereof is.",
    "answer": "Hell",
    "options": ["The Amazon", "The Euphrates", "Hell"]
  },
  {
    "id": 539,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep12:16",
    "question": "The mists of darkness which Nephi saw are the temptations of the devil.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 540,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep12:18",
    "question": "Another name that can be used to describe the large and spacious building which Lehi saw are; the vain imaginations of the children of men.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 541,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep12:18",
    "question": "What personage bears record from the beginning of the world to Nephi’s time and forever that Jesus Christ is the Messiah?",
    "answer": "Holy Ghost"
  },
  {
    "id": 542,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep12:17",
    "question": "What leads men to broad roads; that they perish and are lost?",
    "answer": "Temptations Of The Devil",
    "options": ["False Prophets", "False Doctrine", "Temptations Of The Devil"]
  },
  {
    "id": 543,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep12:22-23",
    "question": "Who was the angel referring to when he said to Nephi “behold these shall dwindle in unbelief”. - (B)",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["Nephites", "Lamanites", "Gentiles"]
  },
  {
    "id": 544,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep12:23, 2Nep5:21",
    "question": "Because of their pagan beliefs, the Lamanites became a dark, loathsome, and filthy people",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 545,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep13:4",
    "question": "Nephi saw among the nations of the Gentiles, the foundation of a great church.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 546,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep13:5",
    "question": "The abominable church slays the saints of God, and tortures and binds them down with a yoke of iron. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 547,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep13:6",
    "question": "Who is the founder foundation of the great and abominable church?",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },
  {
    "id": 548,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep13:8",
    "question": "Of all these things-which is not a desire of the great abominable church?",
    "answer": "Precious Jewels",
    "options": ["Precious Jewels", "Gold", "Silks"]
  },
  {
    "id": 549,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep13:9",
    "question": "The abominable church destroys the saints of God and brings them down into captivity for the praise of the world. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 550,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep13:10",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Nephi looked and saw many waters that divided the Gentiles from the seed of his_____.",
    "answer": "Brethren"
  },
  {
    "id": 551,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep13:11",
    "question": "The angel told Nephi to look and see that the_____ of God was upon the seed of his brethren.",
    "answer": "Wrath",
    "options": ["Hand", "Wrath", "Spirit"]
  },
  {
    "id": 552,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep13:12",
    "question": "In his vision Nephi saw who we know as Christopher Columbus.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 553,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep13:17",
    "question": "Nephi saw what was later to be known as the Revolutionary War in our time?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 554,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep13:23",
    "question": "The book that the angel showed Nephi proceeded out of the mouth of a Jew",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 555,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep13:24-25",
    "question": "When the book first proceeded from the mouth of the Jew, it contained the purity and plainness of the Gospel?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 556,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep13:28",
    "question": "Who or what took away the many plain parts and precious things from the Bible?",
    "answer": "Abominable Church",
    "options": ["Moses", "Abominable Church", "The Jews"]
  },
  {
    "id": 557,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep13:29",
    "question": "Because of the taking away of many plain and precious things from the book/bible, many people stumble and Satan has great power over them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 558,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep13:34",
    "question": "Who or what is the mother of all harlots?",
    "answer": "Abominable Church",
    "options": ["Eve", "Abominable Church", "Wickedness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 559,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep13:37",
    "question": "In what Book of Mormon book do the words “endure unto the end” first mentioned?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 560,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep13:37",
    "question": "What prophet of the Lord is the first to use the words “endure unto the end”?",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["Nephi", "King Benjamin", "Alma The Elder"]
  },
  {
    "id": 561,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep13:38",
    "question": "Nephi saw the book of the Lamb or God, which had proceeded forth from the mouth of the Jew, come unto the seed of his brethren?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 562,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep13:39",
    "question": "Nephi saw other _____ which would testify to the convincing that the record of Jews and twelve apostles of the Lamb of God are true.",
    "answer": "Other Books",
    "options": [
      "A Proclamation",
      "Other Books",
      "A Marvelous Work And A Wonder"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 563,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon Pictures",
    "question": "What animal appears in the Book of Mormon picture where Lehi is holding the Liahona?",
    "answer": "Camal"
  },
  {
    "id": 564,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep13:40",
    "question": "Nephi saw the last records that were among the Gentiles which would establish the truth of the Bible.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 565,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep13:40",
    "question": "Who must come unto the Savior in order to be saved?",
    "answer": "All Men",
    "options": ["Old People", "Sick People", "All Men"]
  },
  {
    "id": 566,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep13:41",
    "question": "There is only one God and one_____over all the earth.",
    "answer": "Shepherd",
    "options": ["Prophet", "Angel", "Shepherd"]
  },
  {
    "id": 567,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep13:40-42",
    "question": "The angel said that the last shall be first, and the first shall be _____.",
    "answer": "Last"
  },
  {
    "id": 568,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep14:1",
    "question": "If the Gentiles hearken unto the Lamb of God, he would manifest himself unto them; in word, in power and in deed",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 569,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep14:3",
    "question": "Who will fill the great pit that was dug for the destruction of men?",
    "answer": "Those That Digged It",
    "options": [
      "Those That Are Not Baptize",
      "The Wicked",
      "Those That Digged It"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 570,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep14:3",
    "question": "The great and abominable church and its founders, were the ones who dug the great pit?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 571,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep14:6",
    "question": "_____ be unto the Gentiles if it so be that they harden their hearts against the Lamb of God.",
    "answer": "Woe",
    "options": ["Too Bad", "Dang It!", "Woe"]
  },
  {
    "id": 572,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep14:7",
    "question": "The Lord will work a great and _____work among the children of men.",
    "answer": "Marvelous"
  },
  {
    "id": 573,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep14:7",
    "question": "The marvelous work that the Lord will bring forth, will be everlasting –either to the convincing of them or life eternal or unto the deliverance of the hardness of their hearts.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 574,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep14:7",
    "question": "Who will bring down men into captivity both temporally and spiritually?",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },
  {
    "id": 575,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep14:8",
    "question": "The angel asked Nephi if he could remember the covenants the Lord had made with the house of Israel.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 576,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep14:10",
    "question": "In First Nephi, the angel said there are only ____ churches?",
    "answer": "Two",
    "options": ["One", "Two", "Three"]
  },
  {
    "id": 577,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep14:10",
    "question": "The angel revealed to Nephi the _____ of all the earth?",
    "answer": "History",
    "options": ["Wickedness", "Whore", "History"]
  },
  {
    "id": 578,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep14:9,13",
    "question": "Who will gather great multitudes of people to do battle with the Lamb of God?",
    "answer": "Great Abominable Church",
    "options": ["Osama Bin Laden", "Moammar Kadafi", "Great Abominable Church"]
  },
  {
    "id": 579,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep14:14",
    "question": "Who was armed with righteousness and with the power of God in great glory, to do battle with the great and Abominable Church?",
    "answer": "Saints Of The Lamb Of God",
    "options": ["The Jews", "Saints Of The Lamb Of God", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 580,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep14:16-17",
    "question": "Another name we can use to describe the Great and Abominable Church is the “mother of harlots”",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 581,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep14:19-20",
    "question": "Nephi beheld a man dressed in a white robe, who was one of the twelve apostles of the Lamb of God?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 582,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep14:20,21,27",
    "question": "The angel showed Nephi _____ the Revelator.",
    "answer": "John"
  },
  {
    "id": 583,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep14:27",
    "question": "Nephi bore record to us that he saw John the Revelator. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 584,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep:14:21",
    "question": "Nephi writes that John the Revelator will write things that have been concerning the world and also of the end thereof. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 585,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep14:23",
    "question": "In what book are the things written that John the Apostle wrote?",
    "answer": "The Bible",
    "options": ["National Enquire", "The Bible", "Wall Street Journal"]
  },
  {
    "id": 586,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep14:24",
    "question": "Nephi was allowed to see all the things that have been and the ending of the world as we know it?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 587,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep14:25, 27-28",
    "question": "Nephi was commanded to write and bear record of all the things he saw by the Angel of the Lord?",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 588,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "-1Nep14:26",
    "question": "Nephi is not the only person that has seen things that have been and things that are to come of this world?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 589,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep14:29",
    "question": "Nephi testified and bear record of the things his father Lehi saw?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 590,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep15:2",
    "question": "Nephi saw his brothers disputing one with another concerning the things Lehi had spoken to them?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 591,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep15:4-5",
    "question": "Nephi was grieved and afflicted because he saw the destruction and fall of his people. Nephities?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 592,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep15:7-9",
    "question": "Nephi’s brothers did not inquire of the Lord concerning the natural branches of the olive-tree and the Gentiles?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 593,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep15:12",
    "question": "The house of Israel is compared to an_____ tree in the first book of Nephi.",
    "answer": "Olive",
    "options": ["Peach", "Apple", "Olive"]
  },
  {
    "id": 594,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep15:14",
    "question": "Nephi and his brothers’ seed will eventually come to the knowledge that they are of the house of Israel though the gospel of Jesus Christ?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 595,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep15:18",
    "question": "In whose seed shall all the kindred’s of the earth be blessed?",
    "answer": "Abraham’s",
    "options": ["Nephi’s", "Lehi’s", "Abraham’s"]
  },
  {
    "id": 596,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep15:20",
    "question": "What prophet spoke concerning the restoration of the Jews in the latter days?",
    "answer": "Isaiah",
    "options": ["Moses", "Isaiah", "Lehi"]
  },
  {
    "id": 597,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep15:20",
    "question": "According to the prophet Isaiah, after the Jews are restored to the gospel, they will never again be confounded or scattered again. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 598,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep15:21",
    "question": "Nephi’s brothers wanted to know what the tree meant that Lehi saw in his dream.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 599,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep15:22",
    "question": "The tree that Lehi saw was a representation on the Tree of Life?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 600,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep15:24",
    "question": "One way we can fight off the fiery darts and the temptations of the devil is by hearkening and holding on to the Rod of Iron?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 601,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep15:27-28",
    "question": "Nephi said the river of water that separates the wicked from God and also his saints.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 602,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep15:30",
    "question": "The justice of God divides the _____ from the righteous.",
    "answer": "Wicked"
  },
  {
    "id": 603,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep15:32",
    "question": "We will be judged by the works we do when we are in our temporal bodies, and also in the days of our probation.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 604,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep15:34-35",
    "question": "Nephi said there is a place already prepared for the filthy and wicked?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 605,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep15:36",
    "question": "Whose fruit is most precious and most desirable above all other fruits?",
    "answer": "Tree"
  },
  {
    "id": 606,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep15:36",
    "question": "What is the greatest of all gifts that God can bestow upon us, according to Nephi?",
    "answer": "Tree"
  },
  {
    "id": 607,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep16:2",
    "question": "Who takes the truth to be hard and cuts them to the very center?",
    "answer": "The Guilty",
    "options": ["Lamanites", "The Wicked", "The Guilty"]
  },
  {
    "id": 608,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep16:7",
    "question": "Zoram took the _____ daughter of Ishmael to wife?",
    "answer": "Eldest",
    "options": ["Prettiest", "Eldest", "Fairest"]
  },
  {
    "id": 609,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep16:10",
    "question": "Lehi found a round ball made of fine brass and of curious workmanship?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 610,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep16:10",
    "question": "Within the ball that Lehi found was _____spindles.",
    "answer": "2",
    "options": ["5", "2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": 611,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep16:10",
    "question": "One of the spindles in the ball told Lehi and his family which direction they should go in the wilderness.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 612,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep16:12",
    "question": "Lehi departed into the wilderness across the _____ River.",
    "answer": "Laman",
    "options": ["Amazon", "Euphrates", "Laman"]
  },
  {
    "id": 613,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep16:13",
    "question": "After Lehi’s family had traveled for four days-they pitched their tents in a place called _____.",
    "answer": "Shazer",
    "options": ["Egypt", "Shazer", "Idaho"]
  },
  {
    "id": 614,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep16:14",
    "question": "Nephi and his brothers hunted with _____ and _____. ",
    "answer": "no",
    "options": ["Bows and Arrows", "Stones and Slings", "Guns and Knives"]
  },
  {
    "id": 615,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep16:14,16",
    "question": "The directions of the ball led them to the more _____ parts of the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Fertile"
  },
  {
    "id": 616,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep16:18",
    "question": "Nephi’s bow was made of _____ steel.",
    "answer": "Fine",
    "options": ["Expensive", "Cheap", "Fine"]
  },
  {
    "id": 617,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep16:18",
    "question": "Nephi broke his bow and his brothers got angry with him",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 618,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Neph16:20",
    "question": "Lehi and some of his sons began to murmur exceedingly because of their afflictions and sufferings in the wilderness.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 619,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep16:23",
    "question": "Nephi made another bow made out of_____",
    "answer": "Wood",
    "options": ["Steel", "Wood", "Fiberglass"]
  },
  {
    "id": 620,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep16:23",
    "question": "How many arrows did Nephi make for his second bow?",
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "id": 621,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep16:23",
    "question": "Who said “Whither shall I go to obtain food”?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 622,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep16:25",
    "question": "Lehi was brought down to the depths of sorrow, for murmuring.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 623,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep16:29",
    "question": "Nephi said “and thus we see that by _____ means the Lord can bring about great things.",
    "answer": "Small"
  },
  {
    "id": 624,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep16:29",
    "question": "A new writing, which was plain to read, appeared on the ball that Lehi found.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 625,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep16:30-31",
    "question": "Nephi went to the _____ of a mountain to obtain food for him and his family.",
    "answer": "Top"
  },
  {
    "id": 626,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep16:34",
    "question": "Who died and was buried in the place which was called Nahom?",
    "answer": "Ishmael",
    "options": ["Ishmael", "Lehi", "Zoram"]
  },
  {
    "id": 627,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep16:35",
    "question": "Ishmael’s daughters murmured against Lehi, saying that they had suffered much affliction, hunger, _____ and fatigue in the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Thirst",
    "options": ["Whippings", "Thirst", "Disease"]
  },
  {
    "id": 628,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep16:38-39",
    "question": "The voice of the_____ did come down and spoke and chastened Laman and Lemuel, exceedingly for murmuring.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 629,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep17:4-5",
    "question": "Lehi’s party wondered_____ years before they came upon a land that had much fruit and wild honey.",
    "answer": "8",
    "options": ["3", "8", "6"]
  },
  {
    "id": 630,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep17:5",
    "question": "What did Lehi and his family call: “the land that had much fruit and wild honey”?",
    "answer": "Bountiful"
  },
  {
    "id": 631,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep17:5",
    "question": "What is the name of the sea, when interpreted; means many waters?",
    "answer": "Irreantum"
  },
  {
    "id": 632,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep17:6",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Lehi’s party pitched their tents by the seashore and they had suffered many afflictions and much difficulty that they could not write them all. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 633,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep17:8",
    "question": "Nephi was told by the Lord to construct a _____?",
    "answer": "Ship",
    "options": ["Spacecraft", "Ship", "Car"]
  },
  {
    "id": 634,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep17:8-9",
    "question": "The ship that Nephi constructed, was after the manner of men?",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 635,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep17:12",
    "question": "The food that Nephi and his brothers hunted did not have to be cooked.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 636,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep17:12",
    "question": "The food that Nephi killed was made sweet by the Lord. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 637,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep17:16",
    "question": "Nephi made tools of the _____ which he molted out of the rock, to build the ship.",
    "answer": "Ore"
  },
  {
    "id": 638,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep17:17-18",
    "question": "Nephi’s brothers did not believe that he had been instructed by the Lord to build the ship.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 639,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep17:19",
    "question": "Nephi was exceedingly _____ because of the hardness of his brothers’ hearts.",
    "answer": "Sorrowful",
    "options": ["Angry", "Sorrowful", "Glad"]
  },
  {
    "id": 640,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep17:22",
    "question": "Nephi’s brothers believed that the people they left in Jerusalem were righteous?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 641,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep17:23-24",
    "question": "According to Nephi-who led the Israelites out of bondage from the Egyptians?",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },
  {
    "id": 642,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep17:26",
    "question": "By whose words did the Red Sea divide hither and thither?",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },
  {
    "id": 643,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep17:27",
    "question": "The armies of the Egyptians belonged to the",
    "answer": "The Pharoah",
    "options": ["Navy Seals", "Army’s Delta Force", "The Pharoah"]
  },
  {
    "id": 644,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep17:29",
    "question": "Moses smote a _____ and there came forth water.",
    "answer": "Rock"
  },
  {
    "id": 645,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep17:28-29",
    "question": "Moses and the Israelites were fed _____ in the wilderness, by God.",
    "answer": "Manna",
    "options": ["Spaghettios", "Mac And Cheese", "Manna"]
  },
  {
    "id": 646,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep17:32",
    "question": "The River Jordan is mentioned in the first book of Nephi.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 647,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep17:36",
    "question": "The Lord's purpose for the creation of earth was so it should be inhabited and that his children should possess it.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 648,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep17:37",
    "question": "The Lord would rise up a righteous nation and destroy the nations of the _____.",
    "answer": "Wicked",
    "options": ["Islam", "Far East", "Wicked"]
  },
  {
    "id": 649,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep17:39",
    "question": "The Lord rules high up in heaven and it is his throne, and the earth is his _____.",
    "answer": "Footstool"
  },
  {
    "id": 650,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep17:35",
    "question": "The Lord esteemes all flesh in one; he that is righteous is favored of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 651,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep17:41",
    "question": "The Lord sent fiery flying serpents to the Israelites in the wilderness.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 652,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep17:41, Hel 8:14",
    "question": "The Lord prepared a way for the Israelites to be healed from the fiery flying Serpents bites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 653,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep17:41,Hel8:14",
    "question": "What did the israelites have to do to be healed from the bites of the fiery flying serpents?",
    "answer": "Was To Look At The Brazen Serpent",
    "options": [
      "Pray",
      "Call Upon The Lord",
      "Was To Look At The Brazen Serpent"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 654,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep17:41",
    "question": "Many of the israelites perished because they refused to look at the serpent.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 655,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep17:43",
    "question": "Nephi knew or saw that almost all of the Israelites that were with Moses were going to be destroyed.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 656,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep17:45",
    "question": "Who said “ye are swift to do iniquity but slow to remember the Lord your God”.",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["Lehi", "Nephi", "Moses"]
  },
  {
    "id": 657,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep17:47",
    "question": "Who was filled with the Spirit of God that his body/frame had no strength?",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["Lehi", "Nephi", "Moses"]
  },
  {
    "id": 658,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep17:53",
    "question": "How did God show Nephi’s brothers that he was “the Lord their God”?",
    "answer": "Shocked Them",
    "options": ["Startled Them", "Made The Earth Move", "Shocked Them"]
  },
  {
    "id": 659,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep17:55",
    "question": "Nephi’s brothers were going to worship him after the Lord had shaken them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 660,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep18:1",
    "question": "Nephi and his brothers worked timbers for the ship of curious workmanship.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 661,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep185-6",
    "question": "Who told Lehi to go down into the ship and prepare to sail?",
    "answer": "The Lord",
    "options": ["The Lord", "Nephi", "No One"]
  },
  {
    "id": 662,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep18:7",
    "question": "How many sons did Lehi beget in the wilderness?____",
    "answer": "2 (3)",
    "options": ["1", "2 (3)"]
  },
  {
    "id": 663,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep18:7",
    "question": "Lehi beget two sons in the wilderness; who was the eldest? Joseph or Jacob",
    "answer": "Jacob"
  },
  {
    "id": 664,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep18:11",
    "question": "The Lord allowed Nephi to be bound by his brothers in order to fulfill his word and to show his power, concerning the wicked?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 665,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep18:12",
    "question": "The compass that was prepared of the Lord ceased to work because Nephi had been bound by cords.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 666,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep18:17",
    "question": "Lehi said many things to Laman, Lemuel, and the sons of Ismael because of their hardness of heart towards Nephi",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 667,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep18:18",
    "question": "Nephi’s parents suffered much grief and sorrow because the iniquity of his _____.",
    "answer": "Brothers"
  },
  {
    "id": 668,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep18:19",
    "question": "Jacob and Joseph needed much _____, and were grieved because of the afflictions of their mother.",
    "answer": "Nourishment"
  },
  {
    "id": 669,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep18:20",
    "question": "The only thing that could soften the heart of Laman and Lemuel was the power of _____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 670,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep18:23",
    "question": "Approximately when did Lehi and his family arrive in the promise land?",
    "answer": "589 B.C.",
    "options": ["600 B.C.", "601 B.C.", "589 B.C."]
  },
  {
    "id": 671,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep18:25",
    "question": "Lehi and his family found all manner of wild animals and beasts in the wilderness.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 672,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep18:25",
    "question": "Nephi found all kinds of ore, both of silver, gold, and copper?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 673,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep19:1",
    "question": "The Lord commanded that only Nephi’s prophecies be engraved on the brass plates.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 674,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep19:4",
    "question": "Nephi commanded his posterity to hand down the plates from one generation to another.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 675,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep19:5",
    "question": "Nephi wanted that the more _____ things may be kept for the knowledge of his people.",
    "answer": "Sacred",
    "options": ["Secret", "Sacred", "Important"]
  },
  {
    "id": 676,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Neh19:6",
    "question": "Nephi only wrote the things that he deemed sacred upon the plates.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 677,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep19:6",
    "question": "Nephi wanted us to forgive his weakness in writing",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 678,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep19:8",
    "question": "Who told Nephi that the Savior would come six hundred years from the time they left Jerusalem",
    "answer": "An Angel",
    "options": ["Little Birdie", "An Angel", "Moses"]
  },
  {
    "id": 679,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep19:9",
    "question": "The world because of their _____ will judge the Savior as a thing of naught?",
    "answer": "Iniquity",
    "options": ["Riches", "Iniquity", "Hatred"]
  },
  {
    "id": 680,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep19:9",
    "question": "Jesus Christ suffered and endured all the things done to him before the crucifixion because of his loving kindness and long-suffering towards the children of men.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 681,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep19:10",
    "question": "Nephi said that the Savior would be lifted up according to the words of what Hebrew prophet?_____",
    "answer": "Zenock",
    "options": ["Moses", "Zenock", "Jeremiah"]
  },
  {
    "id": 682,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep19:10",
    "question": "Nephi said that the Savior would be crucified according to the words of Neum; a Hebrew prophet.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 683,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep19:10 & Alma33:15",
    "question": "The prophets Zenock and Neum said that Jesus Christ would be lifted up and be crucified.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 684,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep19:10",
    "question": "According to the words of the prophet _____, Jesus Christ would be buried in sepulcher.",
    "answer": "Zenos",
    "options": ["Abinidi", "Moses", "Zenos"]
  },
  {
    "id": 685,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep19:10",
    "question": "Zenos the prophet; prophesied that there would be _____ days of darkness given as a sign of Jesus Christ’s death.",
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "id": 686,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep19:10",
    "question": "Zenos said those that inhabit the isles of the sea and the house of Israel would be given more of a sign of his death?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 687,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep19:11",
    "question": "After the crucifixion, the Savior will visit the righteous with his voice unto their great joy and salvation.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 688,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep19:12",
    "question": "The prophet Zenos said that the kings of the isles of the sea will exclaim: The _____ of nature suffers.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 689,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep19:13",
    "question": "The people in Jerusalem will be scourged by all people because they crucified the God of Israel.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 690,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep19:13-14",
    "question": "Who or what people despised the Holy One of Israel?",
    "answer": "Jews"
  },
  {
    "id": 691,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep19:14,19",
    "question": "What people will become a hiss and a by-word, and be hated among all nations?",
    "answer": "Jews"
  },
  {
    "id": 692,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep19:16",
    "question": "Zenos prophesied that the Lord would gather all the people that are from the house of Israel from the four _____ of the earth.",
    "answer": "Quarters"
  },
  {
    "id": 693,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep19:18",
    "question": "Nephi wrote things to persuade his people so they would remember the Lord their Redeemer. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 694,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep19:21 & 3Nep10:16-17",
    "question": "Nephi knew the things concerning the prophets of old because they are written on the plates of brass Lehi had. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 695,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep19:23",
    "question": "Nephi read unto his brothers the things that were written in the book of Moses and also things written by the prophet Isaiah",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 696,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep19:23",
    "question": "Nephi liken all the scriptures unto himself and his family; that it would be for their profit and _____.",
    "answer": "Learning",
    "options": ["Understanding", "Learning", "Good"]
  },
  {
    "id": 697,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep20:1",
    "question": "Another name for the house of Israel is _____",
    "answer": "House Of Jacob",
    "options": ["House Of Abraham", "House Of Jacob", "House Of Righteousness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 698,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep20:13",
    "question": "The Lord said that he had laid the foundation of the earth and my left hand has spanned the heavens. ",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 699,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep20:18",
    "question": "The Lord told the House of Israel that if they would hearken to his commandments-then their peace be as a river, and their righteousness as the waves of the sea. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 700,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep20:22",
    "question": "There is no peace, saith the Lord, unto the _____.",
    "answer": "Wicked",
    "options": ["Humble", "Wicked", "Israelites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 701,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": ") 1Nep21:6",
    "question": "The prophet Isaiah will raise up the tribes of Jacob and also be a light unto the Gentiles? ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 702,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep21:7",
    "question": "Kings will see and arise; princes also shall worship, because the Lord that is faithful. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 703,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep21:16",
    "question": "The Lord has engraved the house of Israel upon the _____ of his hands.",
    "answer": "Palms"
  },
  {
    "id": 704,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep21:22",
    "question": "Isaiah said the Lord would lift up his hand to the Gentiles. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 705,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep21:25",
    "question": "Who said “I will contend with him that contends with thee”.",
    "answer": "The Lord",
    "options": ["Isaiah", "Lehi", "The Lord"]
  },
  {
    "id": 706,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep21:26",
    "question": "The Lord refers to himself as the Mighty One of_____.",
    "answer": "Jacob",
    "options": ["Nephi", "Lehi", "Jacob"]
  },
  {
    "id": 707,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep22:2",
    "question": "Nephi said that “by the Spirit are all things made known unto the prophets”. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 708,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep22:3",
    "question": "The writings of Isaiah that Nephi read to his brothers were both _____ and spiritual.",
    "answer": "Temporal"
  },
  {
    "id": 709,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep22:3",
    "question": "Nephi told his brothers that the house of Israel, sooner or later, will be scattered upon all the earth and nations. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 710,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep22:22",
    "question": "Who should not fear the wrath of God?",
    "answer": "The Righteous",
    "options": ["The Righteous", "Nephites", "Lamanites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 711,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep22:21",
    "question": "Nephi declared that the prophet spoken by Moses; was the Holy One of Israel.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 712,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep22:23",
    "question": "Those who are built up to get gain, power, and be popular and who belong to the kingdom of the devil need to fear the wrath of God. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 713,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep22:24",
    "question": "The righteous must be led up as _____ of the stall, and the Holy One of Israel must reign in dominion, and might, and power, and great glory.",
    "answer": "Calves",
    "options": ["Sheep", "Calves", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": 714,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep22:25",
    "question": "The Lord _____ his sheep; and they know him.",
    "answer": "Numbers",
    "options": ["Numbers", "Marks", "Colors"]
  },
  {
    "id": 715,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep22:26",
    "question": "Because of the peoples’ righteousness, Satan will have no power and the Holy One of Israel will reign for many years. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 716,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep22:26",
    "question": "When the Lord comes again to reign on earth; Mormon writes that the devil will be chained for one-thousand years.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 717,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep22:26",
    "question": "We are never told in the Book of Mormon how long or for how many years the devil will be chained when the Lord comes to reign upon the earth at the last days.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 718,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep22:28",
    "question": "All kindreds, tongues, and people must repent if they are to dwell safely in the Holy One of Israel. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 719,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep22:29-30",
    "question": "Nephi testified that the things written in the brass plates are true and that man must be obedient to the commandments of _____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 720,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep22:30-31",
    "question": "Nephi and Lehi are not the only ones that have written concerning the brass plates. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 721,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep22:31",
    "question": "We need to be obedient to the commandments and _____ to the end, to be saved in the last day.",
    "answer": "Endure"
  },
  {
    "id": 722,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep22:31",
    "question": "The first book of Nephi ends with the word/words",
    "answer": "Adieu",
    "options": ["Adieu", "Amen", "The End"]
  },
  {
    "id": 723,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep1:5",
    "question": "In 2Nephi the Lord covenanted with Lehi; the land of promise to him and all his seed. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 724,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep1:6",
    "question": "Lehi did prophesy; that no one would come to the promise land, unless they would be brought by the _____ of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Hand",
    "options": ["Spirit", "Hand", "Arm"]
  },
  {
    "id": 725,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep1:7",
    "question": "The promise land is consecrated to all of those that the Lord will bring to it. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 726,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep1:7",
    "question": "The promise land will be a land of liberty as long as we serve the Lord according to the commandments. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 727,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep1:7",
    "question": "If we are brought down to captivity in the promise land; it will be because of our iniquity. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 728,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep1:7",
    "question": "If iniquity abounds in the promise land, it will be _____ for the people’s sake.",
    "answer": "Cursed",
    "options": ["Burned", "Cursed", "Flooded"]
  },
  {
    "id": 729,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep1:8",
    "question": "It is wisdom that the promise land be hid from the knowledge of other nations because it would be _____.",
    "answer": "Neither",
    "options": ["Overrun", "Segregated", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": 730,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep1:9",
    "question": "If Lehi and his family keep the commandments of the Lord, they would _____, in the promised land.",
    "answer": "Prosper"
  },
  {
    "id": 731,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep1:10",
    "question": "Lehi and his family/party were given power by the Lord to do all things by faith. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 732,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep1:10",
    "question": "Lehi and his family were brought to the precious land of promise by the Lords' _____ goodness.",
    "answer": "Infinite"
  },
  {
    "id": 733,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep1:13",
    "question": "According to Lehi:  we our bound by awful _____ of hell; that binds us captive to the eternal gulf of misery and woe.",
    "answer": "Chains",
    "options": ["People", "Chains", "Temptations"]
  },
  {
    "id": 734,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep1:14",
    "question": "Who in 2Nephi said “cold and silent grave, from whence no traveler can return”?",
    "answer": "Lehi"
  },
  {
    "id": 735,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep1:18",
    "question": "Lehi feared that his sons would be led to the will and captivity of the devil? ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 736,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep1:17-18",
    "question": "Who will visit Lehi’s sons by the sword and by famine?",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 737,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep1:19",
    "question": "Whose will is always done and his ways are righteousness forever?",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 738,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep1:21",
    "question": "Lehi wanted his sons to be men, and be determined in one mind and in one _____, united in all things.",
    "answer": "Heart"
  },
  {
    "id": 739,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep:23",
    "question": "Lehi said “awake my sons; put on the armor of _____.",
    "answer": "Righteousness",
    "options": ["Steel", "Truth", "Righteousness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 740,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep1:24",
    "question": "Which one of Lehi’s sons had been an instrument in the hands of the Lord from the beginning of their journey?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 741,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep1:25",
    "question": "Who sought the glory of God and the eternal welfare of his brothers during the journey to the promise land?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 742,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep1:26",
    "question": "The sharpness that Nephi used on his brothers was the sharpness of the power of the word of God. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 743,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep1:26",
    "question": "Nephi could not restrain himself from manifesting boldly concerning his brother’s iniquities. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 744,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep1:27",
    "question": "The Spirit of the Lord was the one that opened Nephi’s mouth that he could not shut it. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 745,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep1:28",
    "question": "Lehi told his sons to hearken to the voice of _____ and they would not perish.",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["The Boss", "Nephi", "Their Mother"]
  },
  {
    "id": 746,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep1:30",
    "question": "Lehi knew that _____ was led out of Jerusalem, and was a true friend of Nephi, forever.",
    "answer": "Zoram"
  },
  {
    "id": 747,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep1:31",
    "question": "Lehi said that Zoram’s seed would prosper in the promise land as long as there would be no iniquity among them. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 748,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep1:28-29",
    "question": "Lehi would take away the blessings he gave Laman, Lemuel, and Sam if they did not hearken unto the voice of Nephi. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 749,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep2:4",
    "question": "Lehi told his son Jacob- “and the way is prepared from the fall of man, and _____ is free”.",
    "answer": "Salvation",
    "options": ["Bread", "Salvation", "Life"]
  },
  {
    "id": 750,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep2:5",
    "question": "Men are instructed sufficiently that they know good from evil.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 751,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:6",
    "question": "Lehi said redemption comes in and through the Holy Messiah; for he is full of _____ and truth.",
    "answer": "Grace"
  },
  {
    "id": 752,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:7",
    "question": "The Lord offers himself a sacrifice for sin, to answer the ends of the law, unto all those who have a _____ heart and a contrite spirit.",
    "answer": "Broken"
  },
  {
    "id": 753,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:8",
    "question": "The Holy Messiah will bring to pass the _____ or the dead, being the first that should rise.",
    "answer": "Resurrection"
  },
  {
    "id": 754,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep2:9",
    "question": "The Lord will make intercession for all the children of men; and they that believe in him shall be saved. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 755,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:11",
    "question": "Lehi told Jacob,”for it must needs be, that there is an _____ in all things”.",
    "answer": "Opposition"
  },
  {
    "id": 756,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:11",
    "question": "There must be nor corruption nor _____, happiness nor misery, neither sense nor insensibility.",
    "answer": "Incorruption"
  },
  {
    "id": 757,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep2:13",
    "question": "And if ye shall say there in no law, ye also shall say there no _____.",
    "answer": "Sin",
    "options": ["Mercy", "Gift", "Sin"]
  },
  {
    "id": 758,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep2:14",
    "question": "Lehi testified to his sons that there is a God and he has created all things, both the heavens and the earth. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 759,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep2:17",
    "question": "Lehi read that an angel of God fell from heaven; wherefore, he became a devil, having sought that which was evil before God. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 760,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:27",
    "question": "In 2Nephi- who did Lehi say “seeks that all men might be miserable like unto himself”.",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },
  {
    "id": 761,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep2:18",
    "question": "The Devil is quoted in the Book Of Mormon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 762,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep2:18, 2Nep24:13,14",
    "question": "How many times is the Devil quoted in the Book Of Mormon?",
    "answer": "Three",
    "options": ["One", "Two", "Three"]
  },
  {
    "id": 763,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:18",
    "question": "Who is the father of all lies?",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },
  {
    "id": 764,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:18",
    "question": "Who told Eve to partake of the forbidden fruit, and you shall not die, but you shall be as a God, knowing good from evil?",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },
  {
    "id": 765,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:19",
    "question": "Adam and Eve were driven out of the_____ of Eden, for partaking of the forbidden fruit.",
    "answer": "Garden"
  },
  {
    "id": 766,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:21",
    "question": "According to the will of God; men while in the flesh might repent; wherefore, their state became a state of _____.",
    "answer": "Probation"
  },
  {
    "id": 767,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep2:22",
    "question": "If Adam hat not transgressed, things would have remained in the same state in which they were after they were created, and had no end. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 768,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep2:24",
    "question": "But behold, all things have been done in the _____ of him who knows all things.",
    "answer": "Wisdom",
    "options": ["Wisdom", "Power", "Foresight"]
  },
  {
    "id": 769,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:25",
    "question": "_____ fell that men might he; and men are, that they might have joy.",
    "answer": "Adam"
  },
  {
    "id": 770,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:26",
    "question": "The Messiah comes in the _____ of time, that he may redeem the children of men from the fall.",
    "answer": "Fulness"
  },
  {
    "id": 771,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:26",
    "question": "Men are free to act for themselves and not to be _____ upon.",
    "answer": "Acted"
  },
  {
    "id": 772,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep2:28",
    "question": "Another name that we can use to describe Jesus Christ is the great Mediator.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 773,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:28",
    "question": "Lehi told his sons “I would that ye look to the great _____ and hearken unto his great commandments”.",
    "answer": "Mediator"
  },
  {
    "id": 774,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep2:29",
    "question": "Lehi wanted his sons to not to choose eternal death, according to the will of the flesh and the evil which is therein. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 775,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep2:30",
    "question": "Lehi choose the words of the prophet, and had no other objective; save it be the everlasting welfare of his son’s souls. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 776,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep3:1",
    "question": "Which one of Lehi’s sons was born in the days of his greatest sorrow?",
    "answer": "Joseph"
  },
  {
    "id": 777,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep33, 5",
    "question": "Whose seed did Lehi prophesied would not be utterly destroyed?",
    "answer": "Joseph",
    "options": ["Moses", "Joseph", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 778,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep3:5",
    "question": "Who truly saw the days of the Nephites by a vision and prophecy?",
    "answer": "Joseph"
  },
  {
    "id": 779,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep3:6",
    "question": "Joseph testified that a seer shall the Lord raise up from the fruit of his loins. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 780,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep3:5",
    "question": "In 2Nephi; who obtained a promise from the Lord that his posterity would be a righteous branch of Israel?",
    "answer": "Joseph"
  },
  {
    "id": 781,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep3:15",
    "question": "What is the seer’s first name that the Lord would raise up from Joseph’s loins?",
    "answer": "Joseph"
  },
  {
    "id": 782,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep3:14",
    "question": "They who seek to destroy the choice seer would be confounded. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 783,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "3Nep3:11",
    "question": "The Lord will give power to the seer to bring forth his word unto the seed of _____ loins.",
    "answer": "Joseph"
  },
  {
    "id": 784,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep3:17",
    "question": "Who would the Lord rise up and give him judgment “Unto him in writing”?",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },
  {
    "id": 785,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep3:17",
    "question": "Moses will be mighty in speaking. ",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 786,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep3:17",
    "question": "The Lord will would make a spokesman for Moses",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 787,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep3:17",
    "question": "In the Book of Mormon we are told of the name of the spokesman that the Lord will have for Moses.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 788,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep3:23",
    "question": "The seed of Joseph will _____ unto the words of the book/Mormon.",
    "answer": "Hearken",
    "options": ["Hearken", "Laugh", "Be Confounded"]
  },
  {
    "id": 789,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep3:24",
    "question": "In 2Nephi: Who will be a _____ in the hands of God?",
    "answer": "Instrument",
    "options": ["Instrument", "Leader", "Accomplice"]
  },
  {
    "id": 790,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep3:25",
    "question": "Joseph was told to hearken unto the words of _____ by his father.",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["Alma", "Nephi", "Mosiah"]
  },
  {
    "id": 791,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep3:25",
    "question": "When Lehi was prophesying to Joseph he was in his mid 20’s. ",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 792,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep4:1",
    "question": "Nephi spoke concerning prophecies of Joseph, who was carried into Egypt. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 793,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep4:2",
    "question": "Joseph who was carried into Egypt; truly prophesied concerning all his seed. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 794,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:2",
    "question": "The prophecies of Joseph who was sold in Egypt or written upon the plates of _____.",
    "answer": "Brass"
  },
  {
    "id": 795,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep4:2",
    "question": "There are not many greater prophecies than those of Joseph who was carried into Egypt. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 796,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:3",
    "question": "Lehi called Laman and his sons, and his _____ to give ear unto his words.",
    "answer": "Daughters"
  },
  {
    "id": 797,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep4:6",
    "question": "If Laman and Lemuel seed was cursed, Lehi wanted the curse to be answered upon the heads of him and his wife. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 798,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep4:9",
    "question": "Lehi said that Lamuel’s seed would be blessed at the end. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 799,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep4:11",
    "question": "Whose seed will be numbered with the seed of Nephi and be blessed in all his days.",
    "answer": "Sam",
    "options": ["Laman", "Lemuel", "Sam"]
  },
  {
    "id": 800,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:12",
    "question": "After Lehi gave his blessings to his sons he waxed old and the he _____ and the Spirit of the Lord was him.",
    "answer": "Died"
  },
  {
    "id": 801,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep4:13",
    "question": "Laman, Lemuel, and Ismael were angry with Nephi because of the admonitions of the Lord. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 802,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep4:14",
    "question": "More of Nephi’s sayings and history are written on his other plates. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 803,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:15",
    "question": "Who said “my soul delights in the scriptures, and my heart ponders them”?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 804,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:15",
    "question": "Nephi wrote things of his soul and for the learning and the profit of his _____.",
    "answer": "Children"
  },
  {
    "id": 805,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:16",
    "question": "Whose soul delights in the things of the Lord, and ponders continually upon the things which I have seen and heard?- ",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 806,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:16-35",
    "question": "Wrote the _____ of Nephi, shortly after the death of his father.",
    "answer": "Psalm"
  },
  {
    "id": 807,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:17",
    "question": "Who said “O wretched man that I am! Yea, my heart sorrows because of my flesh; my soul grieves because of mine iniquities”?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 808,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:21",
    "question": "Who is filled with the love of the Lord, even unto consuming of his flesh?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 809,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:23",
    "question": "Who cried by day, and he was given knowledge by visions in the nighttime?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 810,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:24",
    "question": "Who waxed bold in mighty prayer and angels came down and ministered unto him?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 811,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:25",
    "question": "Who was carried upon the wings of the Spirit of the Lord and away upon exceeding high mountains?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 812,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep4:25",
    "question": "Nephi beheld great things, yea even too great for man",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 813,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:25",
    "question": "Nephi was _____ to write some of the great things that he saw by the Lord?",
    "answer": "Forbidden"
  },
  {
    "id": 814,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep4:27",
    "question": "Who said: “Why should I yield to sin, because of my flesh”?",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["Laman", "Lemuel", "Nephi"]
  },
  {
    "id": 815,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:30",
    "question": "Who will praise the Lord forever, and his soul will rejoice in his God; the rock of his salvation?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 816,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep4:32",
    "question": "Who asked the Lord, “wilt thou not shut the gates of thy righteousness before me”?",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["Laman", "Lemuel", "Nephi"]
  },
  {
    "id": 817,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:33",
    "question": "Who said “O Lord, wilt thou encircle me around in the robe of thy righteousness”?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 818,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep4:34",
    "question": "Nephi said “O Lord, I have trusted in thee, and I will trust in thee forever”. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 819,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:34",
    "question": "I will not put my _____ in the arm of the flesh; for I know that cursed is he that puts his trust in the arm of the flesh.",
    "answer": "Trust"
  },
  {
    "id": 820,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:35",
    "question": "I know that _____will give liberally to him that asks.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 821,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep4:35",
    "question": "Nephi said “I will cry unto thee, my God, the rock of my righteousness”. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 822,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep5:3",
    "question": "Nephi’s brothers said that they had much affliction because of Nephi’s words.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 823,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep5:3",
    "question": "Nephi’s brothers began to _____ against him and blame their trials because of him.",
    "answer": "Murmur",
    "options": ["Curse", "Murmur", "Cry"]
  },
  {
    "id": 824,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep5:3",
    "question": "Who thought that they should be the rulers of the people because they were older?",
    "answer": ["Laman", "Lemuel"]
  },
  {
    "id": 825,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep5:4",
    "question": "Nephi wrote all the words which his brothers murmured against him. ",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 826,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep5:5",
    "question": "Who warned Nephi to depart from his brothers and flee into the wilderness?",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 827,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep5:6",
    "question": "Nephi fled into the wilderness with his family and also with the families of Sam and _____.",
    "answer": "Zoram",
    "options": ["Zoram", "Jacob", "Joseph"]
  },
  {
    "id": 828,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep5:6",
    "question": "Nephi had sisters; how many?",
    "answer": "We Don’t Know",
    "options": ["3", "4", "We Don’t Know"]
  },
  {
    "id": 829,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep5:6",
    "question": "All those that believed in the warnings and _____ or God; also fled with Nephi, into the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Revelations"
  },
  {
    "id": 1331,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep5:6, 1Nep2:16",
    "question": "Jacob was older than his large and stature brother Nephi, by six years.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 830,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep5:8",
    "question": "What is the name of the place that the people gave to the place where they pitched their tents after fleeing from Nephi’s brother’s?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 831,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep5:9",
    "question": "What name did the people give themselves after fleeing from Nephi’s brothers?",
    "answer": "The People Of Nephi",
    "options": ["Nephites", "The People Of Nephi", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 832,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep5:11",
    "question": "Nephi’s people began to raise _____, and herds, and animals of every kind.",
    "answer": "Flocks"
  },
  {
    "id": 833,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep5:12",
    "question": "Nephi had the plates of brass; and also the ball, or _____, which was prepared by the hand of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Compass"
  },
  {
    "id": 834,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep5:14",
    "question": "Nephi took the sword of _____, and after the manner of it did make many swords.",
    "answer": "Laban"
  },
  {
    "id": 835,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep5:14",
    "question": "The Lamanites were first given that name in which book?",
    "answer": "2Nephi",
    "options": ["1Nephi", "2Nephi", "3Nephi"]
  },
  {
    "id": 836,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep5:15",
    "question": "Nephi taught his people to build buildings, and to work in all manner of word, iron, and of copper. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 837,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep5:16",
    "question": "Nephi did build a temple; and constructed it after the manner of the temple of _____.",
    "answer": "Solomon"
  },
  {
    "id": 838,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep5:16",
    "question": "Nephi’s temple was build like Solomon’s and it also had all manner of precious things. ",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 839,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep5:16",
    "question": "The workmanship of the temple that Nephi built was exceedingly fine. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 840,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep5:18",
    "question": "Nephi’s people desired that he should be their _____, but he was desirous that there should be no king.",
    "answer": "King"
  },
  {
    "id": 841,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep5 19",
    "question": "The words of the Lord were fulfilled when he spoke that Nephi should be the ruler over his brethren. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 842,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep5:20",
    "question": "What two brothers of Nephi were cut off from the presence of the Lord because they would not hearken to his words?",
    "answer": ["Laman", "Lemuel"]
  },
  {
    "id": 843,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep5:21",
    "question": "The Lord caused that a cursing to come upon Laman and Lemuel and their families. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 844,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep5:21",
    "question": "What color was the skin of Laman and Lemuel before they were cursed?",
    "answer": "White",
    "options": ["White", "Brown", "Black"]
  },
  {
    "id": 845,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep5:21",
    "question": "The Lord God did cause a skin of _____ to come upon Laman and Lemuel and their families.",
    "answer": "Blackness"
  },
  {
    "id": 846,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep5:23",
    "question": "The Lord said: Cursed shall be the seed of him that mixes with the seed of Laman and Lemuel. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 847,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep5:24",
    "question": "Because of the cursing that was upon them the Lamanites did become an idle people, full or mischief and subtlety. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 848,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep5:26",
    "question": "Nephi did consecrate Jacob and Joseph, that they should be priests and _____ over the land of his people.",
    "answer": "Teachers"
  },
  {
    "id": 849,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep5:30 & 1Nep9:23",
    "question": "Nephi was obedient to the Lord and made another set of plates which contain the ministry of his people. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 850,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep5:34",
    "question": "How many years had passed away when Nephi and his people started to have wars and contentions with his brother’s people?",
    "answer": "40",
    "options": ["30", "40", "50"]
  },
  {
    "id": 851,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:1",
    "question": "In chapter six of the Book of 2Nephi; Jacob recounts the history of what tribe of people?",
    "answer": "Jews"
  },
  {
    "id": 852,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:2",
    "question": "_____ was called of God, and ordained after the manner of his holy order, and consecrated by Nephi.",
    "answer": "Jacob"
  },
  {
    "id": 853,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep6:3",
    "question": "Jacob spoke to his people and was desirous for the welfare of their souls. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 854,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:3",
    "question": "Jacob spoke unto his people concerning all things which are written, from the creation of the _____.",
    "answer": "World"
  },
  {
    "id": 855,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:4",
    "question": "Jacob spoke to the Nephites for their sakes, that they would learn and glorify the name of their _____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 856,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:4",
    "question": "Jacob read to his people the words of what Old Testament prophet?- ",
    "answer": "Isaiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 857,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep6:4",
    "question": "Who said, “I would speak unto you concerning things which are, and which are to come”.",
    "answer": "Jacob",
    "options": ["Nephi", "Jacob", "Lehi"]
  },
  {
    "id": 858,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep6:5",
    "question": "There are many things which can be likened unto the Nephites because they are from the house of Israel. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 859,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:6",
    "question": "Who will lift up his hand to the Gentiles, and set up his standard to the people?",
    "answer": ["Lord", "God"]
  },
  {
    "id": 860,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:7",
    "question": "Kings shall be thy nursing fathers’ and their _____ thy nursing mothers.",
    "answer": "Queens"
  },
  {
    "id": 861,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep6:8",
    "question": "The Lord showed Jacob those who were in Jerusalem and those that had been _____ and carried away captive.",
    "answer": "Slain",
    "options": ["Hanged", "Slain", "Trampled."]
  },
  {
    "id": 862,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:9",
    "question": "God, the Holy One of Israel, would manifest himself unto them in the flesh and they will scourge and crucify him.",
    "answer": "Israelites"
  },
  {
    "id": 863,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep6:9",
    "question": "Jacob saw the crucifixion or the Savior. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 864,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:10",
    "question": "After the Israelites hardened their hearts and _____ their necks against the Holy One of Israel his, judgments will come upon them.",
    "answer": "Stiffened"
  },
  {
    "id": 865,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep6:11",
    "question": "Jacob said “the day comes that the Israelites shall be smitten and afflicted”. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 866,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep6:11",
    "question": "Who did the angel refer to when he said:  They shall be afflicted in the flesh, and shall not be suffered to perish, because of the prayers of the faithful?",
    "answer": "Israelites",
    "options": ["Nephites.", "Israelites", "Lamanites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 867,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:11",
    "question": "The angel said: They shall be scattered, and smitten, and _____; nevertheless, the Lord will be merciful unto them.",
    "answer": "Hated"
  },
  {
    "id": 868,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:11",
    "question": "Who will come to the lands of their inheritance, after they come to the knowledge of their Redeemer?",
    "answer": "Israelites"
  },
  {
    "id": 869,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep6:12",
    "question": "What people will be blessed, if they repent and fight not against Zion?",
    "answer": "Gentiles",
    "options": ["Gentiles", "Israelites", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 870,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:13",
    "question": "Who are the covenant people of the Lord who are waiting for him and still waiting for the coming of the Messiah?",
    "answer": ["Jews", "Israelites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 871,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:14",
    "question": "What people according to the words of the prophet? Will the Messiah set himself again the second time to recover them.",
    "answer": ["Jews", "Israelites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 872,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep6:15",
    "question": "Those that believe not him shall be destroyed, both by fire, and by tempest, and by earthquakes. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 873,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep6:15",
    "question": "Who will know that the Lord is God, the Holy One of Israel?",
    "answer": "Unbelievers",
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Unbelievers", "Nephites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 874,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:17",
    "question": "For thus saith the Lord: “I will contend with them that _____ with thee.”",
    "answer": ["Contendeth", "Contends"]
  },
  {
    "id": 875,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:18",
    "question": "All flesh shall know that I the Lord am thy _____ and thy Redeemer, the Mighty One of Jacob.",
    "answer": "Savior"
  },
  {
    "id": 876,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep6:18",
    "question": "The Lord said that those that oppress the Israelites; he will feed them with their own flesh.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 877,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep7:4",
    "question": "Who did the Lord give him a tongue of the learned, that he should know how to speak a word in season, to the house of Israel?- ",
    "answer": "Jacob"
  },
  {
    "id": 878,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep7:6",
    "question": "Who gave his back to the smiter, and his cheeks to them that plucked of his hair?",
    "answer": "Jesus Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 879,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep7:9",
    "question": "They shall wax old as a garment, and the _____ shall eat them up?",
    "answer": "Moth"
  },
  {
    "id": 880,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:19",
    "question": "What ancient garden is mentioned in the Book Of Mormon",
    "answer": "Eden"
  },
  {
    "id": 881,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep8:3",
    "question": "Who will make her wilderness like Eden, and her desert like the garden of the Lord?- ",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 882,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep8:3 & Alma19:14",
    "question": "Of all the national holidays that we celebrate in the United States of America; only _____ is mentioned in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "Thanksgiving"
  },
  {
    "id": 883,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep8:15",
    "question": "But I am the Lord, thy God, whose waves roared; the Lord of _____ is my name.",
    "answer": "Hosts"
  },
  {
    "id": 884,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep9:3",
    "question": "Jacob spoke to his people so that they would rejoice and lift up their heads forever because of the blessings of God. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 885,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:4",
    "question": "Jacob told the Nephites that their flesh must waste away; nevertheless, in their bodies they shall see _____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 886,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep9:5",
    "question": "The creator died for all men, that all men might become subject unto him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 887,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep9:5",
    "question": "It behooves the great creator that he suffers himself to become subject unto man in the _____.",
    "answer": "Flesh",
    "options": ["Night", "Flesh", "Day"]
  },
  {
    "id": 888,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep9:7",
    "question": "Wherefore, it must needs be; an infinite atonement.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 889,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:8",
    "question": "For behold, if the flesh should rise no more our spirits must become subject the _____. ",
    "answer": "Devil "
  },
  {
    "id": 890,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep9:8",
    "question": "In 2Nephi- the devil is describe as an angel by Jacob.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 891,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:9",
    "question": "Who beguiled our first parents?-The ",
    "answer": "Devil "
  },
  {
    "id": 892,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:9",
    "question": "Who has the ability to transform himself as an angel of light?- ",
    "answer": "Devil "
  },
  {
    "id": 893,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:9",
    "question": "He stirs up the children of men unto secret combinations of murder and all manner of secret works of _____.-",
    "answer": "Darkness "
  },
  {
    "id": 894,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": " 2Nep9: 10",
    "question": "Jacob called the death of the body, and the death of the spirit, as a monster.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 895,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": " 2Nep9:12",
    "question": "Jacob spoke and liken; spiritual death as hell.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 896,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:11",
    "question": "What kind of death shall deliver up its dead; which death is the grave?",
    "answer": "Temporal "
  },
  {
    "id": 897,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep9:12",
    "question": "It is by the power of God, that the bodies and the spirits of men will be restored one to the other.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 898,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:13",
    "question": "The paradise of God must deliver up the spirits of the _____ and the grave deliver up the body of the righteous.",
    "answer": "Righteous "
  },
  {
    "id": 899,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep9:14",
    "question": "When we die; we shall have a perfect knowledge of our guilt, and our uncleanness.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 900,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:15",
    "question": "After we die, we must appear before the judgment _____ of the Holy One or Israel.",
    "answer": "Seat "
  },
  {
    "id": 901,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:16",
    "question": "Those who are righteous shall be righteous still, and they who are filthy shall be _____ still.",
    "answer": "Filthy "
  },
  {
    "id": 902,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:16",
    "question": "They who are filthy are the devil and his _____.",
    "answer": "Angels "
  },
  {
    "id": 903,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:16",
    "question": "The devils everlasting torment is as a lake of fire and _____.-",
    "answer": "Brimstone "
  },
  {
    "id": 904,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep9:16",
    "question": "The devil’s lake has a flame that ascends up forever and ever and has no end.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 905,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep9:17",
    "question": "God executes all his words from his mouth, and his law must be _____.",
    "answer": "Fulfilled",
    "options": ["Fulfilled", "False", "Correct"]
  },
  {
    "id": 906,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:19",
    "question": "The lake of fire and brimstone can be describe; as _____ torment.- ",
    "answer": "Everlasting "
  },
  {
    "id": 907,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep9:20",
    "question": "God knows all things, and there is not anything save he knows it.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 908,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:21",
    "question": "Jesus Christ has suffered the pains of all men, the pains of every living creature, both men_____, and children.",
    "answer": "Women "
  },
  {
    "id": 909,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:23",
    "question": "He commands all men, that they must repent, and be _____ in his name, having perfect faith in the Holy One of Israel-.",
    "answer": "Baptized "
  },
  {
    "id": 910,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:24",
    "question": "Those that don’t repent and believe in his name, and _____ to the end, must be damned.",
    "answer": "Endure "
  },
  {
    "id": 911,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep9:25",
    "question": "Wherefore, he has given a law; and where there is no law given there is no _____.",
    "answer": "Punishment",
    "options": ["Mercy", "Punishment", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 912,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:26",
    "question": "For the _____ satisfies the demands of his justice upon all of those who have not the law given to them.",
    "answer": "Atonement "
  },
  {
    "id": 913,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:27",
    "question": "Woe to those that transgress the laws of God, and that waste the days of his _____for awful is state.",
    "answer": "Probation "
  },
  {
    "id": 914,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": " 2Nep9:28",
    "question": "Men when they are learned, think they are wise, and they hearken not unto the counsel of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 915,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:29",
    "question": "But to be_____ is good if they hearken unto the counsels of God.-",
    "answer": "Learned "
  },
  {
    "id": 916,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:30",
    "question": "Woe unto the rich, who are _____ as to the things of this world.-",
    "answer": "Rich "
  },
  {
    "id": 917,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep9:30",
    "question": "The rich love their treasures, and their treasures is their _____",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["Fault", "God", "Downfall"]
  },
  {
    "id": 918,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": " 2Nep9:35",
    "question": "Woe unto the murderer who deliberately kills, for he shall die.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 919,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:37",
    "question": "Yea, woe unto those that worship idols, for the _____ of all devils delights in them.",
    "answer": "Devil "
  },
  {
    "id": 920,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:39",
    "question": "Remember, to be carnally-minded is death, and to be _____-minded is life eternal.",
    "answer": "Spiritually "
  },
  {
    "id": 921,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "1Nep9:40",
    "question": "Another name for the Savior is_____.",
    "answer": "Maker",
    "options": ["Baker", "Shaker", "Maker"]
  },
  {
    "id": 922,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep9:40",
    "question": "The righteous love the truth and were not shaken by Jacob’s words.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 923,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:41",
    "question": "Who is the keeper of the gate of heaven?- ",
    "answer": "Lord "
  },
  {
    "id": 924,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep9:41",
    "question": "The Lord, who is the keeper of the gate of heaven employs a servant/servants there. ",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 925,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep9:41",
    "question": "There is no other way to get to heaven; we must all enter through the gate of heaven.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 926,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep9:42",
    "question": "God despises those that are puffed up because of their learning and their wisdom, and their riches.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 927,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:44",
    "question": "Jacob prayed to his God of salvation that he might view him with his all-_____ eye.",
    "answer": "Searching "
  },
  {
    "id": 928,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep9:45",
    "question": "Jacob wanted his people to come to God, who is the rock of their salvation. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 929,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:48",
    "question": "The Nephites looked up to Jacob as a _____, and it was expedient that he teach them the consequences of sin.",
    "answer": "Teacher "
  },
  {
    "id": 930,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep9:49",
    "question": "Jacob’s soul abhors sin, and his heart delights in righteousness. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 931,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:52",
    "question": "Remember the words of your God; pray unto him continually by day, and give thanks unto his holy name by _____.- ",
    "answer": "Night "
  },
  {
    "id": 932,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep9:53",
    "question": "Future generations of Jacob’s seed shall become a righteous branch unto the house of Israel.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 933,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep10:3",
    "question": "Jacob was told that the Savior’s name would be _____ by an angel of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Christ "
  },
  {
    "id": 934,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": " 2Nep10:3",
    "question": "Christ would come to those that were in the more wicked part of the world.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 935,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep10:5",
    "question": "Because of their _____ and iniquities, they at Jerusalem will stiffen their necks and crucify him.",
    "answer": "Priestcrafts",
    "options": ["Priestcrafts", "Lies", "Dumbness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 936,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep10:8",
    "question": "The Jews he will gather from their long dispersion, from the isles of the sea, and from the _____ of the earth.",
    "answer": "Parts "
  },
  {
    "id": 937,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep10:9",
    "question": "The kings of the Gentiles shall be nursing fathers unto them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 938,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep10:10-11",
    "question": "The land shall be a land of liberty unto the Gentiles and they shall be blessed. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 939,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep10:13",
    "question": "And he that fights against Zion shall perish, says God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 940,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep10:15",
    "question": "The Lord must needs to destroy the secret work of darkness, and of murders, and of _____.",
    "answer": "Abominations "
  },
  {
    "id": 941,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep10:16",
    "question": "For they who are not for me are _____ me, saith our God.",
    "answer": "Against "
  },
  {
    "id": 942,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep10:18",
    "question": "The Lord will afflict the seed of Jacob by the hand of the _____.- ",
    "answer": "Gentiles "
  },
  {
    "id": 943,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep10:23",
    "question": "Jacob told his brethren; remember that ye are free to act for yourselves. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 944,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep10:23",
    "question": "We are free to choose the way of everlasting death or the way of eternal _____.",
    "answer": "Life "
  },
  {
    "id": 945,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep10:24",
    "question": "It is only through the _____ of God that we are saved.",
    "answer": "Grace "
  },
  {
    "id": 946,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep10:25",
    "question": "Wherefore, may God raise you from death by the power of the resurrection, and also from everlasting death by the power of the _____.",
    "answer": "Atonement "
  },
  {
    "id": 947,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep11:1",
    "question": "Nephi wrote all the things that Jacob spoke to the Nephites.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 948,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep11:2",
    "question": "Nephi wrote more of the words of Isaiah, for my soul delights in his words.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 949,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep11:2",
    "question": "Nephi liken the words of _____ unto his people, and he would send them forth unto all his children.",
    "answer": "Isaiah "
  },
  {
    "id": 950,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep11:3",
    "question": "Jacob and Nephi both saw the Savior.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 951,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep11:3",
    "question": "Wherefore, by the words of _____, God hath said, I will establish my word.",
    "answer": "Three "
  },
  {
    "id": 952,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep11:3",
    "question": "Nevertheless, God will send more witnesses, to prove that his words are true. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 953,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep11:3, Testimony of Eight Witnesses",
    "question": "How many more witnesses did the Lord say he would send?____",
    "answer": "8",
    "options": ["6", "8", "10"]
  },
  {
    "id": 954,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep11:4",
    "question": "By the coming of Christ; the law of _____ will come to an end.-",
    "answer": "Moses "
  },
  {
    "id": 955,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep11:6",
    "question": "Nephi’s soul delights in proving unto his people that if Christ had not come, all men must of, perished.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 956,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep11:7",
    "question": "For if there be no Christ there be no God; and if there be no God we are not, for there could have been no _____.-",
    "answer": "Creation "
  },
  {
    "id": 957,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep11:7",
    "question": "Nephi said that Christ would come in the _____ of his own time.- ",
    "answer": "Fulness "
  },
  {
    "id": 958,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep11:8",
    "question": "Nephi wrote some of the words of Isaiah, that his people would liken his words to themselves as well as us in our time.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 959,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep12:1",
    "question": "The father of Isaiah the prophet was _____.-",
    "answer": "Amoz "
  },
  {
    "id": 960,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep12:2",
    "question": "The house of the Lord shall be established in the top of the mountains, and all shall be exalted above the hills, and all nations shall ____ unto it.-",
    "answer": "Flow "
  },
  {
    "id": 961,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep12:6",
    "question": "O Lord, thou hast forsaken the house of Jacob, because they were replenished from the east, and hearken unto soothsayers like the Philistines.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 962,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep12:12",
    "question": "For the day of the Lord of _____soon comes upon all nations.-",
    "answer": "Hosts "
  },
  {
    "id": 963,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep12:13",
    "question": "Yea, the day of the Lord shall come upon all the _____ of Lebanon, for they are lifted up; and upon all the oaks of Bashan.",
    "answer": "Cedars "
  },
  {
    "id": 964,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep12:19",
    "question": "And they shall hide themselves into the holes of the rocks, and into the _____ of the earth, for the fear of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Caves "
  },
  {
    "id": 965,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep13:4",
    "question": "And the Lord said- “I will give children unto them to be their princes, and _____ shall rule over them”. ",
    "answer": "Babes "
  },
  {
    "id": 966,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep13:9",
    "question": "Nephi wrote about the countenance of the people and declared their sin to be even as the city of Sodom.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 967,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep14:6",
    "question": "Nephi said that there should be a _____ for a shadow in the daytime from the heat, and for a place of refuge.",
    "answer": "Tabernacle",
    "options": ["Building", "Tabernacle", "Barn"]
  },
  {
    "id": 968,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep13:16-17",
    "question": "Because the daughters of Zion are haughty, and walk with stretched-forth necks and wanton eyes, the Lord will smite them with a scab on the crown of their heads.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 969,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep15:4",
    "question": "The Lord looked at his vineyard that it might bring forth grapes, but instead it brought forth _____ grapes.-",
    "answer": "Wild "
  },
  {
    "id": 970,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep15:7",
    "question": "For the vineyard of the Lord or Hosts is the house of Israel.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 971,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep15:7",
    "question": "The men of Judah are the Lord of Host’s pleasant_____.",
    "answer": "Plant",
    "options": ["Plant", "Apple", "Orange"]
  },
  {
    "id": 972,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep15:9",
    "question": "The Lord of Hosts has said that many houses shall be desolate, and great and fair cities without inhabitant.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 973,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep15:26",
    "question": "The Lord will lift up an_____ to the nations from afar, and will hiss unto them from the end of the earth.-",
    "answer": "Ensign "
  },
  {
    "id": 974,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep16:1",
    "question": "In what king’s reign did Isaiah see the Lord of Hosts sitting upon a throne, high and lifted up?",
    "answer": "Uzziah",
    "options": ["Uzziah", "King Tut", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 975,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep16:2",
    "question": "When Isaiah saw the Seraphim creature, how many wings did the Seraphim creature have?",
    "answer": "Six",
    "options": ["Two", "Six", "One"]
  },
  {
    "id": 976,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep16:5",
    "question": "Isaiah said that his eyes had seen the King, the Lord of _____. ",
    "answer": "Hosts "
  },
  {
    "id": 977,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep16:8",
    "question": "The Lord asked: “Whom should I send to warn the people”? And Isaiah said, here I am, _____ me. ",
    "answer": "Send "
  },
  {
    "id": 978,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep17:1 and Isaiah 7",
    "question": "King Ahaz made an alliance with the king of Assryria, in order to repel an attack from Syria and Israel.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 979,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep17:8",
    "question": "For the head of Syria is _____.",
    "answer": "Damascus",
    "options": ["Bad", "Smelly", "Damascus"]
  },
  {
    "id": 980,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep17:12",
    "question": "Ahaz did not ask or temp the Lord for a sign.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 981,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep17:14",
    "question": "Jacob said the Lord will show the people a sign: which was a _____ and she shall conceive, and shall bear a son, and his name will be Immauel.",
    "answer": "Virgin "
  },
  {
    "id": 982,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Isaiah2Nep18:1",
    "question": "The Lord has sent his word unto _____ and it he has lighted it upon Israel.",
    "answer": "",
    "options": ["Laman", "Lemuel", ""]
  },
  {
    "id": 983,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep18:2",
    "question": "Isaiah took Uriah the priest and Zechariah the son of Jeberechiah to record and witness the birth of Maher-shalal-hash-baz.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 984,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep18:1",
    "question": "Maher-shalal-hash-baz is the name of_____son.",
    "answer": "Isaiah's",
    "options": ["Nephi's", "Isaiah's", "Zarahemla's"]
  },
  {
    "id": 985,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep18:14",
    "question": "The Lord shall be a sanctuary to the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 986,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep18:19",
    "question": "Jacob asked; should not a people seek unto their God for the living to hear from the dead? ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 987,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep18:20",
    "question": "And those that speak not according to his word; it is because there is no light from God in them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 988,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep19:6",
    "question": "Another name for Jesus Christ is The Prince of _____.",
    "answer": "Peace "
  },
  {
    "id": 989,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep19:6",
    "question": "The Lord refers to himself as The Everlasting Father.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 990,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep19:8",
    "question": "The Lord sent his word unto Jacob and he has lighted it upon the house of _____.",
    "answer": "Israel "
  },
  {
    "id": 991,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep19:12",
    "question": "For all the Lord’s anger against Israel is not turned away, but his hand is _____ out still.",
    "answer": "Stretched "
  },
  {
    "id": 992,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep19:13",
    "question": "The Lord has smitten the house of Israel, but they continue not to turn to him or seek him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 993,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep19:16",
    "question": "The leaders of the people cause them to err; and they that are led of them are destroyed.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 994,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep19:21",
    "question": "Ephraim and _____ will join together and be against Judah.",
    "answer": "Manasseh "
  },
  {
    "id": 995,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep20:22",
    "question": "And though the people of Israel shall be as the sand of the sea, a remnant of them shall return.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 996,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep21:7",
    "question": "Jacob prophesied that in the end of times; the lion shall eat straw like the _____.",
    "answer": "Ox "
  },
  {
    "id": 997,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep21:10",
    "question": "There shall be a root of Jesse which shall stand for an ensign of the people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 998,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep21:15",
    "question": "The Lord shall utterly destroy the tongue of the _____ Sea.",
    "answer": "Egyptian",
    "options": ["Red", "Egyptian", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 999,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep22:2",
    "question": "God is my salvation; I will trust, and not be afraid; the Lord_____ is my strength and my song.",
    "answer": "Jehovah "
  },
  {
    "id": 1000,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep23:19",
    "question": "Jacob said that Babylon, the beauty of the Chaldees’ excellency, shall be as when God overthrew Sodom and _____.",
    "answer": "Gomorrah "
  },
  {
    "id": 1001,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep24:2",
    "question": "The Lord will have mercy on the Jacob and shall take them captives unto whom they were captives and rule over their oppressors.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1002,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep24:12",
    "question": "How art thou fallen from heaven, O Lucifer, son of the _____ ",
    "answer": "Morning "
  },
  {
    "id": 1003,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep24:12",
    "question": "How many times does the name Lucifer appear in the Book Of Mormon?_____-(a) 1 (b) 2 or (c) 3",
    "answer": "no",
    "options": ["no"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1004,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep24:12",
    "question": "The word Lucifer only appears in the Book of Mormon once, name the Book in which it appears in. ",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 1005,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep24:13",
    "question": "Lucifer wanted to ascend into heaven, and wanted to exalt his throne above the stars of _____.",
    "answer": "God "
  },
  {
    "id": 1006,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep24:24",
    "question": "The Lord of Hosts hath sworn, saying: “Surely as I have thought, so shall it come to pass: and as I have purposed, so shall it stand”-",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1007,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:2",
    "question": "Nephi did not teach his people all the things concerning the manner of the Jews, because their works were works of _____, and their doings were doings of abominations.",
    "answer": "Darkness "
  },
  {
    "id": 1008,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep25:1",
    "question": "Nephi said that Isaiah spoke many things which were hard for his people to understand.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1009,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep25:4",
    "question": "Nephi’s plainness started when he left Jerusalem and his soul delighteth in plainness unto his people that they may learn. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1010,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep25:5",
    "question": "Nephi’s soul delighted in the words of Isaiah.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1011,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep25:5",
    "question": "Nephi wrote that he beheld the things of the Jewish people; and that they knew and understood the words of the prophets spoken to them. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1012,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep25:7",
    "question": "Nephi proceeded with his own prophecies in plainness that he knew that no man can err. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1013,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:7",
    "question": "Nephi wrote that in the days that the prophecies of Isaiah shall be fulfilled, men shall know of a surety, at the times when they shall come to _____. ",
    "answer": "Pass "
  },
  {
    "id": 1014,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep25:9",
    "question": "Nephi said that never have any of the Jews been destroyed without warning save it were foretold them by the prophets of the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1015,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:12",
    "question": "Nephi refers to the Savior as the Only_____of the Father.",
    "answer": "Begotten"
  },
  {
    "id": 1016,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep25:12",
    "question": "How many days did Nephi say the Lord would be laid in sepulchre before he shall rise?____",
    "answer": "3",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1017,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep25:13",
    "question": "Nephi’s soul delights to prophesy concerning Jesus Christ, for he had seen his day and his heart did magnify his holy name.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1018,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep25:14",
    "question": "Nephi wrote that after the Messiah has risen from the dead, and has manifested himself unto his people, _____ shall be destroyed again.",
    "answer": "Jerusalem",
    "options": ["Salt Lake City", "Sugar City", "Jerusalem"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1019,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:18",
    "question": "Nephi said there is save one Messiah spoken by the prophets, and that Messiah is he who should be rejected of the _____.",
    "answer": "Jews "
  },
  {
    "id": 1020,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:19",
    "question": "Who is the first person in the Book of Mormon to refer to the Savior by the name of Jesus Christ?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 1021,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:19",
    "question": "According to the words of the prophets, and also the word of the angel of God, his name shall be_____ _____, the Son of God.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 1022,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:20",
    "question": "The Lord gave power unto _____ that he should heal nations after they had been bittern by poisonous serpents; if they would cast their eyes unto the serpent.",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },
  {
    "id": 1023,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep25:20",
    "question": "Nephi said there is no other name given under _____ save it be this Jesus Christ, of which I have spoken, whereby man can be saved.",
    "answer": "Heaven",
    "options": ["The Stars", "Heaven", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1024,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:21",
    "question": "The Lord God promised unto _____ that the things which I write shall be kept and preserved, and handed down unto his seed.",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 1025,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep25:21",
    "question": "The Lord God promised unto Joseph, that his seed should never perish as long as the earth should stand.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1026,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:23",
    "question": "Nephi and Jacob labored diligently to write, to persuade their children and their brethren, to believe in Christ, and to be reconciled to _____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 1027,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:24",
    "question": "The Nephites kept the law of _____, and looked forward with steadfastness unto Christ, until the law would be fulfilled. ",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },
  {
    "id": 1028,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep25:25",
    "question": "Nephi wrote that after Christ should come, the lawords of Mosmones would be dead; and they were made alive in Christ because of their faith.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1029,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:26",
    "question": "Nephi said, “we talk of Christ, we rejoice in Christ, we preach of Christ, we prophesy of _____.”",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 1030,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:26",
    "question": "Who did Nephi say that his children and his brethren should know to what source they may look for a remission of their sins? ",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 1031,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep25:28",
    "question": "The words which Nephi has spoken shall stand as a testimony against his people, and they are sufficient to teach any man the right way.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1032,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:29",
    "question": "And now behold, I say unto you that the right way is to believe in _____, and deny him not, and he is the Holy One of Israel.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 1033,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:29",
    "question": "Wherefore ye must bow down before him, and worship him with all your ____, mind, and strength, and your soul.",
    "answer": "Might"
  },
  {
    "id": 1034,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep26:1",
    "question": "Nephi said that after Christ shall have risen from the dead he would show himself unto the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1035,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:2",
    "question": "Nephi saw many generations pass away, and there would be great _____ and contentions among his people.",
    "answer": "Wars"
  },
  {
    "id": 1036,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep26:3",
    "question": "Nephi wrote that after the Messiah shall come there shall be signs given unto his people of his birth.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1037,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:3",
    "question": "Unto the Nephites there shall be given signs of the Messiah’s death and _____.",
    "answer": "Resurrection"
  },
  {
    "id": 1038,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:3",
    "question": "The wicked perish because they cast out the _____, and the saints, and stone and slay them.",
    "answer": "Prophets"
  },
  {
    "id": 1039,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep26:3",
    "question": "Because the wicked do bad things; the blood of the saints shall ascend up to God from the ground against them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1040,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep26:4",
    "question": "Those that are proud and wicked, the Lord will burn as _____.",
    "answer": "Stubble",
    "options": ["Stubble", "To The Ground", "He Pleases"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1041,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep26:6",
    "question": "The wicked shall be visited with thundering, lightning, and earthquakes, and all manner of destruction.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1042,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep26:8",
    "question": "The righteous look forward unto Christ with steadfastness for the signs which are given, not withstanding all persecution-. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1043,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep26:9",
    "question": "The Son of righteousness shall appear unto the Nephites and he shall heal them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1044,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:9",
    "question": "How many generations will have pass away in righteousness after the Savior appears unto the Nephites? ",
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "id": 1045,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep26:10",
    "question": "The Nephites will reap destruction, because of their pride and foolishness.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1046,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:10",
    "question": "Because the Nephites yielded unto the _____ and choose works of darkness rather than light, therefore they must go down to hell.",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },
  {
    "id": 1047,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:11",
    "question": "Nephi wrote- The _____ of the Lord will not always strive with man. ",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },
  {
    "id": 1048,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep26:11",
    "question": "Nephi said that when the spirit of the Lord ceases to strive with man, then comes speedy destruction.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1049,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:12",
    "question": "Not only do the Jews need to be convinced that Jesus is the very Christ, it must needs be that the _____ be convinced also that Jesus is the Christ, the Eternal God.",
    "answer": "Gentiles"
  },
  {
    "id": 1050,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:12",
    "question": "Who was the first person in the Book of Mormon to call the Savior by the name of Jesus Christ?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 1051,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:13",
    "question": "Jesus Christ manifest's himself unto all those that believe in him by the power of the Holy _____.",
    "answer": "Ghost"
  },
  {
    "id": 1052,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:13",
    "question": "According to the faith among the children of men, God will work mighty _____, signs, and wonders.",
    "answer": "Miracles"
  },
  {
    "id": 1053,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep26:14",
    "question": "Nephi prophesied concerning the last days; concerning the days that the Lord God shall bring mighty things forth unto the children of men.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1054,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:16",
    "question": "For those who shall be destroyed shall speak unto them out of the ground, and their speech shall be low out of the _____.",
    "answer": "Dust"
  },
  {
    "id": 1055,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep26:19",
    "question": "It shall come to pass, that those who have dwindled in unbelief shall be _____ by the hands of the Gentiles.",
    "answer": "Smitten",
    "options": ["Slapped", "Smitten", "Led"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1056,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:20",
    "question": "The Gentiles are lifted up in the _____ of their eyes, and have stumbled.",
    "answer": "Pride"
  },
  {
    "id": 1057,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep26:20",
    "question": "Because of the greatness of their stumbling blocks, the Gentiles have built up many churches.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1058,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:20",
    "question": "The Gentiles put down the power and miracles of _____. ",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 1059,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:20",
    "question": "The Gentiles preach up unto themselves their own wisdom and _____; that they may get gain and grind upon the face of the poor.",
    "answer": "Learning"
  },
  {
    "id": 1060,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep26:21",
    "question": "There are many churches built up which cause envyings, and strifes, and malice.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1061,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:22",
    "question": "The Gentiles are also into _____ combinations, even as in times of old.",
    "answer": "Secret"
  },
  {
    "id": 1062,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:22",
    "question": "Who is the foundation of evil things and works of darkness? The ",
    "answer": "Devil-"
  },
  {
    "id": 1063,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep26:22",
    "question": "The devil leads men by the neck with a _____ cord, until he binds them with his strong cords forever.",
    "answer": "Flaxen",
    "options": ["Stiff", "Flaxen", "Tough"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1064,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Nep26:23",
    "question": "Nephi wrote: “For behold, my beloved brethren, I say unto you that the Lord God works not in darkness”.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1065,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep26:24",
    "question": "The Lord does not do anything but for the benefit of man and the world.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1066,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep26:24",
    "question": "The Lord loves the world; even that he lays down his own life that he may draw all men unto him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1067,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep27:27",
    "question": "Wherefore, the Lord commands all men to partake of his salvation.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1068,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep26:27",
    "question": "The Lord has given all men the opportunity to partake of his salvation for free.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1069,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep26:25",
    "question": "Nephi said the Lord does not cry unto any, saying: “Depart from me”.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1070,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep26:27",
    "question": "The Lord has given his salvation free for all men; and he commanded his people that they should persuade all men to repentance.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1071,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep26:29",
    "question": "The Lord has commanded that there should be no priestcrafts.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1072,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:29",
    "question": "What is the name of the things that men preach and set themselves up for a light unto the world? ",
    "answer": "Priestcrafts"
  },
  {
    "id": 1073,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep26:29",
    "question": "Men do priestcrafts to get gain and praise of the world; but they seek not the welfare of Zion.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1074,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:30",
    "question": "The Lord God has given a commandment that all men should have _____, which charity is love.",
    "answer": "Charity"
  },
  {
    "id": 1075,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep26:30",
    "question": "The Lord God has said that if we do not have charity we are nothing.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1076,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep26:31",
    "question": "Nephi wrote that the laborer in Zion shall labor fro Zion; for if they labor for money they shall perish.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1077,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep26:32",
    "question": "Nephi recited the Ten Commandments in 2Nephi.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1078,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep26:33",
    "question": "No iniquities come of the Lord; for he does that which is _____ among the children of men.",
    "answer": "Good",
    "options": ["Good", "Tasteful", "Awful"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1079,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:33",
    "question": "The Lord does nothing save it be plain unto the children of men; and he invites them all to come unto him and partake of his _____.",
    "answer": "Goodness- "
  },
  {
    "id": 1080,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:33",
    "question": "The Lord denies none that come unto him, black and white, bond and free, _____ and female.",
    "answer": "Male"
  },
  {
    "id": 1081,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep26:33",
    "question": "The Lord remembers the heathen, and all are alike unto God, both Jew and Gentile.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1082,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep27:1",
    "question": "Nephi prophesied that in the days of the Gentiles; all nations of the Gentiles and of the Jews they will be drunken with iniquity and all manner of abominations",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1083,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep27:2",
    "question": "In those days of the Gentiles; the Lord will visit them with storm, tempest, and earthquakes, and with the flame of devouring fire.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1084,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep27:4",
    "question": "For behold, all those that do iniquity; you shall be drunken but not with wine, you shall stagger but not from strong drink.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1085,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep27:6",
    "question": "Nephi said: 'It shall come to pass that the Lord shall bring forth unto you the words of a book, and they shall be the _____ of them which have slumbered'.",
    "answer": "Words"
  },
  {
    "id": 1086,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep27:7",
    "question": "The book that the Lord shall deliver will be sealed up; and in the book shall be a revelation from God, from the beginning of the world to the ending thereof.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1087,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep27:9",
    "question": "But the book shall be delivered unto a man, and he shall deliver the words of the _____.",
    "answer": "Book",
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Book", "2nd Coming"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1088,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep27:10",
    "question": "Nephi said that the man would not deliver the words of the book which are sealed by the power of God. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1089,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep27:10",
    "question": "When will the revelation/revelations of the book be delivered or made known to us?",
    "answer": "The Lords Own Due Time",
    "options": ["2025", "The Lords Own Due Time", "When We Are Worthy"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1090,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep27:10",
    "question": "The portion of the book which is sealed reveals all things from the foundation of the _____ unto the end thereof.",
    "answer": "World"
  },
  {
    "id": 1091,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep27:11",
    "question": "And the day will come that the words of the book which were sealed shall be read upon the _____ tops; and they shall be read by the power of Christ.",
    "answer": "House"
  },
  {
    "id": 1092,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep27:12",
    "question": "None shall behold the book, save it be that _____ witnesses shall behold it, by the power of God, besides him to whom the book shall be delivered.",
    "answer": "Three"
  },
  {
    "id": 1093,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep27:12",
    "question": "Those to whom the book shall be delivered shall testify to the truth of the book and the things therein.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1094,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep27:15",
    "question": "The Lord God shall say unto him whom he shall deliver the book:  Take these words which are not sealed and deliver them to another, that he may show them unto the _____ man.",
    "answer": "Learned",
    "options": ["Learned", "Nosey", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1095,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep27:15",
    "question": "And the learned shall say:  Bring hither the book, and I will read it.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1096,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep27:16-17",
    "question": "Because the learned will try to get gain and the glory of the world and not for God, he will not be able to read the sealed portion of the book.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1097,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep27:19",
    "question": "The Lord will deliver again the book and the words thereof to him that is not learned and he shall say:  “I am not learned”.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1098,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep27:21",
    "question": "Touch not the things which are _____; for I will show unto the children of men that I am able to do mine own work.",
    "answer": "Sealed"
  },
  {
    "id": 1099,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep27:22",
    "question": "The Lord shall see fit in his own wisdom to reveal all things unto the children of men.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1100,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep27:23",
    "question": "For behold, I am God; and I am a God of miracles; and I will show unto the world that I am the same, yesterday, _____, and forever.",
    "answer": "Today"
  },
  {
    "id": 1101,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep27:23",
    "question": "The Lord will not work among the children of men save it be according to their _____.",
    "answer": "Faith",
    "options": ["Obedience", "Usefulness", "Faith"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1102,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep27:26",
    "question": "Therefore, I will proceed to do a marvelous work and a _____, among the people.",
    "answer": "Wonder"
  },
  {
    "id": 1103,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep27:27",
    "question": "Woe unto them that seek deep to hide their counsel from the Lord! And their works are in the dark.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1104,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep27:27",
    "question": "But behold, I will show unto them, saith the Lord of Hosts, that I know all their works.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1105,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep27:29",
    "question": "There will come a day that the deaf shall hear the words of the book and the eyes of the blind shall see out of obscurity and out of _____.",
    "answer": "Darkness- "
  },
  {
    "id": 1106,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep27:30",
    "question": "The poor among the people will rejoice in the Holy One of Israel.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1107,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep27:31",
    "question": "For assuredly as the Lord lives they shall see that the terrible one is brought to _____.",
    "answer": "Naught",
    "options": ["His Knees", "Naught", "Something"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1108,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep27:33",
    "question": "Neither be ashamed neither your face wax pale, says the Lord, who redeemed Abraham, to the house of _____.",
    "answer": "Jacob",
    "options": ["Nephi", "Jacob", "Lehi"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1109,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep27:35",
    "question": "Nephi said that those that erred in spirit shall come to understanding, and they that murmured shall learn doctrine.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1110,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:1",
    "question": "Nephi spoke unto his people, according as the Spirit had constrained him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1111,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep28:2",
    "question": "The things written out of the book; shall be of great worth unto the _____of men.",
    "answer": "Children",
    "options": ["Power", "Children", "Learning"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1112,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:2",
    "question": "The things that are written in the book will be worth especially more unto the seed of Nephi.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1113,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:2",
    "question": "The seed of Nephi is a remnant of the house of Israel. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1114,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:3",
    "question": "A lot of churches will say: I am the Lord’s but not all of them will be built up unto the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1115,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep28:4",
    "question": "In the last days a lot of churches will contend one with another and so will their _____.",
    "answer": "Priests",
    "options": ["Priests", "Angels", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1116,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:4",
    "question": "Churches will teach with their learning, and deny the Holy _____ which gives utterance.",
    "answer": "Ghost"
  },
  {
    "id": 1117,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:5",
    "question": "A lot of churches deny the power of God, the Holy One of Israel.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1118,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:5",
    "question": "Churches will say: Hearken unto us, and hear our precept; for behold there is no God today.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1119,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:5",
    "question": "A lot of churches will say that the Lord the Redeemer has done his work, and he has given his power unto men.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1120,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:6",
    "question": "In the last days churches will say that the Lord God has done away with miracles because he already has done his work.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1121,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:7",
    "question": "Yea, there shall be many which say:  Eat, drink and be _____, for tomorrow we die; and it shall be well with us.",
    "answer": "Merry"
  },
  {
    "id": 1122,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:8",
    "question": "Eat, drink, and be merry; nevertheless, fear God-he will justify in committing a little sin.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1123,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:8",
    "question": "Many will say-dig a pit for thy neighbor; there is no harm in this; for tomorrow we _____. ",
    "answer": "Die"
  },
  {
    "id": 1124,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:8",
    "question": "If we are guilty of doing bad things many will say: God will beat us with a few _____, and at last we shall be saved in the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": "Stripes- "
  },
  {
    "id": 1125,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:9",
    "question": "Many churches shall teach false and vain and foolish doctrines.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1126,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:9",
    "question": "Many will seek to hide their counsels from the Lord; and their works shall be in the dark.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1127,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep28:10",
    "question": "The blood of the saints, shall cry from the _____ against false churches.",
    "answer": "Ground",
    "options": ["Wells", "Ground", "Sky"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1128,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:12",
    "question": "Because of pride, and because of false doctrine, their churches have become corrupted.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1129,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep28:12",
    "question": "Many churches are lifted up because of pride and they are _____ up.",
    "answer": "Puffed",
    "options": ["Puffed", "Fithly", "Lifted"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1130,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:13",
    "question": "Because of their fine sanctuaries and clothing; many churches rob the poor.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1131,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:13",
    "question": "Because of their pride, many churches _____ the meek and the poor in heart.",
    "answer": "Persecute"
  },
  {
    "id": 1132,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:14",
    "question": "Many churches because of wickedness and abominations; have gone astray save it be a few, who are the humble followers of Christ.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1133,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:4",
    "question": "Churches are led, that in many instances they do err because they are taught by the learning of _____.",
    "answer": "Men"
  },
  {
    "id": 1134,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:15",
    "question": "O the wise, and the learned, and the rich, that are puffed up in the pride of their hearts; they shall be thrust down to hell.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1135,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:15",
    "question": "Woe, woe, _____ be unto them, saith the Lord God Almighty, for they shall be thrust down to hell.",
    "answer": "Woe"
  },
  {
    "id": 1136,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:16",
    "question": "For the day shall come that the Lord will speedily visit the inhabitants of the earth; and in that day those who are fully ripe in iniquity shall perish.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1137,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep28:17",
    "question": "Those that repent of their wickedness and _____, they shall not be destroyed, saith the Lord of Hosts.",
    "answer": "Abominations",
    "options": ["Abominations", "Sins", "Filthiness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1138,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:18",
    "question": "The great and _____ church shall tumble to the earth, and great must be the fall thereof.",
    "answer": "Abominable"
  },
  {
    "id": 1139,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep28:19",
    "question": "It shall come to pass that the _____ of the devil shall shake.",
    "answer": "Kingdom",
    "options": ["Pit", "Kingdom", "Earth"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1140,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": " 2Nep28:20",
    "question": "In the last days the devil shall rage in the hearts of the children of men.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1141,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:20",
    "question": "The devil will stir up the children of men, and stir them up to anger against that which is good.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1142,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:21",
    "question": "Carnal-",
    "answer": "The devil will pacify, and lull many of the people to _____ security."
  },
  {
    "id": 1143,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:21",
    "question": "Zion- ",
    "answer": "Many will say:  All is well in _____; yea, Zion prospers, all is well."
  },
  {
    "id": 1144,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:21",
    "question": "The devil cheats many men of their souls, and leads them carefully down to hell.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1145,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:22",
    "question": "Devil-",
    "answer": "The devil flatters away many, and tells them there is no hell; and says unto them:  I am no _____, for there is none."
  },
  {
    "id": 1146,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:22",
    "question": "The devil whispers into people’s ear, until he grasps them with his awful chains, from where there is no deliverance.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1147,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:23",
    "question": "And all that have been seized by the devil must stand before the throne of God, and be judged according to their works. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1148,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:23",
    "question": "The wicked will go to the place prepared for them, even if it is a lake of fire and brimstone. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1149,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:23",
    "question": "Another way to best describe the lake of fire and brimstone is endless torment.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1150,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:24",
    "question": "Nephi said therefore, woe be unto him that is at ease in Zion!",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1151,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:25",
    "question": "Nephi wrote:” Woe be unto him that cries all is well! Even all is well in Zion”.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1152,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:26",
    "question": "Men-",
    "answer": "Woe be unto him that hearkens unto the precepts of _____, and denies the power of God, and the gift of the Holy Ghost!"
  },
  {
    "id": 1153,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:28",
    "question": "For behold, he that is built upon the rock receives the word of God with gladness; and he that is built upon a sandy foundation trembles and he shall fall.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1154,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:29",
    "question": "Word-",
    "answer": "Woe be unto him that shall say:  We have received the _____ of God, and we need no more of the word of God, for we have enough. "
  },
  {
    "id": 1155,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:3”",
    "question": "Precept-",
    "answer": "For behold, thus saith the Lord God “I will give unto the children of men line upon line, precept upon “_____."
  },
  {
    "id": 1156,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:30",
    "question": "Little-",
    "answer": "The Lord gives his word, here a little and there a _____; and blessed are those who hearken unto my precepts. "
  },
  {
    "id": 1157,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:30",
    "question": "The Lord is pleased with us when we lend and ear unto his counsel, and he has said that we will learn wisdom because of it.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1158,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:30",
    "question": "For those that say:  We have enough, from them shall be taken away even that which they already have.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1159,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:31",
    "question": "Nephi wrote: Cursed is he that puts his trust in man, or makes flesh his arm.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1160,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep28:32",
    "question": "Woe be unto the _____, I will be merciful unto them, saith the Lord God, if they will repent and come unto me.",
    "answer": "Gentiles",
    "options": ["Ugly", "Zoramites", "Gentiles"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1161,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:32",
    "question": "The Lord has said unto the Gentiles:  Repent and come unto me; for mine arm is lengthened out all day long for you.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1162,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep29:1",
    "question": "Nephi prophesied that the Lord will set his hand a second time to recover his people, which are of the house of Israel. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1163,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep29:2",
    "question": "Lehi-",
    "answer": "The Lord promised to remember the covenants he made to Nephi and his father named _____."
  },
  {
    "id": 1164,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep29:2",
    "question": "The Lord’s words shall proceed forth out of his mouth unto the seed of Nephi.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1165,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep29:2",
    "question": "God’s words shall hiss forth unto the ends of the earth, for a _____ unto my people, which are of the house of Israel.",
    "answer": "Standard",
    "options": ["Proclamation", "Standard", "Lecture"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1166,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep29:3",
    "question": "Bible-",
    "answer": "Many Gentiles shall say:  A Bible! A _____! We have got a Bible, and there cannot be any more Bible."
  },
  {
    "id": 1167,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep29:4",
    "question": "Who are the Lords ancient covenant people?",
    "answer": "Jews Or (c)",
    "options": ["Louisianan", "Idahoan", "Jews Or (c)"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1168,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep29:5",
    "question": "The Gentiles have not remembered the Lord’s covenant people, but have cursed and hated them, and have not sought to recover them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1169,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep29:6",
    "question": "Those that say:  A Bible, we have got a Bible, and we need no more Bible, they are _____, the Lord has said.",
    "answer": "Fools",
    "options": ["Not Smart", "Not Christians", "Fools"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1170,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep29:7",
    "question": "The Lord asked: “Know ye not that there are more nations than one”?  Know ye not that I, the Lord your God, have created all men.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1171,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep29:7",
    "question": "God remembers every single one of us, even those that are upon the isles of the sea.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1172,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep29:7",
    "question": "Rules-",
    "answer": "The Lord _____ in the heavens above and in the earth beneath."
  },
  {
    "id": 1173,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep29:7",
    "question": "God will bring forth his word unto the children of men, yea, even upon all the nations of the earth.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1174,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep29:8",
    "question": "Murmur-",
    "answer": "Wherefore _____ ye, because that ye shall receive more of my word?"
  },
  {
    "id": 1175,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Nep29:8",
    "question": "The Lord said:  “Know ye not that the testimony of _____ nations is a witness unto you that I am God, and that I remember one nation like unto another”.",
    "answer": "Two",
    "options": ["Two", "Twenty", "Four"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1176,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep29:8",
    "question": "Testimony-",
    "answer": "And when the two nations shall run together the _____ of the two nations shall run together also."
  },
  {
    "id": 1177,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep29:9",
    "question": "The testimony of the two nations will prove unto many that God is the same yesterday, today, and forever.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1178,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep29:9",
    "question": "The Lord’s work is not yet finished; neither shall it be until the end of _____, neither from that time henceforth and forever.",
    "answer": "Man",
    "options": ["Time", "Man", "The Tonight Show"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1179,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep29:10",
    "question": "Bible-",
    "answer": "Wherefore, because that ye have a _____ ye need not suppose that it contains all the Lord’s words."
  },
  {
    "id": 1180,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep29:10",
    "question": "Just because we have a Bible, we need not suppose that it contains all of the Lord’s words and that he has not caused more to be written.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1181,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep29:11",
    "question": "North-",
    "answer": "The Lord has commanded all men, both in the east and west, and in the _____, and in the south; that they should write which he has spoken unto them."
  },
  {
    "id": 1182,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep29:11",
    "question": "The Lord has not commanded the people in the islands of the sea to write the words which he has spoken.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1183,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep29:11",
    "question": "Written-",
    "answer": "God will judge every man according to his works, and according to that which is _____."
  },
  {
    "id": 1184,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep29:12",
    "question": "The Lord will speak unto the Jews and Nephites to write that which he has spoken.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1185,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep29:12",
    "question": "Tribes-",
    "answer": "The other _____ of the house of Israel that the Lord has led away; will also write the words which he has spoken."
  },
  {
    "id": 1186,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep29:13",
    "question": "Jews-",
    "answer": "And it shall come to pass that the Jews shall have the words of the Nephites, and the Nephites shall have the words of the _____."
  },
  {
    "id": 1187,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep29:13",
    "question": "Lost- ",
    "answer": "The Nephites and Jews shall have the words of the _____ tribes of Israel and the lost tribes of Israel shall have the words of the Nephites and Jews."
  },
  {
    "id": 1188,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep29:14",
    "question": "And it shall come to pass that my people; whom are of the house of Israel, shall be gathered home unto the lands of their possessions.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1189,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep29:14",
    "question": "Abraham-",
    "answer": "The Lord will show unto them that fight against his word and people that I am God, and that I covenanted with _____ and that I would remember his seed forever."
  },
  {
    "id": 1190,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep30:1",
    "question": "Nephi wrote:  I, Nephi, would suffer that ye should suppose that ye are more righteous than the Gentiles.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1191,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep30:1",
    "question": "For behold, if we do not keep the commandments of God, we shall likewise perish.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1192,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep30:1",
    "question": "Because of the words that have been written, we should suppose that the Gentiles will be utterly destroyed.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1193,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep30:2",
    "question": "Jews-",
    "answer": "As many of the Gentiles as will repent are the covenant people of the Lord; and as many of the _____ as will not repent shall be cast off."
  },
  {
    "id": 1194,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep30:2",
    "question": "Lord-",
    "answer": "The _____ has covenanted with none save it be with them that repent and believe in his Son, who is the Holy One of Israel."
  },
  {
    "id": 1195,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep30:3",
    "question": "After the book shall come forth, and be written unto the Gentiles, and sealed up again unto the Lord, there shall be many which believe the words that are written.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1196,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep30:3",
    "question": "Gentiles-",
    "answer": "Who will carry forth the words which shall be written in the book unto the remnant seed of Nephi?_____"
  },
  {
    "id": 1197,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep30:4",
    "question": "Jerusalem-",
    "answer": "Then shall the remnant of our seed know concerning the Nephites, how that we came out from _____, and that they are descendants of the Jews."
  },
  {
    "id": 1198,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep30:5",
    "question": "Lemuel-",
    "answer": "The gospel of Jesus Christ shall be declared unto the remnant of the seed of Laman and _____."
  },
  {
    "id": 1199,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep30:5",
    "question": "Lamanites-",
    "answer": "Who shall be restored unto the knowledge of their fathers, and also to the knowledge of Jesus Christ, which was had among their fathers? "
  },
  {
    "id": 1200,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep30:6",
    "question": "When the Lamanites come to the knowledge of their fathers, they will rejoice; for they shall know that it is a blessing unto them from the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1201,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep30:6",
    "question": "Lamanites-",
    "answer": "Whose scales of darkness shall begin to fall from their eyes when the gospel of Jesus Christ shall be declared among them, and they shall be restored unto the knowledge of their fathers?  The "
  },
  {
    "id": 1202,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep30:6",
    "question": "Once there scales of darkness fall off, many generations shall not pass away among them, save they shall be a white and delightsome people",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1203,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep30:7",
    "question": "Pass-",
    "answer": "And it shall come to _____ that the Jews which are scattered also shall begin to believe in Jesus Christ that he is was the Messiah."
  },
  {
    "id": 1204,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep30:7",
    "question": "Christ-",
    "answer": "Many Jews shall begin to gather in upon the face of the land; and as many as shall believe in _____ shall also become a delightsome people. "
  },
  {
    "id": 1205,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep30:8",
    "question": "People-",
    "answer": "And it shall come to pass that the Lord God shall commence his work among all nations, tongues, and _____."
  },
  {
    "id": 1206,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep30:8",
    "question": "The Lord will bring the restoration of the gospel to his people who are upon the earth.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1207,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep30:9",
    "question": "Meek-",
    "answer": "And with righteousness shall the Lord God judge the poor, and reprove with equity the _____ of the earth."
  },
  {
    "id": 1208,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep30:9",
    "question": "Wicked-",
    "answer": "The Lord will smite the earth with the rod of his mouth; and with the breath of his lips shall he slay the _____."
  },
  {
    "id": 1209,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep30:10",
    "question": "For the time speedily comes that the Lord God shall cause a great division among the people, and the wicked will he destroy.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1210,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep30:10",
    "question": "The Lord will spare the righteous and his people, yea, even if it so be that he must destroy the wicked by _____.",
    "answer": "Fire",
    "options": ["Rockets", "Fire", "Flooding The Earth"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1211,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep30:11",
    "question": "And _____ shall be the girdle of his loins, and faithfulness the girdle of his reins.",
    "answer": "Righteousness",
    "options": ["Gentiles", "Righteousness", "Lamanites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1212,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep30:12",
    "question": "And the leopard shall lie down with the kid, and the calf, and the young lion together, and a _____ child shall lead them.",
    "answer": "Little",
    "options": ["Little", "Smart", "Big"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1213,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep30:13",
    "question": "In the last days the cow and the bear shall feed together, and the lion shall eat _____ like the ox.",
    "answer": "Straw",
    "options": ["Straw", "Hay", "Fruit"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1214,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep30:15",
    "question": "The earth shall be full of the knowledge of the Lord, the same as the waters cover the sea.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1215,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep30:16",
    "question": "In the last days – the things of all _____ shall be made known; yea, all things shall be known unto the children of men.",
    "answer": "Nations",
    "options": ["Cities", "Nations", "The Universe"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1216,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep30:17",
    "question": "In the last days not all the secret things will be revealed unto men.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1217,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep30:17",
    "question": "Nephi said concerning the end that there will be no works of darkness save it shall be made manifest in the light.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1218,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep30:18",
    "question": "Wherefore, all things which have been revealed unto the children of men shall not be revealed at that day.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1219,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep30:18",
    "question": "Hearts-",
    "answer": "Nephi wrote that Satan shall have no power over the _____ of the children of men, no more, for a long time."
  },
  {
    "id": 1220,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep30:18",
    "question": "How long did Nephi say that Satan would have no power over the children of men?",
    "answer": "Long Time",
    "options": ["Long Time", "1,000 Years", "A Lot Of Years"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1221,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep30:18",
    "question": "Never in the Book of Mormon are we told by Mormon how long Satan will be chained up for during the second coming of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1222,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep31:1",
    "question": "Nephi wrote but a few things which shall come to pass; neither could he write but of few words of his brother _____.",
    "answer": "Jacob",
    "options": ["Sam", "Jacob", "Laman"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1223,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep31:2",
    "question": "Nephi spoke plainly of the doctrine of Christ, as far as the plainness of his prophesying.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1224,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:3",
    "question": "Nephi wrote:  My soul _____ in plainness; for after this manner does the Lord God work among the children of men.",
    "answer": "Delight"
  },
  {
    "id": 1225,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep31:3",
    "question": "For the Lord God gives light unto all his words and works so that we can be confused.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1226,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:3",
    "question": "For the Lord speaks to each of us according to our _____, so that we can all understand him.",
    "answer": "Language"
  },
  {
    "id": 1227,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:4",
    "question": "Nephi wrote and hoped that we should all remember the Lord and he showed him the _____ who would baptize the Lamb of God.",
    "answer": "Prophet"
  },
  {
    "id": 1228,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Neph31:4",
    "question": "Never in the Book of Mormon are we told by Mormon what the name of the prophet is who will baptize the Lamb of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1229,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep31:4",
    "question": "Nephi said that the Lamb of God would take only the real bad sins away from all of us. ",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1230,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:5",
    "question": "If the Lamb of God should have need to be baptized by _____ , to fulfill all righteousness; should we not all have the need to be baptized by water also? ",
    "answer": "Water"
  },
  {
    "id": 1231,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep31:7",
    "question": "The Lord has shown unto the children of men that, according to the flesh that he has humbled himself before the Father.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1232,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:7",
    "question": "By being baptized; the Lord witnessed unto the Father that he would be obedient unto him in keeping his _____.",
    "answer": "Commandments"
  },
  {
    "id": 1233,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:8",
    "question": "What kind of form of bird descended upon Jesus Christ after he was baptized, as the Holy Ghost?",
    "answer": "Dove"
  },
  {
    "id": 1234,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep31:9",
    "question": "The Lord shows unto the children of men the straightness of the path, and the narrowness of the gate, by which they should enter, he having set the example.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1235,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep31:10",
    "question": "Nephi wrote that the Lord has said unto the children of men to follow the devil and not him.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1236,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:11",
    "question": "And the Father said:”Repent ye, _____ ye, and be baptized in the name of my Beloved Son”.",
    "answer": "Repent"
  },
  {
    "id": 1237,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:11, 2Nep2:28",
    "question": "Other names that we can use to describe Jesus Christ are:  The Messiah, Holy One of Israel, Mediator, and the _____ Son. ",
    "answer": "Beloved"
  },
  {
    "id": 1238,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:12",
    "question": "Be baptized in my name, to him will the _____ give the Holy Ghost, like unto me.",
    "answer": "Father"
  },
  {
    "id": 1239,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:12",
    "question": "The Lord has said:  Follow me, and do the things which ye have seen me _____.",
    "answer": "Do"
  },
  {
    "id": 1240,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:13",
    "question": "We should follow the Son, with a full purpose of heart, repenting of our sins, witnessing unto the Father that we are willing to take upon the name of _____.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 1241,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:13",
    "question": "After we are baptized with water, we shall receive the Holy Ghost; yea, then comes the baptism of _____ and of the Holy Ghost.",
    "answer": "Fire"
  },
  {
    "id": 1242,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep31:14",
    "question": "When we are baptized by water and have received the baptism of fire and of the Holy Ghost, we should not deny Jesus Christ, and if we do, it is better that we should have not known him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1243,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep31:15",
    "question": "Nephi heard God say:”Yea, the words of my Beloved are true and faithful, and he that endures to the end shall be saved”.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1244,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep31:16",
    "question": "Nephi said that unless a man shall endure to the end, in following the example of the Son of the living God, he cannot be _____.",
    "answer": "Saved",
    "options": ["Made Clean", "Saved", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1245,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:17",
    "question": "Nephi was shown by God the _____ by which we should enter the Kingdom of Heaven.",
    "answer": "Gate"
  },
  {
    "id": 1246,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:17",
    "question": "The gate by which we should enter is repentance and baptism by water; and then comes a _____ of our sins by fire and by the Holy Ghost.",
    "answer": "Remission"
  },
  {
    "id": 1247,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep31:18",
    "question": "After we do all the things which God has commanded, we are in the straight and narrow path which leads to _____ life.",
    "answer": "Eternal",
    "options": ["Eternal", "A Better", "Hum, Hum"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1248,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep31:19",
    "question": "After we are in the straight and narrow path of the Lord; we our finished with all that we can do.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1249,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep31:19",
    "question": "We are thus far saved by the word of Christ with unshaken faith in him, relying wholly upon the merits of him who is mighty to save.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1250,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep31:20",
    "question": "Wherefore ye should press forward with a _____ in Christ, having perfect brightness of hope, and of love of God and of all men.",
    "answer": "Steadfastness",
    "options": ["Steadfastness", "Word", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1251,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:20",
    "question": "Wherefore, if ye shall press forward_____ upon the words of Christ, and endure to the end, behold, thus saith the Father:  Ye shall have eternal life.",
    "answer": "Feasting"
  },
  {
    "id": 1252,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:21",
    "question": "Behold, there is none other way or name given under heaven whereby man can be _____ in the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": "Saved"
  },
  {
    "id": 1253,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:21",
    "question": "The doctrine of Christ; is the one and only true doctrine of the _____, and of the Son, and of the Holy Ghost.",
    "answer": "Father"
  },
  {
    "id": 1254,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep32:2",
    "question": "After we receive the Holy Ghost, Nephi said that we can speak with the _____ of angels only by and through the Holy Ghost.",
    "answer": "Tongue"
  },
  {
    "id": 1255,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep32:3",
    "question": "Angels speak by the power of the Holy Ghost.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1256,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep32:3",
    "question": "Wherefore, I said unto you, feast upon the words of Christ; for behold, the words of Christ will tell you all _____ what you should do.",
    "answer": "Things"
  },
  {
    "id": 1257,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep32:4",
    "question": "It we cannot understand the word of Christ, it is because we do not ask, neither do we knock, wherefore, we are not brought into the light, but must perish in the _____.",
    "answer": "Dark"
  },
  {
    "id": 1258,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep32:5",
    "question": "For behold, again I say unto you that if ye will enter in by the way, and receive the Holy Ghost, it will show unto you all the things which ye should do. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1259,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep32:6",
    "question": "Behold, this is the doctrine of Christ, and there will be no more doctrine given until after he shall manifest himself unto you in the _____.",
    "answer": "Flesh",
    "options": ["Flesh", "Day", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1260,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep32:6",
    "question": "After the Lord shall manifest himself in the flesh, and unto the Nephites, the things which he shall say unto you shall ye observe to do.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1261,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep32:7",
    "question": "Nephi could not say more concerning the doctrine of Christ because the _____ stopped his utterance.",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },
  {
    "id": 1262,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep32:7",
    "question": "Nephi mourned because of the stiffneckedness, unbelief, and wickedness of men.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1263,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep32:7",
    "question": "Nephi wrote and said that the Lord has given to us the doctrine of Christ in plainness, even as plain as word could be.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1264,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep32:8",
    "question": "For if we hearken unto the _____, it teaches man to pray.",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },
  {
    "id": 1265,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep32:8",
    "question": "Nephi said that the spirit of the devil also teaches that men must pray unto God.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1266,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep32:9",
    "question": "But behold, I say unto you that ye must pray always, and not _____.",
    "answer": "Faint",
    "options": [
      "Faint",
      "During Monday Night Football",
      "During The Super Bowl"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 1267,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep32:9",
    "question": "We must not perform any thing unto the Lord save in the first place we should pray unto the Father in the name of _____.",
    "answer": ["savior", "lord", "christ"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1268,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep32:9",
    "question": "We pray unto the father in the name of Christ that he may consecrate our performance unto ourselves, and that it will be for the welfare of our _____.",
    "answer": "Souls- "
  },
  {
    "id": 1269,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep33:1",
    "question": "Nephi confessed to us that he was mighty in writing as well as speaking.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1270,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep33:1",
    "question": "Nephi could not write all the things that were taught to the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1271,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep33:1",
    "question": "When a man speaks by the power of the Holy Ghost the power of the Holy Ghost carries it unto the _____ of the children of men.",
    "answer": "Hearts"
  },
  {
    "id": 1272,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep33:2",
    "question": "But behold, there are many that harden their hearts against the Holy Spirit, that it has no place in them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1273,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep33:2",
    "question": "There are many people that cast away the things which are written and esteem them as things of no great worth.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1274,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep33:3",
    "question": "Nephi esteemed the words that he wrote as of great worth, especially unto the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1275,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep33:3",
    "question": "Nephi did not pray very much for his people, because they were beyond forgiveness.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1276,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep33:3",
    "question": "Nephi’s eyes watered his _____ by night, because of the great concern he had for his people.",
    "answer": "Pillow"
  },
  {
    "id": 1277,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep33:3",
    "question": "Nephi cried unto the Lord in faith, and he knew that Heavenly Father would hear his cries.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1278,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep33:4",
    "question": "Nephi testified that the Lord would not consecrate his prayers for the gain of his people. ",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1279,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep33:4",
    "question": "Nephi said that the words that he had written in_____ would be made strong unto his people.",
    "answer": "Weakness"
  },
  {
    "id": 1280,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep33:4",
    "question": "The words of Nephi will persuade the Nephites to do Good. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1281,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep33:4",
    "question": "Nephi’s words made the people of Nephi know concerning their _____.",
    "answer": "Fathers",
    "options": ["Color", "Fathers", "Goodness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1282,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep33:4",
    "question": "Nephi testified that his words spoke of Jesus Christ and persuaded his people to believe in him, and endure to the end.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1283,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep33:4",
    "question": "We do not have to endure to the end to have eternal life.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1284,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep33:5",
    "question": "Nephi’s words speak harshly against sin, according the plainness of the truth.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1285,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep33:5",
    "question": " The people that will be angry with the words that Nephi has written will be those that have the spirit of the _____.",
    "answer": ["devil", "satan"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1286,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep33:6",
    "question": "Nephi gloried in plainness, in truth, and in Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1287,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep33:6",
    "question": "Who has redeemed Nephi’s soul from the depths of hell?",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 1288,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep33:7",
    "question": "Nephi had _____ for his people, and great faith in Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "Charity",
    "options": ["Hope", "Faith", "Charity"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1289,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep33:8",
    "question": "Nephi had charity for the “_____-I say Jew, because I mean them from whence I came”.",
    "answer": "Jew"
  },
  {
    "id": 1290,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep33:7",
    "question": "Nephi had great faith in Jesus Christ and believed that he would meet many of us spotless before the judgment seat of Christ.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1291,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep33:9",
    "question": "Nephi also had charity for the Gentiles but said that they should be reconciled unto _____, and enter the narrow gate and walk in to the straight path that leads to eternal life.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 1292,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep33:9",
    "question": "We must continue in the straight path that leads to eternal life until all the days of our probation.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1293,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep33:10",
    "question": "Nephi wrote to his beloved brethren, and also the Jew, and to all the ends of the _____.",
    "answer": "Earth",
    "options": ["Time", "Earth", "Universe"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1294,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep33:10",
    "question": "Nephi said that we should hearken unto his words and believe in Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1295,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep33:10",
    "question": "Nephi wrote that if we do not believe in his words, at least we should believe in Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1296,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep33:10",
    "question": "Nephi said that if we would not believe in Jesus Christ, we would not believe in the words that he had written.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1297,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep33:10",
    "question": "Whose words are the words that Nephi has written?",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 1298,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep33:10",
    "question": "Who gave Nephi the words that he should write and teach all men that they should do good?",
    "answer": ["savior", "lord", "jesus", "christ"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1299,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep33:11",
    "question": "We should not judge the words of Jesus Christ; for if we do, he will show us with power and great _____, that they are his at the last day.",
    "answer": "Glory",
    "options": ["Force", "Glory", "Intention"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1300,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep33:11",
    "question": "Nephi and us will stand face to face before the judgment bar of Jesus Christ?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1301,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep33:11",
    "question": "We will not all see Nephi in the last day, before the judgment seat of Jesus Christ. ",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1302,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep33:11",
    "question": "Nephi was not commanded by Jesus Christ or anyone else to write the words he wrote.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1303,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep33:11",
    "question": "Nephi had weakness in his knees when he wrote the words that he was commanded to write by Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1304,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep33:12",
    "question": "Nephi prayed unto the Father in the name of Jesus Christ that many of us, if not all, would be saved.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1305,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep33:12",
    "question": "In what kingdom did Nephi wanted us to be saved in the last day?",
    "answer": ["father", "christ"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1306,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep33:13",
    "question": "Nephi spoke to us as the voice of one _____, from the dust.",
    "answer": "Crying",
    "options": ["Yelling", "Begging", "Crying"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1307,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2Nep33:13",
    "question": "Nephi wrote unto us and said _____, until that great day shall come.",
    "answer": "Farewell",
    "options": ["Goodbye", "Farewell", "Adieu"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1308,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep33:14",
    "question": "Nephi said farewell to those that would not partake in the goodness of God, and not respect the words of the Jews, and also his words.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1309,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep33:14",
    "question": "Nephi words and other people’s words; will not condemn us at the last day.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1310,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep33:14",
    "question": "Nephi was commanded by the Lord to seal on earth all things or words that will be brought against us at the judgment bar of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1311,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep33:14",
    "question": "Nephi’s last four words to us were:  I must obey.  Amen ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1312,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac1:1",
    "question": "When the Book of Jacob begins; how many years had passed away since Lehi and his party left Jerusalem.",
    "answer": "55",
    "options": ["25", "55", "75"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1313,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:27",
    "question": "How many chapters are there in the Book of Jacob?",
    "answer": "7",
    "options": ["5", "6", "7"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1314,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:1",
    "question": "Jacob was commanded by the Lord to write the words which he wrote in what is now known to us as- the Book of Jacob.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1315,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac1:1",
    "question": "On what size of plates did Jacob write the things which he was commanded by Nephi?",
    "answer": "Small",
    "options": ["Large", "Small", "Very Small"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1316,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac1:2",
    "question": "Jacob wrote upon the plates a _____ of the things which he considered to be most precious.",
    "answer": "Few",
    "options": ["A Lot", "Few", "Bunch"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1317,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:2",
    "question": "Jacob was not to touch, save it were lightly, concerning the history of the people of Nephi.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1318,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:3",
    "question": "The history of Jacob’s people should be engraved on other plates.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1319,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:3",
    "question": "Jacob said that the history of his people would be engraved on more than one set of plates.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1320,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac1:3",
    "question": "Jacob was commanded by Nephi to preserve these plates and hand them down unto his seed, from generation to _____.",
    "answer": "Generation"
  },
  {
    "id": 1321,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:4",
    "question": "Jacob was to engrave the heads of them upon the plates, if they were preaching which was sacred, or revelation which was great, or prophesying.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1322,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac1:4",
    "question": "Jacob was to touch or write upon the plates as much as it was possible, for ____ sake, and for the sake of his people.",
    "answer": "Christ’s",
    "options": ["His", "Christ’s", "The Devils"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1323,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac1:5",
    "question": "Because of _____ and great anxiety, it truly had been made manifest unto Jacob’s people, what things should happen to them.",
    "answer": "Faith"
  },
  {
    "id": 1324,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac1:6",
    "question": "Jacob and his people had many revelations, and the spirit of much _____.",
    "answer": "Prophecy",
    "options": ["Thinking", "Prophecy", "Foolishness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1325,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:6",
    "question": "Because of revelation and much prophecy, Jacob and his people knew of Jesus Christ; and his kingdom which should come.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1326,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac:17",
    "question": "Wherefore Jacob labored _____ among his people to persuade them to come to Christ and partake of his goodness.",
    "answer": "Diligently"
  },
  {
    "id": 1327,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:8",
    "question": "Jacob wanted to persuade all men not to rebel against God, and provoke him to get angry.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1328,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:8",
    "question": "God does not get angry with the children of men.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1329,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:9",
    "question": "Jacob hoped that all men would believe in Christ, and view his death, and suffer his cross and bear the shame of the world.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1330,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac1:9",
    "question": "Jacob took it upon himself to fulfill the _____ of his brother Nephi.",
    "answer": "Commandment",
    "options": ["Commandment", "Words", "Record"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1332,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:9",
    "question": "Nephi anointed a man to be a king and ruler of his people, according to the reigns of kings.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1333,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac1:10",
    "question": "The Nephites loved Nephi _____.",
    "answer": "Exceedingly",
    "options": ["Truly", "Exceedingly", "So And So"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1334,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac1:10",
    "question": "Nephi had been a great protector of the Nephites and had wielded the sword of _____ in their defense.",
    "answer": "Laban"
  },
  {
    "id": 1335,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:10",
    "question": "Nephi did not labor very much in his days with the Nephites for their welfare.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1336,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:11",
    "question": "The Nephites wanted to honor and retain in remembrance his name, so whoever reigned in his stead was called 2nd Nephi, 3rd Nephi, and so forth.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1337,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:12",
    "question": "When Nephi died, the words that were spoken during his funeral are written down for us to read and remember.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1338,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:13",
    "question": "There were many people during Jacob’s day and that put the suffix-ites, according to the name of their Leaders.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1339,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:14",
    "question": "Jacob would not distinguish some of the different tribes or people by their names of their leaders.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1340,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:14",
    "question": "Jacob said that those that were friendly toward the Nephites’, or the people of Nephi were Nephites. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1341,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:14",
    "question": "Jacob wrote that those that seeked to destroy the Nephites were called Lamanites, according to the reigns of the kings.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1342,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac1:15",
    "question": "In what reign of king did the Nephites begin to grow hard in their hearts, and indulge themselves somewhat in wicked practices.",
    "answer": "2nd",
    "options": ["2nd", "3rd", "4th"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1343,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac1:15",
    "question": "Jacob compared the Nephites practices like of King David of old, desiring many wives and _____.",
    "answer": "Concubines"
  },
  {
    "id": 1344,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac1:15",
    "question": "Jacob mentioned what son of King David of the bible in his writings.",
    "answer": "Solomon"
  },
  {
    "id": 1345,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:16",
    "question": "The Nephites began to search for much gold, and silver, and be lifted up somewhat in their pride.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1346,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac1:17",
    "question": "Jacob taught the Nephites the words that were taught to him in the _____ by the Lord.",
    "answer": "Temple"
  },
  {
    "id": 1347,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac1:18, 2Nep5:6",
    "question": "Jacob and his younger brother _____ were consecrated priests and teachers by the hand of Nephi.",
    "answer": "Joseph"
  },
  {
    "id": 1348,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:19",
    "question": "Jacob and Joseph did not magnify their offices or callings unto the Lord.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1349,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:19",
    "question": "Jacob and Joseph took upon the responsibility, answering the sins of the people upon their heads if they did not teach them the word of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1350,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:19",
    "question": "If Jacob and Joseph did not labor diligently, the blood of the Nephites would come upon their garments on judgment day.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1351,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Jac:19",
    "question": "It is safe to assume that Jacob and Joseph will be found spotless at the last day.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1352,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:2",
    "question": "Jacob did not magnify his office with soberness as he ought to have had: As to rid his garments of the Nephites sins.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1353,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac2:2",
    "question": "Jacob declared the word of God unto the Nephites in a _____.",
    "answer": "Temple",
    "options": ["Church", "Temple", "Salt Box"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1354,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:3",
    "question": "Jacob was weighed down with much desire and anxiety for the welfare of the Nephites _____.",
    "answer": "Souls"
  },
  {
    "id": 1355,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:5",
    "question": "Jacob did not refer to Jesus Christ as the Creator.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1356,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:5",
    "question": "The Nephites were beginning to labor in sin, which appeared very abominable unto him and unto God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1357,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:6",
    "question": "Because of the sins of the Nephites- it grieved Jacob’s soul, and caused him to shrink before his _____. ",
    "answer": "Maker"
  },
  {
    "id": 1358,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:6",
    "question": "Jacob testified before his Maker, concerning the wickedness of the hearts of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1359,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:7",
    "question": "It grieved Jacob that he had to use so much boldness of speech concerning the Nephites, before their _____ and their children.",
    "answer": "Wives"
  },
  {
    "id": 1360,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:7",
    "question": "The feelings of the Nephites wives and children were exceedingly tender and chaste and delicate before God, which thing is pleasing unto God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1361,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:8",
    "question": "The pleasing _____ or words of God could heal the wounded soul of the Nephites and can also be applied unto us.",
    "answer": "Word"
  },
  {
    "id": 1362,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac2:9",
    "question": "Jacob was given a _____ commandment by God to admonish the Nephites according to their crimes and to enlarge the wounds of those who they have already wounded.",
    "answer": "Strict",
    "options": ["Strict", "Lesser", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1363,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:9",
    "question": "Jacob was told to say other words by God, instead of consoling and healing those that had been wounded.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1364,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac2:9",
    "question": "Jacob said that the Nephites had placed _____ to pierce their souls and wound their delicate minds in those that they had already wounded.",
    "answer": "Daggers",
    "options": ["Knives", "Daggers", "Swords"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1365,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac2:10",
    "question": "Jacob was to tell his people concerning their wickedness, and _____, in the presence of the pure in heart, and the broken heart.",
    "answer": "Abominations",
    "options": ["Looks", "Doings", "Abominations"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1366,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:10",
    "question": "According to Jacob, the Almighty God has a piercing eye and can see us in a glance.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1367,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:11",
    "question": "Jacob told the Nephites the truth according to the plainness of the word of _____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 1368,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:11",
    "question": "Jacob would never inquire of the Lord, and instead, relied upon his own wisdom and understanding.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1369,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac1:11",
    "question": "Jacob was told by the Lord to go up into the _____, and declare the word which I will give thee unto this people.",
    "answer": "Temple"
  },
  {
    "id": 1370,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:12",
    "question": "Jacob said that the land of promise had _____, silver, and all manner of precious ores.",
    "answer": "Gold"
  },
  {
    "id": 1371,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:13",
    "question": "Some of the Nephites had obtained more abundantly than their brethren, and were lifted up in the pride of their hearts.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1372,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:13",
    "question": "Some of the Nephites would wear stiff necks and high heads because of the costliness of their _____.",
    "answer": "Apparel"
  },
  {
    "id": 1373,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:13",
    "question": "Jacob wrote that some of the Nephites would persecute their brethren because some had more worldly things than others.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1374,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:14",
    "question": "But he has condemned you, and if you persist in your evil ways his judgments must _____ come unto you.",
    "answer": "Speedily"
  },
  {
    "id": 1375,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac2:15",
    "question": "Jacob wished the Lord would show the Nephites that he could pierce them with the glance of his eye and smite them to the _____!",
    "answer": "Dust",
    "options": ["Sky", "Kingdom Come", "Dust"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1376,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:16",
    "question": "Jacob wanted his people to get rid of their iniquities and _____.",
    "answer": "Abominations"
  },
  {
    "id": 1377,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac2:16",
    "question": "O that you would listen unto the word of his commands and not let this _____ of your hearts destroy your souls!",
    "answer": "Pride Or (b) Harlot",
    "options": ["Lust", "Pride Or (b) Harlot"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1378,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:17",
    "question": "Jacob wanted his brethren to familiarize themselves to everyone else and to free themselves of their substance.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1379,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:18",
    "question": "But before ye seek for _____, seek ye; for the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": "Riches- "
  },
  {
    "id": 1380,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:19",
    "question": "And after you have obtained a _____ in Christ you shall obtain riches.",
    "answer": "Hope"
  },
  {
    "id": 1381,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac2:19",
    "question": "After we obtained riches, we should clothe the naked, feed the hungry, and administer relief to the sick and the _____.",
    "answer": "Afflicted",
    "options": ["Poorest Of The Poor", "Afflicted", "Broken Heart"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1382,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:21",
    "question": "The Lord esteems or thinks some people are better than others.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1383,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:21",
    "question": "The Lord told Jacob that all the flesh, are of the dust.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1384,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:21",
    "question": "The Lord did not create men to keep his commandments and glorify him forever.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1385,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:22",
    "question": "Jacob’s heart would rejoice exceedingly because of the things the Nephites were doing.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1386,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac2:23",
    "question": "The word of God burdens Jacob because he had to speak to the Nephites concerning their _____ crimes.",
    "answer": "Grosser",
    "options": ["Grosser", "Hateful", "War"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1387,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:23",
    "question": "The Nephites began to _____ in iniquity; and they did not understand the scriptures, and they seeked to excuse themselves of committing whoredoms.",
    "answer": "Wax"
  },
  {
    "id": 1388,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:23",
    "question": "Because of the things written about David, and Solomon his son, the Nephites did not understand the scriptures.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1389,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:24",
    "question": "Behold, David and Solomon truly had many wives and concubines, and it was an abominable thing before the sight of the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1390,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:25",
    "question": "The Lord did not lead the people out of Jerusalem, so that he could rise up a righteous branch out of the loins of Joseph.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1391,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:26",
    "question": "The Lord would not suffer that the Nephites would do the same things as those of ancient times.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1392,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac2:27",
    "question": "Jacob wanted the _____ to hearken unto the words of the Lord; and have one wife and no concubines.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Nephites", "Ishmaelites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1393,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:28",
    "question": "“For I, the Lord God, delight in the _____ of women”.",
    "answer": "Chastity"
  },
  {
    "id": 1394,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac2:28",
    "question": "Whoredoms are an; _____ before me; thus saith the Lord of Host.",
    "answer": "Abomination",
    "options": ["Ugly", "Atrocity", "Abomination"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1395,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:29",
    "question": "The Lord said that if the Nephites did not keep his commandments, he would curse the land for their sakes.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1396,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:31",
    "question": "The Lord did not see the sorrow, neither the mourning of the daughters of his people in the lands of Jerusalem and elsewhere.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1397,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:32",
    "question": "I will not suffer that the cries of the fair daughters of Jerusalem; shall come up unto me against the men of my people, saith the Lord of Hosts.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1398,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:33",
    "question": "The Lord said that the Nephites should lead away in captivity the daughters of his people because of their tenderness.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1399,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:34",
    "question": "And now behold, my brethren, ye know that these commandments were given to our father, _____.",
    "answer": "Lehi"
  },
  {
    "id": 1400,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:35",
    "question": "Jacob said that the Nephites had done greater iniquities than their brethren, the _____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 1401,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac2:35",
    "question": "The Nephites had broken the heart of their tender wives, and lost the confidence of their _____.",
    "answer": "Children",
    "options": ["Lord", "Children", "Horses"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1402,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:35",
    "question": "Because of the bad example before their children, the soberness of their hearts ascended up to God against them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1403,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac2:35",
    "question": "Jacob wrote:  Because of the strictness of the word of God, many hearts of women died, pierced with deep _____.",
    "answer": "Wounds",
    "options": ["Wounds", "Daggers", "Swords"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1404,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:1-35",
    "question": "Jacob taught humility and morality in chapter two, in his writings or book.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1405,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac3:1",
    "question": "Jacob said that he would speak to those that are pure in _____.",
    "answer": "Heart"
  },
  {
    "id": 1406,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac3:1",
    "question": "Jacob said to look unto God with a firmness of _____, and pray unto him with exceeding faith.",
    "answer": "Mind",
    "options": ["Belief", "Mind", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1407,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:1",
    "question": "Jacob told the Nephites that if they would pray, God would plead their cause and send down justice upon those that seek to destroy them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1408,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac3:2",
    "question": "All you that are pure in heart; lift up your _____ and receive the pleasing word of God.",
    "answer": "Heads",
    "options": ["Heads", "Swords", "Arms"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1409,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:3",
    "question": "Jacob said: “Woe, Woe, Woe, unto those that are pure in heart; that are filthy this day before God”.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1410,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac3:3",
    "question": "What tribe of people, are cursed with a sore cursing and shall scourge the Nephites even unto destruction?",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 1411,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:4",
    "question": "And the time speedily comes that the Lord will lead away the righteous from among the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1412,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac3:5",
    "question": "The Nephites hated the _____ because of their filthiness and the cursing which had come upon their skin.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 1413,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac3:5",
    "question": "At the time that Jacob wrote the words in chapter three of his book; the Lamanites were more righteous than the _____.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 1414,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:5",
    "question": "The Lamanites were more righteous than the Nephites because they observed to keep the commandments of the Lord by having one wife and no concubines.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1415,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:6",
    "question": "The Lamanites or a seed of them will become a blessed people in the last days.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1416,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac3:7",
    "question": "Jacob wrote: Their husbands love their wives, and their wives love their husbands; and their husbands and their wives love their _____.",
    "answer": "Children",
    "options": ["Gold", "Platinum", "Children"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1417,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:7",
    "question": "The Lamanites unbelief and hatred towards the Nephites was because the iniquity of their fathers.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1418,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:7",
    "question": "Jacob asked the Nephites:  How much better are you than they, in the sight of your great Creator?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1419,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:8",
    "question": "Jacob feared that the skin of the Lamanites would be whiter than that of the Nephites, when they would be brought with them before the throne of God. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1420,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:8",
    "question": "Jacob did never, mentioned God having a throne of any kind.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1421,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac3:9",
    "question": "Jacob reminded the Nephites to look upon their own filthiness and to remember that the filthiness of the_____ came because or their fathers.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 1422,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:10",
    "question": "Jacob told the Nephites to remember their children and how much grief they had brought upon them, because of their bad examples.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1423,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:10",
    "question": "It was the Nephites strength and power that would bring their children unto destruction.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1424,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac3:11",
    "question": "O my brethren, hearken unto my word; arouse the _____ of your soul; shake yourselves that ye may awake from the slumber of death.",
    "answer": "Faculties",
    "options": ["Faculties", "Body", "Frame"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1425,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:11",
    "question": "If we are to loose ourselves from the chains of hell, we will become angels of the devil.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1426,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac3:11",
    "question": "If we are cast into the lake of fire and brimstone, we will receive what is called a _____ death.  Second ",
    "answer": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 1427,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:11",
    "question": "The lake of fire and brimstone is also called a second death by Jacob.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1428,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac3:12",
    "question": "Jacob spoke to the Nephites concerning _____ and lasciviousness, and every other kind of sin.",
    "answer": "Fornication",
    "options": ["Adultery", "Fornication", "Marriage"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1429,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:12",
    "question": "Jacob did not tell the Nephites concerning their sins and the awful consequences of them.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1430,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac3:13",
    "question": "A _____ part of the proceedings of the Nephites cannot be written upon the plates that Jacob was talking about.",
    "answer": "Hundredth",
    "options": ["Thousand", "Hundredth", "Million"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1431,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:13",
    "question": "Many of the proceedings of the Nephites are written on much smaller plates.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1432,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac3:13",
    "question": "The large plates of the Nephites contain their wars, and contentions, and the _____ of their kings.",
    "answer": "Reigns"
  },
  {
    "id": 1433,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:14",
    "question": "The plates that contain the words of Jacob; are called the plates of Jacob.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1434,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac3:14",
    "question": "By whose hand were the plates of Jacob made? ",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 1435,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac3:14",
    "question": "Jacob could not make his own plates because he _____.",
    "answer": "We Don’t Know Why",
    "options": ["Had Arthritis", "Did Not Know How", "We Don’t Know Why"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1436,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:1",
    "question": "Jacob did not minister the words of Christ unto his people.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1437,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:1",
    "question": "Jacob could not write but a little of his words upon the plates because of the difficulty in engraving.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1438,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:1",
    "question": "Jacob knew nevertheless, that the things which he and Nephi wrote upon the plates would one day be erased or destroyed.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1439,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:2",
    "question": "Jacob wrote that he and Nephi could write on other things besides the plates and they would not perish or vanish.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1440,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:2",
    "question": "Because the Lord would protect their writings; Jacob knew that they could write upon plates of Brass.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1441,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:2",
    "question": "Jacob and Nephi wrote in order to give their children, and beloved brethren, a small degree of knowledge concerning them and their fathers.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1442,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac4:3",
    "question": "Nephi and Jacob labored diligently to engrave words on the plates in order that their children and their brethren, world receive them with thankful _____.",
    "answer": "Hearts",
    "options": ["Souls", "Hearts", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1443,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:3",
    "question": "Jacob and Nephi wanted their brethren to look upon the plates and learn with joy and not sorrow, neither with contempt, concerning their last parents.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1444,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:4",
    "question": "Nephi and Jacob wrote with the intent that their brethren would know that they knew of _____.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 1445,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac4:4",
    "question": "Nephi and Jacob knew of Jesus Christ and had a hope of his glory a _____ years before his coming.",
    "answer": "100",
    "options": ["1,000", "200", "100"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1446,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:4",
    "question": "The holy prophets also had a hope of Jesus Christ and his glory, even those that came before Nephi and Jacob and testified before his actual coming.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1447,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:5",
    "question": "The holy prophets believed in Christ and worshiped the _____ in his name, and also Jacob and Nephi worshiped the Father in his name.",
    "answer": "Father"
  },
  {
    "id": 1448,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:5",
    "question": "The intent that Jacob and his people kept the Lawords of Mosmones; was that it would point their souls to the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1449,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:5",
    "question": "Jacob only mentioned Abraham the father of Isaac, once in the Book of Mormon. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1450,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:5",
    "question": "When Abraham offered Isaac unto God, it was a similitude of God and his Only_____ Son.",
    "answer": "Begotten"
  },
  {
    "id": 1451,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:6",
    "question": "We search the prophets, and have the many revelations and the spirit of prophecy; we obtain a hope and our faith becomes unshaken.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1452,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:6",
    "question": "Jacob and Nephi wrote that they can command in the name of _____; and the very trees obey us, or the mountains, or the waves of the sea.",
    "answer": "Jesus"
  },
  {
    "id": 1453,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:7",
    "question": "Jacob wrote: nevertheless, the Lord God shows us our weakness that we may know that it is by his grace and his great condescensions, that they have power to do these things.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1454,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:8",
    "question": "Jacob said that the Lord’s works were no big deal and not very marvelous.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1455,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:8",
    "question": "Jacob wrote that it is impossible for man to know all the mysterious and the ways of our Heavenly Father.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1456,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:8",
    "question": "And no man knows the ways of the Lord, except it be revealed unto him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1457,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac4:8",
    "question": "Jacob told his brethren not to despise the _____ of God.",
    "answer": "Revelations",
    "options": ["Things", "Revelations", "Glory"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1458,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:9",
    "question": "Jacob wrote that by the power of God’s word, man came upon the face of the earth.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1459,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac4:10",
    "question": "Jacob told his brethren to seek not to _____ the Lord, but to take counsel from his hand.",
    "answer": "Counsel",
    "options": ["Question", "Criticize", "Counsel"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1460,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:10",
    "question": "God counsels in _____, and in justice, and in great mercy, over all his works.",
    "answer": "Wisdom"
  },
  {
    "id": 1461,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:11",
    "question": "Jacob told us to be _____ unto God through the atonement of Christ, his Only Begotten Son, and ye may obtain a resurrection.",
    "answer": "Reconciled"
  },
  {
    "id": 1462,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:12",
    "question": "Jacob told his brethren to marvel at the things that he had spoken to them, and not to publicly speak of the atonement of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1463,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:13",
    "question": "According to Jacob, the Spirit speaks the truth and lies when it only benefits us.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1464,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:13",
    "question": "Wherefore, the Spirit speaks of things as they really are, and of things as they really will be, wherefore, these things are manifested plainly unto us.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1465,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:13",
    "question": "Jacob said that we ourselves, are the only witnesses to and of the things the Spirit tells us.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1466,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:13",
    "question": "God is also a witness to the things the Spirit witnesses to us and also are his _____.",
    "answer": "Prophets"
  },
  {
    "id": 1467,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:14",
    "question": "But behold, the _____ were a stiffnecked people, and they despised the words of plainness.",
    "answer": "Jews"
  },
  {
    "id": 1468,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:14",
    "question": "Who killed the prophets, and sought for things they could not understand?",
    "answer": "Jews"
  },
  {
    "id": 1469,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac4:14",
    "question": "Wherefore because of their blindness, which blindness came by looking beyond the _____.",
    "answer": "Mark",
    "options": ["Truth", "Mark", "Point"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1470,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:14",
    "question": "The Jews must fall, because they were looking beyond the mark.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1471,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac4:14",
    "question": "Why did God take away his plainness from the Jews, and delivered unto them many things which they could not understand?",
    "answer": "They Desired It",
    "options": ["They Deserved It", "They Desired It", "We Don’t Know"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1472,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:14",
    "question": "The Jews stumbled because of the things they desired and the Lord has done it.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1473,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac4:15",
    "question": "Who led Jacob to prophesy of things to his brothers?",
    "answer": "The Spirit",
    "options": ["Nephi", "Lehi", "The Spirit"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1474,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:15",
    "question": "Jacob prophesied that by the stumbling of the _____ they will reject the very stone upon which they might build and have a safe foundation.",
    "answer": "Jews"
  },
  {
    "id": 1475,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac4:16",
    "question": "According to the _____ this stone shall become the great, and the last, and the only foundation, upon which the Jews can build.",
    "answer": "Scriptures",
    "options": ["Scriptures", "Prophets", "The Koran"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1476,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:17 & Jac5:50-77",
    "question": "Jacob said that it is possible for the Jews to build a foundation on the stone even after they have rejected it.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1477,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac5:1",
    "question": "What prophet of old did Jacob refer to in Chapter 5 concerning the allegory of the tame and wild olive tree?",
    "answer": "Zenos",
    "options": ["Zenock", "Zenos", "Zeniff"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1478,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Look at your dictionary",
    "question": "An allegory is the expression by means of symbolic fictional figures and actions of truths or generalizations about human existence.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1479,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac5:19",
    "question": "In what part of the vineyard did the Lord and the servant look to see if the natural branches of the tree which they had planted had brought forth much fruit.",
    "answer": "Nethermost",
    "options": ["Southernmost", "Nethermost", "Northernmost"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1480,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac5:2",
    "question": "The nethermost part of the vineyard was the poorest spot in all the land of the vineyard.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1481,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac5:21",
    "question": "The Lord told the servant not to question him or counsel him on the spot that he had chosen for the tree. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1482,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac5:22",
    "question": "The Lord did not know that it was the poorest place in the vineyard to plant the olive tree.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1483,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": " Jac5:22",
    "question": "Because the Lord had nourished the tree for a long time, it had brought much fruit.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1484,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac5:49",
    "question": "The Lord asked the servant what he could have done more for his vineyard.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1485,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac5:50",
    "question": "The servant told the Lord of the vineyard to do what to the tree to bring more good fruit.",
    "answer": "Spare It A Little Longer",
    "options": [
      "Cut It And Start Again",
      "Spare It A Little Longer",
      "To Forget About It Because It Was Useless"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 1486,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac5:59",
    "question": "Why did the Lord of the vineyard pluck the ripened branches from the tree?",
    "answer": "Hoped The Roots May Take Strength Because Of Their Goodness",
    "options": [
      "Because They Smelled Bad",
      "Hoped The Roots May Take Strength Because Of Their Goodness",
      "We Don’t Know"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 1487,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac5:59",
    "question": "Because of the changes the Lord of the vineyard had done to the branches of the olive tree; he hoped that good may overcome the evil.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1488,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac5:61",
    "question": "The Lord of the vineyard told his servant go to, and call servants, that we may labor _____ with our might in the vineyard.",
    "answer": "Diligently"
  },
  {
    "id": 1489,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac5:71",
    "question": "If we labor with our might in the vineyard of the Lord, he has said that we shall have joy in the fruit which he shall lay up unto himself.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1490,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac5:74",
    "question": "The natural fruit of the vineyard of the Lord is the most _____ unto him from the beginning.",
    "answer": "Precious",
    "options": ["Desirable", "Precious", "Most Worthy"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1491,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac5:75",
    "question": "Who was the Lord of the vineyard referring to when he said “Blessed art thou; for because you have been diligent in laboring with me in the vineyard”?",
    "answer": "Servants"
  },
  {
    "id": 1492,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac5:77",
    "question": "There will come a time when the evil fruit shall come again into the vineyard of the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1493,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac5:77",
    "question": "In the end; the Lord of the vineyard will cause that both the good and the _____ fruit shall be gathered; and the good will he preserve unto himself.",
    "answer": "Bad- "
  },
  {
    "id": 1494,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac5:77",
    "question": "What will happen to the Lord’s vineyard in the end?",
    "answer": "Be Burned With Fire",
    "options": [
      "Be Burned With Fire",
      "Will Become Flooded",
      "Be Bombed By Jets"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 1495,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac6:1",
    "question": "In the allegory of the olive-tree, what prophet spoke concerning the house of Israel in which he likened them unto a tame olive-tree that must surely come to pass?",
    "answer": "Zenos",
    "options": ["Zenock", "Zenos", "Zeniff"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1496,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac6:2",
    "question": "In the last time-Who shall go forth in his power to nourish and prune his vineyard?",
    "answer": "His Servants",
    "options": ["Muslims", "His Servants", "Migrant Workers"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1497,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac6:2",
    "question": "After his servants prune his vineyard; the end soon comes.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1498,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac6:3",
    "question": "Those that have labored diligently in his vineyard will not be blessed? ",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1499,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac6:3",
    "question": "_____ are they who shall be cast out into their own place!",
    "answer": "Cursed",
    "options": ["Damned", "Perish", "Cursed"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1500,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac6:2-3",
    "question": "The world in the last day will be burned by fire.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1501,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac6:4",
    "question": "And how _____ is our God unto us, for he has remembered the house of Israel.",
    "answer": "Merciful",
    "options": ["Merciful", "Thoughtful", "Diligent"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1502,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac6:4",
    "question": "The Lord our God has also remembered both _____ and branches of the house of Israel.",
    "answer": "Roots"
  },
  {
    "id": 1503,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac6:4",
    "question": "God _____ forth his hand unto all his people all day long.",
    "answer": "Stretches",
    "options": ["Extends", "Stretches", "Gives"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1504,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac6:4",
    "question": "Who did Jacob say were gainsaying and stiffnecked people?",
    "answer": "A And B",
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Those Of The House Of Israel", "A And B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1505,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac6:4",
    "question": "Those that harden their hearts shall be saved in the kingdom of God?",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1506,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac6:5",
    "question": "Jacob beseech to us in words of soberness that we would _____.",
    "answer": "Repent",
    "options": ["Believe His Words", "Repent", "Not Go To Hell"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1507,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac6:5",
    "question": "Jacob wants us to come with a full purpose of heart and cleave unto God. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1508,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac6:5",
    "question": "Jacob said that God “cleaves” unto us.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1509,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac6:5",
    "question": "We should cleave unto our______ while we are in this mortal life",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["God", "Our Riches", "Our Faith"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1510,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac6:5",
    "question": "We should not harden our hearts when the arm of mercy from the Lord is extended to us.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1511,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac6:7",
    "question": "Jacob said, “For behold, after you have been _____ by the good word of God all day long”.",
    "answer": "Nourished",
    "options": ["Bless", "Nourished", "Astonished"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1512,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac6:7",
    "question": "If we bring forth evil fruit, we must be hewn down and cast into the fire.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1513,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac6:9",
    "question": "Jacob said the Nephites did not know that the power of the redemption and the resurrection, which is in Christ.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1514,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac6:9",
    "question": "According to the power of Justice, the power of the redemption and resurrection which is in Christ can be denied.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1515,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac6:10",
    "question": "Who or what has flames that are unquenchable?",
    "answer": "The Lake Of Fire And Brimstone",
    "options": [
      "The Lake Of Fire And Brimstone",
      "An Atomic Blast",
      "Neither A Nor B"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 1516,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac6:10",
    "question": "What did Jacob say is another name for endless torment?",
    "answer": "brimstone"
  },
  {
    "id": 1517,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac6:11",
    "question": "What gate did Jacob want us to enter?",
    "answer": "The Strait And Narrow",
    "options": [
      "Pearly Gates",
      "The Strait And Narrow",
      "The Long And Winding Gate"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 1518,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac6:11",
    "question": "Jacob wanted us to enter the strait and narrow gate until we shall obtain eternal life.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1519,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac6:12",
    "question": "In Jacob chapter six; Jacob said- “O be wise; what can I say more”.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1520,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac6:13",
    "question": "Jacob bid us farewell until we shall meet him before the pleasing bar of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1521,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac6:13",
    "question": "What thing or bar “strikes the wicked with awful dread and fear”.",
    "answer": "Pleasing Bar Of God",
    "options": ["#10 Rebar", "Snickers Bar", "Pleasing Bar Of God"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1522,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:1",
    "question": "Who is considered, by many Book of Mormon scholars; to be the first anti-Christ mentioned in the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "Sharem"
  },
  {
    "id": 1523,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:1",
    "question": "In the beginning of chapter 7 what did Sharem do or say to the people of Nephi?",
    "answer": "There Should Be No Christ",
    "options": [
      "Christ Had Already Came",
      "There Should Be No Christ",
      "Jesus Is Not The Messiah"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 1524,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:2",
    "question": "Sharem did not flatter many Nephites with his flattering words.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1525,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:2",
    "question": "Sharem was trying to do what with his flattering words?",
    "answer": "Overthrow The Doctrine Of Christ",
    "options": [
      "Say That God Loves All People",
      "Say That He Was The Messiah",
      "Overthrow The Doctrine Of Christ"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 1526,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": " Jac7:3",
    "question": "Sharem labor diligently that he might lead away the hearts of the people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1527,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:3",
    "question": "Even though Shem used many flattering words; he did not lead away or astray many of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1528,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:3",
    "question": "Sharem did not know that Jacob had faith in Christ.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1529,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:3",
    "question": "In chapter #7; who did Jacob have faith in?",
    "answer": "In Christ",
    "options": ["His Own Wisdom", "In Christ", "The Words Of Plato"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1530,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:3",
    "question": "Who sought much opportunity that he might come unto Jacob?",
    "answer": "Sharem",
    "options": ["Moroni", "Lehi", "Sharem"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1531,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:4",
    "question": "Sharem was not very wise or learned individual?",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1532,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:4",
    "question": "Sharem had a_____ knowledge of the language of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Perfect",
    "options": ["So And So", "Perfect", "Better"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1533,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:4",
    "question": "Because of Sharem’s knowledge of the language of the Nephites he used much _____.",
    "answer": "Flattery",
    "options": ["Flattery", "Wisdom", "Understanding"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1534,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:4",
    "question": "Sharem had much power in his oratory or speech.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1535,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:4",
    "question": "Who gave Sharem the power of his speech?",
    "answer": "The Devil Or Satan",
    "options": ["Jesus Christ", "God", "The Devil Or Satan"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1536,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:5",
    "question": "Sharem had hoped to shake Jacob of his _____.",
    "answer": "Faith",
    "options": ["Status", "Faith", "Wisdom"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1537,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:5",
    "question": "Jacob had seen many revelations concerning the doctrine of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1538,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:5",
    "question": "What had Jacob seen that ministered unto him?",
    "answer": "Angels",
    "options": ["Demons", "Angels", "UFO’s"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1539,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:5",
    "question": "Whose voice had Jacob heard from time to time?",
    "answer": "The Lord’s",
    "options": ["His Own", "The Lord’s", "Satan’s"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1540,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:5",
    "question": "Because of the voice Jacob had heard; he could not be shaken from his faith, by the evil Sharem. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1541,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:6",
    "question": "When Sharem first saw Jacob; he called him",
    "answer": "Brother Jacob",
    "options": ["Hey Dude", "Brother Jacob", "Jacob"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1542,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:6",
    "question": "Sharem had not sought much opportunity to speak with Jacob.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1543,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:6",
    "question": "Sharem accused Jacob of preaching the gospel or the doctrine of Christ?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1544,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:7",
    "question": "Sharem accused Jacob of leading away many of the Nephites unto perverting the right way of _____.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["Satan", "God", "The World"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1545,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:7",
    "question": "What law did Sharem say was the “right way”?",
    "answer": "Lawords Of Mosmones",
    "options": [
      "Law Of Physics",
      "Lawords Of Mosmones",
      "The Articles Of Faith"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 1546,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:7",
    "question": "Sharem said that Moses or the “Lawords of Mosmones” had already come to pass.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1547,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:7",
    "question": "Sharem tries to confuse Jacob or us by first saying that the Lawords of Mosmones is the right way, then saying that no man knows of the things to come.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1548,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:7",
    "question": "In chapter #7, Sharem accuses Jacob of being a_____.",
    "answer": "Blasphemy",
    "options": ["False Prophet", "Blasphemy", "We Don’t Know What"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1549,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:7",
    "question": "Jacob did not write unto us the matter of which Sharem contended with him.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1550,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:8",
    "question": "The Lord God poured his _____ into Jacob’s soul.",
    "answer": "Spirit",
    "options": ["Thoughts", "Words", "Spirit"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1551,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": " Jac7:8",
    "question": "Because the Lord had poured his Spirit unto Jacob; he confounded Sharem in all his words.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1552,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:9",
    "question": "Jacob said to Sharem: “Denies thou the _____ who should come'?",
    "answer": "Christ",
    "options": ["3 Days Of Darkness", "Hailey’s Comet", "Christ"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1553,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:9",
    "question": "Sharem said that if there would be a Christ, he would deny him or his existence.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1554,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:9",
    "question": "In the Book of Jacob who said: “There is no Christ, neither has been, nor ever will be”?",
    "answer": "Sharem"
  },
  {
    "id": 1555,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:10",
    "question": "Sharem told Jacob the he believed the scriptures.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1556,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:10",
    "question": "In the Book of Jacob; what did Jacob ask Sharem if he believed in what?",
    "answer": "The Scriptures",
    "options": [
      "Einstein’s Theory Of Relativity",
      "The Scriptures",
      "The Book Of Mormon"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 1557,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:11",
    "question": "Jacob said that Sharem did not understand the scriptures.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1558,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:11",
    "question": "Who did Jacob say the scriptures testify of?",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 1559,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:11",
    "question": "Who did Jacob say had written and testified concerning Jesus Christ?",
    "answer": "The Prophets",
    "options": ["Satan", "The Mormon’s", "The Prophets"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1560,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:12",
    "question": "Jacob had seen and heard the things concerning Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1561,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:12",
    "question": "By who or what power did the things concerning Jesus Christ been manifested to Jacob?",
    "answer": "The Holy Ghost",
    "options": ["Jesus Christ", "God", "The Holy Ghost"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1562,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:12",
    "question": "Jacob said that if there should be no _____ made, all mankind would be lost.",
    "answer": "Atonement"
  },
  {
    "id": 1563,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:13",
    "question": "Sharem asked Jacob to show him a sign of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1564,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:13",
    "question": "Sharem accused Jacob of knowing much about this personage? ",
    "answer": "Ghost- "
  },
  {
    "id": 1565,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:14",
    "question": "Jacob said that he would not tempt God because Sharem knew that God did really exist.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1566,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:14",
    "question": "Jacob knew that if he would show Sherem a sign that Jesus Christ did really exist, he would still deny it.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1567,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:14",
    "question": "In the Book of Jacob; Who said the words? “Art of the Devil”?",
    "answer": "Jacob "
  },
  {
    "id": 1568,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:14",
    "question": "Jacob said told Sharem that thy will would be done. ",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1569,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:14",
    "question": "If God would smite Sharem, it would be a sign that he has great power?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1570,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:14",
    "question": "Jacob said that God has great power both in _____ and in earth.",
    "answer": "Heaven"
  },
  {
    "id": 1571,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:14",
    "question": "Jacob said that Christ shall come, and that his will would be done.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1572,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:14",
    "question": "Because Jacob spoke of many things concerning Jesus Christ; the power of the Lord came upon whom?",
    "answer": "Jacob",
    "options": ["Jacob", "Sharem", "The Devil"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1573,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:15",
    "question": "In the Book of Jacob who fell to the earth because of the Lord’s great power? ",
    "answer": "Sharem"
  },
  {
    "id": 1574,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:15",
    "question": "In the end of the Book of Jacob who was nourished of the power of Jesus Christ for many days.",
    "answer": "Sharem"
  },
  {
    "id": 1575,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:15",
    "question": "Sharem was nourished of the power of Jesus Christ for ____.",
    "answer": "Many Days",
    "options": ["Two Days", "Many Days", "Three Days"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1576,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:16",
    "question": "Who told the people to gather together because he wanted to speak to them before he died?",
    "answer": "Sharem",
    "options": ["Jacob", "Ishmael", "Sharem"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1577,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:16",
    "question": "Sharem the Anti-Christ knew the exact day that he would die.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1578,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:17",
    "question": "Because Sharem did not speak very plainly to the Nephites, they could not understand him very well.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1579,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:17",
    "question": "In the end, Sharem denied the things that he had taught the _____.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["Nephites", "Lamanites", "Zoramites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1580,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:17",
    "question": "Finally, in his last days, Sharem confessed of the existence of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1581,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:17",
    "question": "Sharem confessed of the _____ of the Holy Ghost in the end.",
    "answer": "Power",
    "options": ["Reality", "Power", "Existence"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1582,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:17",
    "question": "Sharem did not believe in the ministering of angels.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1583,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:18",
    "question": "Sharem was deceived by the power of whom? ",
    "answer": "Satan- "
  },
  {
    "id": 1584,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:18",
    "question": "Sharem spoke of _____, and of eternity, and of eternal punishment.",
    "answer": "Hell",
    "options": ["Hell", "Nephi", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1585,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:19",
    "question": "Sharem felt that he had committed an unpardonable sin.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1586,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:19",
    "question": "Sharem said that he had lied unto God; and denied the Christ.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1587,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:20",
    "question": "When Sharem confessed of his wrongdoing he gave up the _____.",
    "answer": "Ghost",
    "options": ["Plates", "Ghost", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1588,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:21",
    "question": "The multitude had witnessed the things which Sharem had spoken at the end of his life. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1589,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:22",
    "question": "Jacob was not pleased when the power of God came onto the multitude after Sharem had spoken.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1590,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "7:21",
    "question": "The multitude fell to the _____ when God showed his power to the multitude.",
    "answer": "Earth"
  },
  {
    "id": 1591,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:22",
    "question": "Jacob had requested of _____ to show his matchless power to the Nephites.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 1592,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:22",
    "question": "At the end of chapter #7 of the Book of Jacob; God had heard whose cry and answered his prayer.",
    "answer": "Jacob"
  },
  {
    "id": 1593,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:23",
    "question": "What two things came to pass that was restored again among the people.",
    "answer": "Peace And Love God",
    "options": [
      "Freedom Of Speech And Writing",
      "Peace And Love God",
      "The Will Of Agency And Baptism"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 1594,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:23",
    "question": "The Nephites searched the_____, and hearkened, no more to the wicked man known as Sharem.",
    "answer": "Scriptures"
  },
  {
    "id": 1595,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:24",
    "question": "In the end of the Book of Jacob we are told that many ways were devised to reclaim and restore the Lamanites to the truth of the Gospel.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1596,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:24",
    "question": "The Lamanites delighted in wars and _____.",
    "answer": "Bloodshed",
    "options": ["Partying", "Whoredoms", "Bloodshed"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1597,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:24",
    "question": "The Lamanites had an_____ hatred for their brethren, the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Eternal- "
  },
  {
    "id": 1598,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:24",
    "question": "Who sought by the power of their arms to destroy the Nephites?",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 1599,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:25",
    "question": "The people of_____ fortified their armies against the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["Nephi", "Zoram", "Ishmaelites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1600,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:25",
    "question": "What people used their might, trusting in the God and the rock of their salvation?",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 1601,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:25",
    "question": "Because the Nephites trusted in God; they became conquerors of their enemies, during Jacob’s life.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1602,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:26",
    "question": "When Jacob began to be old, he said that the record of the Nephites was kept on the other plates of _____.",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["Laban", "Nephi", "Lehi"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1603,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:26",
    "question": "Jacob concluded with his record, declaring that he had written according to the best of his_____.",
    "answer": "Knowledge",
    "options": ["Knowledge", "Penmanship", "Memory"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1604,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:26",
    "question": "Jacob said that his life and the lives of the Nephites had passed away like as it were a dream.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1605,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:26",
    "question": "In the end of his writings: What tribe of people did Jacob declare were wanderers?",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Nephites", "Ishmaelites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1606,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:26",
    "question": "The people of Nephi were lonesome and solemn people, cast out from what city.",
    "answer": "Jerusalem",
    "options": ["Salt Lake", "Dallas", "Jerusalem"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1607,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:26",
    "question": "Jacob wrote that he and his people were born in tribulation, and in a wilderness.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1608,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:26",
    "question": "What thing or attitude caused wars and contentions between the Nephites and Lamanites?",
    "answer": "Hatred",
    "options": ["Pride", "Hatred", "Agency"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1609,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:26",
    "question": "In the end of the Book of Jacob, he said that he and the people of Nephi mourn out our last days.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1610,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:27",
    "question": "At the end of his life, what son of Jacob took over the plates?",
    "answer": "Enos "
  },
  {
    "id": 1611,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:27",
    "question": "Jacob was_____ when he passed away.",
    "answer": "We Don’t Know",
    "options": ["75", "100", "We Don’t Know"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1612,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:27",
    "question": "What is the name of Enos’s uncle who told Jacob of things he had commanded him to do? ",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 1613,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:27",
    "question": "Enos promised Jacob that he would be obedient unto his commands.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1614,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:27",
    "question": "Jacob considered that his writing on the plates had been_____.",
    "answer": "Small",
    "options": ["Small", "Sufficient", "Too Much"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1615,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:27",
    "question": "At the end of his writing, Jacob bid us all farewell.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1616,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:27",
    "question": "Jacob hoped that of his many of his brethren would read his writings.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1617,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:27",
    "question": "What is the last word that is written in the Book of Jacob? Adieu ",
    "answer": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 1618,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:l",
    "question": "Who was Nephi’s nephew that wrote the third book in the Book of Mormon? ",
    "answer": "Enos"
  },
  {
    "id": 1619,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Enos1:1",
    "question": "It came to pass that Enos knew that his father was a_____ man.",
    "answer": "Just",
    "options": ["Just", "Holy", "Unworthy"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1620,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:1",
    "question": "Was a prophet of the Lord and also the father of Enos?",
    "answer": "Jacob"
  },
  {
    "id": 1621,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:1,27",
    "question": "How many chapters are in the book of Enos?",
    "answer": ["One", "1"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1622,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:1",
    "question": "Enos was not taught in the language of his father, therefore he made up his own.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1623,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:1",
    "question": "Who taught Enos of the nurture and admonition of the Lord? ",
    "answer": "Father"
  },
  {
    "id": 1624,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:2",
    "question": "And I will tell you of the_____ which I had before God, before I received a remission of my sins.",
    "answer": "Wrestle"
  },
  {
    "id": 1625,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:2",
    "question": "The word wrestle is only mentioned once in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1626,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Enos1:3",
    "question": "Enos went to hunt_____ in the forest.",
    "answer": "Beasts",
    "options": ["Wild Game", "Bears", "Beasts"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1627,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:3",
    "question": "Enos’s father spoke to him concerning eternal_____, and the joy of the saints, and those words sank deep into his heart.",
    "answer": "Life"
  },
  {
    "id": 1628,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Enos1:4",
    "question": "And my soul hungered; and I kneeled down before my_____.",
    "answer": "Maker",
    "options": ["Alter", "Maker", "Pile Of Gold"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1629,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:4",
    "question": "Enos cried unto his Maker in mighty prayer and supplication for his own soul.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1630,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Enos1:4",
    "question": "Enos cried unto his Maker all day long, and when the night came, he raised his voice high that it reached the_____.",
    "answer": "Heavens",
    "options": ["Heavens", "Moon", "Stars"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1631,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:5",
    "question": "Who said: “Enos, thy sins are forgiven thee, and thou shalt be blessed” ",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 1632,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:6",
    "question": "And I, _____, knew that God could not lie; wherefore, my guilt was swept away.",
    "answer": "Enos"
  },
  {
    "id": 1633,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:7",
    "question": "Enos asked the Lord how it was done that his sins were forgiven.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:8",
    "question": "How was Enos’ guilt for his sins forgiven?",
    "answer": "faith"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:8",
    "question": "The Lord told Enos that two years would pass away before Christ would manifest himself in the flesh.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1636,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:8",
    "question": "The Lord told Enos that his faith alone did not make him whole.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1637,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Enos1:9",
    "question": "When Enos heard the words of the Lord he began to feel a desire, for the welfare of his brethren, the_____.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Nephites", "Zoramites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1638,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:9",
    "question": "Enos poured out his whole soul unto God, for the welfare of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1639,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:10",
    "question": "Enos struggled in the spirit while he was praying for the welfare of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1640,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:10",
    "question": "The Lord told Enos that he would visit his brethren according to their_____ in keeping his commandment.",
    "answer": "Diligence"
  },
  {
    "id": 1641,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:10",
    "question": "Enos was told by the Holy Ghost that the land of promise was a holy land.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1642,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Enos1:10",
    "question": "The Lord told Enos that he would curse the land of promise save it be for the cause of_____.",
    "answer": "Iniquity",
    "options": ["Iniquity", "Wars", "Contentions"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1643,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:10",
    "question": "Their transgressions will I bring down with sorrow upon their own_____.",
    "answer": "Heads"
  },
  {
    "id": 1644,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:11",
    "question": "After Enos heard the words of the Lord, his faith began to be unshaken in the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:11",
    "question": "Enos prayed unto the Lord with many long struggles, for his brethren, the_____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 1646,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:12",
    "question": "Enos prayed and labored with all his diligence unto the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Enos1:12",
    "question": "The Lord said unto Enos that he would grant his desires because of his_____.",
    "answer": "Faith",
    "options": ["Wishes", "Faith", "Humble Heart"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1648,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:13",
    "question": "Enos desired of the Lord: That if the Nephites should fall because of transgression and the Lamanites should not be destroyed, that he would preserve the record of his people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1649,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:13",
    "question": "Enos desired that the record of his people be brought forth at some future day unto the_____; that they may be brought forth unto salvation.",
    "answer": "Lamanites- "
  },
  {
    "id": 1650,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:14",
    "question": "For at the present our struggles were vain in restoring Lamanites to the true_____.",
    "answer": "Faith"
  },
  {
    "id": 1651,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Enos1:14",
    "question": "The Lamanites swore in their wrath that if it were possible, they would destroy the Nephites and their records, and also all the_____ of their fathers.",
    "answer": "Customs",
    "options": ["Traditions", "Customs", "Their Sign Language."]
  },
  {
    "id": 1652,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:15",
    "question": "Enos cried unto the Lord continually because he knew that he would preserve their records.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1653,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:15",
    "question": "The Lord said to Enos:  “Whatsoever thing ye shall ask in_____, believing that ye shall receive in the name of Christ, ye shall receive it”.",
    "answer": "Faith"
  },
  {
    "id": 1654,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:15",
    "question": "Because Enos had faith in the Lord; he knew that whatsoever he asked of him, he would receive it.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1655,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:16",
    "question": "The Lord_____ with Enos that he would bring forth his records unto the Lamanites in his own due time.",
    "answer": "Covenanted"
  },
  {
    "id": 1656,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:16",
    "question": "Enos said that the Lord would bring forth his records unto the Lamanites when he would still be alive.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Enos1:17",
    "question": "Enos knew that the Lord would do with the records that which he had covenanted with him; wherefore his soul did_____.",
    "answer": "Rest",
    "options": ["Rest", "Yearn", "Wander"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1658,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Enos1:18",
    "question": "The Lord compared Enos’ faith like that of his_____.",
    "answer": "Fathers",
    "options": ["Brothers", "Fathers", "Children"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1659,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:19",
    "question": "Enos went about among the people of Nephi, _____ of things to come.",
    "answer": "Prophesying"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:19",
    "question": "Enos testified to the Nephites of the things which he had heard and seen.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1661,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:20",
    "question": "And I Enos, _____ record that the people of Nephi did seek diligently to restore the Lamanites unto the true faith of God.",
    "answer": "Bear"
  },
  {
    "id": 1662,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:20",
    "question": "Enos and his brothers’ labors were in vain because the Lamanites hatred was fixed, and they were led by their evil nature.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1663,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Enos1:20",
    "question": "Because of their evil nature, the Lamanites became a wild, ferocious, and____ people.",
    "answer": "Bloodthirsty",
    "options": ["Mean", "Dirty", "Bloodthirsty"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1664,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:20",
    "question": "According to Enos, the Lamanites were full of idolatry and filthiness; feeding upon beast’s of_____, and dwelling in tents.",
    "answer": "Prey"
  },
  {
    "id": 1665,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:20",
    "question": "The Lamanites would wander in the wilderness with a short skin girdle about their loins and their_____ shaven.",
    "answer": "Heads"
  },
  {
    "id": 1666,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:20",
    "question": "The Lamanites skill was not in the bow, and in the cimeter, and the ax.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1667,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Enos1:20",
    "question": "Many of the Lamanites did eat nothing but_____ meat; continually seeking to destroy the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Raw",
    "options": ["Raw", "Unhealthy", "Good"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1668,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:21",
    "question": "In his book Enos, he describes the way of life in the Nephite culture and also of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1669,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:21",
    "question": "The people of Nephi did not till the ground but raised cattle instead.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1670,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:21",
    "question": "The Nephites did till the land, and raised all kinds of grain, and fruit, and flocks of herds.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1671,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:21",
    "question": "The Nephites raised_____ of all manner of cattle of every kind, and goats, and wild goats.",
    "answer": "Flocks"
  },
  {
    "id": 1672,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:21",
    "question": "During the time that Enos was on the earth the Nephites did not have horses.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1673,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:22",
    "question": "Enos said that there were many prophets in the land among them but that the people were a_____ people, hard to understand.",
    "answer": "Stiffnecked"
  },
  {
    "id": 1674,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:23",
    "question": "Enos said that there was exceeding harshness, preaching and prophesying of_____, and contentions and destructions.",
    "answer": "Wars"
  },
  {
    "id": 1675,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:23",
    "question": "Because of the exceeding harshness, preaching and prophesying of wars, the people were continually reminded of death.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1676,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:23",
    "question": "The people were continually reminded of the judgments and _____ of God.",
    "answer": "Power"
  },
  {
    "id": 1677,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:23",
    "question": "Because of the exceeding great plainness of speech, it would keep the people from going down speedily to destruction.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1678,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:24",
    "question": "Enos did not see many wars between the Nephites and Lamanites in the course of his days.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1679,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:25",
    "question": "Enos was wrought upon the power of God that he must preach and prophesy unto the people and declare the word according to the truth which is in_____. Christ ",
    "answer": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 1680,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:26",
    "question": "Enos declared in all his days to the truth which is in Christ, and rejoiced in it above that of the world.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1681,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:27",
    "question": "Enos said that he knew that he would go to the place of his rest, which is with his Redeemer; and knew that in him he would rest. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1682,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:27",
    "question": "Enos rejoiced in the day that his mortal shall put on_____; and shall stand before him; and would see his face with pleasure.",
    "answer": "Immortality"
  },
  {
    "id": 1683,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:27",
    "question": "Enos said that the Lord would say to him:  “Come unto me, ye blessed, there is a place prepared for you in the_____, of my Father”.",
    "answer": "Mansions"
  },
  {
    "id": 1684,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jarom",
    "question": "What was Enos’ son name that was also a record keeper?",
    "answer": "Jarom"
  },
  {
    "id": 1685,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jarom",
    "question": "The Book of Jarom has only one chapter.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1686,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jarom",
    "question": "What Book of Mormon historian/record keeper wrote the fewest verses in his book?",
    "answer": "Jarom"
  },
  {
    "id": 1687,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jar1:1",
    "question": "Jarom wrote a few words according to the commandment of the Lord.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1688,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jar1:1",
    "question": "Jarom wrote because of the commandment of his father that the_____ of the Nephites may be kept.",
    "answer": "Genealogy",
    "options": ["Genealogy", "Truth", "Records"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1689,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jar1:2",
    "question": "Jarom said that the plates he wrote on were small.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1690,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jarom1:2",
    "question": "Jarom wrote very little and would not write of his prophesying neither of his revelations because the plates were small.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1691,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jar1:2",
    "question": "Jarom wrote with the intent of the benefit of his brothers, the_____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 1692,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jar1:2",
    "question": "Who said: “For what could I write more than my fathers have written? For have they not revealed the plan of salvation”?",
    "answer": "Jarom"
  },
  {
    "id": 1693,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jar1:2",
    "question": "Because his fathers wrote concerning the plan of salvation, it suffices Jarom.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1694,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jar1:3",
    "question": "Jarom wrote that it is expedient that much should be done among his people because of their hardness of their hearts, and the _____ of their ears, and the blindness of their minds.",
    "answer": "Deafness"
  },
  {
    "id": 1695,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jar1:3",
    "question": "Jarom wrote that the Lamanites had a stiffness of their necks.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1696,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jar1:3",
    "question": "Jarom said that_____ is exceedingly merciful unto the Lamanites and has not yet swept them off from the land.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 1697,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jar1:4",
    "question": "In Jarom’s time, there were many Nephites who had revelations.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1698,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jar1:4",
    "question": "Because the Nephites were not a stiffnecked people, many of them did not have revelations.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1699,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jar1:4",
    "question": "Many Nephites were not stiffnecked and had faith and communion with the Holy_____.",
    "answer": "Spirit",
    "options": ["Spirit", "Ghost", "Grail"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1700,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jar1:4",
    "question": "According to our faith, what makes itself manifest to us? ",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },
  {
    "id": 1701,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jar1:5",
    "question": "How many years had passed away that the people of Nephi waxed strong in the land.",
    "answer": "200",
    "options": ["100", "200", "300"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1702,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jar1:5",
    "question": "The Nephites observed to keep the Law of_____, and the Sabbath day holy unto the Lord.",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },
  {
    "id": 1703,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jar1:5",
    "question": "Jarom said that the Nephites did not profane, neither did they blaspheme because the laws of the land were strict.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1704,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jar1:5",
    "question": "During the time that Jarom lived, the laws of the land of the Nephites, were not very strict.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jar1:6",
    "question": "The Lamanites and_____ were scattered all over the land, and the Lamanites were more numerous that the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 1706,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jar1:6",
    "question": "The Lamanites loved murder, and would drink the blood of wild_____.",
    "answer": "Beasts",
    "options": ["Animals", "Beasts", "Pigs"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1707,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jar1:7",
    "question": "The Lamanites came many times to battle with the Nephites, but their kings and leader were mighty men in the faith of the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1708,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jar1:7",
    "question": "The kings and leaders of the Nephites were not mighty men and did not teach them the ways of the Lord.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1709,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jar1:7",
    "question": "The_____ swept away the Lamanites from their lands and cities and fortified whatsoever place of their inheritance.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 1710,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jar1:8",
    "question": "The Nephites multiplied exceedingly, and became rich in gold, and in silver, and in precious_____.",
    "answer": "Things"
  },
  {
    "id": 1711,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jar1:8",
    "question": "The Nephites were also skilled in fine workmanship of wood, in buildings, and in machinery.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1712,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jar1:8",
    "question": "The Nephites made all manner of tools of every kind to till the ground, and weapons of_____.",
    "answer": "War"
  },
  {
    "id": 1713,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jar1:8",
    "question": "The Nephites also made sharp pointed arrows, and the quiver, and the dart.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1714,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jar1:8",
    "question": "The people of Jarom were also skilled in the manner of the preparations of wars.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1715,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jar1:8",
    "question": "During the time that Jarom lived, there were no such things as javelins.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1716,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jar1:9",
    "question": "Because of the preparations of war, the _____ did not prosper against the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 1717,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jar1:9",
    "question": "The words of the Lord were verified which he spoke unto our fathers saying that: “In as much as ye will keep my commandments ye shall_____ in the land”.",
    "answer": "Prosper"
  },
  {
    "id": 1718,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jar1:10",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the_____ of the Lord did threaten the people of Nephi, according to the word of God.",
    "answer": "Prophets",
    "options": ["Prophets", "Kings", "Leaders"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1719,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jar1:10",
    "question": "The prophets of the Lord told the people of Nephi that if they did not keep the commandments of the Lord and fall into transgression, they would be destroyed off from the face of the land.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1720,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jar1:11",
    "question": "Wherefore, the prophets, and the priests, and the_____, did labor diligently, exhorting with all long-suffering the people to diligence.",
    "answer": "Teachers"
  },
  {
    "id": 1721,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jar1:11",
    "question": "What law did the prophets, and the priests, and the teachers teach the people?",
    "answer": ["Law", "Moses"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1722,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jar1:11",
    "question": "The prophets taught the Lawords of Mosmones and the intent for which it was given.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1723,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jar1:11",
    "question": "The priests and teachers tried to persuade the Nephites to look forward unto the coming of the_____, and believe in him to come through he already was.",
    "answer": "Messiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 1724,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jar1:11",
    "question": "The prophets, teachers, and priests did_____ their hearts with the word, continually stirring them unto repentance.",
    "answer": "Prick",
    "options": ["Uplift", "Prick", "Stab"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1725,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jar1:11",
    "question": "The prophets, teachers, and priest did not prick the hearts of the people with the word, continually stirring them unto repentance.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1726,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jar1:14",
    "question": "Jarom mentioned two sets of plates; large and small.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1727,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jar1:14",
    "question": "Jarom told us to refer to the other plates of Nephi; upon them the records of their wars are engraved.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1728,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jar1:14",
    "question": "According to the writings of the kings, they did not cause that a record be written of their wars.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1729,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jar1:15",
    "question": "Jarom delivered the small plates into the hands of his son_____.",
    "answer": "Omni"
  },
  {
    "id": 1730,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jar1:15",
    "question": "Jarom’s fathers did not give him a commandment to keep a record.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1731,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni",
    "question": "There is only one chapter of Omni in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1732,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jar1:15 & Words of Mormon1:18",
    "question": "Omni is the second to the last historian to write the least verses in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1733,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:1",
    "question": "Omni was commanded by his father_____, to write upon the plates to preserve their genealogy.",
    "answer": "Jarom"
  },
  {
    "id": 1734,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:1",
    "question": "Omni in his days; would that ye should know that “I fought much with the_____, to preserve my people, the Nephites”.",
    "answer": "Sword"
  },
  {
    "id": 1735,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:1",
    "question": "Omni fought much with the sword to preserve the Nephites from falling into the hands of their enemies, the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1736,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:1",
    "question": "Who wrote: “But behold, I myself am a wicked man, and I have not kept the statutes and the commandments of the Lord as I ought to have done”? ",
    "answer": "Omni"
  },
  {
    "id": 1737,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:2",
    "question": "Omni was not a wicked man, and obeyed all the commandments of the Lord.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1738,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Omni1:3",
    "question": "Omni wrote that they had six seasons of peace; and had many_____ of serious war and bloodshed.",
    "answer": "Seasons",
    "options": ["Seasons", "Times", "Years"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1739,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:3",
    "question": "Omni only wrote three verses in the Book of Omni.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1740,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:3",
    "question": "Who did Omni confer the plates to?",
    "answer": "Amaron"
  },
  {
    "id": 1741,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:3",
    "question": "Amaron was the son of what Book of Mormon historian?",
    "answer": "Omni"
  },
  {
    "id": 1742,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:4",
    "question": "Amaron tells us that he wrote only a few words in the book of his father.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1743,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:5",
    "question": "And it came to pass that three hundred and twenty years had passed away, and the more wicked part of the_____ were destroyed.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 1744,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:6",
    "question": "The Lord would not suffer that his words should not be verified, when he said to Omni’s fathers:  “Inasmuch as ye will not keep my _____ ye shall not prosper in the land”.",
    "answer": "Commandments"
  },
  {
    "id": 1745,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Omni1:7",
    "question": "The Lord visited the Nephites in great_____.",
    "answer": "Judgment",
    "options": ["Numbers", "Power", "Judgment"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1746,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:7",
    "question": "The Lord did spare the righteous that they should not perish.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1747,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:7",
    "question": "The Lord did spare the_____ Nephites that they should not perish and delivered them out of the hands of their enemies.",
    "answer": "Righteous"
  },
  {
    "id": 1748,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:8",
    "question": "Who was the brother of Omni that he delivered the plates to?",
    "answer": "Chemish"
  },
  {
    "id": 1749,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:9",
    "question": "What Book of Mormon historian only wrote one verse in the Book of Mormon? ",
    "answer": "Chemish"
  },
  {
    "id": 1750,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:9",
    "question": "Chemish wrote that his brother Omni wrote on the plates on the same day that he delivered the plates unto him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1751,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:9",
    "question": "Chemish wrote that he saw the last which his brother wrote, and that he wrote it with his own hand.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1752,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "10-11",
    "question": "What Book of Mormon record keeper wrote only two versus in the Book of Omni?  Abinadom-",
    "answer": "Omni1:"
  },
  {
    "id": 1753,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1-10",
    "question": "Who was the son of Chemish, who was also a record keeper?",
    "answer": "Abinadom"
  },
  {
    "id": 1754,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Omni1:10",
    "question": "Abinadom wrote that he had taken the lives of many of Lamanites by using what kind of weapon?",
    "answer": "Sword",
    "options": ["Sword", "Cimeter", "Sling"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1755,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:11",
    "question": "Abinadom wrote that the record of the Lamanites is engraved upon the plates which is had by the kings.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1756,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:11",
    "question": "Abinadom wrote that he knew of no revelation save that which has been written, neither prophecy; so he did not write anymore.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1757,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:12",
    "question": "What record keeper of the Book of Mormon was the son of Abinadom?",
    "answer": "Amaleki"
  },
  {
    "id": 1758,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:30",
    "question": "Amaleki was the last record keeper to write in the Book of Omni.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1759,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:12",
    "question": "In what book is the prophet Mosiah first mentioned? ",
    "answer": "Omni"
  },
  {
    "id": 1760,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:12",
    "question": "Amaleki spoke concerning Mosiah, who was made king over the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1761,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:12",
    "question": "In the Book of Omni: What king of Zarahemla was warned of the Lord to flee out of the land of Nephi? ",
    "answer": "Mosiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 1762,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:12",
    "question": "The Lord told Mosiah to flee out of the land of Nephi, and to take as many of the Nephites that would hearken unto him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1763,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Omni1:12",
    "question": "Where did the Lord tell Mosiah and his people to go when they fled out of the land of Nephi?",
    "answer": "Wilderness",
    "options": ["Forest", "Wilderness", "Another City"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1764,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:13",
    "question": "And it came to pass, that Mosiah did not do according to what the Lord had commanded of him. ",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1765,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:13",
    "question": "Mosiah and his followers were led by preachings and prophesyings.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1766,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:13",
    "question": "Mosiah and the Nephites were admonished continually by the word of _____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 1767,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Omni1:13",
    "question": "Mosiah and his people were led by the power of the_____ of God through the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Arm",
    "options": ["Arm", "Word", "Mercy"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1768,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:13",
    "question": "Mosiah and his people were led by the arm of God into the land which is called the land of_____.",
    "answer": "Zarahemla"
  },
  {
    "id": 1769,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Omni1:14",
    "question": "Mosiah discovered a people who were called the people of____.",
    "answer": "Zarahemla",
    "options": ["Nephi", "Zoram", "Zarahemla"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1770,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:14",
    "question": "When Mosiah arrived in the land of Zarahemla, there was not any rejoicing or happiness.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1771,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:14",
    "question": "Who rejoiced exceedingly because the Lord had sent the people of Mosiah with the plates of brass? ",
    "answer": "Zarahemla"
  },
  {
    "id": 1772,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:14",
    "question": "Zarahemla did rejoice because the plates contained the record of the Jews.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1773,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "25:2",
    "question": "Who was Zarahemla? A descendent of Mulek-",
    "answer": "Mosiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 1774,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:15",
    "question": "Mosiah discovered that the people of Zarahemla came out from Jerusalem.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1775,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:15",
    "question": "The people of Zarahemla came out from Jerusalem at the time that Zedekiah, king of Judah, was carried away captive into Babylon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1776,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:15",
    "question": "Zedekiah was the king of_____, when he was carried away captive into Babylon.",
    "answer": "Judah"
  },
  {
    "id": 1777,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Omni1:16",
    "question": "Zarahemla and his people were brought by the hand of the Lord across the____ waters, into the land where Mosiah discovered them.",
    "answer": "Great",
    "options": ["Many", "Great", "Deep"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1778,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:17",
    "question": "At the time that Mosiah discovered them, the people of Zarahemla had become exceedingly numerous. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1779,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:17",
    "question": "The people of Zarahemla had had many wars and serious contentions, and had fallen by the_____ from time to time.",
    "answer": "Sword"
  },
  {
    "id": 1780,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:17",
    "question": "The language of the people of Zarahemla had become corrupted; and they had brought no records with them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1781,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:17",
    "question": "The people of Zarahemla did not deny the being of their Creator.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1782,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:17",
    "question": "Because of the language that they spoke:  _____ neither the people of Mosiah, could not understand them.",
    "answer": "Mosiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 1783,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:18",
    "question": "What prophet caused the people of Zarahemla to be taught in the language of the Nephites?",
    "answer": "Mosiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 1784,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:18",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Mosiah caused that the people of Zarahemla were taught in the language of Mosiah.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1785,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:18",
    "question": "After Zarahemla was taught in the language of Mosiah, he gave a genealogy of his_____.",
    "answer": "Fathers"
  },
  {
    "id": 1786,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:18",
    "question": "Zarahemla gave a genealogy of his fathers according to his memory.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1787,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:18",
    "question": "Zarahemla gave a genealogy of his fathers according to his memory; and they are written but not on the plates of Nephi. ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1788,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:19",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people of_____, and of Mosiah united together.",
    "answer": "Zarahemla- "
  },
  {
    "id": 1789,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:19",
    "question": "Who was appointed king over the people of Zarahemla and of the people of Mosiah? ",
    "answer": "Mosiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 1790,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:20",
    "question": "In the days of Mosiah, there was a small stone brought to him with engravings on it.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1791,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Omni1:20",
    "question": "And it came to pass that in the days of Mosiah, there was a large stone brought unto him with_____ on it.",
    "answer": "Engravings",
    "options": ["Writings", "Hieroglyphics", "Engravings"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1792,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:20",
    "question": "Mosiah did interpret the engravings on the large stone by the gift and_____ of God.",
    "answer": "Power"
  },
  {
    "id": 1793,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Omni1:21",
    "question": "The large stone that Mosiah interpreted gave an account of_____, and the slain of his people.",
    "answer": "Coriantumr",
    "options": ["Zoram", "Coriantumr", "Zarahemla"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1794,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Ether12:1 & 14:24",
    "question": "Coriantumr was a descendant of what tribe of people?",
    "answer": "Jaredites"
  },
  {
    "id": 1795,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:21",
    "question": "The large stone that Mosiah interpreted gave an account of_____ and the slain of his people.",
    "answer": "Coriantumr"
  },
  {
    "id": 1796,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:21",
    "question": "The stone that Mosiah interpreted did not give an account of Coriantumr or the slain of his people.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1797,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:21",
    "question": "By what people was Coriantumr discovered?",
    "answer": "Zarahemla"
  },
  {
    "id": 1798,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Omni1:21",
    "question": "Coriantumr dwelt with the people of Zarahemla for the space of nine_____.",
    "answer": "Moons",
    "options": ["Moons", "Years", "Days"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1799,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:21",
    "question": "The word moons; only appears once in the text of the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1800,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:21",
    "question": "In what Book of Mormon book can we find the word Moons?",
    "answer": "Omni"
  },
  {
    "id": 1801,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:22",
    "question": "The Book of Mormon speaks of the Tower of Babel by name.-",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1802,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:22",
    "question": "Coriantumr’s first parents came out from the tower, at the time the Lord confounded the language of the people",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1803,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:22",
    "question": "The severity of the Lord fell upon Coriantumr’s people, according to his judgments, which are_____.",
    "answer": "Just"
  },
  {
    "id": 1804,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Omni1:22",
    "question": "The bones of the people of Coriantumr are scattered in the land_____.",
    "answer": "Northward",
    "options": ["Eastward", "Northward", "Southward"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1805,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:23",
    "question": "In the Book of Omni, what Book of Mormon historian was born in the days of King Mosiah?",
    "answer": "Ameleki"
  },
  {
    "id": 1806,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:23",
    "question": "What Book of Omni record keeper lived to see the days of King Mosiah and also his death? ",
    "answer": "Amaleki"
  },
  {
    "id": 1807,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:23",
    "question": "Who did the record keeper Amaleki say reign after the death of his father?",
    "answer": "Benjamin"
  },
  {
    "id": 1808,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:24",
    "question": "Amaleki said that in the days of King Benjamin he had seen a serious war and much bloodshed between the Nephites and Lamanites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1809,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:24",
    "question": "During the days of King Benjamin, the Nephites obtained much advantage over the_____ according to Ameleki.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 1810,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:24",
    "question": "King Benjamin did not drive the Lamanites out of the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1811,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:25",
    "question": "The record keeper Ameleki; did not have any seed.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1812,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:25",
    "question": "Ameleki testified that he knew King_____ was a just man before the Lord.",
    "answer": "Benjamin"
  },
  {
    "id": 1813,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:25",
    "question": "Who did Ameleki deliver the plates to? Exhorting all men to come unto God, the Holy One of Israel.",
    "answer": "Benjamin"
  },
  {
    "id": 1814,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:25",
    "question": "Ameleki wanted us to believe in prophesying, and in revelations, and in the ministering of_____.",
    "answer": "Angels"
  },
  {
    "id": 1815,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:25",
    "question": "Ameleki wanted us to believe in the gift of speaking with tongues, and the gift of interpreting languages, and in all things which are good.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1816,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:25",
    "question": "Who is the first person in the Book of Mormon to say? “For there is nothing which is good save it comes from the Lord; and that which is evil cometh from the devil”.",
    "answer": "Ameleki"
  },
  {
    "id": 1817,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:26",
    "question": "And now my beloved brethren, I would that ye should come, unto_____, who is the Holy One of Israel, and partake of his salvation.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 1818,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:26",
    "question": "Ameleki wanted us to come unto Christ, who is the Holy One of Israel, and partake of his_____ and the power of his redemption.",
    "answer": "Salvation"
  },
  {
    "id": 1819,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Omni1:26",
    "question": "Ameleki wants us to come unto Christ and offer our whole_____ as an offering to him.",
    "answer": "Souls",
    "options": ["Bodies", "Tithes", "Souls"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1820,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:26",
    "question": "Ameleki writes that we should continue in fasting and praying, and endure to the end; and as the Lord lives we will be saved.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1821,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:27& 2Nep:2",
    "question": "Ameleki said that there were a certain number of people who went to the land of Nephi, and were desirous to possess the land of their inheritance.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1822,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Omni1:28",
    "question": "Ameleki writes that the people that went up unto the wilderness had a leader who was a strong and_____ man, wherefore he caused a contention among them.",
    "answer": "Mighty",
    "options": ["Mighty", "Awful", "Delightsome"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1823,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": " Omni1:28, Mos7:21, Mos9:3-4",
    "question": "The strong and mighty man that went up to the wilderness was_____.",
    "answer": "Zeniff",
    "options": ["Nephi", "Zeniff", "Zenos"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1824,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:30",
    "question": "Ameleki wrote that he had a brother that went with Zefiff and has not since known concerning them or him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1825,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:30",
    "question": "Ameleki wrote that the_____ were full and that he was about to lie down in his grave.",
    "answer": "Plates"
  },
  {
    "id": 1826,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon",
    "question": "The Words of Mormon is an abridgment of the plates by whom?",
    "answer": "Mormon"
  },
  {
    "id": 1827,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon",
    "question": "There is only one chapter written in the Words of Mormon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1828,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon",
    "question": "There are only eighteen verses in the Words of Mormon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1829,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:1",
    "question": "In the beginning of the Words of Mormon; Mormon is about to deliver the plates to his son_____.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 1830,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:1",
    "question": "Who wrote in the Words of Mormon; that he has witnessed almost all the destruction of his people the Nephites?",
    "answer": "Mormon"
  },
  {
    "id": 1831,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:2",
    "question": "When Mormon wrote the Words of Mormon; it had been many hundred years after the coming of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1832,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:2",
    "question": "Mormon wrote: That it supposes him that Moroni will witness the entire destruction of the_____.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 1833,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:2",
    "question": "Mormon wrote: May God grant that Moroni may survive and write concerning his people and somewhat concerning Christ, that perhaps one day it may profit them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1834,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:3",
    "question": "Mormon made an abridgment from the plates of Nephi, down to the reign of King_____.",
    "answer": "Benjamin"
  },
  {
    "id": 1835,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:3",
    "question": "Mormon searched among the records which had been delivered into his hands which contained a small account of the prophets.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1836,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:3",
    "question": "When Mormon searched among the records he found that they gave an account of the prophets, from Jacob down to King Benjamin, and also many of the words of_____.",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 1837,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:4",
    "question": "The things which Mormon found on the plates were pleasing unto him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1838,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:4",
    "question": "Mormon found the plates pleasing unto him because it contained the prophecies of the coming of_____.",
    "answer": "Christ",
    "options": ["Abraham", "Nephi", "Christ"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1839,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:4",
    "question": "Mormon wrote that he knew that many things as have been prophesied concerning them down to his day have been fulfilled",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1840,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:4",
    "question": "Mormon also wrote that he knew as many prophesies as going beyond his day must surely come to_____.",
    "answer": "Pass"
  },
  {
    "id": 1841,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:5",
    "question": "Mormon wrote to us and said that he could not write a hundredth part of the things of the people of Nephi.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1842,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:6",
    "question": "Mormon took the plates which contained the Prophesies and revelations of the Nephites and put them with the remainder of his record.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1843,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:6",
    "question": "Mormon said that his record was choice unto him, and knew that it would be choice unto his brethren and a later date.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1844,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:7",
    "question": "Mormon wrote the things on his record because it was a wise purpose in him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1845,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:7",
    "question": "According to the workings of the Spirit of the_____, it whispered to Mormon to write the things he did in his record.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 1846,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:7",
    "question": "Mormon confessed that he did not know all things but that the_____ knows all things and all things which are to come.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 1847,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:7",
    "question": "Mormon knew all things and things which are to come.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1848,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mor1:8",
    "question": "Mormon prayed to_____ concerning the Lamanites; that they may once again come to the knowledge of God and the redemption of Christ.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["Holy Ghost", "The Stars", "God"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1849,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mormon1:8",
    "question": "Mormon prayed to God concerning the Lamanites; that they may once again be a_____ people.",
    "answer": "Delightsome",
    "options": ["Nice", "Delightsome", "Kind"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1850,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:9",
    "question": "Mormon proceeded to finish his record which he took from the Plates of_____.",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 1851,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mormon1:9",
    "question": "Mormon proceeding with the record and made it according to the knowledge and the_____ which God had given him.",
    "answer": "Understanding.",
    "options": ["Gift", "Power", "Understanding."]
  },
  {
    "id": 1852,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:9",
    "question": "Mormon proceeding with the record and made it according to the knowledge and the understanding; which God had given unto him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1853,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mormon1:10",
    "question": "Wherefore it came to pass that_____ had delivered these plates into the hands of King Benjamin.",
    "answer": "Amaleki",
    "options": ["Mormon", "Nephi", "Amaleki"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1854,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:10",
    "question": "Amaleki delivered the plates of Nephi; and also other records which had been handed down by the kings and delivered them into the hands of King Benjamin.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1855,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:11",
    "question": "The records were handed down from King Benjamin, from generation to generation until they had fallen into the hands of_____.",
    "answer": "Mormom"
  },
  {
    "id": 1856,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:11",
    "question": "Mormon prayed to God that the records would be preserved from his time henceforth.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1857,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:11",
    "question": "Mormon knew and testified that the records would be preserved because they had great things written upon them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1858,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mormon1:11",
    "question": "The things written on Mormon’s record and the other plates were important because the Nephites and their brethren would be judged at the great and_____ day.",
    "answer": "Last",
    "options": ["Gloomy", "Last", "Glorious"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1859,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:11",
    "question": "The words of God are not written on the plates of Nephi or in the record of Mormon.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1860,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:12",
    "question": "Mormon wrote that King Benjamin had somewhat contentions among his people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1861,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:13",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the armies of the_____ came down to battle to the land of Nephi against King Benjamin and his people.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 1862,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:13",
    "question": "King Benjamin withstood the armies of the Lamanites with his own strength of his arm, and with the sword of_____.",
    "answer": "Laban"
  },
  {
    "id": 1863,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:13",
    "question": "What is the name of the sword that King Benjamin wielded in battle against the Lamanites?  Sword of ",
    "answer": "Laban"
  },
  {
    "id": 1864,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Words or Mormon1:14",
    "question": "With whose strength did King Benjamin and his people contend with against the Lamanites?  The ",
    "answer": "Lord’s"
  },
  {
    "id": 1865,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:14",
    "question": "Because King Benjamin and his people had the strength of the Lord on their side, they were able to drive out the Lamanites out of the lands of their inheritance.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1866,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Words or Mormon1:15",
    "question": "During the time of King Benjamin, it came to pass that after there had been false Christs, and their mouths had been shut, they were punished for their crimes.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1867,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Words or Mormon1:16",
    "question": "During the time of King Benjamin; there had been false_____, and false preachers, and false teachers.",
    "answer": "Prophets"
  },
  {
    "id": 1868,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:16",
    "question": "During the time of King Benjamin; there had been false prophets, preachers, and teachers among the people and were punished for their crimes.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1869,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:16",
    "question": "King Benjamin had much contention and dissensions among his people and many went away into the Lamanites during his reign.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1870,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:16",
    "question": "There were holy prophets among King Benjamin and his people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1871,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:17",
    "question": "Mormon wrote that King Benjamin was not a holy man, and reigned in unrighteousness.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1872,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:17",
    "question": "Mormon wrote that King Benjamin was a holy man and reigned in_____.",
    "answer": "Righteousness"
  },
  {
    "id": 1873,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mormon1:17",
    "question": "During the reign of King Benjamin there were many holy men in the land, and they spoke with the power and_____ of God.",
    "answer": "Authority",
    "options": ["Authority", "Gift", "Knowledge"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1874,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:17",
    "question": "The holy men spoke with power and authority of God to the people of King Benjamin and used much sharpness because of the_____ of the people.",
    "answer": "Stiffneckedness"
  },
  {
    "id": 1875,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Words of Mormon1:18",
    "question": "King Benjamin labored with all the might of his body and the faculty of his whole_____, to once establish peace in the land.",
    "answer": "Soul"
  },
  {
    "id": 1876,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Words or Mormon1:18",
    "question": "With the help of the holy men, and by using all his might and the faculty of his whole soul, King Benjamin was able to establish peace once again in the land.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1877,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Nep5:20",
    "question": "Mormon was a pure descendant of whom?",
    "answer": "Lehi",
    "options": ["Laman", "Nephi", "Lehi"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1878,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:23",
    "question": "What was the name of King Benjamin's father?",
    "answer": "Mosiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 1879,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:1",
    "question": "After King Benjamin was able to establish peace in the land of Zarahemla, he had continual peace all the remainder of his days.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1880,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:2",
    "question": "King Benjamin had five sons.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1881,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:2",
    "question": "King Benjamin caused that his sons be taught in all the language of his fathers that thereby they might become men of understanding.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1882,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos1:2",
    "question": "King Benjamin wanted his sons to know concerning the_____ which had been spoken by the mouths of their fathers.",
    "answer": "Prophecies",
    "options": ["Prophecies", "10 Commandments", "Lawords Of Mosmones"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1883,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:2",
    "question": "By whose hand were the prophecies delivered to the mouths of the prophets in the Book of Mosiah?  The ",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 1884,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:3",
    "question": "King Benjamin taught his sons concerning the records which were engraved on the_____ of brass.",
    "answer": "Plates"
  },
  {
    "id": 1885,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:3",
    "question": "Mosiah wrote that if it were not for the records and commandments written on them, they would have suffered in ignorance.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1886,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:3",
    "question": "Mosiah wrote that if it were not for the Plates of_____, they would have suffered in ignorance, not knowing the mysteries of God.",
    "answer": "Brass"
  },
  {
    "id": 1887,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:4",
    "question": "Mosiah said that it was not possible for Lehi to remember “all these things” and having taught them to his children if it was not for the help of the plates of brass.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1888,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:4",
    "question": "According to Mosiah, Lehi was taught in the language of the Egyptians and could read the things engraved on the plates.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1889,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:4",
    "question": "King Benjamin wrote that Lehi taught his children in the language of the Egyptians thereby teaching their children and so forth, fulfilling the word of God down to his present time.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1890,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:5",
    "question": "King Benjamin said to his sons that if it were not for the plates of brass; the Nephites would have dwindled in unbelief.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1891,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos1:5",
    "question": "King Benjamin wrote that if it were not for the plates of brass, the Nephites would have dwindled in unbelief and not known of the commandments of God or his_____.",
    "answer": "Mysteries",
    "options": ["Plans", "Mysteries", "Miracles"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1892,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:5",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that the_____ know nothing concerning the things of God, or even do not believe them when they are taught, because of the traditions of their fathers.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 1893,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos1:5",
    "question": "Who preserved the records and the plates of brass by their hand according to King Benjamin?",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["Nephi", "Lehi", "God"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1894,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:5",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that the traditions of the Lamanites and their fathers, was correct.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1895,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:6",
    "question": "King Benjamin testified of the truthfulness of the sayings, records, and the plates of Nephi.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1896,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:6",
    "question": "The plates of_____, contain the records and sayings of the fathers of King Benjamin from the time they left Jerusalem until his present time.",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 1897,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:6",
    "question": "King Benjamin testified of the surety of the records and of the plates of Nephi because they had them before their very eyes.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1898,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:7",
    "question": "King Benjamin wanted his sons to search the records diligently so they could profit from them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1899,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:7",
    "question": "King Benjamin told his sons that if they searched the records diligently, and keep the commandments of the Lord, they would prosper in the land, according to the_____ the Lord had made with their fathers.",
    "answer": "Promise"
  },
  {
    "id": 1900,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:8",
    "question": "All the things that King Benjamin taught his sons are written in the Book of Mosiah.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1901,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:9",
    "question": "When King Benjamin was thirty years old and soon go to his grave; he conferred the kingdom to one of his sons.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1902,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos1:9",
    "question": "King Benjamin decided to confer the kingdom to one of his sons because he_____ old and saw that he must soon go to the way of the earth.",
    "answer": "Waxed",
    "options": ["Waxed", "Grew", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1903,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:10",
    "question": "Who did King Benjamin confer the kingdom to, and was also one of his sons?",
    "answer": "Mosiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 1904,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:10-Mos2:1",
    "question": "Who made the first proclamation mentioned in the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "Mosiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 1905,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:10",
    "question": "King Benjamin wanted Mosiah to send out a proclamation to the people of Zarahemla and the people or Mosiah.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1906,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:10",
    "question": "King Benjamin wanted to proclaim out of his own mouth to the people that_____ would be their next king and a ruler over them.",
    "answer": "Mosiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 1907,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:11",
    "question": "King Benjamin wanted to give a people a name that thereby they may be distinguished above all the people the Lord God had brought out of Jerusalem.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1908,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:11",
    "question": "King Benjamin gave the people the name of Christ because they had been diligent in keeping the commandments of the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1909,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:12",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that the name that he gave the people of Zarahemla and Mosiah would never be_____ out, except it be; through transgression.",
    "answer": "Blotted"
  },
  {
    "id": 1910,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:12",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that the name that he gave the people would never be blotted out except through transgression.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1911,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos1:13",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that the people of Zarahemla and Mosiah were a highly favored_____ of the Lord.",
    "answer": "People",
    "options": ["Tribe", "People", "Bunch"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1912,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:13",
    "question": "If the people that are highly favored of the Lord should fall into transgression; the Lord would deliver them up and become a weak people like their brethren the_____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 1913,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:13",
    "question": "If the Nephites fall into transgression; the Lord will not preserve them by his_____ and marvelous power.",
    "answer": "Matchless"
  },
  {
    "id": 1914,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos1:14",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that if the Lord had not extended his_____ in the preservation of the Nephites, they would have fallen into the hands of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Arm",
    "options": ["Arm", "Power", "Wisdom"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1915,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:14",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that the Lord extended his arm in the preservation of the Nephites so that they would not become victims of the hatred of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1916,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:15",
    "question": "After King Benjamin made an end of his sayings to his son, he gave him charge concerning all the affairs of the_____.",
    "answer": "Kingdom"
  },
  {
    "id": 1917,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:16",
    "question": "The ball or director led the fathers of King Benjamin through the wilderness according to the heed and_____ which they gave unto him.",
    "answer": "Diligence"
  },
  {
    "id": 1918,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:16 & Alma37:38",
    "question": "The Liahona led the fathers of King Benjamin through the wilderness according to the heed and diligence they gave unto the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1919,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:33",
    "question": "The word Liahona only appears once in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1920,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:38",
    "question": "The word Liahona appears how many times in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "Once",
    "options": ["Once", "Twice", "Thrice"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1921,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:38",
    "question": "In what Book of Mormon book does the word Liahona first appear? ",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 1922,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:4",
    "question": "The Liahona contained_____that pointed the way Lehi and his company should travel.",
    "answer": "Spindle",
    "options": ["Spindle", "Spindles", "No Spindles"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1923,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos1:17",
    "question": "If the fathers of King Benjamin were unfaithful, they would not prosper neither_____ in their journey in the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Progress",
    "options": ["Be Blessed", "Progress", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1924,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:17",
    "question": "When the fathers of King Benjamin incurred the displeasure of God upon them; they were smitten with famine and sore_____ to stir them up in remembrance of their duty.",
    "answer": "Afflictions"
  },
  {
    "id": 1925,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:18",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Mosiah did not do what his father King Benjamin commanded him to do by sending out a proclamation to the people.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1926,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:18",
    "question": "At what place did the people of Zarahemla and Mosiah gather together to hear the words of King Benjamin.",
    "answer": "Temple"
  },
  {
    "id": 1927,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:2",
    "question": "The people that gathered around the temple were so great, that they did not number them; for they had multiplied exceedingly and waxed great in the land.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1928,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mosiah2:1",
    "question": "What person in the Book of Mormon is the first one to make a proclamation unto the people?",
    "answer": "Mosiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 1929,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mosiah2:1",
    "question": "Who made the first proclamation unto the Nephites; King Benjamin or his son Mosiah?",
    "answer": "Mosiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 1930,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos2:3",
    "question": "The people took the_____ of their flocks, that they might offer sacrifice and burnt offerings according to the Lawords of Mosmones.",
    "answer": "Worst",
    "options": ["Worst", "Firstlings"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1931,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:4",
    "question": "The people offered sacrifice and burnt offerings to the Lord for the purpose of given him thanks for bringing them out of Jerusalem and delivering them from the hands of their enemies.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1932,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:4",
    "question": "Who appointed just men and teachers for the Nephites and also a just man to be their king in the land of Zarahemla and the land of Mosiah?",
    "answer": "Lord "
  },
  {
    "id": 1933,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:4",
    "question": "Who taught the people of Zarahemla to keep the commandments of God, that they might be filled with love towards God and all men?",
    "answer": "Benjamin"
  },
  {
    "id": 1934,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:5",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people pitched their tents around the temple to hear the words of King_____.",
    "answer": "Benjamin"
  },
  {
    "id": 1935,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:5",
    "question": "The people pitched their tents around the temple, according to his family from the eldest to the youngest, every family being separate one from another.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1936,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos2:6",
    "question": "In relation to the temple; in what direction did the people pitch the door of their tents toward the temple?",
    "answer": "Facing The Temple",
    "options": [
      "Facing The Temple",
      "North Of The Temple",
      "South Of The Temple."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 1937,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:6",
    "question": "The multitude of the people was so great that King Benjamin could not teach them all within the wall of the_____.",
    "answer": "Temple"
  },
  {
    "id": 1938,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos2:7",
    "question": "King Benjamin caused that a_____ be erected so that he could speak to the people and that they could hear his words.",
    "answer": "Tower",
    "options": ["Tower", "Building", "Temple"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1939,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:8",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when King Benjamin started to speak to the people, not all of them could here his words.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1940,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:9",
    "question": "King Benjamin caused that the words which he should speak unto the people be written upon plates.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1941,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:9",
    "question": "What were the first two words that King Benjamin said to the people when he spoke to them in the tower. ",
    "answer": "Breathren"
  },
  {
    "id": 1942,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:9",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the people that he had not commanded them to trifle with the words he should speak, but to hearken unto him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1943,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos2:10",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the people that he had not commanded them to gather together and should fear them, and think that he was more than a_____ man.",
    "answer": "Better",
    "options": ["Better", "Mortal"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1944,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:11",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that he was just like the people and subjected to all manner of infirmaties in body and mind.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1945,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:11",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that he had been consecrated by his father, and was suffered by the_____ of the Lord to be a king and ruler of the people.",
    "answer": "Hand"
  },
  {
    "id": 1946,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:11",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the people that he had been preserved by the Lord’s matchless power, to serve them with all the might, mind and_____ which the Lord had granted unto him.",
    "answer": "Strength"
  },
  {
    "id": 1947,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:12",
    "question": "King Benjamin had suffered all his days in the service of his people and not sought after gold, or silver, or any manner of_____ from them.",
    "answer": "Riches"
  },
  {
    "id": 1948,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:13",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the people; neither have I suffered that ye should be confined to dungeons.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1949,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos2:13",
    "question": "King Benjamin would not suffer that the people make slaves of one another, nor that they should murder, plunder, steal, or commit_____.",
    "answer": "Adultery",
    "options": ["Adultery", "Crimes", "Crimes Against Humanity"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1950,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:13",
    "question": "King Benjamin would not suffer the people to commit any manner of_____, and had taught them to keep the commandments of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Wickedness"
  },
  {
    "id": 1951,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:14",
    "question": "King Benjamin said: “Even I, myself, have labored with mine own_____ that I might serve you, and that ye should not be laden with taxes”.",
    "answer": "Hands"
  },
  {
    "id": 1952,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:14",
    "question": "King Benjamin wanted that his people; to do nothing that was grievous to be borne of them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1953,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:14",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the people that they were witnesses to all the things which he was speaking to them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1954,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:15",
    "question": "When King Benjamin spoke to the people on the tower; he wanted to boast of the things and service he had done for them.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1955,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:15",
    "question": "King Benjamin wanted the people to know that he could answer to_____ with a clear conscience.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 1956,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:16",
    "question": "King Benjamin did not desire to boast to the people, but said that he had only been in the_____ of God.",
    "answer": "Service"
  },
  {
    "id": 1957,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos2:17",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the people things so that they could learn_____.",
    "answer": "Wisdom",
    "options": ["Of God", "Wisdom", "Or How To Make Speeches"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1958,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:17",
    "question": "Who was the first person in the Book of Mormon to say the following words: “When ye are in the service of your fellow beings ye are only in the service of your God”.",
    "answer": "Benjamin"
  },
  {
    "id": 1959,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:17",
    "question": "King Benjamin taught his people wisdom by wanting them to learn, that when they were in service to their fellow beings they were only in the service of their_____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 1960,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:18",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that if he was the king and labored for the people, should they not labor to serve one another?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1961,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:19",
    "question": "King Benjamin did not want the people to thank their heavenly King because he had labored all his days in the service of God and the people.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1962,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:20",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the people that they should render all their thanks and praise which their soul possessed to that God that had created them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1963,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos2:20",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the Nephites that God had created them and had kept and preserved them that they should live in______ with one another.",
    "answer": "Peace",
    "options": ["Peace", "Harmony", "Contention"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1964,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:21",
    "question": "What has the Lord lend unto us that we may live and move according to our own will, and supports us from one moment to another?",
    "answer": "Breath"
  },
  {
    "id": 1965,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:21",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that even if we were to serve God with all our whole souls, we would still be unprofitable servants.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1966,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:22",
    "question": "King Benjamin tells the Nephites and us: 'That all the Lord requires of us is to keep his commandments and we will prosper in the Land''.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1967,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:22",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that the Lord varies from time to time of the things which he has said",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1968,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:23-24",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that because the Lord has created us and granted us our lives we are required to keep his commandments.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1969,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:23-24",
    "question": "According to King Benjamin we will always be indebted to our heavenly father, forever and ever.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1970,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:24",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that if we do what the Lord commands us to do, he will immediately bless us",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1971,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:25",
    "question": "King Benjamin wrote that even the dust is greater than all of us.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1972,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos2;25",
    "question": "King Benjamin testified and knew that we were created from the_____.",
    "answer": "Dust",
    "options": ["Earth", "World", "Dust"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1973,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:25",
    "question": "King Benjamin wrote that because we were created from the dust of the earth; we do not belong to our heavenly father.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1974,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:26",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the Nephites that even him, whom they called their king; was no better than them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1975,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos2:27",
    "question": "King Benjamin had caused that the people gather together that he might be found_____, and that there blood should not come upon him at judgment day.",
    "answer": "Blameless",
    "options": ["Blameless", "Spotless", "Unworthy"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1976,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:28",
    "question": "King Benjamin caused the people to assemble together that he might rid his_____ of their blood.",
    "answer": "Garments"
  },
  {
    "id": 1977,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos2:28",
    "question": "King Benjamin wished that he would go down in peace and that his spirit may join the_____ above in singing praises of a just God.",
    "answer": "Choirs",
    "options": ["Heavens", "Choirs", "Assemblies"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1978,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:28",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that God was only just when he wanted to be.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1979,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:29",
    "question": "King Benjamin had the people gather together to tell them that he could no longer be their teacher, nor their_____.",
    "answer": "King"
  },
  {
    "id": 1980,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:30",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the people that even at this time, his whole frame trembled exceedingly while attempting to speak to them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1981,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:30",
    "question": "The_____ supported King Benjamin because his frame was trembling while he spoke to the people.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 1982,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:30",
    "question": "Who commanded King Benjamin to declare to the people that his son Mosiah2 be the king and ruler of the Nephites? ",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 1983,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos2:31",
    "question": "Who did King Benjamin say would deliver the commandments of the Lord to the people?",
    "answer": "Mosiah2",
    "options": ["Mosiah2", "God", "Adam"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1984,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:32",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that contentions would arise among the people if they list to obey the evil spirit spoken by his father Mosiah.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1985,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:33",
    "question": "King Benjamin wrote that if we choose to listen to the evil spirit and obey him, and remain and die in our sins, we will be drinking damnation to our soul.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1986,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:34",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the_____ that there were not any among them, except little children that had been taught the things of God.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 1987,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:34",
    "question": "During King Benjamin time, all the Nephites had been taught concerning the records except the little children.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1988,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:34",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the Nephites that they were eternally indebted to their heavenly father and to render all that they have and are unto him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1989,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:36",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the Nephites if they should transgress and go contrary to that which had been spoken to them, the_____ of the Lord would withdraw from them.",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },
  {
    "id": 1990,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:37",
    "question": "King Benjamin taught that those who openly rebel against God; “become an enemy to all_____”. ",
    "answer": "Righteousness"
  },
  {
    "id": 1991,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:37",
    "question": "King Benjamin taught that if we openly rebel against God, we become an enemy to all righteousness; therefore, the Lord has no place for us.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1992,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:37",
    "question": "According to King Benjamin the Lord sometimes dwells in unholy temples.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 1993,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:38",
    "question": "If we do not repent, and remain and die an enemy to God, the demands of divine justice will awaken our immortal soul to our guilt, and we will shrink from the presence of the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1994,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:38",
    "question": "If we shrink from the presence of the Lord because of our guilt our breast will be filled with guilt, and_____, and anguish.",
    "answer": "Pain"
  },
  {
    "id": 1995,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:38",
    "question": "Our guilt, and pain, and anguish, is like an unquenchable fire, whose_____ ascends up forever and ever.",
    "answer": "Flame"
  },
  {
    "id": 1996,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:39",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that mercy has no claim on the man; therefore his final doom is to endure a_____-ending torment.",
    "answer": "Never"
  },
  {
    "id": 1997,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:40",
    "question": "King Benjamin spoke plainly to all the old men, young men, and little children.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 1998,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos2:40",
    "question": "King Benjamin prayed that all the people should awake to a remembrance of the awful situation of those that had fallen into_____.",
    "answer": "Transgression",
    "options": ["The Bottomless Pit", "Transgression", "Hell"]
  },
  {
    "id": 1999,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:41",
    "question": "King Benjamin wanted his people to consider all the blessed and happy state of those that keep the commandments of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2000,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:41",
    "question": "If we keep the commandments of God, we are blessed both temporally and spiritually.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2001,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:41",
    "question": "King Benjamin said if we are faithful to God to the end, we are received into heaven, that thereby we may dwell with him in a state of_____ happiness.",
    "answer": "ending"
  },
  {
    "id": 2002,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:41",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the people that the things of which he had spoken of were somewhat true.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2003,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos3:2",
    "question": "The things that King Benjamin told the Nephites were made known unto him by_____.",
    "answer": "Angel From God",
    "options": ["Moses", "Nephi", "Angel From God"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2004,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:2",
    "question": "The angel told King Benjamin to awake, and he awoke, and behold he stood before him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2005,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:3",
    "question": "The angel of the Lord came to declare: “glad tidings of great joy” unto King _____.",
    "answer": "Benjamin"
  },
  {
    "id": 2006,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:4",
    "question": "The angel told King Benjamin that the Lord had judged him in righteousness and sent him to declare that he could rejoice.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2007,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:5",
    "question": "For behold, the time comes, and is not far distant, that with power, the Lord_____, who reigns, from all eternity to all eternity and shall come down from heaven among the children of men.",
    "answer": "Omnipotent- "
  },
  {
    "id": 2008,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:5",
    "question": "The Lord will not cure all manner of diseases.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2009,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "6,8",
    "question": "Who did King Benjamin say would cast out devils, or the evil spirits which shall dwell in the hearts of the children of men?  Jesus -",
    "answer": "Mo3:"
  },
  {
    "id": 2010,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "7-8",
    "question": "Who did King Benjamin say shall suffer temptations, and pain of body, thirst, and fatigue, even more than man can suffer?  Jesus -",
    "answer": "Mos3:"
  },
  {
    "id": 2011,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:7",
    "question": "King Benjamin wrote that Jesus Christ would bleed from every pore, and so great will be his anguish for the wickedness and the abominations of his people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2012,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:8",
    "question": "King Benjamin saw the crucifixion of Jesus Christ?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2013,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:8-9",
    "question": "The word crucifixion never appears in the text of the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2014,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:8 & 2nd Nep25:19",
    "question": "What person in the Book of Mormon: is the second person to refer to the Savior by the name of Jesus Christ?",
    "answer": "Benjamin"
  },
  {
    "id": 2015,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:8",
    "question": "What prophet in the Book of Mormon is the first to mention the name of Mary as being the name of the mother of Jesus Christ?",
    "answer": "Benjamin"
  },
  {
    "id": 2016,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:8",
    "question": "Another name for Jesus Christ is the Creator of all things from the beginning.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2017,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:9",
    "question": "And lo, “He comes unto his own, and they shall consider him a man, and say that he has a devil, and shall scourge him, and_____ him”.",
    "answer": "Crucify"
  },
  {
    "id": 2018,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:10",
    "question": "And he shall rise the_____ day from the dead; and behold he stands to judge the world.",
    "answer": "Third"
  },
  {
    "id": 2019,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:10",
    "question": "The Lord will rise from the dead on the third day; and these things are done that a righteous judgment might come upon the children of men.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2020,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos3:11",
    "question": "Jesus Christ blood atones for the sins of those who have fallen by the transgression of_____.",
    "answer": "Adam",
    "options": ["Satan", "Adam", "Noah"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2021,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:11",
    "question": "According to King Benjamin, there are those who died not knowing the will of God concerning them, or who have ignorantly sinned.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2022,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:12",
    "question": "King Benjamin wrote: “But woe, woe unto him who knows that rebels against God!",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2023,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:12",
    "question": "Salvation comes to none except it be through the repentance and_____ on the Lord Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "Faith"
  },
  {
    "id": 2024,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos3:13",
    "question": "In the Book of Mosiah; Who did the Lord send to declare things among the children of men?_____",
    "answer": "Holy Prophets",
    "options": ["Peter", "Paul", "Holy Prophets"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2025,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:13",
    "question": "The Lord sent holy prophets to declare his things to every kindred, nation, and_____.",
    "answer": "Tongue"
  },
  {
    "id": 2026,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:13",
    "question": "The Lord wanted the people to receive a remission of their sins, and rejoice with exceeding great joy, even as though he had already come among them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2027,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:14",
    "question": "Because the people were stiffnecked, the Lord appointed to them a law which was called_____.",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },
  {
    "id": 2028,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:15",
    "question": "And many signs, and wonders, and types, were shown to the Nephites; and also holy prophets spoke concerning the coming of Christ, and yet they hardened their_____.",
    "answer": "Hearts"
  },
  {
    "id": 2029,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:16",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that it was not possible for little children to sin and even if they did, the blood of Jesus Christ atones for their sins.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2030,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:17",
    "question": "King Benjamin wrote that there shall be no other name given, or any other way or means whereby salvation can come to the children of men, only in and through the name of Christ, the Lord Omnipotent.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2031,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:18",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that a baby that dies in infancy perishes.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2032,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:18",
    "question": "Who did King Benjamin say “he judges, and his judgment is just”?  Jesus ",
    "answer": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 2033,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos3:18",
    "question": "Men drink damnation to there own_____, except they humble themselves and become as little children, and believe that salvation was, and is to come, in and through the atoning blood of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "Souls",
    "options": ["Bodies", "Souls", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2034,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:19",
    "question": "For the_____ man is an enemy to God, and has been since the fall of Adam.",
    "answer": "Natural"
  },
  {
    "id": 2035,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:19",
    "question": "The natural man is an enemy to God, and will be forever and ever, unless he yields to the enticing of the Holy Spirit.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2036,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:19",
    "question": "We must put off the natural man and become as a child, submissive, meek, and humble and yield to the enticing of the Holy Spirit.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2037,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:19",
    "question": "We must be willing to submit to all things which the_____ sees fit to inflict upon us, even as a child does submit to his father.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 2038,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:20",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that the time shall come when the knowledge of the_____ shall spread throughout every nation, kindred, tongue and people.",
    "answer": "Savior"
  },
  {
    "id": 2039,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos3:21",
    "question": "And behold, when the time comes, none shall be found blameless before God, except it be_____ children, only through repentance and faith on the name of the Lord God Omnipotent.",
    "answer": "Little",
    "options": ["Little", "Ugly", "Cute"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2040,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:23",
    "question": "King Benjamin spoke the words that the Lord had commanded him to speak to the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2041,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:24",
    "question": "The words which King Benjamin spoke to the Nephites while he was on the tower will not stand as a bright testimony against them.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2042,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:24",
    "question": "Thus saith the Lord:  “wherefore they shall be judged, every man according to his works, whether they be good, or whether they be_____”.",
    "answer": "Evil"
  },
  {
    "id": 2043,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:25",
    "question": "If your works were evil; you are consigned to an awful view of your own guilt and abominations, and an endless torment, from where you cannot return to the Lord’s presence.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2044,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos3:26",
    "question": "If you drink damnation to your soul, you have drunk out of the cup of the_____ of God.",
    "answer": "Wrath",
    "options": ["Tea", "Coffee", "Wrath"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2045,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:26",
    "question": "Adam fell because he partook of the_____ fruit.",
    "answer": "Forbidden"
  },
  {
    "id": 2046,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:27",
    "question": "If we go to hell our torment it is a lake of fire and_____, whose flames are unquenchable, and whose smoke ascends up forever and ever.",
    "answer": "Brimstone"
  },
  {
    "id": 2047,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:1",
    "question": "When King Benjamin was ending his address to the Nephites, he cast his eyes round about the multitude, and behold, they had fallen to the earth.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2048,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:2",
    "question": "The people that were at King Benjamin’s address fell to the earth, because the fear of the Lord had come upon them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2049,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos4:3",
    "question": "When King Benjamin finished his address to the Nephites; they viewed themselves in their own_____ state, even less than the dust of the earth.",
    "answer": "Carnal"
  },
  {
    "id": 2050,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos4:3",
    "question": "At the end of King Benjamin’s address; how did the people know that they had received forgiveness for their sins?",
    "answer": "Were Filled With Joy",
    "options": [
      "Burning Chest Sensation",
      "Were Filled With Joy",
      "Had A Halo Placed Of Their Heads"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 2051,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos4:3",
    "question": "The people had exceeding_____ in Jesus Christ who should come, according to the words which King Benjamin had spoken unto them.",
    "answer": "Faith"
  },
  {
    "id": 2052,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:5",
    "question": "When King Benjamin spoke of man’s “nothingness” he was referring that we all depend on God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2053,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:6",
    "question": "King Benjamin spoke to the people of the knowledge and goodness of God, and his matchless power.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2054,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos4:7",
    "question": "King Benjamin said the atonement was prepared from the_____ of the world. ",
    "answer": "Foundation"
  },
  {
    "id": 2055,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:9",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the Nephites and wrote to us to believe in God; believe that he is, and that he created all things, both in heaven and in earth.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2056,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos4:10",
    "question": "King Benjamin said we must repent of our sins and forsake them, and humble ourselves before God; and ask in sincerity of heart that he would forgive us, then we should_____ that we do them.",
    "answer": "See"
  },
  {
    "id": 2057,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:11",
    "question": "According to King Benjamin we should repent of our sins and should always retain in remembrance, the greatness of God, and our own nothingness, and his long-suffering towards us.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2058,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:11",
    "question": "King Benjamin told his people that they should not be calling on the name of the Lord daily.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2059,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:11",
    "question": "King Benjamin told his people that they should be standing steadfastly in the faith of that which is to come, which was spoken by the mouth of the angel.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2060,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos4:11",
    "question": "King Benjamin said as we come to the knowledge of the_____ of God, we will have known of his goodness and have tasted of his love. ",
    "answer": "Glory"
  },
  {
    "id": 2061,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos4:11",
    "question": "King Benjamin said when we come to the knowledge and_____ of God; we will have received a remission of our sins, and it will cause exceeding great joy in our soul.",
    "answer": "Glory",
    "options": ["Glory", "Love", "Gift"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2062,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:12",
    "question": "If we are filled with the love of God, and always retain a remission of our sins; we shall grow in the knowledge of the glory of him that created us, or in the knowledge of that which is just and true.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2063,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos4:14",
    "question": "King Benjamin taught that our children must not_____ and quarrel one with another and serve the devil.",
    "answer": "Fight"
  },
  {
    "id": 2064,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos4:14",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that the_____ is the master of sin, or who is the evil spirit spoken by his fathers, and is an enemy to all righteousness.",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },
  {
    "id": 2065,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:15",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that we should teach our children to walk in the ways of truth and soberness; to teach them to love one another, and to serve one another.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2066,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:16,18",
    "question": "King Benjamin said we have great cause to repent if we do not succor those that stand in need of our succor.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2067,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos4:19",
    "question": "King Benjamin said “for behold, are we not all_____? Do we not all depend upon the same Being, even God, for all our substance?”",
    "answer": "Beggars",
    "options": ["People", "Human", "Beggars"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2068,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:20",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that the Lord caused the hearts of the Nephites to be filled with joy because the Lord had poured out his Spirit upon them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2069,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:21",
    "question": "King Benjamin wrote that God will grant unto us whatsoever we ask that is right, in faith, believing that we will receive.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2070,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:21",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the Nephites that not only had God created them, but that they were dependent on him for their lives, and for all that they have and are.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2071,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos4:22",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that our lives and all our substance belongs to_____, who has created us.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 2072,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:24",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that we should not deny the beggar, because we have not; I would that ye say in your hearts that: “I give not because I have not, but if I had I would give”.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2073,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos4:26",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that we should impart of our substance unto the_____, every man according to what he has.",
    "answer": "Poor",
    "options": ["Poor", "Needy", "Homeless"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2074,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos4:27",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that we should see that all things are done in_____ and in order.",
    "answer": "Wisdom",
    "options": ["Correctly", "Wisdom", "Right Way"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2075,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:27",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that it is not “requisite that a man should run faster than he has strength”.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2076,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:28",
    "question": "We commit a sin when we borrow a tool from our neighbor and then don’t return it; and perhaps we shall cause that our neighbor might commit a sin also.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2077,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos4:29",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the_____ that there are so many ways to commit sin that he could not number them.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 2078,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos4:29",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the Nephites and us, to watch ourselves in our thoughts, and in our words, and in our_____, and observe the commandments of God.",
    "answer": "Deeds"
  },
  {
    "id": 2079,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos5:2",
    "question": "When King Benjamin spoke to the people it brought a mighty change in them and also in their hearts because of the Spirit of the Lord_____.",
    "answer": "Omnipotent"
  },
  {
    "id": 2080,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos5:2",
    "question": "Because to Spirit of the Lord Omnipotent had brought a mighty change in their hearts, the Nephites had no more disposition; to do_____, but to do good continually.",
    "answer": "Evil"
  },
  {
    "id": 2081,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos5:4",
    "question": "It was their faith that brought the great change in the people of King Benjamin",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2082,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos5:4",
    "question": "It was by_____ in the things that King Benjamin had spoken to them; that the people had no more disposition to do evil, but do good continually.",
    "answer": "Faith",
    "options": ["Witnessing", "Wisdom", "Faith"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2083,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos5:5",
    "question": "The people at King Benjamin address entered a covenant with God to do his will, and to be obedient to his commandments.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2084,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "5Mos3:26",
    "question": "Who had spoken to King Benjamin and told him to tell the people not to bring upon themselves a never-ending torment; that they may not drink out of the cup of wrath of God?.",
    "answer": "An Angel",
    "options": ["An Angel", "Nephi", "Enos"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2085,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos5:6",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the Nephites that they had not made a righteous covenant with the Lord.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2086,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos5:7",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the people because of the covenant they had made with the Lord was a righteous covenant; that they would be called the children of_____.",
    "answer": "Christ",
    "options": ["Moses", "Christ", "Paul"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2087,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos5:8",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the Nephites that “there is no other name given whereby salvation comes” therefore, I would that ye should take upon you the name of Christ.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2088,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos5:9",
    "question": "According to King Benjamin; at the end of our lives it is better for us to be found on the right hand of God than of the left.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2089,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos5:9",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that if we take upon the name of Christ and be obedient unto the end of our lives, we shall be found on the_____ hand of God.",
    "answer": "Right",
    "options": ["Left", "Right", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2090,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos5:9",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the Nephites that they would know the name by which they are called.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2091,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos5:10",
    "question": "King Benjamin said to the Nephites that if they did not take upon them the name of Christ, they must be called by some other name; therefore, they would find themselves on the_____ hand of God.",
    "answer": "Left"
  },
  {
    "id": 2092,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos5:11",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the Nephites that there names would never be blotted out, except it be through transgression.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2093,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos5:12",
    "question": "King Benjamin told his people should not be found on the left hand of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2094,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos5:12",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the Nephites that they should here and know; the_____ by which ye shall be called, and also, the name by which he shall call you. ",
    "answer": "Voice"
  },
  {
    "id": 2095,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos5:13",
    "question": "For how knows a man the_____ whom he has not served, and also is a stranger unto him.",
    "answer": "Master"
  },
  {
    "id": 2096,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos5:15",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the Nephites and us that we should be steadfast and_____, always abounding in good works.",
    "answer": "Immovable"
  },
  {
    "id": 2097,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos6:1",
    "question": "When King Benjamin finished speaking to the people, he thought that it was expedient that he should take the names of the people who had entered a covenant with God to keep his commandment.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2098,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos6:2",
    "question": "And it came to pass that every soul and all the little children that had entered into a covenant had taken upon them the name of Christ.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2099,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos6:3",
    "question": "What kind of people did King Benjamin appoint at the end of his reign to remind the people of the oath they had made with the Lord?",
    "answer": "Priests",
    "options": ["Prophets", "Teachers", "Priests"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2100,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos6:4",
    "question": "How old was Mosiah2 when he began to reign in his father’s stead?",
    "answer": "30",
    "options": ["25", "30", "35"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2101,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos6:5",
    "question": "After King Mosiah2 began his reign; how many more years did King Benjamin live?",
    "answer": "3",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2102,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos6:6",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Mosiah2 did not walk in the ways of the Lord, and was an unrighteous king.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2103,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos6:6",
    "question": "King Mosiah2 did walk in the ways of the Lord, and did observe his judgments and statues.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2104,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos6:7",
    "question": "King Mosiah2 caused that his people till the earth.  And he himself tilled the_____; that thereby he might not become a burden to his people.",
    "answer": "Earth"
  },
  {
    "id": 2105,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos6:7 & Mos7:1",
    "question": "King Mosiah2 had no contentions and had continual peace for the first three years of his reign.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2106,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:1",
    "question": "King Mosiah2 desired to know what had become of the people who went up to dwell in the land/city called Lehi-Nephi.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2107,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos7:2",
    "question": "King Mosiah2 granted that_____ of his strong men go up to the land of Lehi-Nephi to inquire concerning their brethren.",
    "answer": "16",
    "options": ["15", "16", "17"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2108,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:3",
    "question": "One of the men sent by King Mosiah2 to look for their brethren; was_____, and he is a descendant of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": "Ammon"
  },
  {
    "id": 2109,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:3",
    "question": "Ammon was a strong and mighty man, and a descendant of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2110,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:3",
    "question": "Ammon was not the leader on the band of sixteen men who went to the land of Lehi-Nephi to inquire about their brethren.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2111,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "4,5",
    "question": "How many days did Ammon and his brethren wonder in the wilderness before they came to a hill; which is north of the land of Shilom, and pitched their tents.",
    "answer": "40",
    "options": ["40", "50", "60"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2112,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "-(B)",
    "question": "Of the party of sixteen men that went with Ammon, only himself and_____ of his brethren met with the king of the people of the land of Nephi/Shilom.",
    "options": ["2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2113,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:7",
    "question": "Ammon and his brothers were surrounded by the king’s guard and were taken, and were bound, and were committed to prison.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2114,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:8",
    "question": "Ammon and his brothers were in prison for three days before they were brought before the king and permitted to speak.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2115,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:8",
    "question": "What was the name of the king who commanded that Ammon and his brothers to answer his questions?",
    "answer": "_____Limhi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2116,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:9",
    "question": "What was the name of King Limhi’s father who was a wicked man and king of the land known as Lehi-Nephi?",
    "answer": "Noah"
  },
  {
    "id": 2117,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:9",
    "question": "King Noah was the son of_____, who came up out of the land of Zarahemla to inherit the land of his fathers.",
    "answer": "Zeniff"
  },
  {
    "id": 2118,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos7:9",
    "question": "King Limhi was chosen to be the king of the land by:",
    "answer": "Voice Of The People",
    "options": [
      "Played Paper, Rock, Scissors,",
      "Popular Vote",
      "Voice Of The People"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 2119,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:12",
    "question": "When Ammon was permitted to speak to King Limhi, he bowed himself before the king and endeavored to speak with boldness.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2120,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:13",
    "question": "Ammon told King Limhi that if he would have known who he was, he would not have caused that he and his brethren be bound and put in prison.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2121,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:13",
    "question": "Ammon did not tell King Limhi that he was a descendant of Zarahemla, and did not come up to his land to inquire concerning the brethren, whom Zeniff brought up out of that land.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2122,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:14",
    "question": "King Limhi was exceedingly glad when_____ told him who he was and why they were inquiring of their brethren.",
    "answer": "Ammon"
  },
  {
    "id": 2123,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:15",
    "question": "King Limhi told Ammon that he and his people were in bondage to the_____, and were taxed with a tax which was grievous to be borne.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 2124,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:15",
    "question": "King Limhi said to Ammon that is better to be slaves to the_____ than to pay tribute to the king of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 2125,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:16",
    "question": "King Limhi commanded his guards that they should no more bind Ammon and his brethren that thereby they might eat, and_____, and rest themselves from their labors of their journey.",
    "answer": "Drink"
  },
  {
    "id": 2126,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos7:16",
    "question": "Ammon and his brethren had suffered many things; they had suffered hunger, thirst, and_____; from the labors of their journey.",
    "answer": "Fatigue",
    "options": ["Fatigue", "Poisonous Snakes", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2127,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos7:17",
    "question": "King Limhi sent a_____ among all his people so that they could gather together at the temple to hear his words.",
    "answer": "Proclamation",
    "options": ["Epistle", "Letter", "Proclamation"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2128,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:19",
    "question": "King Limhi told his people; lift up your heads, and rejoice, and put your trust in me and Ammon.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2129,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:19",
    "question": "King Limhi told his people to put their trust in God, in that God who was the God of Abraham, and Isaac, and_____.",
    "answer": "Jacob"
  },
  {
    "id": 2130,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:19",
    "question": "King Limhi knew that God had brought the children of Israel out of the land of_____.",
    "answer": "Egypt"
  },
  {
    "id": 2131,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:19",
    "question": "King Limhi said that God had caused that the children of Israel should walk through the _____ Sea on dry ground. ",
    "answer": "Red"
  },
  {
    "id": 2132,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:19",
    "question": "King Limhi wrote that God fed the Israelites_____ that they might not perish in the wilderness, and many more things did he do for them.",
    "answer": "Manna"
  },
  {
    "id": 2133,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:20",
    "question": "King Limhi said it is because of our iniquities and abominations that they were brought into bondage to the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2134,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:21",
    "question": "Who did King Limhi say was over-zealous to inherit the land of his fathers and was deceived by the cunning and craftiness of King Laman?",
    "answer": "Zeniff"
  },
  {
    "id": 2135,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:21 & Mos9:5-8",
    "question": "In the Book of Mosiah; what over-zealous king entered into a treaty with the king of the Lamanites?",
    "answer": "Zeniff"
  },
  {
    "id": 2136,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:22",
    "question": "King Limhi told Ammon that they pay one half of the amount of every thing that they possess to the king of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2137,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos7:24",
    "question": "King Limhi told the people that they had reason to mourn because many of their brethren had been slain, and their blood had been spilled in vain, and all because of_____.",
    "answer": "Iniquity",
    "options": ["Bad Judgments", "Iniquity", "Abominations"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2138,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:25",
    "question": "If the people of King Limhi had not fallen into transgression the_____ would not have suffered that they have or go though the afflictions which they had.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 2139,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:25",
    "question": "King Limhi said that the people would not hearken unto his words; but there arose contentions among them, even so much that they did shed_____ among themselves.",
    "answer": "Blood"
  },
  {
    "id": 2140,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:26",
    "question": "King Limhi said that a prophet of the Lord have they slain; a chosen man of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2141,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:26-28",
    "question": "What prophet of the Lord if first mentioned in the Book of Mosiah chapter #7 versus 26 through 28 but were are not given his name?",
    "answer": "Abinidi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2142,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:26 & Mos17:20",
    "question": "What prophet of the Lord is considered by many Book of Mormon scholars to be the first person martyred in the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "Abinidi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2143,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:26",
    "question": "What prophet of the Lord did King Limhi say was slain because he told them of their wickedness and abominations? ",
    "answer": "Abinidi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2144,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:26",
    "question": "Abinidi also prophesied of many things which are to come, yea, even of the coming of Christ.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2145,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:27",
    "question": "Abinidi testified that Christ was the God, the Father of all things, and said that he should take upon him the image of_____.",
    "answer": "Man"
  },
  {
    "id": 2146,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:27",
    "question": "Abinidi testified that man was created after the image of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2147,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:28",
    "question": "Abinidi said that God should come down among the children of men, and take upon him flesh and_____, and go forth upon the face of the earth.",
    "answer": "Blood"
  },
  {
    "id": 2148,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:28",
    "question": "Because Abinidi said many things, the priests of Noah put him to death and brought the wrath of God upon them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2149,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos7:31",
    "question": "The Lord has said: “If my people shall sow filthiness they shall reap the_____ wind, which brings immediate destruction”.",
    "answer": "East",
    "options": ["East", "West", "South"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2150,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:32",
    "question": "King Limhi said: “And now, behold, the promise of the Lord is fulfilled, and ye are smitten and afflicted”.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2151,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:33",
    "question": "King Limhi told his people to turn to the Lord with a full purpose of_____, and put their trust in him, and serve him with all diligence of mind.",
    "answer": "Heart"
  },
  {
    "id": 2152,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:33",
    "question": "If we turn to the Lord with a full purpose of heart, and put our trust in him, and serve him with all diligence of mind; he will, according to his own will and pleasure, deliver us out of any bondage we are in.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2153,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:1",
    "question": "All the things that King Limhi spoke to the Nephites are written in the Book of Mosiah.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2154,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:2",
    "question": "King Limhi caused that Ammon should stand up before the multitude, and rehearse unto them all that had happened unto their brethren from the time Zeniff went out of the land to the present time.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2155,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos8:3",
    "question": "Ammon rehearsed unto the people of King Limhi the last words that King_____ had taught them, so that they might understand all the words which he spoke.",
    "answer": "Benjamin"
  },
  {
    "id": 2156,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos8:5",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Limhi caused that the plates which contained the record of his people be brought before_____; that he might read them.",
    "answer": "Ammon"
  },
  {
    "id": 2157,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:6",
    "question": "As soon as Ammon had read the record, King Limhi inquired of him to know if he could interpret languages.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2158,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:6",
    "question": "Ammon was well versed in the art of interpreting languages so it was very easy for him to interpret the thing that King Limhi desired of him.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2159,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "-Mos8:7",
    "question": "King Limhi caused that forty-three of his people should take a journey into the wilderness, to look for the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2160,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos8:7",
    "question": "The reason King Limhi sent forty-three of his people to look for_____ was that they might appeal to their brethren to deliver them out of bondage.",
    "answer": "Zarahemla"
  },
  {
    "id": 2161,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:8",
    "question": "The forty-three people that King Limhi sent to find Zarahemla; were diligent but they were not able to find the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2162,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos8:8",
    "question": "King Limhi’s people traveled on a land among many waters, having discovered a land which was covered with the bones of_____, and of beasts.",
    "answer": "Men"
  },
  {
    "id": 2163,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:8",
    "question": "The land that King Limhi’s people traveled was covered with ruins of buildings of every kind.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2164,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos8:8",
    "question": "King Limhi’s people discovered a land which had been peopled with a people who were as numerous as the hosts’ of_____.",
    "answer": "Israel"
  },
  {
    "id": 2165,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos8:9",
    "question": "King Limhi’s people brought back_____ plates filled with engravings as a testimony of the things they have said were true.",
    "answer": "24 Or (25)",
    "options": ["23", "24 Or (25)"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2166,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos8:9",
    "question": "The twenty-four plates that the people of Kim Limhi brought back with them and were filled with engravings and were made out of pure_____.",
    "answer": "Gold",
    "options": ["Brass", "Silver", "Gold"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2167,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:10",
    "question": "The people of King Limhi also brought back with them breastplates which were large.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2168,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:10",
    "question": "The breastplates that the people of King Limhi brought back with them were large and made of brass and copper, and were perfectly sound.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2169,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos8:11",
    "question": "And again, they have brought_____, the hilts thereof have perished, and the blades thereof were cankered with rust.",
    "answer": "Swords"
  },
  {
    "id": 2170,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "11-12",
    "question": "King Limhi asked_____ if he was able to translate the twenty-four plates that his people had brought back and in if he knew of anyone that could.  Ammon-",
    "answer": "Mos8:"
  },
  {
    "id": 2171,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:12",
    "question": "King Limhi desired that the records be translated because they might give him knowledge of a remnant of the people who have been destroyed and from whence the records came.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2172,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:13",
    "question": "Ammon told King Limhi that he could translate the twenty-four plates because he had been given the gift of translating by God.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2173,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos8:13",
    "question": "Ammon told King Limhi that he could not translate the records but that he knew of a man that could translate all records that are of ancient date; and it is a_____ of God.",
    "answer": "Gift",
    "options": ["Record", "Thing", "Gift"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2174,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:13",
    "question": "Ammon told King Limhi that the man possessed things which were called interpreters that enable him to translate.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2175,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:13",
    "question": "Ammon told King Limhi that no man can look in the interpreters except he be commanded by God, lest he should look for that he ought not and he should perish.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2176,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos8:13",
    "question": "Ammon told King Limhi that whosoever is commanded to look in them, the same is called a_____. ",
    "answer": "Seer"
  },
  {
    "id": 2177,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos8:13 & Mos21:28",
    "question": "The man that was able to look at the interpreters and not perish lived in the land of Zarahemla and was also their king; what was his name?",
    "answer": "Mosiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 2178,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:14",
    "question": "Ammon told King Limhi that King Mosiah2 had been given this high gift from God to be able to translate records of ancient date",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2179,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:15",
    "question": "King Limhi asked Ammon if a seer is greater than a prophet.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2180,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos8:16",
    "question": "Ammon told King Limhi that a seer is a_____ and a prophet also.",
    "answer": "Revelator"
  },
  {
    "id": 2181,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:16",
    "question": "Ammon told King Limhi that no man can have a greater gift given to him, except he should possess the power of God, which no man can.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2182,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos8:16",
    "question": "Ammon told King Limhi that a man can have great_____ given to him from God.",
    "answer": "Power",
    "options": ["Power", "Knowledge", "Wisdom"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2183,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos8:17",
    "question": "Ammon said that a seer can know of things which are past, and also of things which are to____, and by them shall all things be revealed.",
    "answer": "Come"
  },
  {
    "id": 2184,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:17",
    "question": "Ammon told King Limhi that though and by a seer shall secret things be made manifest.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2185,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:17",
    "question": "Ammon said through a seer hidden things shall come to light, and things which are not known shall be made known by him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2186,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos8:18",
    "question": "Ammon said that God has provided a means that man, through_____, might work mighty miracles.",
    "answer": "Faith",
    "options": ["The Atonement", "Faith", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2187,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:18",
    "question": "God has provided a means that man, through faith might work mighty miracles, therefore becoming a great benefit to his fellow beings.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2188,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:19",
    "question": "When Ammon was done speaking to King Limhi about what a seer and the interpreters can do for man, the king did not rejoice exceedingly.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2189,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos8:19",
    "question": "King Limhi told Ammon that it is doubtless a great mystery is contained within these plates; and those interpreters were doubtless prepared for the purpose of unfolding all such_____ to the children of men.",
    "answer": "Mysteries"
  },
  {
    "id": 2190,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos8:20",
    "question": "“O how_____ are the works of the Lord, and how long does he suffer with his people”.",
    "answer": "Marvelous",
    "options": ["Marvelous", "Great", "Unimaginable"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2191,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos8:20",
    "question": "How blind and impenetrable are the understandings of the children of men; for they will not seek wisdom, neither do they desire that_____ shall rule over them.",
    "answer": "She",
    "options": ["She", "He", "It"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2192,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:21",
    "question": "King Limhi said that the children of men are as a wild flock which flee from the shepherd, and scattered, and are driven, and are devoured by the beasts of the forest.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2193,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9-22 & Mos7:21",
    "question": "In the Book of Mosiah, chapters 9 though 22 inclusively give the record of King Zeniff.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2194,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos9 Heading",
    "question": "The record of King Zeniff gives an account of his people, from the time they left the land of_____ until the time that they were delivered out of the hands of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Zarahemla"
  },
  {
    "id": 2195,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:1",
    "question": "Zeniff was not taught in all of the language of the Nephites, but only in some parts.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2196,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos9:1",
    "question": "Zeniff was taught in all the language of the_____ and had a knowledge of the land of Nephi or of the land of his fathers first inheritance.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 2197,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos9:1",
    "question": "Zeniff was sent as_____ among the Lamanites that he might spy out their forces, that their army might come upon them and destroy them.",
    "answer": "Spy"
  },
  {
    "id": 2198,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:1",
    "question": "When Zeniff saw that which was good among them (Lamanites) I was desirous that they should not be destroyed.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2199,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos9:2",
    "question": "Zeniff contended with his brethren that their ruler would make a treaty with the_____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 2200,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos9:2",
    "question": "Zeniff said that the ruler of their army was an austere and a blood_____ man and commanded that Zeniff be slain.",
    "answer": "Thirsty"
  },
  {
    "id": 2201,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:2",
    "question": "Zeniff said that he was rescued by the shedding of much blood; for father fought against father, and brother against brother, until the greater of their army was destroyed in the wilderness.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2202,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos9:3",
    "question": "Zeniff and his brethren were smitten with famine and sore afflictions because they “were slow to remember the Lord their _____”.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 2203,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:5",
    "question": "Zeniff took four of his men into the city, in unto the king that he may know of the disposition of the king.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2204,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:6",
    "question": "The king of the Lamanites coveted with Zeniff that he might possess the land of Lehi-Nephi, and the land of Shilom.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2205,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos9:10",
    "question": "The name of the king that coveted with Zeniff that he could possess the land of Lehi-Nephi is King_____.",
    "answer": "LamanI"
  },
  {
    "id": 2206,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:7",
    "question": "King Laman1 did not command the people to leave the land of Lehi-Nephi so that Zeniff and his people could possess it.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2207,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:8",
    "question": "Zeniff and his people began to build buildings, and to repair the walls of the city of Lehi-Nephi and of the city of Shilom.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2208,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos9:9",
    "question": "Zeniff and his people began to till the ground, yea, even will all manner of_____, with seeds of corn, wheat, barley, and with seeds of all manner of fruit.",
    "answer": "Seeds",
    "options": ["Seeds", "Tools", "Machinery"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2209,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:9",
    "question": "Zeniff and his people did not begin to multiply and to prosper in the land because of their slow remembrance of the Lord.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2210,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos9:10",
    "question": "It was the cunning and the craftiness of King_____; that brought Zeniff and his people into bondage, that he yielded up the land that they might possess it.",
    "answer": "LamanI"
  },
  {
    "id": 2211,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos9:11",
    "question": "Zeniff and his people dwelt in the land for_____ years; before King Laman1 began to grow uneasy.",
    "answer": "12",
    "options": ["3", "6", "12"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2212,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:11",
    "question": "King Laman began to grow uneasy about Zeniff and his people because he feared that they would wax strong in the land, and he could not overpower them and bring them into bondage.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2213,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos9:12",
    "question": "Zeniff wrote that the Lamanites were a lazy and_____ people, and were desirous to bring them into bondage.",
    "answer": "Idolatrous",
    "options": ["Dark", "Idolatrous", "Idle"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2214,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:12",
    "question": "Zeniff wrote the Lamanites did not want to glut themselves with the labors of the hands of his people.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2215,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:12",
    "question": "Zeniff said the Lamanites wanted to feast themselves upon the flocks of their fields.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2216,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos9:13",
    "question": "Therefore it came to pass that King Laman1 began to stir up his people that they would contend with_____ and his people.",
    "answer": "Zeniff"
  },
  {
    "id": 2217,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:13,14",
    "question": "In the thirteenth year of the reign of King Zeniff there began to be wars and contentions in the land.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2218,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos9:14",
    "question": "The Lamanites began to slay the people of Zeniff and to take off with their flocks, and the_____ of the fields.",
    "answer": "Corn",
    "options": ["Corn", "Rice", "Potatoes"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2219,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:16",
    "question": "King Zeniff began to arm his people with bows and arrows, with swords, and with cimeters.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2220,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos9:16",
    "question": "King Zeniff’s people had clubs, slings, and all manner of weapons of_____ they could invent to fight against the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "War"
  },
  {
    "id": 2221,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos9:17",
    "question": "Zeniff and his people had the strength of the_____ when they went to battle against the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 2222,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:17",
    "question": "Zeniff and his people used their own bodily strength to fight the armies of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2223,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:17",
    "question": "King Zeniff and his people did cry mightily unto the Lord that he would deliver them out of the hands of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2224,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos9:17",
    "question": "Because King Zeniff and his people had cried mightily unto the Lord, they were awakened of the deliverance of their_____.",
    "answer": "Fathers",
    "options": ["Daughters", "Brothers", "Fathers"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2225,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:18",
    "question": "The Lord did not hear the cries of Zeniff and his people therefore he did not deliver them out of the hands of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2226,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos9:18",
    "question": "King Zeniff’s people went with the might of the Lord against the_____, and did drive them out of their lands.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 2227,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:18",
    "question": "In one day and a night the people of King Zeniff did slay three thousand and forty-three Lamanites.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2228,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos9:19",
    "question": "King Zeniff, himself, with his own _____ did bury the dead.",
    "answer": "Hands",
    "options": ["Shovel", "Hands", "Arms"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2229,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:1",
    "question": "King Zeniff and his people began to establish the kingdom and did establish peace throughout the land and also to possession of it again.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2230,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Zeniff had his people made all kinds of weapons of war in case the Lamanites might come up to war with his people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2231,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:2",
    "question": "King Zeniff caused that guards be place round about throughout the land so they would be aware if the Lamanites should come upon them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2232,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:5",
    "question": "King Zeniff caused that the Nephite woman should spin, and toil, and to work all manner of fine_____.",
    "answer": "Linen"
  },
  {
    "id": 2233,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos10:5",
    "question": "King Zeniff caused that the women of his people work all manner of cloth so they might clothe their_____.",
    "answer": "Nakedness",
    "options": ["Bodies", "Nakedness", "Tents"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2234,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:6-Mos24:3",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Laman1 died, and his_____ began to reign in his stead.",
    "answer": "Son"
  },
  {
    "id": 2235,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:6-Mos24:3",
    "question": "What is the name of the king who succeeded King Lamam I?",
    "answer": "Laman"
  },
  {
    "id": 2236,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:6",
    "question": "King Laman2 began to stir his people up in rebellion against the people of King Zeniff.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2237,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos10:7",
    "question": "King Zeniff sent_____ out round about the land of Shemlon, that he might discover the plans and preparations of King Laman2 and his people.",
    "answer": "Spies",
    "options": ["Spies", "People", "Teancum"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2238,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:8",
    "question": "King Laman2’s men were armed with bows and arrows, and with swords, and with cimeters, and with stones, and with _____. ",
    "answer": "Slings"
  },
  {
    "id": 2239,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos10:8",
    "question": "King Zeniff wrote that the Lamanites that came up against them to war had their_____ shaven.",
    "answer": "Legs",
    "options": ["Legs", "Chests"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2240,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:8",
    "question": "King Zeniff said that the Lamanites were naked; and they were girded with a leather girdle about their loins.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2241,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:9",
    "question": "And it came to pass the King Zeniff caused that the women and children of his people should hide in the_____.",
    "answer": "Wilderness"
  },
  {
    "id": 2242,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:9",
    "question": "King Zeniff also had his old men and also all the young men that were able to bear arms, that they should gather themselves together to do battle with the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2243,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:9",
    "question": "King Zeniff did not have all the old men and the young men that could bear arms gather together in their ranks, every man according to his age.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2244,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:10",
    "question": "In the Book of Mosiah; King Zeniff writes that when King Laman2 and his numerous hosts came to do battle with him and his people, he was only 30 years old.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2245,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:10",
    "question": "King Laman himself, even in his old age, did go up to battle against the Lamanites in the strength of the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2246,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:11",
    "question": "King Zeniff said that the Lamanites knew nothing concerning the_____, nor the strength of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 2247,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:11",
    "question": "King Zeniff wrote that the Lamanites were a strong people, as to the strength of_____.",
    "answer": "Men"
  },
  {
    "id": 2248,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:12",
    "question": "The Lamanites were a_____, and ferocious, and a blood-thirsty people, believing in the traditions of their fathers.",
    "answer": "Wild"
  },
  {
    "id": 2249,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:12",
    "question": "The Lamanites believed in the traditions of their fathers; which is this-believing that they were driven out of the land of Jerusalem because of the iniquities of their fathers",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2250,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos10:12",
    "question": "The Lamanites believed they were _____ in the wilderness by their brethren.",
    "answer": "Wronged",
    "options": ["Wronged", "Taken Advantage", "Left To Wonder"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2251,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:12",
    "question": "The Lamanites also believed they were wronged while crossing the sea; to get to the Promised Land.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2252,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:13",
    "question": "The Lamanites believed they were wronged by their brethren while in the land of their_____ inheritance, after they had crossed the sea.",
    "answer": "First"
  },
  {
    "id": 2253,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:13",
    "question": "Zeniff wrote that Nephi was more faithful in keeping the commandments of the Lord; therefore he was favored of the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2254,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:13",
    "question": "Zeniff wrote that the Lord heard _____ prayers and answered them.",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2255,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:13",
    "question": "Who did Zeniff say, took the lead of Lehi’s party in their journey in the wilderness?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2256,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:14",
    "question": "Laman and _____ were wroth with Nephi because they did not understand the dealings of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Lemuel"
  },
  {
    "id": 2257,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos10:14",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel were also wroth with Nephi upon the waters because they hardened their_____ against the Lord.",
    "answer": "Hearts",
    "options": ["Head", "Hearts", "Minds"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2258,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:15",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel were wroth with Nephi: because after they had arrived in the promise land; he had taken the ruling of the people out of their hands, and they sought to kill him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2259,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:16",
    "question": "Nephi’s older brothers were wroth with him because he had departed into the wilderness as the Lord had commanded him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2260,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:16",
    "question": "Nephi’s older brothers were wroth with him because he took the records which were engraven on the_____ of brass, for they said that he had robbed them.",
    "answer": "Plates"
  },
  {
    "id": 2261,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos10:17",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel had taught their children that they should hate the people of Nephi, and should_____ them.",
    "answer": "Murder",
    "options": ["Scalp", "Behead", "Murder"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2262,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:17",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel had also taught their children that they should hate the Nephites, and they should murder, and they should plunder them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2263,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:17",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel did not teach their children that they should plunder the Nephites.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2264,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:17",
    "question": "The Lamanites were taught to do all they could to destroy the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2265,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos10:17",
    "question": "Because of the things that Laman and Lemuel taught the Nephites; their children have an_____ hatred toward the children of Nephi.",
    "answer": "Eternal",
    "options": ["Everlasting", "Eternal", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2266,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:18",
    "question": "King Zeniff said that King Laman1 had deceived him by his cunning and lying craftiness, and his fair promises.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2267,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:19",
    "question": "After King Zeniff told his people about why the Lamanites hated the Nephites and other things, he stimulated his people to go to battle with all their might against the_____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 2268,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:19",
    "question": "King Zeniff and his people put their trust in the_____; therefore, they did contend with the Lamanites face to face.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 2269,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:20",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Zeniff and his people slaughtered so many of the Lamanites that they did not number them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2270,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:22",
    "question": "When King Zeniff began to be old, he did confer the Kingdom upon one of his daughters.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2271,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:1",
    "question": "King Zeniff conferred the kingdom to one of his sons; and his name was_____.",
    "answer": "Noah"
  },
  {
    "id": 2272,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "-Mos11:1",
    "question": "Noah began to reign in the stead of his father; and he did not walk in the ways of his father.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2273,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:2",
    "question": "For Behold, Noah did not keep the commandments of God, but he did walk after the desires of his_____.",
    "answer": "Heart",
    "options": ["Mistress", "Heart", "Eyes"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2274,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:2",
    "question": "King Noah had many wives and_____.",
    "answer": "Concubines"
  },
  {
    "id": 2275,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:2",
    "question": "King Noah caused his people to commit_____, and do that which was abominable in the sight of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Sin"
  },
  {
    "id": 2276,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:2",
    "question": "King Noah’s people committed whoredoms and all manner of wickedness.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2277,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:3",
    "question": "King Noah laid a tax of one fifth part of all the Nephites possessed, such as; gold, silver, copper, and brass.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2278,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:3",
    "question": "King Noah did not tax the people of one fifth part of all the iron, fatlings, and grain they possessed because he did not feel that it was worth it.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2279,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:4",
    "question": "The purpose that King Noah taxed the Nephites was so that he could support his_____ and concubines.",
    "answer": "Wives"
  },
  {
    "id": 2280,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:4",
    "question": "King Noah had to also support his priests, and their wives and concubines.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2281,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:4",
    "question": "King Noah changed the affairs of the kingdom by doing all the wicked things that he did.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2282,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:5",
    "question": "King Noah put down all the_____ that had been consecrated by his father, and consecrated new ones in their stead.",
    "answer": "Priests"
  },
  {
    "id": 2283,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:5",
    "question": "King Noah consecrated priests that were lifted up in the pride of their hearts.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2284,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:6",
    "question": "King Noah and his priests were supported in their_____.",
    "answer": "Laziness",
    "options": ["Laziness", "Welfare", "Workings"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2285,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:6",
    "question": "King Noah and his priests were also supported by the people in their idolatry and their whoredoms.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2286,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:6",
    "question": "King Noah and his priests were supported by the taxes he put on the people and the people did labor exceedingly to support_____.",
    "answer": "Iniquity",
    "options": ["Whoredoms", "Laziness", "Iniquity"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2287,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:7",
    "question": "The Nephites became an idolatrous people, because they were deceived by the vain and flattering words of the king and his priests.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2288,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:7",
    "question": "King Noah and his priests spoke flattering things to the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2289,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:8",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Noah built many elegant and spacious_____.",
    "answer": "Buildings",
    "options": ["Warehouses", "Houses", "Buildings"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2290,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:8",
    "question": "King Noah built many elegant and spacious building and ornamented them with fine work of wood.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2291,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:8",
    "question": "The buildings that King Noah built were made of precious things, of _____, and of silver, and of brass. ",
    "answer": "Gold"
  },
  {
    "id": 2292,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:8",
    "question": "King Noah built elegant buildings that were also made of iron, and of copper, and_____.",
    "answer": "Ziff",
    "options": ["Titanium", "Platinum", "Ziff"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2293,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:8",
    "question": "In the Book of Mormon we are told that Ziff is a type of metal.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2294,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:3,8",
    "question": "In the Book of Mormon we are never told what Ziff is or if it is a type of metal.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2295,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:9",
    "question": "King Noah built him a spacious _____, and a throne in the midst thereof, all which was of fine wood.",
    "answer": "Palace",
    "options": ["Palace", "Building", "House"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2296,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:9",
    "question": "The palace that King Noah built with a throne was ornamented with gold and silver and_____ things.",
    "answer": "Precious"
  },
  {
    "id": 2297,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:10",
    "question": "King Noah caused that his workmen should work all manner of fine work within the walls of the_____.",
    "answer": "Temple",
    "options": ["Temple", "House", "Building"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2298,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:10",
    "question": "King Noah’s temple walls were made of fine wood, and of copper, and of brass.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2299,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:11",
    "question": "The seats of the priests of King Noah were set above all other seats and were ornamented with pure_____.",
    "answer": "Gold"
  },
  {
    "id": 2300,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:11",
    "question": "King Noah caused that the seats of the priests be built with a breastwork before them, that they might rest their bodies and their _____.",
    "answer": "Arms",
    "options": ["Legs", "Arms", "Heads"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2301,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:11",
    "question": "King Noah caused a breastwork to be built before them, that they may rest their bodies and arms upon while they should speak lying and vain words to his people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2302,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:12",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Noah built a_____ near the temple; yea, a very high tower.",
    "answer": "Tower"
  },
  {
    "id": 2303,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:12",
    "question": "King Noah built a very high tower so he could stand upon the top thereof and overlook the land of Shilom, and also the land of Shemlon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2304,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "12-13",
    "question": "The land that King Noah possessed and caused that a very high tower be built was called_____.  Shilom-",
    "answer": "Mos11:"
  },
  {
    "id": 2305,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:12",
    "question": "The land of Shemlon was possessed by the_____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 2306,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:13",
    "question": "King Noah caused that a great tower be built on the hill north of the land of Shilom.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2307,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "12,13",
    "question": "What was the name of the land that had been a resort for the Nephites when they were told by the Lord to flee into the wilderness?",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["Shilom", "Shemlon", "Nephi"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2308,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:14",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Noah placed his_____ upon his riches.",
    "answer": "Heart"
  },
  {
    "id": 2309,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:14",
    "question": "King Noah spent his time in riotous living with his wives and_____.",
    "answer": "Concubines"
  },
  {
    "id": 2310,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:14",
    "question": "King Noah and his priests did not spend their time in riotous living and with harlots.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2311,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:15",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Noah planted vineyards about the land, and wine-presses.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2312,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:15",
    "question": "King Noah did not built wine-presses for the making of wine but for the making of jams.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2313,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:15",
    "question": "King Noah became a_____ and also his people, because he built an abundance of wine-presses.",
    "answer": "Wine"
  },
  {
    "id": 2314,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:15",
    "question": "The term or word wine-bibber is only used one time in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2315,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:15",
    "question": "The term or word wine-bibber is only mentioned one time in the Book of Mormon and it is used to describe King_____ and his people.",
    "answer": "Noah"
  },
  {
    "id": 2316,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:15",
    "question": "In what Book of Mormon book can we find the word wine-bibber used?",
    "answer": "Mosiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 2317,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:16",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites began to come upon the people of King Noah.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2318,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:16",
    "question": "The_____ began to slay the people of King Noah in their fields while they were tending their flocks.",
    "answer": "Lamanites- "
  },
  {
    "id": 2319,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:18",
    "question": "The Lamanites began to kill the Nephites and drove many of their flocks out of their land; and to exercise their hatred toward them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2320,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:18",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Noah sent his armies against the Lamanites and they were driven back, therefore the Nephites returned rejoicing in their spoil.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2321,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:19",
    "question": "Because of the great victory against the Lamanites, the Nephites were lifted up in the_____ of their hearts.",
    "answer": "Pride"
  },
  {
    "id": 2322,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:19",
    "question": "The Nephites began to boast in their own strength, saying that their fifty could stand against _____ of Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Thousands",
    "options": ["Hundreds", "Thousands", "Millions"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2323,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:19",
    "question": "The Nephites did boast, and they did delight in blood, and the shedding of the_____ of their brethren.",
    "answer": "Blood"
  },
  {
    "id": 2324,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:19",
    "question": "Because of the wickedness of King Noah and his priests, the Nephites delighted in the shedding of the blood of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2325,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:20",
    "question": "And it came to pass that there was one among the people of King Noah whose name was_____; and he went forth among them, and began to prophesy.",
    "answer": "Abinidi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2326,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:20",
    "question": "The man that was among the people of King Noah that begin to prophesy was not named Abinidi.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2327,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:20",
    "question": "Abinidi was commanded by the_____ to prophesy to the people of King Noah.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 2328,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:20",
    "question": "The Lord told Abinidi to tell the people of King Noah that he had seen their abominations.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2329,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:20",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people that the Lord had seen their_____ and their whoredoms.",
    "answer": "Wickedness"
  },
  {
    "id": 2330,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:20",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people that if they did not repent the Lord would visit them in his_____.",
    "answer": "Anger",
    "options": ["Temple", "House", "Anger"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2331,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:21",
    "question": "The Lord told Abinidi to tell the people that unless they repented he would deliver them unto the hands of their enemies.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2332,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:21",
    "question": "_____ told the people that if they did not repent, they shall be brought into bondage.",
    "answer": "Abinidi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2333,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:21",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people of King Noah that unless they repented they shall be afflicted by the hand of their_____.",
    "answer": "Enemies",
    "options": ["Enemies", "Sisters", "Fathers"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2334,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:22",
    "question": "And it shall come to pass that they shall know that I am the Lord their _____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 2335,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11-22",
    "question": "God told Abinidi to tell the people that he was not a jealous God.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2336,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:22",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people that God is a jealous God and would visit the iniquities of his people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2337,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:23",
    "question": "And it shall come to pass that except this people repent and turn unto the Lord their _____, they shall be brought into bondage.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 2338,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:23",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people that they needed to repent and turn unto their God, and if they didn’t; none would deliver them out of bondage except him the Almighty God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2339,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:24",
    "question": "And it shall come to pass that when they shall cry unto me I will be slow to hear their_____.",
    "answer": "Cries"
  },
  {
    "id": 2340,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:24",
    "question": "The Lord told Abinidi to tell the people that he would suffer them to be_____ by their enemies.",
    "answer": "Smitten",
    "options": ["Smitten", "Beaten", "Whipped"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2341,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:25",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people that they needed to repent in sackcloth and ashes, and cry_____ to the Lord their God.",
    "answer": "Mightily"
  },
  {
    "id": 2342,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:25",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people that if they did not repent in sackcloth and ashes, and cry mightily unto the Lord, he would not hear their prayers.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2343,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:25",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people that he was commanded by the_____ to tell the people that he would not deliver them out of their afflictions and other things if they did not repent.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 2344,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:26",
    "question": "After Abinidi told the Nephites of the things the Lord had commanded him to say they and were wroth with him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2345,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:26",
    "question": "Because the people were wroth with Abinidi, they sought to take away his_____.",
    "answer": "Life"
  },
  {
    "id": 2346,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:26",
    "question": "The Lord delivered Abinidi, out of the hands of the people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2347,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:27",
    "question": "When King_____ had heard of the words which Abinidi had spoken unto the people, he was also wroth.",
    "answer": "Noah"
  },
  {
    "id": 2348,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:27",
    "question": "King Noah said: “Who is_____, that I and my people should be judged of him”? ",
    "answer": "Abinidi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2349,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:27",
    "question": "King Noah also said: “Who is the Lord; that shall bring upon my people such great afflictions”",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2350,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:28",
    "question": "King Noah commanded the_____ to bring Abinidi to him so that he could slay him.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["Zoramites", "Lamanites", "Nephites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2351,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:28",
    "question": "King Noah said that Abinidi had said things to the Nephites to stir up his people to anger one with the other.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2352,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:28",
    "question": "King Noah said that Abinidi had said things to raise contentions among his people; therefore I will_____ him.",
    "answer": "Slay",
    "options": ["Fry", "Slay", "Hang"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2353,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:29",
    "question": "The eyes of the people were not blinded, therefore they did not hardened their hearts against the words of Abinidi.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2354,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:29",
    "question": "King Noah hardened his_____ against the word of the Lord, and he did not repent of his evil doings.",
    "answer": "Heart"
  },
  {
    "id": 2355,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:29",
    "question": "King Noah did not harden his heart against the words of Abinidi and the Lord; therefore he did repent of his wickedness.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2356,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos12:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that after the space of two years that Abinidi came among the people in_____.",
    "answer": "Disguise",
    "options": ["A Costume", "Disguise", "Raggedy Clothes"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2357,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:1",
    "question": "Abinidi came in a disguise among the people and began to prophesy among them and they did not recognize him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2358,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:1",
    "question": "The Lord told _____ to prophesy to the people again because they had hardened their hearts against his words.",
    "answer": "Abinidi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2359,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:1",
    "question": "The Lord told Abinidi to prophesy to the Nephites that if they did not repent of their evil doings; he would visit them in his anger.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2360,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:1",
    "question": "The Lord told Abinidi to prophesy to the people that he would not visit them in his fierce anger, and in their iniquities and abominations.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2361,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos12:2",
    "question": "The Lord told Abinidi to stretch forth his_____ and prophesy to the Nephites: thus saith the Lord, it shall come to pass that this generation, because of their iniquities shall be brought into bondage.",
    "answer": "Hand",
    "options": ["Hand", "Arm", "Body"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2362,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:2",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people that they shall be smitten on the cheek; yea, and shall be driven by men.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2363,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos12:2",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people that they would be slain; and the_____ of the air, and the dogs, and the wild beast, shall devour their flesh.",
    "answer": "Vultures",
    "options": ["Eagles", "Hawks", "Vultures"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2364,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:2",
    "question": "What kind of birds of prey did Abinidi tell the Nephites would devour their flesh if they did not repent? ",
    "answer": "Vultures"
  },
  {
    "id": 2365,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:3",
    "question": "And it shall come to pass that the life of King Noah shall be valued even as a garment in a_____ furnace.",
    "answer": "Hot"
  },
  {
    "id": 2366,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:3",
    "question": "Abinidi prophesied that the life of King Noah shall be valued even as a garment in a hot furnace and that he would know the Lord is God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2367,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:4",
    "question": "And if shall come to pass that the Lord will smite the people with famine and_____.",
    "answer": "Pestilence"
  },
  {
    "id": 2368,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:4",
    "question": "Because of the famine and pestilence brought upon by the Lord; the people will howl all day long.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2369,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos12:5",
    "question": "The Lord will cause that the people of King Noah have burdens lashed upon their_____; and they shall be driven like a dumb ass.",
    "answer": "Backs",
    "options": ["Shoulders", "Backs", "Chests"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2370,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:6",
    "question": "And it shall come to pass that the Lord will send forth hail among the Nephites and it shall smite them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2371,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos12:6",
    "question": "What kind of direction of the wind that the Lord say he would send to the people of King Noah?",
    "answer": "East",
    "options": ["East", "West", "North"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2372,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:6",
    "question": "The Lord said that the Nephites will be smitten with the east wind; and insects will pester their land and devour their grain.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2373,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos12:7",
    "question": "The Nephites will be smitten with a great pestilence-and this the Lord would do because of their_____ and abominations.",
    "answer": "Iniquities",
    "options": ["Iniquities", "Laziness", "Wickedness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2374,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:8",
    "question": "The Lord said that if the Nephites did not repent he would utterly destroy them from the_____ of the earth.",
    "answer": "Face"
  },
  {
    "id": 2375,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:8",
    "question": "Abinidi testified that King Noah and his people would leave a record behind and that the Lord would preserve it.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2376,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:8",
    "question": "The record that King Noah and his people would leave behind shall be possessed by other nations which shall possess the land.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2377,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:8",
    "question": "The purpose that the Lord wanted to preserve the record is so that he could discover the abominations of King Noah’s people to other nations which shall possess the land.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2378,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:8",
    "question": "King Zeniff wrote all of the prophesies that Abinidi said to the people of King Noah and they are written in the Book of Mosiah chapter #12.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2379,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:9",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people were angry with Abinidi and carried and bound him before King_____.",
    "answer": "Noah"
  },
  {
    "id": 2380,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:9",
    "question": "The people told King Noah that Abinidi prophesied evil concerning his people, and said that God would destroy them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2381,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos12:10",
    "question": "The Nephites told King Noah that Abinidi had prophesied evil concerning his life and said that it would be as valued as a garment in a_____ of fire.",
    "answer": "Furnace",
    "options": ["Pit", "Blaze", "Furnace"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2382,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:11",
    "question": "The people told King Noah that Abinidi had also prophesied that his life would be as a stalk, even as a dry stalk of the field, which is run over by the beasts and trodden under foot.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2383,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:12",
    "question": "The Nephites said that Abinidi had said that King Noah shall be as the blossoms of a thistle, which, when it is fully ripened and the wind blows, it is driven forth upon the face of the land.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2384,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:12",
    "question": "The people of King Noah said that Abinidi had prophesied all things unto them and said that he pretended that the Lord had spoken it.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2385,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:12",
    "question": "The Nephites told King Noah that_____ said that unless he repented; bad things would come upon the people and King Noah because of their iniquities.",
    "answer": "Abinidi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2386,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:13",
    "question": "The people asked King Noah:  “O king, what great evil have you done, or what great sins have we committed, that we should be condemned of God or judged of this_____”?",
    "answer": "Man"
  },
  {
    "id": 2387,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:14",
    "question": "The people told King Noah that he was guiltless, and had not sinned; therefore, this man has lied concerning him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2388,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:14",
    "question": "The people told King Noah that because he had not sinned, _____ had prophesied in vain.",
    "answer": "Abinidi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2389,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:15",
    "question": "And behold, we are strong, we shall not come into_____, or be taken captive by our enemies.",
    "answer": "Bondage"
  },
  {
    "id": 2390,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:16",
    "question": "The people delivered Abinidi into the hands of King Noah and told him to do with him as he seemed fit.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2391,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos12:17",
    "question": "And if came to pass that King Noah caused that Abinidi should be cast into_____.",
    "answer": "Prison",
    "options": ["A Dungeon", "A Pit", "Prison"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2392,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:17",
    "question": "King Noah commanded that his_____ gather together that he might hold a counsel with them concerning what they should do with Abinidi.",
    "answer": "Priests"
  },
  {
    "id": 2393,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:18",
    "question": "And it came to pass that they said unto King Noah: Bring him to us that we may question him; and the king_____ that he should be brought before them.",
    "answer": "Commanded"
  },
  {
    "id": 2394,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:19",
    "question": "The priests of King Noah began to question Abinidi that they might cross him that thereby they might have wherewith to accuse him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2395,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:19",
    "question": "Abinidi answered the questions of King Noah’s priests boldly, and withstood all their questions.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2396,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:12",
    "question": "To the astonishment of the priests of King Noah, Abinidi did withstand them in all their questions and confounded them in all their_____.",
    "answer": "Words"
  },
  {
    "id": 2397,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:20",
    "question": "And it came to pass that one of the priest of King Noah asked Abinidi to interpret some words that were written by their fathers and what was the meaning of them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2398,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:24",
    "question": "Some of the words that the priests of King Noah said were these: The Lord has made bare his_____ arm in the eyes of all the nations, and all the ends of the earth shall see the salvation of God.",
    "answer": "Holy"
  },
  {
    "id": 2399,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:25",
    "question": "Abinidi replied to them by saying unto them:”Are you priests pretend to teach this people, and to understand the spirit of prophesying, and yet desire to knowords of me monwhat these things mean”?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2400,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:26",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests of King Noah:  Woe, be unto you for perverting the ways of the Lord! For if ye understand these things ye have not taught them; therefore, ye have perverted the ways of the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2401,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos12:27",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests that they had not applied their hearts to understanding; therefore, they had not been_____.",
    "answer": "Wise",
    "options": ["Wise", "Enlightened", "Useful"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2402,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:27",
    "question": "Abinidi asked the priests of King Noah: “What do you teach the people”?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2403,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:28",
    "question": "The priest of King Noah told Abinidi that they taught the people the Law of_____.",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },
  {
    "id": 2404,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:29",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests of King Noah if they taught the Lawords of Mosmones; why do you not keep it?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2405,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:29",
    "question": "Abinidi asked the priests of King Noah: Why they set their_____ upon riches? ",
    "answer": "Hearts"
  },
  {
    "id": 2406,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:29",
    "question": "Abinidi asked the priests of King Noah why they commit whoredoms and spend their strength with harlots?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2407,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:30",
    "question": "Abinidi knew that the priests of King Noah knew that the things he had spoken to them were true.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2408,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:31",
    "question": "And it shall come to pass that you will be_____ for your iniquities, for you have said that you teach the Lawords of Mosmones.",
    "answer": "Smitten"
  },
  {
    "id": 2409,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:31-32",
    "question": "Abinidi asked the priests of King Noah:  Does salvation come by the Lawords of Mosmones?  And they answered and said that salvation did come by the Law of_____.",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },
  {
    "id": 2410,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:33",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests of King Noah that he knew if they kept the commandments of God they would be saved.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2411,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:33",
    "question": "On what mountain did Abinidi say that the Lord delivered the commandments unto Moses?",
    "answer": "Sinai"
  },
  {
    "id": 2412,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:35-36",
    "question": "Abinidi recited part of the Ten Commandments to the priests of King Noah.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2413,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:37",
    "question": "According to Abinidi, King Noah and his people kept the Lawords of Mosmones.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2414,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:33-37",
    "question": "Abinidi was inspired to say the things he did because of the words of the five books of Moses.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2415,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:33-37",
    "question": "Abinidi testified to King Noah and his priests that there are actually six books of Moses and that the sixth book is lost unto the children of men.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2416,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:2",
    "question": "King Noah’s priests stood forward and attempted to lay their hands on Abinidi; but he withstood them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2417,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos13:3",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests of King Noah that if they were to touch him and lay their hands upon him, the_____ would smite them.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 2418,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos13:4",
    "question": "The priests of King Noah could not do a thing to Abinidi because he had not finished delivering the_____ that the Lord wanted him to deliver.",
    "answer": "Message",
    "options": ["Package", "Handbag", "Message"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2419,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:4",
    "question": "Because Abinidi told and spoke the things the Lord had commanded him to say and had told them the truth; the priests of King Noah were angry with him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2420,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos13:4",
    "question": "Because Abinidi spoke the word of God, the priests judged him to be _____.",
    "answer": "Mad",
    "options": ["Terrible", "Mad", "Crazy"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2421,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos13:5",
    "question": "The people of King Noah did not dare to lay their hands upon Abinidi because the_____ of the Lord which was upon him.",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },
  {
    "id": 2422,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos13:5",
    "question": "The face of Abinidi shone with exceeding luster, even as_____, did while in the mount of Sinai, while speaking with the Lord.",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },
  {
    "id": 2423,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:33&13:5",
    "question": "Mount Sinai is spoken of only in the Book of Mosiah.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2424,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos13:6",
    "question": "Abinidi spoke with the power and_____ from God.",
    "answer": "Authority",
    "options": ["Finesse", "Likeness", "Authority"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2425,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:7",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people that they had no power to slay him; therefore, he would finish his message.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2426,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos13:7",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people of King Noah that he perceived that his message cuts them to their_____, because he told them the truth concerning their iniquities.",
    "answer": "Hearts"
  },
  {
    "id": 2427,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:8",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people that his words did not fill them with wonder and amazement, and with anger.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2428,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:9",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people of King Noah that it did not matter where he went after he finished his message, if it so be that he would he saved.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2429,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos13:10",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people: “What you do with me, after this, shall be as a type and a_____ of the things which are to come”.",
    "answer": "Shadow"
  },
  {
    "id": 2430,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos13:11",
    "question": "Abinidi perceived that the commandments of_____ were not written in their hearts.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["Moses", "God", "Nephi"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2431,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:11",
    "question": "Abinidi perceived that the Nephites had studied and taught iniquity for the most part of their lives.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2432,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:12-24",
    "question": "Abinidi read unto the people of King Noah the remainder of the ten commandments of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2433,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:35&13:12-24",
    "question": "The Ten Commandment of God are never written or recited by anyone in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2434,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:25",
    "question": "After Abinidi had finished speaking: he asked the priests of King Noah if they had taught the people to observe the commandments and to keep them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2435,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos13:26",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests of King Noah that if they had taught and observe the commandments of God; the Lord would not have caused him to come forth and to prophesy_____ concerning them.",
    "answer": "Evil",
    "options": ["Evil", "Destruction", "Calamities"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2436,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos13:27",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people that it was expedient for them to keep the Lawords of Mosmones as of yet; but that it would come a time when it shall no more be expedient to keep the_____ of Moses.",
    "answer": "Law"
  },
  {
    "id": 2437,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:28",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people that salvation does not come by the Lawords of Mosmones alone.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2438,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:28",
    "question": "Abinidi said that if it were not for the atonement, which God himself shall make for the sins and iniquities of his people; that they most unavoidably perish, not withstanding the Lawords of Mosmones.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2439,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos13:29",
    "question": "And now I say unto you that it is expedient that there should be a law given to the children of _____.",
    "answer": "Israel",
    "options": ["Nephi", "Lehi", "Israel"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2440,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:29",
    "question": "According to Abinidi the Lawords of Mosmones was not very strict or hard to live.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2441,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos13:29",
    "question": "The purpose the Lawords of Mosmones was given to the children of Israel because they were a stiffnecked people, quick to do iniquity, and slow to_____ their God.",
    "answer": "Remember"
  },
  {
    "id": 2442,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:30",
    "question": "The Lawords of Mosmones was a law of performances and of ordinances, a law which they were to observe strictly from day to day.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2443,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos13:30",
    "question": "The Lawords of Mosmones was also given to the children of_____ to keep them in remembrance of God and their duty to him.",
    "answer": "Israel"
  },
  {
    "id": 2444,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:31",
    "question": "Abinidi said that the Lawords of Mosmones and all the other things were types of things to come.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2445,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos13:32",
    "question": "The children of Israel did not understand the Lawords of Mosmones because of the hardness of their_____.",
    "answer": "Hearts",
    "options": ["Arteries", "Minds", "Hearts"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2446,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos13:32",
    "question": "The children of Israel could not understand that there could not any man be saved except it were through the redemption of_____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 2447,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:33",
    "question": "Abinidi said: “Did not Moses prophesy unto them concerning the coming of the Messiah”?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2448,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:33",
    "question": "Abinidi said that all the prophets more or less have prophesied concerning the Messiah and of other things since the world began.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2449,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos13:34",
    "question": "The prophets have prophesied and said that_____ himself should come down among the children of men, and take upon him the form of a man.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 2450,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:34",
    "question": "The prophets have also prophesied that God himself shall go forth in mighty power upon the face of the earth.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2451,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:35",
    "question": "Abinidi said:  Have not the prophets also said that he should bring to pass the resurrection of the dead, and that he, himself, should be oppressed and afflicted?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2452,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos14:1",
    "question": "In chapter #14 what Old Testament prophet does Abinidi quote to the priests of King Noah?",
    "answer": "Isaiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 2453,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos14:3",
    "question": "Abinidi said told the priests of King Noah that the Lord he will be despised and rejected of men.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2454,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos14:5",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests that Jesus Christ was wounded for our transgressions, he was bruised for our_____.",
    "answer": "Iniquities",
    "options": ["Iniquities", "Mistakes", "Shortcomings"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2455,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos14:5",
    "question": "Abinidi also told the priests of King Noah that the chastisement of our peace was upon Jesus Christ; and with his stripes we are_____.",
    "answer": "Healed",
    "options": ["Made Clean", "Made Whole", "Healed"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2456,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos14:6",
    "question": "Abinidi said “All men are like sheep, have gone astray; we have turned every one to his own way; and the Lord hath laid on him the iniquities of us all”.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2457,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos14:7",
    "question": "He was oppressed, and he was afflicted, yet he opened not his_____.",
    "answer": "Mouth"
  },
  {
    "id": 2458,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos14:7",
    "question": "He is brought as a lamb to the slaughter; and as a sheep before her_____ is dumb so he opened not his mouth.",
    "answer": "Shearers",
    "options": ["Master", "Shepherd", "Shearers"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2459,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos14:8",
    "question": "Abinidi quoted the prophet Isaiah when he said: “For he was cut off out of the land of the living; for the transgressions of my people was he stricken”.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2460,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos14:9",
    "question": "And he made his grave with the wicked; and with the rich in his death; because he had done no_____, neither was any deceit in his mouth.",
    "answer": "Evil",
    "options": ["Good", "Harm", "Evil"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2461,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos14:10",
    "question": "Abinidi said that it did not please the Lord to bruise him; yet he has put him to grief.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2462,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos14:10",
    "question": "When thou shall make him his soul an offering for sin he shall see his seed, he shall prolong his days and the pleasure of the Lord shall prosper in his hand.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2463,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos14:11",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests of King _____:  He shall see the travail of his soul, and shall be satisfied. ",
    "answer": "Noah"
  },
  {
    "id": 2464,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos14:11",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests: By his knowledge shall my righteous servant justify many; for he shall bear their iniquities.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2465,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos14:12",
    "question": "Therefore will I divide him a portion with the great, and he shall divide the spoil with the_____, because he has poured out his soul unto death.",
    "answer": "Strong",
    "options": ["Poor", "Strong", "Weak"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2466,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos14:12",
    "question": "Abinidi said that Jesus Christ was numbered with the transgressors; and he bore the sins of many, and made intercessions for the transgressors.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2467,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos15:1",
    "question": "Abinidi tell the priests of King Noah I would that you should understand that_____ himself shall come down among the children of men, and shall redeem his people.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 2468,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos15:1",
    "question": "Because God will dwell in the_____ he shall be called the Son of God.",
    "answer": "Flesh"
  },
  {
    "id": 2469,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos152",
    "question": "Because God will subjected his flesh to the will of the Father, he will be the Father and the Son",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2470,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos15:3",
    "question": "Abinidi said that he will be the Father because he was conceived by the power of God; and the Son, because of the flesh; thus becoming the Father and the_____.",
    "answer": "Son"
  },
  {
    "id": 2471,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:4",
    "question": "Abinidi said that Jesus Christ and God are one God, yea, the very Eternal Father of heaven and of the earth.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2472,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos15:5",
    "question": "And thus the flesh becoming subject to the Spirit, or the Son to the Father, being one God, suffering temptation, and not yielding to_____.",
    "answer": "Temptation",
    "options": ["Temptation", "His Will", "Sin"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2473,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:5",
    "question": "Jesus Christ will suffer himself to be mocked, and scourged, and cast out, and will not be disowned by his people.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2474,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos15:6",
    "question": "Jesus Christ will work mighty miracles among the children of men; yet he shall be led, even as Isaiah said, as a_____ before the shearer is dumb, so he opened not his mouth.",
    "answer": "Sheep"
  },
  {
    "id": 2475,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:7",
    "question": "Abinidi said: Jesus Christ shall be led, crucified, and be slain, the flesh becoming subjected even unto death, the will of the Son being swallowed up in the will of the Father.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2476,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos15:8",
    "question": "Abinidi said one of the most important statements about the atonement of Jesus Christ when he said: “Thus God breaketh the_____ of death, having gained the victory over death, giving the Son power to make intercession for the children of men”.",
    "answer": "Bands"
  },
  {
    "id": 2477,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos15:9",
    "question": "Abinidi said that Jesus Christ will have ascended into heaven, having the bowels of mercy; being filled with compassion towards the children of_____.",
    "answer": "Men"
  },
  {
    "id": 2478,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:9",
    "question": "Jesus Christ will stand between the children of men and justice; having broken the bands of death.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2479,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos15:9",
    "question": "Because Jesus Christ will break the bands of death he will take upon himself the iniquities and transgressions of the children of men, having redeemed them and satisfied the demands of_____.",
    "answer": "Justice"
  },
  {
    "id": 2480,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:10",
    "question": "Abinidi said: When the soul of Jesus Christ has been made an offering for sin he shall see his seed.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2481,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:11",
    "question": "Abinidi said that whosoever has heard the words of the holy prophets who have prophesied concerning the coming of the Lord and have kept his Commandments; look forward to the remission of their sins.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2482,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:11",
    "question": "Those that have hearkened into the words of the prophets and believed that the Lord would redeem his people, and have looked forward to the remission of their sins are heirs of the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2483,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:12",
    "question": "The people whose sins Jesus Christ has borne; these are they for whom he has died to redeem them from transgressions are his seed.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2484,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos15:13",
    "question": "Abinidi said that all the_____ who have opened their mouths since the world began and have not fallen into transgression are also his seed.",
    "answer": "Prophets",
    "options": ["People", "Tribes", "Prophets"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2485,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:14",
    "question": "The prophets of the Lord have published peace, who have brought good tidings of good, who have published salvation: and said unto Zion: Thy God reigns are also the seed of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2486,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos15:16",
    "question": "“O how beautiful upon the mountains are the_____ of those who are still publishing peace”!",
    "answer": "Feet",
    "options": ["Legs", "Arms", "Feet"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2487,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:18",
    "question": "Abinidi said that the Lord is the founder of peace, and it is he who has redeemed his people and granted salvation unto his people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2488,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos15:19",
    "question": "The redemption of Jesus Christ was prepared from the_____ of the world.",
    "answer": "Start",
    "options": ["Start", "Ending"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2489,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:19",
    "question": "If it was not for the redemption of Jesus Christ that he has made for his people, all mankind must perish.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2490,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos15:20",
    "question": "Because Jesus Christ broke the bands of death and he reigns and has the power over the dead, he brings to pass the resurrection of the_____.",
    "answer": "Dead"
  },
  {
    "id": 2491,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:21",
    "question": "All those that died before the resurrection of Jesus Christ, will not be a part of the first resurrection.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2492,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:23",
    "question": "Those people who have believed in the words of the prophets and have kept the commandments of God will dwell with God who has raised them and have eternal life through Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2493,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:24",
    "question": "Those who have died before Jesus Christ came to earth and have come in their ignorance, not having salvation declared unto them; the Lord will bring about the restoration to them and are a part of the first resurrection.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2494,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:25",
    "question": "Abinidi said that little children that have died before Jesus Christ came to the earth have no eternal life.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2495,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos15:26",
    "question": "Abinidi said those who willingly rebel against God and have known of his commandments and did not keep them have no part in the_____ resurrection.",
    "answer": "1st",
    "options": ["1st", "2nd", "3rd"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2496,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:27",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests of King Noah that the Lord cannot deny himself; for he cannot deny justice when it has its claim.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2497,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos15:28",
    "question": "Abinidi said that the time shall come that the salvation of the Lord shall be declared to every_____, kindred, tongue and people.",
    "answer": "Nation"
  },
  {
    "id": 2498,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos15:29",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests that the watchmen shall lift up their voices together and sing; for they shall see eye to eye, when the Lord shall bring again_____.",
    "answer": "Zion",
    "options": ["Jews", "The Nephites", "Zion"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2499,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos15:31",
    "question": "The Lord has made bare his holy arm in the eyes of all nations; and all the ends of the earth shall see the_____ of our God.",
    "answer": "Salvation",
    "options": ["Salvation", "Mercy", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2500,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Abinidi said the time shall come when all shall see the salvation of the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2501,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos16:1",
    "question": "Not only will every nation, kindred, tongue, and people see the salvation of the Lord but they shall also see_____ to eye and shall confess before God that his judgments are just.",
    "answer": "Eye"
  },
  {
    "id": 2502,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos16:2",
    "question": "The wicked shall be cast out, and they shall have cause to howl, weep and wail, and gnash their_____.",
    "answer": "Teeth"
  },
  {
    "id": 2503,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos16:2",
    "question": "The wicked will be cast out because they would not hearken unto the _____ of the Lord; therefore, the Lord will not redeem them.",
    "answer": "Voice",
    "options": ["Teachings", "Voice", "Principles"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2504,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:3",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests of King Noah that men are carnal and devilish and the devil has power over them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2505,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:3",
    "question": "Abinidi said that the old serpent beguiled our first parents, which was the cause of their fall.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2506,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:3",
    "question": "Abinidi mentions our first parents by name.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2507,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos16:3",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests that the fall caused that all mankind become carnal, sensual, and devilish, knowing evil from_____; subjecting themselves to the devil.",
    "answer": "Good"
  },
  {
    "id": 2508,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos16:4",
    "question": "Who redeemed his people from their lost and fallen state?",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["Moses", "God", "Adam"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2509,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:4",
    "question": "All mankind were lost, and they would have been endlessly lost were it not that God redeemed his people from their lost and fallen state.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2510,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:5",
    "question": "Abinidi said that we should remember that he that persists in his own carnal nature, and goes on in the ways of sin and rebellion against God, remains in his fallen state.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2511,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos16:5",
    "question": "Abinidi said that those that remain in their fallen state; that the devil has power over them, therefore, it is though there was no redemption made, being an enemy to_____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 2512,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos16:5",
    "question": "What is the name of the person that is an enemy to God and will always be forever and forever?",
    "answer": ["Devil", "Satan", "Adversary"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2513,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:6",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests of King Noah that if Christ had not come into the world, speaking of things to come as though they have already come, there could have been no redemption.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2514,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:7",
    "question": "And if Jesus Christ had not risen from the dead, and broke the bands of death the grave should have no victory or sting, therefore, there could have been no resurrection.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2515,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos16:8",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests that there is a resurrection therefore the grave has no victory, and the sting of death is swallowed up in_____.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 2516,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos16:9",
    "question": "Who did Abinidi say is the light and the life of the world? Jesus ",
    "answer": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 2517,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos16:9",
    "question": "Jesus Christ is the light that is endless, that can never be_____.",
    "answer": "Darkened",
    "options": ["Put Out", "Darkened", "Shutoff"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2518,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:9",
    "question": "Jesus Christ is not only an endless light but also a life which is endless that there can be no death.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2519,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos16:10",
    "question": "Abinidi said that even this mortal body shall put on immorality, and this corruption shall put on_____.",
    "answer": "Incorruption"
  },
  {
    "id": 2520,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:10",
    "question": "Abinidi tells the priests of King Noah and us that will shall be brought before the judgment bar of God to be judged.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2521,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos16:10",
    "question": "Abinidi tell us that we shall be judged according to or works whether they be good or whether they be_____.",
    "answer": "Evil"
  },
  {
    "id": 2522,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:11",
    "question": "If our works are good we will go to the resurrection of endless life and happiness; and if they be evil, to the resurrection of endless damnation.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2523,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos16:11",
    "question": "If our works are evil we will go to the resurrection of endless damnation, being delivered up to the_____, who has subjected us, which is damnation---- ",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },
  {
    "id": 2524,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:12",
    "question": "Because the devil has subjected us to damnation; we will have gone according to our own carnal wills and desires having never called upon the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2525,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos16:12",
    "question": "The Lord will always have his arms of mercy extended to us, if we call upon him and are faithful in keeping his _____.",
    "answer": "Commandments"
  },
  {
    "id": 2526,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:12",
    "question": "The Lord had his arms of mercy extended to the Nephites and they would not call upon him; and they were warned of their iniquities and yet they would not depart from them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2527,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos16:12",
    "question": "Abinidi said that the people were commanded to_____ and yet they would not repent.",
    "answer": "Repent"
  },
  {
    "id": 2528,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:13",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests of King Noah that they should tremble and remember that only in and through Christ can they be saved.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2529,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos16:14",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests that if they teach the Law of_____, also teach that it is a shadow of those things which are to come.",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },
  {
    "id": 2530,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:14",
    "question": "Abinidi did not tell the priests of King Noah that if they teach to the Lawords of Mosmones; also teach that it is not a shadow of those things which are to come.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2531,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos16:15",
    "question": "Abinidi also told the priests of King Noah to teach to the people that redemption comes through Christ the Lord, who is the very_____ Father.",
    "answer": "Eternal",
    "options": ["Good", "Eternal", "Busy"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2532,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:1",
    "question": "When Abinidi finished saying the things that he said to the priest; King Noah commanded that the_____ should take him and cause that he should be put to death.",
    "answer": "Priests",
    "options": ["Priests", "People", "Nephites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2533,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:2",
    "question": "Which one of the priests of King Noah believed in the words of Abinidi?",
    "answer": "Alma1",
    "options": ["Amulon", "Gadianton", "Alma1"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2534,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos17:2",
    "question": "What Book of Mormon record keeper and prophet was Alma1 descendant of? ",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2535,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:2",
    "question": "When Alma1 first heard and believed the words of Abinidi he was in his fifty’s.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2536,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:2",
    "question": "Alma1 believed the words that Abinidi spoken, for he knew of the iniquity which he had testified against them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2537,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos17:2",
    "question": "Who began to plead with King Noah not to be angry with Abinidi, but that he might depart in peace?",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 2538,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:3",
    "question": "Because of the things that Alma1 said King Noah was more wroth, and caused that he should be_____ out from among them.",
    "answer": "Cast",
    "options": ["Delivered", "Cast", "Taken"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2539,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:3",
    "question": "King Noah sent his servants after Alma1 that they might slay him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2540,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:4",
    "question": "Alma1 fled from the king’s servants and they could not find him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2541,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:4",
    "question": "What is the name of the person that wrote all the words which Abinidi had spoken?",
    "answer": "Alma1",
    "options": ["Nephi", "Laman", "Alma1"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2542,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos17:5",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Noah had his Guards surround_____ and take him; and they bound him and cast him into prison.",
    "answer": "Abinidi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2543,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:6",
    "question": "How many days did King Noah hold council with his priests, and caused that Abinidi, be brought before him?",
    "answer": "3",
    "options": ["1", "Or", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2544,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:7",
    "question": "King Noah told Abinidi that they had found an accusation against him and that he was worthy of_____.",
    "answer": "Death",
    "options": ["Hanging", "Money", "Death"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2545,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:8",
    "question": "The main reason Abinidi was put to death was because he said that God himself should come down in the flesh among the children of men",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2546,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos17:8",
    "question": "King Noah wanted_____ to recall the words he said to him and his people.",
    "answer": "Abinidi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2547,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:8",
    "question": "King Noah wanted Abinidi to not recall the words he had said and said that he had spoken evil concerning him and his people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2548,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:9",
    "question": "Abinidi said that he would recall the words that he had spoken to King Noah concerning his people.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2549,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:9",
    "question": "Abinidi told King Noah that the words he had spoken to him and his people were_____; and that he may know of their surety because I have suffered myself and have fallen into your hands.",
    "answer": "True",
    "options": ["True", "False", "Terrible"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2550,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:10",
    "question": "Abinidi said that he would suffer death rather than recall his words he had spoken to King Noah and his people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2551,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:10",
    "question": "Abinidi said that his words would stand as testimony against King Zoram.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2552,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:10",
    "question": "Abinidi said that he would not recall his words and that his words would stand against a testimony to King Noah.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2553,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:10",
    "question": "Abinidi warned King Noah that if he would slay him, he would be shedding innocent_____, and that it would stand as a testimony against him at the last day.",
    "answer": "Blood",
    "options": ["Heart", "Blood", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2554,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:11",
    "question": "King Noah did not want to release Abinidi and he did not fear his words; because he did not fear the judgments of God and that they would come upon him.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2555,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos17:12",
    "question": "The priests lifted up their voices against _____, and began to accuse him of reviling King Noah.",
    "answer": "Abinidi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2556,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:12",
    "question": "King Noah was angry because of the words his priests had said concerning Abinidi, and he delivered him up that he might be slain.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2557,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:13",
    "question": "And it came to pass that they took Abinidi and bound him, and scourged his skin with_____, yea, even unto death.",
    "answer": "Faggots",
    "options": ["Gasoline", "Kerosene", "Faggots"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2558,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:14",
    "question": "When the flames began to scorch Abinidi, he did not say a word but suffered a horrible death.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2559,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:15",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests of King Noah: “Even as ye have done unto me, so shall it come to pass that thy seed shall cause that many shall suffer even pains of death by fire”.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2560,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:15",
    "question": "Abinidi said that the seed of the priest would suffer the pains of death by fire because they belived in the salvation of the Lord their _____.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["Man", "God", "Leader"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2561,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:16",
    "question": "Abinidi also told the priests that it shall come to pass that they shall be afflicted with all manner of_____ because of their iniquities.",
    "answer": "Diseases",
    "options": ["Wars", "Pestilences", "Diseases"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2562,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:17",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests and the people that they shall be smitten on every hand.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2563,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:17",
    "question": "Abinidi also told the priests and the people, that they shall be driven and scattered back and forth, even as a wild flock is driven by wild and ferocious _____.",
    "answer": "Beasts",
    "options": ["Lions", "Tigers", "Beasts"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2564,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:18",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests that they would be hunted and shall be taken by the_____ of their enemies, and then shall they suffer, like he has suffered the pains of death by fire.",
    "answer": "Hand",
    "options": ["Neck", "Hand", "Sword"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2565,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:19",
    "question": "God executes vengeance upon those that destroy his people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2566,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:19",
    "question": "The last words Abinidi spoke before he died were: “O God, receive my soul”.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2567,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:20",
    "question": "Abinidi suffered the pains of death by what means?",
    "answer": "Fire",
    "options": ["Hanging", "Torture", "Fire"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2568,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma25:11&Mos17:20",
    "question": "According to Alma1; Abinidi is considered to be the first prophet in Nephite history to die from fire because of his beliefs and also because of his belief in Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2569,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:20",
    "question": "Alma1 wrote that Abinidi was put to death because he would not deny the commandments of God, having sealed the truth of his words by his death.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2570,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos18:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma1 the one who had fled from the servants of King Noah, repented of his sins and_____.",
    "answer": "Iniquities",
    "options": ["Abomination", "Iniquities", "Wickedness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2571,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos18:1",
    "question": "Alma1 went about privately among the people and began to teach the people the words of_____.",
    "answer": "Abinidi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2572,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:2",
    "question": "Alma1 taught the people about the power, sufferings, and death of Jesus Christ; and his resurrection and ascension into heaven.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2573,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos18:3",
    "question": "Alma1 taught the people privately because he did not want King____ to come to the knowledge that he was teaching them.",
    "answer": "Noah"
  },
  {
    "id": 2574,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:3",
    "question": "Many of the people that Alma1taught did not believe his words.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2575,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos18:4,8",
    "question": "What is the name of the place where Alma1 taught the people?",
    "answer": "Mormon"
  },
  {
    "id": 2576,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:4",
    "question": "The waters of Mormon bordered a land that had been infested, by times or at seasons, by wild beasts.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2577,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos18:5",
    "question": "At the place called Mormon there was a fountain of pure_____.",
    "answer": "Water",
    "options": ["Gold", "Water", "Silver"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2578,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:5",
    "question": "And it came to pass that as many people believed Alma1’s words gathered together at the place called Mormon to hear his words.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2579,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos18:7",
    "question": "Alma did teach them, and did preach unto them_____, and redemption, and faith on the Lord.",
    "answer": "Repentance",
    "options": ["Chastity", "Doctrine", "Repentance"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2580,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:8",
    "question": "The people that had gathered at the Waters of Mormon were desirous to come unto the fold of God, and to be called his people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2581,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:8",
    "question": "The people who were with Alma1 were not willing to bear one anothers' burdens, that they might be light.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2582,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos18:9",
    "question": "The people at the Waters of Mormon were willing to mourn with those that_____; and comfort those that stand in need of comfort.",
    "answer": "Mourn"
  },
  {
    "id": 2583,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos18:9",
    "question": "As disciples of Jesus Christ we must stand as witnesses of God at all times and in all things, and in all_____.",
    "answer": "Places"
  },
  {
    "id": 2584,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:9",
    "question": "As we stand as witnesses of God at all times and in all things, and in all places; we will be numbered with those of the first resurrection, that we may have eternal life",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2585,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:10",
    "question": "Alma1 asked the people if they were willing to be baptized in the name of the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2586,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:10",
    "question": "Alma1 asked to people to be baptized and to witness before him that they would enter a covenant with him, and keep his commandments.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2587,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos18:10",
    "question": "Alma1 told the people that if they were baptized and keep the Lord’s commandments; he would pour his_____ more abundantly upon them.",
    "answer": "Spirit",
    "options": ["Soul", "Heart", "Spirit"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2588,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos18:11",
    "question": "When the people heard the words of Alma1, they clapped their hands for joy, and exclaimed:  This is the desire of our_____.",
    "answer": "Hearts",
    "options": ["Souls", "Hearts", "Heads"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2589,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos18:12",
    "question": "Who was one of the first persons to be baptized by Alma1 in the Waters of Mormon?",
    "answer": "Helam"
  },
  {
    "id": 2590,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "13,18",
    "question": "Who gave Alma1 the authority to baptize people in the Waters of Mormon?",
    "answer": "Almighty God",
    "options": ["Almighty God", "Nephi", "Moses"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2591,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:14",
    "question": "Alma1 and Helam were buried in the water and baptized at the same time and arose and came forth out of the water rejoicing, being filled with the Spirit of the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2592,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:16,35",
    "question": "All the people that were at the Waters of Mormon with Alma1 were baptized.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2593,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos18:16",
    "question": "Alma1 baptized 240 souls at the Waters of Mormon and they were filled with the grace of_____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 2594,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:17",
    "question": "The people that Alma1 baptized were called the Church of God, or the Church of Christ, from that time forward.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2595,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos18:18",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma1, having authority from God, ordained priests; even one____ to every fifty of their number.",
    "answer": "Priest",
    "options": ["Teacher", "Priest", "Deacon"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2596,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:18",
    "question": "The priests that Alma1 ordained were to teach the people concerning the things pertaining to the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2597,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos18:19",
    "question": "Alma1 commanded the priests to teach nothing except the things which he had taught, and things which had been spoken by the mouth of the holy_____.",
    "answer": "Prophets",
    "options": ["Ghost", "Spirit", "Prophets"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2598,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:20",
    "question": "Alma1 did not command the priests to preach nothing save it were repentance and faith in the Lord, who had redeemed his people.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2599,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:21",
    "question": "Alma1 did not command the people that they should get along one with the other and that they should have no contentions among them.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2600,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos18:21",
    "question": "Alma1 told the people that they should look forward with one eye, having one faith and one_____, having their hearts knit together in unity and love one towards another.",
    "answer": "Baptism"
  },
  {
    "id": 2601,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos18:23",
    "question": "Alma1 commanded the people to observe the _____day, and keep it holy and also to give thanks to the Lord their God every day.",
    "answer": "Sabbath"
  },
  {
    "id": 2602,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:24",
    "question": "Alma1 commanded the priests whom he had ordained, that they should get paid by the people for their labors and support.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2603,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos18:25",
    "question": "There was one day of every week that was set apart that they should gather themselves together to teach the people, and to worship the_____ their God.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 2604,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:26",
    "question": "The priests were not to depend upon the people for their support; but for their labor they were to receive the grace of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2605,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos18:26",
    "question": "The priests by their labor were to receive the grace of God and that they might wax strong in the Spirit, having the knowledge of God; that they might teach with the power and_____ from God.",
    "answer": "Authority",
    "options": ["Authority", "Knowledge", "Grace"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2606,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:27",
    "question": "Alma1 commanded the people of the church to impart of their substance, every one according to that which they had; if he had more abundantly he should impart more abundantly.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2607,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos18:28",
    "question": "The people of the church were to impart of their_____ of their own free will and good desires towards God, and to those priests that stood in need, and to every needy, naked soul.",
    "answer": "Substance"
  },
  {
    "id": 2608,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos18:29",
    "question": "The people were commanded of God; and they did walk uprightly before God, imparting to one another both temporally and_____ according to their needs and wants.",
    "answer": "Spiritually"
  },
  {
    "id": 2609,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:30",
    "question": "And it came to pass that all things that Alma1 commanded the people to do were done in the Waters or Mormon, in the forest that was near the Waters of Mormon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2610,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:30",
    "question": "“Oh! How beautiful are they to the eyes of them who come to the knowledge of their Redeemer; and how blessed are they, for they shall sing to his praise forever”.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2611,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos18:32",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Noah, having discovered a movement among the people, sent his_____ to watch them.",
    "answer": "Servants",
    "options": ["Army", "Troops", "Servants"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2612,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:33",
    "question": "King Noah said that Alma1 was stirring up the people to rebellion against him at the Waters of Mormon; therefore he sent his army to destroy them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2613,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:34",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma1 and the people of the Lord were apprised of the coming of the king’s army and departed into the wilderness.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2614,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos19:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Noah’s army found Alma1 and the people of the church and destroyed them.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2615,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos19:2",
    "question": "And now behold, the forces of the King Noah were big, and there began to be a division among the people.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2616,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos19:3",
    "question": "The lesser part of the people began to breathe out threats against the king, and there began to be a great contention among them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2617,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos19:4",
    "question": "What was the name of the man who was among the people who was an enemy of King Noah?",
    "answer": "Gideon",
    "options": ["Alma1", "Gideon", "Moroni"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2618,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos19:4",
    "question": "Gideon was a strong man and an enemy to King Noah, therefore he drew his_____, and swore in his wrath the he would slay the king.",
    "answer": "Sword",
    "options": ["Pistol", "Rifle", "Sword"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2619,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos19:5",
    "question": "Gideon and King Noah fought each other; and when the king saw that he was about to be overpowered by Gideon, he fled and got upon the tower which was near the temple.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2620,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos19:6",
    "question": "When King Noah was upon the tower he cast his eyes round about towards the land of Shemlon and saw that the armies of the_____ were within the borders of the land.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["Zoramites", "Nephites", "Lamanites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2621,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos19:7",
    "question": "King Noah cried out:  Gideon, spare me, for the Lamanites are upon us, and they will destroy us and they will destroy my people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2622,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos19:8",
    "question": "Gideon spared the life of King Noah because the king was more concerned about the people than his own life.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2623,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos19:11",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Noah commanded that all men should leave their wives and their children, and flee before the_____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 2624,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos19:12",
    "question": "All the men that King Noah commanded to flee before the Lamanites left their wives and children.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2625,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos19:13",
    "question": "And it came to pass that some of the men who had tarried with their wives and children caused that their fair_____ should stand forth and plead with the Lamanites that they would not slay them.",
    "answer": "Daughters",
    "options": ["Children", "Daughters", "Boys"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2626,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos19:14",
    "question": "The Lamanites had compassion for the daughters of the Nephites and they were charmed with the beauty of their women.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2627,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos19:15",
    "question": "The Lamanites did spare the lives of the Nephites and took them captives and carried them back to the land of_____.",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["Nephi", "Shemlon", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2628,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos19:15",
    "question": "The Lamanites wanted the Nephites to deliver up their property and King Noah and even one half of all they possessed and to pay tribute to the king of the Lamanites from year to year.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2629,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos19:17",
    "question": "Among those that were taken captive by the Lamanites was one of the sons of King Noah; and he desired that his father should not be destroyed.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2630,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos19:17",
    "question": "What was the name of King Noah son who was a just man and was not ignorant of the iniquities of his father?",
    "answer": "Limhi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2631,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos19:18",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Gideon sent men into the wilderness secretly, to search for King_____ and those that were with him.",
    "answer": "Noah"
  },
  {
    "id": 2632,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos19:20",
    "question": "The people were angry with King Noah and caused that he should suffer, even unto death by_____.",
    "answer": "Fire",
    "options": ["Hanging", "Fire", "Firing Squad"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2633,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos19:23",
    "question": "The people told the men of_____ that they had slain the king, and his priests had fled from them farther into the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Gideon"
  },
  {
    "id": 2634,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos19:26",
    "question": "Limhi was the son of King Noah that had the kingdom conferred upon him by the people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2635,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos19:27",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King_____ began to establish the kingdom and to establish peace among his people.",
    "answer": "Limhi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2636,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos20:1",
    "question": "What was the name of the place where the daughters of the Lamanites gathered themselves together to sing, and to dance and to make themselves merry?",
    "answer": "Shemlon",
    "options": ["Shemlon", "Waters Of Mormon", "Shilom"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2637,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos20:5",
    "question": "How many daughters of the Lamanites did the priests of King Noah carry into the wilderness?",
    "answer": "24",
    "options": ["24", "34", "44"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2638,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos20:6",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the_____ were angry with the people of Limhi because they thought it was them that had carried away their daughters into the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 2639,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos20:8",
    "question": "The king of the Lamanites himself and his armies went to the land of Nephi to destroy the people of Limhi because of what they thought they had done.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2640,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos20:8",
    "question": "King Limhi discovered the Lamanites from the _____, even all the preparations of war did he discover; therefore he gathered his people together for war.",
    "answer": "Tower",
    "options": ["Tall Balcony", "Highest Wall", "Tower"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2641,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos20:10",
    "question": "The people of King Limhi began to slay the Lamanites and the battle became exceedingly sore, and they fought like_____ for their prey.",
    "answer": "Lions",
    "options": ["Lions", "Tigers", "Leopards"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2642,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos20:11",
    "question": "The people of King Limhi began to drive the Lamanites before them; they fought for their lives, and for their wives, and for their_____.",
    "answer": "Children"
  },
  {
    "id": 2643,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos20:11",
    "question": "Because to the things that the people of King Limhi were fighting for, they exerted themselves, and like tigers did they fought.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2644,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos20:12",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people of King Limhi found the king of the Lamanites among the number of their dead; yet he was not dead.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2645,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos20:12",
    "question": "Because the flight of the people of the Lamanites was so speedy they thought that their king had died in battle, but actually he was only wounded.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2646,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos20:14,15",
    "question": "The king of the Lamanites had broken the oath that he had previously made with King_____ because he thought that the Nephites had carried away their daughters.",
    "answer": "Limhi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2647,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos20:16",
    "question": "King Limhi caused that a search among his people be made so that they could find out which persons were involved in carrying away the daughters of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2648,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos20:17",
    "question": "What is the name of the person who was the captain of the army of King Limhi?",
    "answer": "Gideon"
  },
  {
    "id": 2649,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos20:18",
    "question": "Gideon told King Limhi that his father’s priests were the ones who had taken and stolen the daughters of the_____ and that he must tell the Lamanites this to pacify them.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 2650,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos20:21",
    "question": "Gideon said that the words of_____ were fulfilled; which he prophesied against them because they would not hearken unto the words of the Lord, and turn from their iniquities.",
    "answer": "Abinidi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2651,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos20:22",
    "question": "Gideon told King Limhi that is better for them to lose their lives than to be in bondage unto the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2652,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos20:23",
    "question": "King Limhi told the king of the Lamanites all the things concerning his father, and the priests that had fled into the wilderness and attributed the carrying away of their daughters to them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2653,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos20:24",
    "question": "After King Limhi told the king of the Lamanites concerning the things about his father and his priests, he was pacified",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2654,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos20:25",
    "question": "The king of the Lamanites did not bow down before the armies of the Lamanites and pleaded on behalf of the people of King Limhi.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2655,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos20:26",
    "question": "The _____saw that the people of King Limhi were without weapons of war and had compassion on them and returned with their king in peace to their own land.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 2656,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos21:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Limhi and his people returned to the city of_____ and dwelt in the land in peace.",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["Nephi", "Mormon", "Shemlon"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2657,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos21:2,3",
    "question": "After many days the Lamanites were stirred up in anger against the Nephites and they did not slay them because of the oath their king had made unto King Limhi.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2658,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos21:3",
    "question": "The Lamanites began to smite the Nephites on their_____, and exercise authority over them; and began to put heavy burdens upon their backs.",
    "answer": "Cheeks",
    "options": ["Backs", "Cheeks", "Behinds"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2659,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos21:3",
    "question": "The Lamanites began to smite the Nephites on their cheeks and do other things to them and also began to drive them as they would a dumb ass.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2660,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos21:4",
    "question": "All kind of bad things happened to the Lamanites so that the words of the Lord might be fulfilled.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2661,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos21:6",
    "question": "The people began to murmur with the king because of their_____; and they began to be desirous to go to battle against the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Afflictions",
    "options": ["Downfall", "Sorrow", "Afflictions"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2662,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos21:7,8",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites and Nephites went to battle and the Lamanites did slay many of the_____ and drove them back to their lands.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 2663,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "11,12",
    "question": "How many times did the Nephites battle with the Lamanites and were beaten and suffered much loss before they returned to the city of Nephi?",
    "answer": "3",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2664,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos21:13",
    "question": "The Nephites did humble themselves even to the dust, subjecting themselves to the yoke of bondage, to be smitten and to be driven to and fro.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2665,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos21:14",
    "question": "The Nephites did humble themselves even to the depths of humility unto God; and did cry mightily to_____ that he might deliver them out of their afflictions.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["God", "Nephi", "Moses"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2666,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos21:15",
    "question": "The Lord was slow to hear the cries of the Nephites because of their _____.",
    "answer": "Iniquities",
    "options": ["Pride", "Iniquities", "Stubbornness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2667,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos21:15",
    "question": "The Lord did hear the cries of the Nephities and began to soften the hearts of the_____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 2668,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos21:15",
    "question": "Even though the Lord heard the cries of the Nephities he still did not deliver them out of bondage.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2669,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos21:17",
    "question": "During this time in Nephite history there were more men than women.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2670,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos21:18",
    "question": "King Limhi and his people kept together in a body as much as it was possible, and secured their grain and their_____.",
    "answer": "Flocks",
    "options": ["Lands", "Flocks", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2671,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos21:22",
    "question": "And it came to pass that there was no more disturbance between the Lamanites and the people of King _____; even until the time Ammon and his brethren came into the Land.",
    "answer": "Limhi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2672,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos21:23",
    "question": "King Limhi and his Guards discovered_____ and his brethren and supposed they were the priests of Noah.",
    "answer": "Ammon"
  },
  {
    "id": 2673,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos21:23",
    "question": "King Limhi and his guards did not discover Ammon and his brethren and did not supposed that they were the priests of King Noah.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2674,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos21:23",
    "question": "King Limhi caused that Ammon and his brethren should be taken, and bound, and cast into prison.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2675,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos21:24",
    "question": "King Limhi found that Ammon and his brethren were his brethren, and had come from the land of_____.",
    "answer": "Zarahemla"
  },
  {
    "id": 2676,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos21:24",
    "question": "King Limhi was not filled with joy when he found out that Ammon and his brethren had come from the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2677,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos21:25",
    "question": "Before the coming of Ammon, King Limhi had sent a small number of men to search for the land of_____; but they could not find it and got lost in the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Zarahemla"
  },
  {
    "id": 2678,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos21:26",
    "question": "The search party that King Limhi sent out discovered a land which had been peopled and covered with dry bones.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2679,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos21:26",
    "question": "King Limhi’s search party thought the land they had discovered was the land of Zarahemla and returned to the land of_____.",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2680,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos21:27",
    "question": "King Limhi’s search party brought a record with them, even a record of the people whose_____ they had found.",
    "answer": "Bones",
    "options": ["Bones", "Bodies", "Weapons"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2681,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos21:27",
    "question": "The record that King Lemhi’s search party found was engraven on plates made of _____.",
    "answer": "Ore",
    "options": ["Brass", "Gold", "Ore"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2682,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos21:28",
    "question": "King Limhi was filled with joy because he found out from Ammon that King_____ had a gift from God, whereby he could interpret such engravings.",
    "answer": "Mosiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 2683,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos21:29,30",
    "question": "Ammon and his brethren were filled with sorrow because so many of their brethren had been slain and did mourn the death of_____.",
    "answer": "Abinidi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2684,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos21:30",
    "question": "Alma1 and the people that fled with him formed a church of_____ though the strength and power of God.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 2685,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos21:31",
    "question": "Ammon and his brethren did mourn for Alma1 and the people that fled with him because they did not know where they had gone.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2686,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos21:31",
    "question": "Ammon and his brethren had entered a covenant with God to serve him and keep his_____.",
    "answer": "Commandments"
  },
  {
    "id": 2687,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos21:32",
    "question": "Since the coming of Ammon, King Limhi had also entered into a covenant with God and also so many of his people, to serve him and keep his commandments.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2688,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos21:33",
    "question": "King Limhi and his people were desirous to be baptized; but there was no one in the land that had the_____ from God.",
    "answer": "Authority",
    "options": ["Say So", "Authority", "Gift"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2689,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos21:33",
    "question": "Ammon declined to baptized King Limhi and his people because he considered himself an unworthy servant.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2690,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos21:35",
    "question": "King Limhi and his people were desirous to be baptized as a witness and a_____ that they were willing to serve God with all their hearts.",
    "answer": "Testimony"
  },
  {
    "id": 2691,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos22:2",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Ammon and King Limhi and his people could not find a way to deliver themselves out of bondage from the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2692,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos22:3,4",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Gideon went forth and stood before King Limhi and desired to speak to him and his people that he might be his servant and deliver them form bondage.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2693,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos22:7",
    "question": "Gideon’s plan was to pay tribute to the Lamanites with_____, and get them drunk and he would pass though the secret pass while they were drunk with sleep.",
    "answer": "Wine",
    "options": ["Gold", "Wine", "Silver"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2694,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos22:9",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Limhi would not hearken to the words of Gideon.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2695,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos22:10",
    "question": "King Limhi caused that his people should gather their flocks together; and he sent the tribute of wine to the_____. ",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 2696,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos22:11",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people of King Limhi did depart by night into the wilderness towards the land of_____, being led by Ammon and his brethren.",
    "answer": "Zarahemla"
  },
  {
    "id": 2697,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos22:13",
    "question": "After many days in the wilderness they arrived in the land of Zarahemla, and joined the people of King _____, and became his subjects.",
    "answer": "Mosiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 2698,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos22:14",
    "question": "King Mosiah received King Lemhi and his people with joy; and also received their records, and also the records which had been found by King Lemhi’s search party.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2699,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos22:15,16",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites sent an army to pursue King Limhi and his people; and after two days they could no longer follow their tracks and were lost in the_____.",
    "answer": "Wilderness"
  },
  {
    "id": 2700,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos23:1",
    "question": "Who warned Alma1 and his people that the armies of King Noah would come upon them?",
    "answer": "The Lord",
    "options": ["The Lord", "Gideon", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2701,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos23:1",
    "question": "Alma1 and his people gathered together their flocks, and took their grain, and departed into the wilderness before the armies of King Noah.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2702,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:2",
    "question": "Who strengthen Alma1 and his people that the people of King Noah could not overtake them?",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 2703,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos23:4",
    "question": "After traveling for eight days in the wilderness, Alma1 and his people came to a land that was beautiful and pleasant, a land of pure_____.",
    "answer": "Water",
    "options": ["Gold", "Pleasantries", "Water"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2704,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos23:5",
    "question": "Alma1 and his people pitched their tents, and began to till the ground, and began to build_____; they were industrious, and did labor exceedingly.",
    "answer": "Buildings",
    "options": ["Houses", "Barns", "Buildings"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2705,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:6",
    "question": "The people were desirous that_____ should be their king, because he was beloved by all his people.",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 2706,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos23:7",
    "question": "Alma1 told the people that it was not expedient that they should have a king.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2707,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:7",
    "question": "The Lord has said:”Ye shall not esteem one flesh above another, or one_____ shall not think himself above another”.",
    "answer": "Man"
  },
  {
    "id": 2708,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos23:8",
    "question": "Alma1 told the people: That if it was possible that they could always have just men to be there kings it would be well for them to have a king.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2709,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos23:9",
    "question": "Alma1 reminded the people of the iniquity King Noah and his priests had caused the people to commit and that he himself was caught in a snare.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2710,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:10",
    "question": "The Lord heard the cries of Alma1 and did answer his prayers and he made him an_____ in his hands in bringing so many people to the knowledge of the truth.",
    "answer": "Instrument"
  },
  {
    "id": 2711,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos23:11",
    "question": "Alma1 gloried in being an instrument in the hands of the Lord because he said he was a worthy servant.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2712,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos23:12",
    "question": "Alma1 reminded the people how they had been oppressed by King Noah and his priests, and had been in bondage and that they had been brought to iniquity by them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2713,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos23:12",
    "question": "Alma1 also told the people that they were bound by the bands of_____.",
    "answer": "Iniquity",
    "options": ["Death", "Sin", "Iniquity"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2714,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:13",
    "question": "Alma1 told the people that they had been delivered by the power of_____ out of these bonds; even out of the hands of King Noah and his people, and also from the bonds of iniquity.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 2715,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos23:13",
    "question": "Alma1 told the people to stand fast in this liberty wherewith they had been made free, and that they must trust no_____ to be a king over them.",
    "answer": "Man",
    "options": ["Woman", "Lamanite", "Man"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2716,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:14",
    "question": "Alma1 told the people to trust no one to be there teacher or minister, except he be a man of_____, walking in his ways and keeping his commandments.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 2717,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:16",
    "question": "Alma1 was the people’s_____ priest, he being the founder of their church.",
    "answer": "High"
  },
  {
    "id": 2718,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos23:17",
    "question": "And it came to pass that none received authority to preach or teach except it were given to him from God; and Alma consecrated all their priests and teachers and they were just men.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2719,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:19",
    "question": "The people began to prosper exceedingly in the land; and they called the land Helam, and also build a city and called it_____.",
    "answer": "Helam"
  },
  {
    "id": 2720,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:21",
    "question": "Nevertheless the Lord sees fit to chasten his people; yea, and he also tries their patience and their_____.",
    "answer": "Faith"
  },
  {
    "id": 2721,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:22",
    "question": "Nevertheless; whosoever puts his trust in the Lord the same shall be_____ up at the last day.",
    "answer": "Lifted"
  },
  {
    "id": 2722,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:23",
    "question": "Mormon wrote that he would show unto us that the people were brought into bondage, and none could deliver them but the Lord their God, even the God of Abraham and Isaac and of_____.",
    "answer": "Jacob"
  },
  {
    "id": 2723,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos23:24",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lord did deliver the people, and he did show forth his mighty_____.",
    "answer": "Power",
    "options": ["Rod", "Arm", "Power"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2724,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:25",
    "question": "The people did rejoice because of their deliverance; and while they were tilling the land of Helam, behold an army of the_____ came upon them.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 2725,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:27",
    "question": "Alma1 went forth and stood among the people and exhorted them that they should not be frightened; but that they should remember the_____ their God and he would deliver them.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 2726,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos23:28",
    "question": "The people began to cry unto the Lord that he would soften the hearts of the Lamanites, that they would spare them, and their wives and children.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2727,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos23:28",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lord did not hear the cries of the people because of their iniquities, and he did not soften the hearts of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2728,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos23:30",
    "question": "The armies of the Lamanites which had followed after the people of King Limhi were lost in the wilderness for_____ days.",
    "answer": "Many",
    "options": ["3", "4", "Many"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2729,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos23:31",
    "question": "The armies of the Lamanites found those priests of King Noah in a place they called Amulon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2730,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:32",
    "question": "What was the name of the priest that was the leader of the priests of King Noah?",
    "answer": "Amulon"
  },
  {
    "id": 2731,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:33",
    "question": "Amulon sent forth their wives, (who were the daughters of the_____), to plead with their brethren, that they should not destroy their husbands.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 2732,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos23:34",
    "question": "The Lamanites had compassion on Amulon and his brethren, and did not destroy them because of their_____.",
    "answer": "Wives",
    "options": ["Gold", "Silver", "Wives"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2733,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos23:35",
    "question": "Amulon and his brethren did join the Lamanites, and they were traveling in the wilderness in search of the land of Nephi, when they discovered the land of Helam.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2734,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:36",
    "question": "The Lamanites promised unto_____ and his brethren, that if they would show them the way which led to the land of Nephi that they would grant unto them their lives and liberty.",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 2735,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos23:37",
    "question": "After Alma1 had shown the Lamanites the way that led to the land of Nephi they did not keep their_____.",
    "answer": "Promise",
    "options": ["Vows", "Promise", "Word"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2736,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos23:38",
    "question": "The remainder of them went to the land of Nephi; and a part of them returned to the land of Helam.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2737,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:39",
    "question": "The king of the Lamanites granted unto_____ that he should be a king and a ruler over his people, who were in the land of Helam.",
    "answer": "Amulon"
  },
  {
    "id": 2738,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos24:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Amulon did not gain favor with the king of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2739,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos24:2",
    "question": "Because the Lamanites had taken possession of all the lands; the king of the Lamanites had appointed kings over all the lands.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2740,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:3",
    "question": "What was the name of the king of the Lamanites who was called after the name of his father and was a king over a numerous people? ",
    "answer": "Laman"
  },
  {
    "id": 2741,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos24:4",
    "question": "King Laman appointed_____ of the brethren of Amulon in every land; and thus the language of Nephi began to be taught among all the people of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Teachers",
    "options": ["Teachers", "Priests", "Professors"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2742,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos24:5",
    "question": "The Lamanites were a people who were friendly one with another; nevertheless they did know God.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2743,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:5",
    "question": "The brethren of Amulon did not teach the Lamanites anything concerning the Lord their God, neither the Law of_____.",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },
  {
    "id": 2744,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:5",
    "question": "The brethren of Amulon also did not teach the Lamanites anything concerning the words of_____. ",
    "answer": "Abinidi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2745,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos24:6",
    "question": "The brethren of Amulon taught the Lamanites that they should keep their record, and that they might write one to another.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2746,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:7",
    "question": "The Lamanites began to increase in riches, and began to trade with one another and wax great, and began to be a cunning and a_____ people, as to the wisdom of the world.",
    "answer": "Wise"
  },
  {
    "id": 2747,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:7",
    "question": "The Lamanites were a very cunning people, delighting in all manner of_____ and plunder, except it was among their own brethren.",
    "answer": "Wickedness"
  },
  {
    "id": 2748,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:8",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Amulon began to exercise authority over_____ and his brethren.",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 2749,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:9",
    "question": "Amulon knew that Alma1 had been one of King Noah’s priests, and that it was he that believed the words of_____.",
    "answer": "Abinidi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2750,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos24:9",
    "question": "Amulon began to exercise authority over Alma1 and the Nephites and put tasks upon them, and put task-masters over them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2751,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos24:10",
    "question": "And it came to pass that so great were the afflictions of the Nephites that they began to cry mightily to God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2752,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:11",
    "question": "Who commanded the Nephites to stop their cries to the Lord; that whosoever should be found calling upon God should be put to death?",
    "answer": "Amulon"
  },
  {
    "id": 2753,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos24:12",
    "question": "Alma1 and his people did not raise their voices to the Lord their God, but did pour out their_____ to him: and he did know the thoughts of their hearts.",
    "answer": "Hearts",
    "options": ["Souls", "Hearts", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2754,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos24:13",
    "question": "The voice of the Lord came to the people in their afflictions, saying:  Lift up your_____ and be of good comfort, for I know of the covenant which ye have made unto me.",
    "answer": "Heads",
    "options": ["Heads", "Arms", "Swords"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2755,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos24:14",
    "question": "The Lord did not ease the burdens of the Nephites which were put upon their shoulders.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2756,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:14",
    "question": "The Lord eased the burdens of the Nephites because he wanted them to know and stand as a witness that he does visit his people in their_____. ",
    "answer": "Afflictions"
  },
  {
    "id": 2757,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos24:15",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the burdens which were laid upon Alma1 and his brethren were made light; and they did submit cheerfully and with patience to all the will of the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2758,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:16",
    "question": "So great was their faith and the patience of the people of Alma1 that the voice of the Lord came unto them and said tomorrow he would deliver them from_____.",
    "answer": "Bondage"
  },
  {
    "id": 2759,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:19",
    "question": "The Lord caused that a deep_____ to come upon the Lamanites and all their tasks-masters were in a profound sleep.",
    "answer": "Sleep"
  },
  {
    "id": 2760,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:20",
    "question": "Alma1 and his people departed into the wilderness and after they had traveled all day they pitched their tents in a valley, and they called the valley_____, because he had led their way.",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 2761,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos24:21,22",
    "question": "Alma1 and all those that could speak lifted their voices in the praises of their God, and gave him thanks for delivering them from bondage in the valley of Alma1.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2762,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:23",
    "question": "Who told Alma1 to leave the valley and the land they were in because the Lamanites were in pursuit of them?",
    "answer": ["Lord", "God"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2763,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:25",
    "question": "After Alma1 and his people left the valley of Alma they traveled for twelve days and arrived in the land of_____; and King Mosiah did also receive them with joy.",
    "answer": "Zarahemla"
  },
  {
    "id": 2764,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos25:2",
    "question": "Zarahemla was a descendant of_____.",
    "answer": "Mulek"
  },
  {
    "id": 2765,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25:2",
    "question": "The word Mulekites never appears in the Book of Mormon text.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2766,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25",
    "question": "The word “Mulekites” only appears in the heading of Chapter#25 and never again in the entire Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2767,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25",
    "question": "Someone made up the name of “Mulekites” in the Book of Mormon and put it on the heading of Chapter #25.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2768,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25:2",
    "question": "There are no such people as Mulekites ever mentioned in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2769,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25:2",
    "question": "The so called “Mulekites' Were the people Zarahemla who were descendants of Mulek",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2770,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25:3",
    "question": "There were more Lamanites than the people of Nephi and of the people of Zarahemla put together.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2771,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos25:5",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Mosiah did read, and caused to be read, the records of King_____ to his people.",
    "answer": "Zeniff"
  },
  {
    "id": 2772,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25:5",
    "question": "King Mosiah read the record of King Zeniff from the time they left the land of Zarahemla until they returned again.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2773,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos25:6",
    "question": "King Mosiah also read the account of_____ and his brethren, and all their afflictions, from the time they left the land of Zarahemla until the time they returned again.",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 2774,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25:7",
    "question": "When King Mosiah had made an end of reading the records, his people who tarried in the land and struck with wonder and amazement.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2775,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos25:9",
    "question": "The people of King Mosiah were filled with sorrow, and even shed many_____ of sorrow because so many of their brethren had been slain by the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Tears"
  },
  {
    "id": 2776,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25:11",
    "question": "The people of King Mosiah were filled with pain and anguish for the welfare of the souls of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2777,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25:12",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the children of Amulon and his brethren, who had taken to wife the daughters of the Lamanites; were not displeased with the conduct of their fathers.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2778,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25:12",
    "question": "The children of Amulon and his brethren were so displeased with the conduct of their fathers, that they would no longer be called by the names of their fathers.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2779,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos25:12",
    "question": "The children of Amulon and his brethren took it upon themselves the name of Nephi, that they might be called the children of Nephi and be numbered among those who were_____.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 2780,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos25:13",
    "question": "All the people of Zarahemla were numbered with the Nephites; and this because the kingdom had been conferred upon none but those who were descendant’s of_____.",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2781,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos25:14",
    "question": "When King Mosiah had made an end of his speaking and reading to the people, he desired that_____ should also speak to the people.",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 2782,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos25:15",
    "question": "Alma1 did speak unto the people, going from one body to another, preaching unto the people repentance and_____ on the Lord.",
    "answer": "Faith"
  },
  {
    "id": 2783,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos25:16",
    "question": "Alma1 did exhort the people of King Limhi and his brethren, and all those that had been delivered out of bondage; that they should remember that it was the_____ that had delivered them.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 2784,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25:17",
    "question": "After Alma1 had taught the people many things and made an end to his speaking, King Limhi and all his people were desirous to be baptized.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2785,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos25:18",
    "question": "Alma1 did go forth into the water and baptize the people in the manner that he had baptized his brethren in the Waters of_____.",
    "answer": "Mormon"
  },
  {
    "id": 2786,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos25:19",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King_____ granted unto Alma1 that he might establish churches throughout the land of Zarahemla, and gave him power to ordain priests and teacher over every church.",
    "answer": "Mosiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 2787,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25:20",
    "question": "One of the reasons King Mosiah granted Alma1 to ordain priest and teachers throughout the land was because there were so many people that they could not all be taught by one or more persons",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2788,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25:21",
    "question": "Every different priest and teacher taught what they desired in their heart.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2789,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos25:22",
    "question": "Even though there were many churches throughout the land of Zarahemla, they were all one church of_____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 2790,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos25:23",
    "question": "And it came to pass that whosoever was desirous to take upon them the name of_____, or of God, they did join the churches of God.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 2791,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25:24",
    "question": "The Lord did not pour out his Spirit upon those that were baptized; therefore they were not blessed and did not prosper in the land.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2792,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that there were many of the rising generation that could not understand the words of King_____, because they had been little children when he had spoken to the people.",
    "answer": "Benjamin"
  },
  {
    "id": 2793,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:2",
    "question": "Many of the rising generation did not believe concerning the_____ of the dead, neither did they believe concerning the coming of Christ.",
    "answer": "Resurrection"
  },
  {
    "id": 2794,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos26:3",
    "question": "Because many of the rising generation did not believe what King Benjamin had taught, they could not understand the word of God; and their hearts were hardened.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2795,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos26:4",
    "question": "Many of the rising generation would not be baptized; neither would they join the church of God and they were a separate people as to their faith, and remained so ever after.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2796,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos26:4",
    "question": "Many of the rising generation remained in their carnal and _____state; for they would not call upon the Lord their God.",
    "answer": "Sinful",
    "options": ["Bad", "Lustful", "Sinful"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2797,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:5",
    "question": "In the reign of King_____ there were more people that did not believe in God; and because of dissensions among the brethren they became more numerous.",
    "answer": "Mosiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 2798,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:6",
    "question": "And it came to pass that those that did not belong to the church; did deceive many with their _____words, who were in the church.",
    "answer": "Flattering"
  },
  {
    "id": 2799,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos26:6",
    "question": "It became expedient that those that those who committed sin, that were in the church, should be admonished by the church.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2800,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos26:9",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma1 did not know what to do because there were many witnesses against the sinners, and people stood and testified of their iniquity in abundance.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2801,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:10",
    "question": "There had not any such thing happened before in the church; therefore_____ was troubled in spirit and he caused that they be brought before King Mosiah.",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 2802,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos26:12",
    "question": "King Mosiah said unto Alma1:  “Behold, I judge them not; therefore I deliver them into thy hands to be judged”.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2803,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:13",
    "question": "Because Alma1 was troubled in spirit; he went and inquired of the_____ what he should do concerning those that had sinned because he did not want to do judge wrong.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 2804,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:14",
    "question": "The Lord blessed Alma1 because of his exceeding faith in the words that had been said by his servant_____.",
    "answer": "Abinidi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2805,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos26:17,18",
    "question": "The Lord also blessed Alma1 because he had established a church; and because some of the people were willing to bear his name.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2806,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos26:19",
    "question": "The Lord blessed Alma1 because he had inquired of him concerning what to do with the_____.",
    "answer": "Transgressors",
    "options": [
      "Transgressors",
      "Righteous",
      "The People That Were Not Of The Church"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 2807,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:20",
    "question": "The Lord made a covenant with Alma1 that he would have_____ life if he would serve him and go forth in his name, and shall gather together his sheep.",
    "answer": "Eternal"
  },
  {
    "id": 2808,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos26:21",
    "question": "The Lord told Alma1 that those who will hear his_____ shall be his sheep; and he will receive them into the church and also receive them.",
    "answer": "Voice",
    "options": ["Shouts", "Voice", "Trumpet"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2809,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos26:22",
    "question": "The Lord told Alma1 that it was Alma1’s church and that he would forgive them freely if they took upon themselves his name.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2810,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:23",
    "question": "For it is I that have created them; and it is I that grants unto him that believe in me until the end, a place at my_____ hand.",
    "answer": "Right"
  },
  {
    "id": 2811,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos26:25",
    "question": "And it shall come to pass that when the_____ trumpet shall sound then shall they that never knew me come forth and shall stand before me.",
    "answer": "Second",
    "options": ["First", "Second", "Third"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2812,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos26:26",
    "question": "When the second trumpet shall make its sound those that did not believe in the Lord their God shall know that he is their Redeemer; but they would not be redeemed.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2813,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos26:27",
    "question": "After the second trumpet shall sound, the Lord will confess to those that came forward and did not believe in the Lord as their Redeemer that he never knew them; and they shall depart into an everlasting fire.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2814,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:27",
    "question": "The Lord has prepared an everlasting fire for the devil and his_____.",
    "answer": "Angels"
  },
  {
    "id": 2815,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos26:28",
    "question": "The Lord told Alma1 that he that will not hear his voice, the same shall he not receive into his church, and that he would not receive them at the last day.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2816,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:29",
    "question": "The Lord told Alma1: He that confesses his sins before him and the Lord, and repents in the sincerity of his_____, his shall you forgive, and I will forgive him also.",
    "answer": "Heart"
  },
  {
    "id": 2817,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:31",
    "question": "You shall also forgive one another your trespasses; for verily I say unto you, he that doesn’t forgive his neighbor’s trespasses when he says that he repents, the same has brought himself under_____.",
    "answer": "Condemnation"
  },
  {
    "id": 2818,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos26:32",
    "question": "Those of us that will not repent of our sins, the same shall not be numbered among the Lord’s people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2819,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:33",
    "question": "Alma1 wrote the words he had heard from the Lord that he might have them to judge the people of the church according to the commandments of_____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 2820,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos26:36",
    "question": "Those that did not confess their sins and repent of their iniquity, the same were not numbered among the people of the church, and their names were_____ out from the records.",
    "answer": "Blotted",
    "options": ["Erased", "Inked", "Blotted"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2821,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:37",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____ did regulate the affairs of the church; and they began again to have peace and to prosper exceedingly in the affairs of the church.",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 2822,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos26:38",
    "question": "Alma1 and his fellow laborers did walk in all diligence, teaching the word of God in all things, suffering all matter of afflictions, being persecuted by all those that were not of the church.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2823,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:39",
    "question": "Alma1 and his fellow laborers did admonish there brethren; and they were also admonished, every one by the word or_____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 2824,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos26:39",
    "question": "The Lord commanded those that had committed sins to_____ without ceasing, and to give thanks in all things.",
    "answer": "Pray",
    "options": ["Work", "Labor", "Pray"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2825,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:1",
    "question": "The persecutions which were inflicted on the church by the unbelievers became so great that the church began to murmur.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2826,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:1",
    "question": "The people of the church complained to Alma1 and to King_____, and King Mosiah consulted with his priests.",
    "answer": "Mosiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 2827,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos27:2",
    "question": "What did King Mosiah send out throughout all the land that there should not be any persecutions to those that did belong to the church of God?",
    "answer": "Proclamation",
    "options": ["Text Message", "Proclamation", "Letter"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2828,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:4",
    "question": "It was not a commandment that there should be no pride or any haughtiness to disturb the peace of the people; that every man should esteem his neighbor as himself.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2829,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:5",
    "question": "Everyone was to labor with their own hands for their support; even all the priests and teachers, and doing these things, they did have the grace of God in abundance.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2830,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "6,7",
    "question": "Because the Lord blessed the people they began to prosper and became numerous and began to scatter upon the face of the_____.",
    "answer": "Earth",
    "options": ["Earth", "World", "Globe"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2831,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:8",
    "question": "The sons of King Mosiah were numbered among the unbelievers.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2832,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:8",
    "question": "One of the sons of Alma1 was also numbered among the unbelievers and his name was _____, he being called after his father.",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 2833,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:8",
    "question": "Alma the Younger was a very wicked and idolatrous man; and he was a man of many words and began to speak flattering words to the people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2834,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos27:8",
    "question": "Because of the words of Alma the Younger he led many of the people to do after the manner of his_____.",
    "answer": "Iniquities",
    "options": ["Pleasures", "Ways", "Iniquities"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2835,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:9",
    "question": "Alma the Younger became a great hindrance to the prosperity of the church of God; stealing away the_____ of the people and causing much dissension among them.",
    "answer": "Hearts"
  },
  {
    "id": 2836,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:9",
    "question": "Because of the words that Alma the Younger flattered the people with, he gave a chance to the enemy of_____ to exercise his power over them.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 2837,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:10",
    "question": "Alma the Younger and the sons of King Mosiah went about secretly seeking to destroy the church of God, and to lead astray the people of the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2838,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:11",
    "question": "Who appeared to Alma the Younger and to the sons of King Mosiah as they went about rebelling against God?  An angel of the ",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 2839,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:11",
    "question": "The angel of the Lord spoke as it were a voice of thunder, which caused the earth to shake upon which Alma the Younger and the sons of King Mosiah stood.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2840,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:12",
    "question": "So great was the astonishment to Alma the Younger and the sons of King Mosiah that they fell to the earth, and could not understand the words which the_____ spoke to them.",
    "answer": "Angel"
  },
  {
    "id": 2841,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:13",
    "question": "The Angel asked Alma the Younger why he persecuted the church of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2842,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:14",
    "question": "Alma the Elder had prayed with much_____ concerning his son that he may come to the knowledge of the truth.",
    "answer": "Faith"
  },
  {
    "id": 2843,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:14",
    "question": "The Angel of the Lord came to convince Alma the Younger of the power and authority of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2844,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos27:14",
    "question": "The Angel of the Lord also came to convince Alma the Younger that the prayers of his_____ might be answered according to their faith in him.",
    "answer": "Servants",
    "options": ["Subjects", "Servants", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2845,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:15",
    "question": "Who sent the Angel to say the things he said to Alma the Younger?",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 2846,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:16",
    "question": "The Angel of the Lord told Alma the Younger to go his way and to not seek to destroy the church of God no more.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2847,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:18",
    "question": "Alma the Younger and the sons of King Mosiah fell a second time to the earth; they knew that there was nothing except the power of God that could shake the earth and cause it to_____.",
    "answer": "Tremble"
  },
  {
    "id": 2848,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:19",
    "question": "The astonishment of Alma the Younger was so great that he became dumb, that he could not open his_____; and he became weak and could not move his hands.",
    "answer": "Mouth"
  },
  {
    "id": 2849,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos27:19",
    "question": "Who was taken and laid before his father?",
    "answer": "Alma The Younger",
    "options": ["Sons Of King Mosiah", "Alma The Younger", "Helaman"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2850,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:20",
    "question": "When the sons of King Mosiah rehearsed to Alma the Elder what had happened to them, he wasn’t happy.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2851,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:20",
    "question": "Alma the Elder knew that it was the power to God that could only have stuck Alma the Younger dumb, therefore, he rejoiced.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2852,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:21",
    "question": "Alma the Elder caused that the people gather together so they might witness what the_____ had done to his son.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 2853,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:22",
    "question": "Who caused that the priests should assemble themselves together to pray and to fast for Alma the Younger?",
    "answer": "Elder"
  },
  {
    "id": 2854,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:22",
    "question": "The_____ prayed to the Lord their God that he would open the mouth of Alma the Younger, that he might speak, and also that his limbs might receive their strength.",
    "answer": "Priest"
  },
  {
    "id": 2855,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:22",
    "question": "The priests also prayed to the Lord their God that the _____of the people might be opened to see and know of the goodness and glory of God.",
    "answer": "Eyes"
  },
  {
    "id": 2856,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos27:23",
    "question": "How many days and nights did the priests fast and pray to the Lord their God that the limbs of Alma the Younger might received their strength.",
    "answer": "Two Days And Two Nights",
    "options": [
      "One Day And One Night",
      "Two Days And Two Nights",
      "Three Days And Three Nights"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 2857,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:23",
    "question": "When Alma the Younger regained his strength he began to speak to the priests and bid them to be of good comfort.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2858,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:24",
    "question": "Alma the Younger also told the priests that he had repented of his sins, and had been redeemed by the Lord and that he was born of the Spirit.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2859,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:25",
    "question": "The Lord told Alma the Younger that all_____ and all nations, kindreds, tongues and people must be born again; yea born of God.",
    "answer": "Mankind"
  },
  {
    "id": 2860,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:25",
    "question": "We must all be born again of God, changed from our carnal and fallen state, to a state of_____, being redeemed of God, becoming his sons and daughters.",
    "answer": "Righteousness"
  },
  {
    "id": 2861,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:26",
    "question": "Unless we are changed and become new people we can not inherit the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2862,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:29",
    "question": "Alma the Younger said that his soul had been redeemed from the gall of_____ and bonds of iniquity.",
    "answer": "Bitterness"
  },
  {
    "id": 2863,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos27:29",
    "question": "Alma the Younger said that he was in the darkest_____; but that he now beheld the marvelous light of God.",
    "answer": "Abyss",
    "options": ["Black Hole", "Abyss", "Alley"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2864,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:30",
    "question": "Alma the Younger said that he had rejected his Redeemer but that now he knew that he would come and that he remembers every creature that he has created.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2865,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:30",
    "question": "According to Alma the Younger; only the righteous shall the Lord manifest himself to them.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2866,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:31",
    "question": "Every_____ shall bow, and every tongue shall confess before him that he is God.",
    "answer": "Knee"
  },
  {
    "id": 2867,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:31",
    "question": "Those that lived in the world without God in their lives; shall confess that the judgment of an everlasting punishment is just upon them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2868,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:31",
    "question": "Those that receive the judgment of an everlasting punishment shall quake, and tremble, and shrink beneath the glance of the Lords all-_____ eye.",
    "answer": "Searching"
  },
  {
    "id": 2869,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:32",
    "question": "And it came to pass that from this time forward Alma the Younger and the Sons of King Mosiah began to preach the word of God in much tribulation.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2870,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:32",
    "question": "Alma the Younger and the Sons of King Mosiah did not suffer much tribulation or persecution from the unbelievers, and were smitten by many of them.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2871,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:33",
    "question": "Alma the Younger and the Sons of King Mosiah confirmed their faith unto the people, and exhorting them with much travail to keep the_____ of God.",
    "answer": "Commandments"
  },
  {
    "id": 2872,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:34",
    "question": "King Mosiah had how many sons that were with Alma the Younger preaching the word of God?",
    "answer": "Four"
  },
  {
    "id": 2873,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:34",
    "question": "The names of King Mosiah’s sons were:  Ammon, Aaron, Omner, and_____.",
    "answer": "Himni"
  },
  {
    "id": 2874,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:35",
    "question": "Alma the Younger and the sons of King Mosiah traveled throughout the land of_____, zealously striving to repair all the injuries they had done to the church of God.",
    "answer": "Zarahemla"
  },
  {
    "id": 2875,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:36",
    "question": "Alma the Younger and the Sons of King Mosiah were_____ in the hands of God in bringing many to the knowledge of the truth and to the knowledge of their Redeemer.",
    "answer": "Instruments"
  },
  {
    "id": 2876,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:37",
    "question": "Alma the Younger and the Sons of King Mosiah did publish peace; they did publish good tidings of good; and they did declare unto the people that the_____ reigns.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 2877,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos28:1",
    "question": "The Sons of King Mosiah desired from King Mosiah permission to preach the things which they had heard, and they might impart the word of God to their brethren, the_____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 2878,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos28:2",
    "question": "The Sons of King Mosiah did not want to bring the Lamanites to the knowledge of the Lord their God.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2879,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos28:2",
    "question": "The Sons of King Mosiah wanted to convince the Lamanites of the iniquity of their fathers; and that they might cure them of the hatred towards the_____.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 2880,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos28:2",
    "question": "The Sons of King Mosiah also wanted to convince the Lamanites to become friendly to one another, and that there should be no more contentions in all the land the Lord had given them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2881,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos28:3",
    "question": "The Sons of King Mosiah were desirous that _____ should be declared to every creature, because they could not bear that any human should perish.",
    "answer": "Salvation",
    "options": ["Cleanliness", "Neatness", "Salvation"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2882,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos28:3",
    "question": "The very thought that any_____ should endure endless torment did cause the Sons of King Mosiah to quake and tremble.",
    "answer": "Soul",
    "options": ["Creature", "Soul", "Person"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2883,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos28:4",
    "question": "The Spirit of the Lord did work upon the Sons of King Mosiah because they were the vilest of sinners.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2884,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos28:4",
    "question": "The Lord saw fit to spare the Sons of King Mosiah in his infinite_____.",
    "answer": "Mercy",
    "options": ["Mercy", "Kindness", "Thoughtfulness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2885,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos28:5",
    "question": "How many days did the Sons of King Mosiah plead with him that they might go to the land of Nephi to preach the word of the Lord their God?",
    "answer": "Many",
    "options": ["One", "Two", "Many"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2886,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos28:6",
    "question": "King Mosiah inquired of the_____ if he should let his sons go up among the Lamanites to preach the word of God.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 2887,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos28:7",
    "question": "The Lord told King Mosiah not to let his sons go to the land of Nephi to preach his word among the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2888,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos28:7",
    "question": "The Lord told King Mosiah that many of the Lamanites would believe the words of his sons and that they shall have eternal life.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2889,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos28:7",
    "question": "The Lord told King Mosiah that he would_____ his sons out of the hands of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Deliver",
    "options": ["Protect", "Look Out After", "Deliver"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2890,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos28:8,9",
    "question": "Because King Mosiah was worried for the welfare of his sons, he did not let them go up to the land of Nephi to preach the word of the Lord.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2891,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos28:10",
    "question": "King Mosiah had no one to confer the kingdom upon because there were not any of his sons who would accept the_____.",
    "answer": "Kingdom"
  },
  {
    "id": 2892,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos28:11",
    "question": "King Mosiah had the records which were engraved on the plates of brass and also the Plates of_____, and all the other things he had kept and preserved according to the commandments of God.",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2893,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos28:11",
    "question": "What kind of metal were the plates made of that the people of King Limhi found?",
    "answer": "Gold",
    "options": ["Gold", "Brass", "Copper"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2894,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos28:11",
    "question": "King Mosiah also had the plates of gold that which had been found by the people of_____, which were delivered to him by the hand of King Limhi.  King ",
    "answer": "Limhi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2895,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos28:12",
    "question": "The people of King Mosiah had great anxiety because they were desirous beyond measure to know concerning those people that had been destroyed.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2896,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos28:13",
    "question": "King Mosiah translated the gold plates found by the people of King Limhi by the means of_____ stones which were fastened into two rims of a bow.",
    "answer": "Two",
    "options": ["Two", "Three", "Four"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2897,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos28:15",
    "question": "Who had prepared the two stones which were fastened into two rims for the purpose of translating languages?  The Lord, ",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 2898,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos28:15",
    "question": "The two stones and two rims were prepared by the Lord that he should discover to every creature who should possess the land of the iniquities and abominations of his people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2899,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos28:16",
    "question": "Whosoever used the two stones which were fastened into two rims is called a_____, after the manner of old times.",
    "answer": "Seer"
  },
  {
    "id": 2900,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos28:17",
    "question": "King Mosiah gave his people an account of the people that had been destroyed after he had finished translating the gold plates.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2901,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos28:17",
    "question": "The gold plates contained the account of the people back to the building of the great_____, at the time the Lord had confounded the language.",
    "answer": "Tower"
  },
  {
    "id": 2902,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos28:17",
    "question": "The gold plates also contained the account way back to the creation of what person of old times?",
    "answer": "Adam"
  },
  {
    "id": 2903,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos28:19",
    "question": "Mormon tells us in the Book of Mosiah; that it is expedient that all people should know the things which are written in the account of the gold plates.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2904,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos28:20",
    "question": "King Mosiah took the plates of brass, and all the things which he had kept and conferred them to whom?",
    "answer": "Younger"
  },
  {
    "id": 2905,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos28:20",
    "question": "In what Book of Mormon book is Alma the Younger made custodian of the 24 plates and other records?",
    "answer": "Mosiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 2906,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos28:20",
    "question": "King Mosiah also conferred all the records, and also the interpreters to Alma the Younger and commanded him that he should keep and preserve them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2907,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos28:20",
    "question": "King Mosiahdid not command Alma the Younger to keep a record of the people.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2908,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos28:20",
    "question": "King Mosiah commanded that all the things he had conferred upon Alma the Younger to be handed down from one generation to another, even as they had been handed down from the time that _____ left Jerusalem.",
    "answer": "Lehi"
  },
  {
    "id": 2909,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:2",
    "question": "Which son of King Mosiah did the people wish to be their king and ruler?",
    "answer": "Aaron",
    "options": ["Ammon", "Aaron", "Himni"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2910,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:3",
    "question": "Aaron did not want to take upon him the kingdom; neither were any of the Sons of Mosiah willing to take upon them the kingdom.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2911,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:2,Mos29:7",
    "question": "King Mosiah told the people that the kingdom rightfully belonged to his son _____; and if another was appointed in his stead he feared that contentions would rise among the people.",
    "answer": "Aaron"
  },
  {
    "id": 2912,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:7",
    "question": "King Mosiah also feared that contentions among his people would cause wars and the shedding of much blood and pervert the ways of the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2913,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:11",
    "question": "Because none of his sons wanted the kingdom; King Mosiah told the people that he would be their king the rest of his days and that they should appoint_____ to judge this people according to the law.",
    "answer": "Judges"
  },
  {
    "id": 2914,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:11",
    "question": "King Mosiah said that they should appoint judges that will judge the people according to his commandments.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2915,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:12",
    "question": "King Mosiah said that it is better that a man be should be judged of_____, rather than of man.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 2916,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:12",
    "question": "King Mosiah said that the judgments of God are always _____.",
    "answer": "Just",
    "options": ["Ok", "Righteous", "Just"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2917,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:12",
    "question": "King Mosiah said that the judgments of men are not always just, like that of the Lord’s.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2918,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:13",
    "question": "King Mosiah told the people that if it was possible to have just men to be their kings, who would establish the laws of God, who would do even as his father did whose name was King_____.",
    "answer": "Benjamin"
  },
  {
    "id": 2919,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:14",
    "question": "King Mosiah said that he himself had labored with all the power and faculties which he possessed, to teach them the commandments of_____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 2920,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:14",
    "question": "King Mosiah taught the people that there should be no wars, no stealing, no plundering and no_____ and no manner of iniquity.",
    "answer": "Murdering",
    "options": ["Drinking", "Bad Mouthing", "Murdering"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2921,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:15",
    "question": "King Mosiah told the people that whosoever had committed iniquity, he had punished them according the_____ which was given to them by their fathers.",
    "answer": "Law"
  },
  {
    "id": 2922,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:16",
    "question": "King Mosiah told the people that because all_____ are not just; it was not expedient that they should have a king or kings to rule over them.",
    "answer": "Men"
  },
  {
    "id": 2923,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:17",
    "question": "King Mosiah told the people:”For behold; how much iniquity does one wicked king cause to be committed, and what great destruction!",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2924,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:18",
    "question": "King Mosiah told the people to remember the iniquities that King Noah had done; and because of his iniquities they were brought into bondage.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2925,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:19",
    "question": "King Mosiah told the people that if it was not for the interposition of their all-wise_____, they must have remained in bondage until now.",
    "answer": "Creator",
    "options": ["Creator", "Nephi", "King Benjamin"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2926,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:19",
    "question": "The word interposition only appears once in the Book of Mormon; and it appears in the Book of_____.",
    "answer": "Mosiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 2927,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:20",
    "question": "The Lord delivered the people because they did humble themselves before _____.",
    "answer": "The Lord",
    "options": ["King Mosiah", "King Benjamin", "The Lord"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2928,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:20",
    "question": "Because the people cried mightily to the Lord, he did deliver them out of_____ from the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Bondage"
  },
  {
    "id": 2929,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:20",
    "question": "King Mosiah said that the Lord in all cases does work his power among all the children of men, extending the arm of mercy towards them that put their_____ in him.",
    "answer": "Trust"
  },
  {
    "id": 2930,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:21",
    "question": "King Mosiah told the people that they could not dethrone an iniquitous king save it be through much contention, and the shedding of much_____.",
    "answer": "Blood",
    "options": ["Skin", "Blood", "Scalps"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2931,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:22",
    "question": "King Mosiah said that an iniquitous king has_____ in iniquity, and tears up the laws of those who have reigned in righteousness before him.",
    "answer": "Friends",
    "options": ["Friends", "Power", "The Right Of Way"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2932,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:23",
    "question": "King Mosiah said that an iniquitous king sends laws among them after the manner of his wickedness.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2933,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:23",
    "question": "King Mosiah told the people that an unrighteous king perverts the ways of_____.",
    "answer": "Righteousness"
  },
  {
    "id": 2934,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:25",
    "question": "Who did King Mosiah say gave the laws to there fathers’ to give to them.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 2935,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:26",
    "question": "King Mosiah told the people that it is common for the lesser part of the people to desire that which is not right.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2936,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:27",
    "question": "King Mosiah said to the people that if the time comes that the_____ of the people do choose iniquity; then is the time that the judgments of God will come upon them.",
    "answer": "Voice"
  },
  {
    "id": 2937,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:28",
    "question": "King Mosiah told the people that if the judges they had appointed did not judge according to the law, they should cause that they may be judged of a_____ judge.",
    "answer": "Higher",
    "options": ["Better", "Wiser", "Higher"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2938,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:29",
    "question": "King Mosiah said that if the higher judges do not judge righteous judgments; they should cause that a small number of the lower judges gather together and judge them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2939,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:30",
    "question": "King Mosiah commanded the people to have no king and to do all the things that he had told them because of the fear of the_____.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 2940,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:30",
    "question": "King Mosiah told the people that if they commit sins and iniquities they shall be answered upon their own_____.",
    "answer": "Heads"
  },
  {
    "id": 2941,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:32",
    "question": "King Mosiah desired that the people be equal in the land; especially among his people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2942,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:32",
    "question": "King Mosiah desired that the land be a land of_____, and every man may enjoy his rights and privileges alike.",
    "answer": "Liberty",
    "options": ["Wealth", "Liberty", "Freedom"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2943,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:34",
    "question": "King Mosiah told the people many more things which ought not to be; but that the burden should come upon all the people, that every man might bear his part.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2944,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:35",
    "question": "King Mosiah also unfolded unto the people all the disadvantages they labor under, by having an unrighteous_____ to rule over them.",
    "answer": "King"
  },
  {
    "id": 2945,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:38",
    "question": "Because of the things that King Mosiah said concerning unrighteous kings; the people relinquished their desires for a king.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2946,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:38",
    "question": "The people became exceedingly anxious that every man should have an equal chance throughout all the land; and every man expressed a willingness to answer for their own_____.",
    "answer": "Sins",
    "options": ["Thoughts", "Sins", "Crimes"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2947,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:39",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people assembled themselves together in bodies throughout all the land, to cast their_____, concerning who should be their judges.",
    "answer": "Voices",
    "options": ["Votes", "Ballets", "Voices"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2948,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:40",
    "question": "The people did not wax strong in the love towards King Mosiah; and they did not esteem him more over any other man.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2949,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:40",
    "question": "King Mosiah did not delight in the shedding of blood and had established peace throughout the land.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2950,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:40",
    "question": "The people esteemed King _____ exceedingly beyond measure because he had granted unto his people that they should be delivered from all manner of bondage.",
    "answer": "Mosiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 2951,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:41",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people did appoint judges to rule over them, or to be judged according to the_____.",
    "answer": "Law",
    "options": ["Commandments", "Rules", "Law"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2952,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:42",
    "question": "Who did the people appoint to be there first chief judge? ",
    "answer": "Younger"
  },
  {
    "id": 2953,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:42",
    "question": "Alma the Younger was also a high priest because Alma the Elder had conferred that office upon him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2954,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:42",
    "question": "Who had given Alma the Younger charge concerning all the affairs of the church?",
    "answer": "Elder"
  },
  {
    "id": 2955,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:43",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma the Younger did walk in the ways of the Lord, and he did keep his commandments, and did judge righteous judgments.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2956,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:40,47",
    "question": "Who was the last king of the people of Nephi?",
    "answer": "Mosiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 2957,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:44",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the reign of the Judges commenced throughout the land of_____, among all the people who were called Nephites.",
    "answer": "Zarahemla"
  },
  {
    "id": 2958,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:45",
    "question": "Alma the Elder lived to be_____ years old before he died, having lived to fulfil the commandments of God.",
    "answer": "82",
    "options": ["72", "82", "92"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2959,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:46",
    "question": "How many years did King Mosiah reign for before he passed away?",
    "answer": "33",
    "options": ["23", "33", "43"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2960,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:46",
    "question": "How old was King Mosiah when he passed away?",
    "answer": "63",
    "options": ["63", "73", "83"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2961,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:47",
    "question": "King Mosiah left his son Orihah to reign after him",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2962,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:47",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the reign of the kings over the people of Nephi ended; and so did the days of Alma the_____, who was the founder of their church.",
    "answer": "Elder"
  },
  {
    "id": 2963,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:46-47­",
    "question": "Who was the last king of the Nephites?",
    "answer": "Mosiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 2964,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma1:1",
    "question": "In what year of the judges did King Mosiahdie?_____",
    "answer": "1",
    "options": ["1", "(2)", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2965,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:1",
    "question": "In the Book of Alma:  Mormon wrote that King Mosiah had “warred a good warfare, walking uprightly before God”.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2966,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma1:2",
    "question": "In the first year in the reign of Alma in the judgment-seat, there was a man brought before him to be judged, a man who was_____, and was noted for much strength.",
    "answer": "Large",
    "options": ["Small", "Overweight", "Large"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2967,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:3",
    "question": "The man that was brought forth to Alma to be judged had gone about among the people, preaching to them which he determined to be the word of_____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 2968,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:3",
    "question": "The man was also bearing down against the church; declaring that every_____ and teacher should become popular; and that they should not labor with their hands.",
    "answer": "Priest"
  },
  {
    "id": 2969,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:3",
    "question": "The man also declared that every priest and teacher should be supported by whom?  The ",
    "answer": "people"
  },
  {
    "id": 2970,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:4",
    "question": "The large man also testified unto the people that all mankind should be saved in the_____ day. And that they need not fear or tremble.",
    "answer": "Last"
  },
  {
    "id": 2971,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:4",
    "question": "The large man also said that the Lord had created all men, and had also redeemed all men; and, in the end, all men should have eternal life.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2972,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma1:5",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the large man did teach these things so much that many of the _____ believed his words, that they began to support him and give him money.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["Nephites", "Priests", "Lamanites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2973,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:6",
    "question": "The large man began to be lifted up in the pride of his heart, and to wear_____ apparel.",
    "answer": "Costly"
  },
  {
    "id": 2974,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:6",
    "question": "The large man began to establish a church after the manner of his preaching.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2975,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:7",
    "question": "And it came to pass that as the large man was going about the land, he met a man who belonged to the church of_____, and he was teacher in the church.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 2976,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:7",
    "question": "The large man started to contend with the man of the church sharply, that he might lead away the people of the church; but the man withstood him, admonishing him with the words of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2977,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma1:8",
    "question": "What was the name of the man that admonished the large man with his words?",
    "answer": "Gideon",
    "options": ["Abinidi", "Samuel The Lamanite", "Gideon"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2978,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma1:8",
    "question": "Gideon was the man that was an instrument in the hands of God in delivering the people of King_____ out of bondage.",
    "answer": "Limhi",
    "options": ["Benjamin", "Limhi", "Mosiah"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2979,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma1:9",
    "question": "The large man was wroth with Gideon; because Gideon was stricken with many years he could not defend himself and the large man slew him with his_____.",
    "answer": "Sword",
    "options": ["Sword", "Knife", "Tomahawk"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2980,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:10",
    "question": "The large man was taken by the people to what Nephites’ judge to be judged according to the crimes which he had committed? ",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 2981,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma1:11",
    "question": "The large man stood before Alma2 and pleaded for himself with much_____.",
    "answer": "Boldness",
    "options": ["Arrogance", "Moxie", "Boldness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2982,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:12",
    "question": "What did Alma2 say to the large man that he had introduced to the people for the first time?",
    "answer": "Priestcraft"
  },
  {
    "id": 2983,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:12",
    "question": "Alma2 told the large man that he was not only guilty of priestcraft, but had endeavored to enforce it by the sword.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2984,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:12",
    "question": "What did Alma2 say to the large man would prove to be the entire destruction of the people if they would to embrace it?",
    "answer": "Priestcraft"
  },
  {
    "id": 2985,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:13",
    "question": "Alma2 told the large man that he had not only shed the blood of a righteous man, but the blood of a man that had done much good among the people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2986,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:14",
    "question": "Alma did not condemn the large man to die according to the law which was given to them by King Mosiah.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2987,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:15",
    "question": "The name of the large man who had slew Gideon with his sword was_____.",
    "answer": "Nehor"
  },
  {
    "id": 2988,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:15",
    "question": "What was the name of the hill which the people took Nehor to die; and he suffered an ignominious death?",
    "answer": "Manti"
  },
  {
    "id": 2989,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:15",
    "question": "Before Nehor died he acknowledge between the heavens and the earth that what he had taught the people was contrary to the word of_____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 2990,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:16",
    "question": "When Nehor died it put an end to priestcrafts.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2991,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma1:16",
    "question": "There were many people who loved the_____ things of the world, and they went forth preaching false doctrines in order to get rich and to obtain honor from the people.",
    "answer": "Vain",
    "options": ["Good", "Pretty", "Vain"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2992,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:17",
    "question": "During the time of Alma2 as the chief judge, liars were punished; therefore they pretended to preach according to their belief.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2993,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:17",
    "question": "During the time of Alma the chief judge he could punish people for their beliefs.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 2994,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:18",
    "question": "Murder was punishable by death during the time that Alma2 the chief judge was the peoples’ judge.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2995,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:19",
    "question": "And it came to pass that those that did not belong to the church of God began to persecute those that did belong to the church of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 2996,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma1:22",
    "question": "Many of those that did not belong to the church of God began to be proud and contend with their adversaries, even unto blows; they would smite one another with their_____.",
    "answer": "Fists",
    "options": ["Swords", "Fists", "Knives"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2997,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma1:23",
    "question": "The fighting between the people of the church and those that were not of the church occurred in what year of Alma2’s reign?",
    "answer": "2nd",
    "options": ["1st", "2nd", "3rd"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2998,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma1:24",
    "question": "Because of the fighting many of the peoples hearts were hardened, and their names were_____ out, and they were remembered no more among the people of God.",
    "answer": "Blotted",
    "options": ["Erased", "Scratch", "Blotted"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2999,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:25",
    "question": "The people of the church suffered much persecution; nevertheless, they were_____ and immovable in keeping the commandments of God.",
    "answer": "Steadfast"
  },
  {
    "id": 3000,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:26",
    "question": "During this time in Nephite history all the people were equal, and they did all labor, every man according to his own strength.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3001,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:27",
    "question": "The people imparted of their substance, every man according to that which he had, to the poor, and the needy, and the_____; and they did not were costly apparel.",
    "answer": "Afflicted"
  },
  {
    "id": 3002,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:29",
    "question": "Because of the steadiness of the people of the church they began to be exceedingly rich, having abundance of all things whatsoever they stood in need of.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3003,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:30",
    "question": "Because of their prosperity the people did not send any away that were naked, or that were hungry, or that were sick.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3004,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:31",
    "question": "The people that did not belong to the church were more wealthy than the people that did belong to the church of God.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3005,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:32",
    "question": "Those who did not belong to the church of God indulge in sorceries, idolatry or idleness, and in babblings.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3006,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:32",
    "question": "The law was not enforced on the people that did wickedness and committed robberies.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3007,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma1:33",
    "question": "And it came to pass that by exercising the law upon the people that committed crimes; people began to not commit crimes, and therefore, there was peace again among the people of_____.",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["Lehi", "Nephi", "Samuel The Lamanite"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3008,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:2",
    "question": "During the fifth year of the reign of the judges there began to be contention among the people of Nephi.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3009,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma2:1",
    "question": "What was the name of the man that came among the Nephites during the fifth year of the reign of the judges that was very cunning and wise as to the wisdom of the world?",
    "answer": "Amilici"
  },
  {
    "id": 3010,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:15 & Alma2:1",
    "question": "Amilici was after the order of_____ who had slew Gideon and was executed according to the law.",
    "answer": "Nehor"
  },
  {
    "id": 3011,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma2:2",
    "question": "Because Amilici was very cunning he drew away many people and they began to be very powerful.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3012,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma2:2",
    "question": "The very powerful people that Amilici had on his side desired to make him the_____ over the people of Nephi.",
    "answer": "King"
  },
  {
    "id": 3013,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma2:3",
    "question": "The people of the church of God were alarmed because they knew that according to Nephite law, such things- as electing a king must be established by the voice of the people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3014,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma2:4",
    "question": "Amlici was not a wicked man and did not want to destroy the church of God.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3015,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma2:4",
    "question": "Amlici is considered to be one of the four Anti-Christ’ in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3016,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma2:7",
    "question": "The voice of the people did not favor_____ and he was not made king over the people.",
    "answer": "Amlici"
  },
  {
    "id": 3017,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma2:9,10",
    "question": "Amlici was made king over some of the people and he stirred his people to anger against their brethren and to take arms against them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3018,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma2:10",
    "question": "Amlici wanted to make some of the Nephites as his_____.",
    "answer": "Subjects",
    "options": ["Subjects", "Slaves", "Laborers"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3019,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma2:11",
    "question": "The people that were under the rule of Amlici were called_____; and the rest of the people were called Nephites, or the people of God.",
    "answer": "Amlicites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3020,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma2:12",
    "question": "The Nephites armed themselves with cimeters, stones, slings, and with_____, to go to battle against the Amlicites.",
    "answer": "Swords",
    "options": ["Guns", "Axes", "Swords"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3021,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma2:16",
    "question": "Because_____ was the chief judge and governor of the Nephites; he went at the head of his armies to do battle with Amlici and his armies.",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 3022,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma2:18",
    "question": "Who strengthened the hand of the Nephites that they slew many of the Amlicites?",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 3023,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma2:20",
    "question": "When Alma and his armies could no longer pursue Amlici and his armies they pitched their tents in the valley of_____ that was called after the name of the man that Nehor had slain with his sword.",
    "answer": "Gideon"
  },
  {
    "id": 3024,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma2:21",
    "question": "Alma sent spies to follow the remnant of the Amlicites that he might know of their plans and their plots.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3025,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma2:24",
    "question": "The spies that Alma sent to watch the Amlicites were astonished because the Amlicites had joined forces with the_____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["Zoramites", "Lamanites", "Ismaelites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3026,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma2:26",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Nephites departed out of the valley of Gideon towards their city, which was the city of_____.",
    "answer": "Zarahemla",
    "options": ["Sidon", "Zarahemla", "Minon"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3027,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma2:27",
    "question": "As the Nephites were crossing the river_____, the Lamanites and Amlicites, which were as numerous as the sands of the sea; came upon them to destroy them.",
    "answer": "Sidon"
  },
  {
    "id": 3028,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma2:28",
    "question": "Because the Nephites had prayed mightily to the Lord, he heard their cries and did strengthen them and the Lamanites and Amlicites did fall before them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3029,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma2:29",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma2 fought with_____ with the sword, face to face and contended mightily, one with another.",
    "answer": "Amlici"
  },
  {
    "id": 3030,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma2:30",
    "question": "Because Alma2 was a man of God he exercised much faith and cried to the Lord to spare his life so that he could be an instrument in his hands and preserve the people of_____.",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 3031,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma2:31",
    "question": "What kind of weapon of war did Alma2 use to slay Amlici?",
    "answer": "Sword",
    "options": ["Knife", "Gun", "Sword"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3032,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma2:31",
    "question": "Alma2 was strengthened by the Lord and he slew_____ with his sword.",
    "answer": "Amlici"
  },
  {
    "id": 3033,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma2:32",
    "question": "Alma2 also contended with the king of the Lamanites but he fled and sent his guards to contend with Alma2",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3034,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma2:37",
    "question": "What is the name of the wilderness that was infested by wild and ravenous beasts that the Lamanites and Amlicites fled to?",
    "answer": "Hermounts"
  },
  {
    "id": 3035,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma2:38",
    "question": "Many of the Lamanites and Amlicites did not die because of their wounds when the fled into the part of the wilderness called Hermouts",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3036,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma2:38",
    "question": "Many of the dead Lamanites bodies were devoured by the wild beasts and also by what birds of prey?",
    "answer": "Vultures",
    "options": ["Hawks", "Eagles", "Vultures"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3037,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma3:3",
    "question": "And it came to pass that many of the bodies of the Lamanites and Amlicites who had been slain were cast into the waters of Sidon and their bones are in the depths of the_____.",
    "answer": "Sea"
  },
  {
    "id": 3038,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma3:4",
    "question": "What color was the mark that the Amlicites had marked themselves on the forehead to distinguish them from the Nephites?",
    "answer": "Red",
    "options": ["Red", "White", "Blue"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3039,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma3:4",
    "question": "Not only had the Amlicites mark themselves with the color red on their foreheads they had also shaved their heads like the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3040,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma3:",
    "question": "The heads of the Lamanites were shaved and they were naked except for the parts that were covered by their armor.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3041,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma3:6",
    "question": "The skins of the Lamanites were_____, according the mark which was set upon their fathers, which was a curse upon them because of their transgression and rebellion against their brethren.",
    "answer": "Dark",
    "options": ["Black", "Brown", "Dark"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3042,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma3:6",
    "question": "The names of the brothers that the Lamanites fathers rebelled against were-Nephi, Jacob, Joseph, and_____.",
    "answer": "Sam"
  },
  {
    "id": 3043,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma3:7",
    "question": "The Lord God set a mark upon Laman and Lemuel, and also the sons of Ismael, and the Daughters of_____.",
    "answer": "Ismael"
  },
  {
    "id": 3044,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma3:8",
    "question": "The Lord set a mark upon the Lamanites that their seed might be distinguished from the seed of their brethren, that thereby he might preserve his people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3045,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma3:8",
    "question": "The Lord also set a mark upon the Lamanites that they might not mix and believe in the incorrect_____ of their fathers; which would prove their destruction.",
    "answer": "Traditions",
    "options": ["Religion", "Beliefs", "Traditions"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3046,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma3:9",
    "question": "And it came to pass that whosoever did mingle his seed with that of the_____ did bring the same curse upon his seed.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3047,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma3:11",
    "question": "Those that believed in those records which were brought out of Jerusalem, and also in the traditions of their fathers were called Lamanites.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3048,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma3:11",
    "question": "Those that believed in the correct traditions of their fathers according to the records which were brought from Jerusalem and kept the commandments of God were called_____.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3049,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma3:12",
    "question": "What is the name of the people that have kept the records which are true of their people, and also of the Lamanite people called?",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3050,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma3:14",
    "question": "The word of the Lord was fulfilled when he told Nephi:”the Lamanites have I cursed, and I will set a mark on them that they and their seed may be separated from thy seed”.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3051,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma3:14",
    "question": "The mark or curse that the Lord set upon the Lamanites will not last forever, except they repent of their wickedness and turn to the Lord that he may have mercy upon them.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3052,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma3:18",
    "question": "The Amlicites did not know that they were fulfilling the word of the Lord when they began to mark themselves in their foreheads.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3053,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma3:18",
    "question": "The_____ had come out in open rebellion against God; therefore it was expedient that the curse should fall upon them.",
    "answer": "Amlicites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3054,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma3:19",
    "question": "Mormon writes that the Amlicites brought upon themselves the curse; and so does every man that is cursed bring upon himself his own comdemnation.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3055,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma3:22",
    "question": "The second time the Lamanites came to battle with the Nephites; Alma did not go to battle against them because he was afflicted with a_____.",
    "answer": "Wound",
    "options": ["Wound", "Cold", "Bad Back"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3056,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma3:26",
    "question": "In one year there were thousands and tens of thousands of souls sent to the eternal world, that they might reap their rewards according to their works, whether they were good or whether they were_____.",
    "answer": "Bad"
  },
  {
    "id": 3057,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma3:26",
    "question": "The souls that went to the eternal world were to reap eternal happiness or eternal misery, according to the spirit which they listed to obey, whether it was a good spirit or a bad one.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3058,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma3:27",
    "question": "For every man receives wages of him whom he listens to obey, and this is according to the words of the_____ of prophecy.",
    "answer": "Spirit",
    "options": ["Angel", "Spirit", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3059,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:3",
    "question": "Because many people believed that it was the judgments of God sent upon them because of their wickedness and their abominations; they were awakened to a remembrance of their duty.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3060,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma4:4",
    "question": "The people began to establish the church more fully and many were baptized by Alma2 in the waters of_____, because he had been consecrated a high priest.",
    "answer": "Sidon"
  },
  {
    "id": 3061,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:5",
    "question": "There were about 3,500 souls that had united themselves to the church of God and were baptized in the waters of Sidon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3062,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:6",
    "question": "The people of the church began to wax proud because of their exceeding riches, and in their fine silks, and their fine-twined linen, and their gold and silver.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3063,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma4:7",
    "question": "Because the people had begun to wax proud, _____ and his teachers, and priests, and elders of the church were sorely grieved for the wickedness which they saw that had begun among their people.",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 3064,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma4:8",
    "question": "Alma2 saw with great sorrow that the people of the church began to be lifted up in the pride of their_____.",
    "answer": "Eyes",
    "options": ["Hearts", "Eyes", "Heads"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3065,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:8",
    "question": "Alma2 saw with great sorrow that the people also began to set their hearts upon riches and upon the vain things of the world.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3066,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:8",
    "question": "Those that belonged to the church of God began to persecute those that did not believe according to their own pleasure.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3067,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:9",
    "question": "Alma2 saw that there began to be great contentions among the people of the church because of their pride.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3068,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma4:9",
    "question": "There were envyings, strife, malice, persecutions, and pride even to exceed the pride of those that did not belong to the_____ of God. ",
    "answer": "Church"
  },
  {
    "id": 3069,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma4:10",
    "question": "The wickedness of the people of the church began to be a great stumbling-_____ to those who did not belong to the church; therefore the church began to fail in its progress.",
    "answer": "Block"
  },
  {
    "id": 3070,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:11",
    "question": "In the commencement of the 9th year Alma2 saw the example of the wickedness of the church began to lead those who were unbelievers from one iniquity to another, thus bringing on the destruction of the people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3071,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:12",
    "question": "Because of the inequality among the people; some were lifting themselves in their pride.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3072,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:12",
    "question": "Because of the inequality of people some began despising others, and turning their backs upon the needy, and the naked, and those that were hungry.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3073,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:13",
    "question": "Some of the people succored those who stood in need of succor, such as imparting their substance to the poor and needy, and suffering all manner of afflictions, for Christ’s sake, who should come according to the spirit of prophecy.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3074,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:14",
    "question": "Some of the people were not looking forward to the day when Christ would come retaining a remission of their sins.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3075,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma4:14",
    "question": "Some of the people were filled with joy because of the_____ of the dead, according to the will and power and deliverance of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "Resurrection"
  },
  {
    "id": 3076,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma4:16",
    "question": "Alma2 selected a_____ man among the elders of the church, and gave him power according to the voice of the people, to enact the laws according to the laws which had been given.",
    "answer": "Wise",
    "options": ["Large", "Ignorant", "Wise"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3077,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma4:17",
    "question": "The wise man that Alma2 selected to be a chief judge; and sat at the judgment-seat to judge and to govern the people was_____.",
    "answer": "Nephihah"
  },
  {
    "id": 3078,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:18",
    "question": "Alma2 also granted Nephihah the office of high priest over the people of the church.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3079,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:19",
    "question": "Alma2 granted the judgment-seat to Nephihah so that he himself might go forth among the Nephites to preach the word of God unto them, to stir them up in remembrance of their duty.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3080,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma14:19",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted to pull down by the power of_____ all the pride and craftiness and contentions which were among his people.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 3081,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:20",
    "question": "When Alma2 delivered up his judgment-seat to Nephihah he confined himself wholly to the high priesthood of the holy order of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3082,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma4:20",
    "question": "Alma2 also gave his testimony of the word, according to the spirit of_____ and prophecy.",
    "answer": "Revelation",
    "options": ["Goodness", "Revelation", "Knowledge"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3083,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:1",
    "question": "What was the name of the land where Alma2 first went to deliver the word of God before he went to other places?",
    "answer": "Zarahemla"
  },
  {
    "id": 3084,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:7",
    "question": "Because of Alma2’s words the people changed their hearts and were awakened out of a deep sleep or in a midst of darkness, and awoke unto God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3085,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:9,13",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that those that his father_____ had taught had broken the chains of hell which encircled them and had broken the bands of death because the faith in his words.",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 3086,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:13",
    "question": "Because the people in Alma the Elder’s life had a change of heart and did humble themselves and put their_____ in God and were faithful until the end; they were saved.",
    "answer": "Trust"
  },
  {
    "id": 3087,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:15",
    "question": "Alma the Younger asked the people if they had exercised faith in the redemption of Jesus Christ who had created them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3088,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma5:15",
    "question": "Alma2 asked the people if they looked forward with an eye of_____, and view their mortal body raised in immortality, and this corruption raised incorruption.",
    "answer": "Faith",
    "options": ["Faith", "Soberness", "Clarity"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3089,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:20",
    "question": " Alma2 asked the people if thought they could be saved when they had yielded themselves to become subjects of the_____.",
    "answer": ["devil", "satan"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3090,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma5:21",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that no man can be saved except his_____are washed white and purified until they are cleansed from all stain.",
    "answer": "Garments",
    "options": ["Pants", "Robes", "Garments"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3091,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:21",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that the only person who could clean their garments was Jesus Christ through his blood and that should come to redeem his people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3092,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:24",
    "question": "Alma2 said that murderers and also those that are guilty of all manner of wickedness can not have a place to sit down in the kingdom of God, with Abraham, with Isaac, and with_____.",
    "answer": "Jacob"
  },
  {
    "id": 3093,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:27,28",
    "question": "Alma2 asked the people if they had kept themselves blameless before God within themselves and had been sufficiently humble, and if they had also been stripped of pride.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3094,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma5:28",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people if they had not been stripped of their pride they cannot be prepared to meet God; behold you must prepare quickly for the kingdom of heaven is soon at_____.",
    "answer": "Hand",
    "options": ["Hand", "Their Feet", "Daybreak"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3095,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:31,",
    "question": "Alma2 said if told the Nephites if they mock their brethren and persecute them they were not prepared to meet their God and the time is at hand that he must repent or he cannot be saved.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3096,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:32",
    "question": "Woe unto all workers of iniquity; repent, for the Lord_____ has spoken it!",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 3097,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma5:33",
    "question": "Behold, the Lord sends an_____unto all men, for the arms of mercy are extended towards them, and he says:”Repent, and I will receive you”.",
    "answer": "Invitation",
    "options": ["Card", "Invitation", "Text Message"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3098,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:34",
    "question": "The Lord has said:”Come unto me and you shall partake of the fruit of the tree of_____; and shall eat and drink of the bread and the waters freely”.",
    "answer": "Life"
  },
  {
    "id": 3099,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:35",
    "question": "Come unto me and bring forth works of_____, and you shall not be hewn down and cast into the fire of endless torment.",
    "answer": "Righteousness"
  },
  {
    "id": 3100,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:36",
    "question": "For behold, the time is at hand that whosoever brings forth not good fruit; or whosoever does not the works of righteousness, the same have cause to wail and mourn.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3101,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:37",
    "question": "Those that have professed to have known the way of righteousness and have nevertheless gone astray, as sheep having no shepherd, the Lord is still calling after you, but you will not hearken unto his voice!",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3102,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:38",
    "question": "The Lord still calls you which is the name of Christ; and if you will not hearken unto the voice of the_____ shepherd, to the name by which you are called, behold, you are not the sheep of the good shepherd.",
    "answer": "Good"
  },
  {
    "id": 3103,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:39",
    "question": "According to Alma2; if we are not the fold of the good shepherd, we are of the Devil’s and his fold.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3104,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:40",
    "question": "Alma2 has said that whatsoever is good comes from God, and whatsoever is evil comes from the_____.",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },
  {
    "id": 3105,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma5:41",
    "question": "If a man brings forth good works he has hearkened unto the voice of the good shepherd, and follows him, and whosoever brings forth evil works, the same is a_____ of the devil.",
    "answer": "Child",
    "options": ["Person", "Child", "Woman"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3106,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:42",
    "question": "If we follow the devil our wages are of him; therefore, we receive death, as to the things pertaining unto righteousness, being dead unto all_____ works.",
    "answer": "Good"
  },
  {
    "id": 3107,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:43",
    "question": "Alma2 spoke with the energy of all his soul to the Nephites and plainly that they could not err, and had spoken according to the commandments of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3108,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:44",
    "question": "Alma2 was called to speak after this manner, according to the_____ order of God, which is Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "Holy"
  },
  {
    "id": 3109,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:44",
    "question": "Alma2 was not commanded to testify unto his people the things which had been spoken by their fathers concerning the things which are to come.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3110,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:46",
    "question": "Alma2 knew that the things which he had spoken to the Nephites were true because they were made know to him by the Holy_____ of God.",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },
  {
    "id": 3111,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:46",
    "question": "Alma2 had fasted and prayed many days in order that he might know the truth of the things he told the Nephites for himself.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3112,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:46",
    "question": "Alma2 knew the things which he told the people were true because they had been manifested to him by God by and his Holy Spirit which was the spirit of revelation.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3113,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:47",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Nephites that the things which had been revealed to him and the words which had been spoken by their fathers were true according to the spirit of_____ which was in him.",
    "answer": "Prophecy"
  },
  {
    "id": 3114,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:48",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that he knew whatsoever thing he told them concerning that which is to come was true; and he said unto them that he knew that Jesus_____ shall come.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 3115,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:48",
    "question": "Alma2 said to the Nephites that Jesus Christ was the only begotten son of God the Father, full of mercy, grace and truth.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3116,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:48",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that Jesus Christ would come to take away the sins of the_____, and the sins of every man who steadfastly believed in his name.",
    "answer": "World"
  },
  {
    "id": 3117,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma5:49",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that he was called to preach unto his beloved brethren, and to every one that dwelled in the land both old and young, both bond and_____.",
    "answer": "Free",
    "options": ["Imprisoned", "Free", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3118,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:50",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Nephites that they must be born again, and repent, and all the ends of the earth, for the kingdom of heaven is soon at hand.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3119,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:50",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Nephites that the Son of God comes in his glory, in his might, majesty, power and dominion.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3120,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:50",
    "question": "Behold the glory of the King of all the earth; and also the King of heaven shall very soon shine forth among all the children of_____.",
    "answer": "Men"
  },
  {
    "id": 3121,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma5:51",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people to repent; for except you repent you can nowise inherit the kingdom of_____.",
    "answer": "Heaven",
    "options": ["Planets", "Stars", "Heaven"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3122,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:52",
    "question": "Behold, the ax is laid at the root of the tree; therefore every tree that does not bring good fruit shall be hewn down and cast into the fire.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3123,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:52, 2Nep9:16, Mos3:27",
    "question": "The lake of fire and brimstone is a fire that cannot be consumed and is unquenchable.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3124,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma5:53",
    "question": "Alma2 told his beloved brethren not to lay aside the things which he had said and not to trample the Holy One under their_____.",
    "answer": "Feet",
    "options": ["Feet", "Legs", "Bodies"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3125,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:54",
    "question": "Those that have humbled themselves and do walk after the holy order of God, have been brought into the church and have been sanctified by the Holy_____, and they do bring forth good works which are meet for repentance.",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },
  {
    "id": 3126,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:56",
    "question": "Those that persist in wickedness, these are they who shall be hewn down and cast into the fire except they speedily repent.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3127,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:57",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Nephites that those who were desirous to follow the voice of the good_____, to come out from the wicked people and separate themselves from them and to touch not unclean things.",
    "answer": "Shepherd"
  },
  {
    "id": 3128,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:57",
    "question": "The words of the Lord were fulfilled when he said that the wicked shall mingle with the names of his people.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3129,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:58",
    "question": "What is the name of the book in which the names of the righteous is written on? ",
    "answer": "Life"
  },
  {
    "id": 3130,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma5:60",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people not to let no ravenous_____ enter among them, that they may be destroyed.",
    "answer": "Wolf",
    "options": ["Dog", "Raccoon", "Wolf"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3131,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:61",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Nephites that he spoke by way of commandment unto them in the language of him that had commanded him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3132,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:61",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted the Nephites not to observe to do the words which he had spoken unto them.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3133,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:62",
    "question": "Alma2 told those that did not belong to the church that he spoke to them by way of invitation, saying:'Come and be baptized unto repentance, that you also may be partakers of the fruit of the tree of_____'.",
    "answer": "Life"
  },
  {
    "id": 3134,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma6:3",
    "question": "And it came to pass that those who did not belong to the church and did not repent of their wickedness and humble themselves before God-the same were rejected.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3135,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma6:3",
    "question": "Those that did not humble themselves before God and repent; their names were blotted out, that their names were not numbered among those of the righteous.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3136,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma6:5",
    "question": "Mormon wants us to understand that the word of God was liberal unto all, that none were deprived of the privilege of assembling themselves together to hear the word of_____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 3137,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma6:7",
    "question": "After Alma2 had taught those in the city of Zarahemla he departed and left and went into the valley of Gideon to teach the people in the city of_____.",
    "answer": "Gideon"
  },
  {
    "id": 3138,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma6:8",
    "question": "Alma2 taught the people in the city of Gideon the truth of the word which had been spoken by his fathers, and according to the spirit of prophecy and his testimony of Jesus Christ the Son of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3139,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:1",
    "question": "In chapter seven of the Book of Alma; Alma2 delivers to the people in the city of Gideon the words which are written according to his record.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3140,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma7:1",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people of the city of Gideon that he could not come sooner unto them because he had been confined to the_____-seat, having had much business.",
    "answer": "Judgment"
  },
  {
    "id": 3141,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:2",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people in the city Gideon that it was through much mercy that the Lord had granted unto him to come and teach them",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3142,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma7:3",
    "question": "Alma2 had hoped to find the people of the city of Gideon blameless before him, and that they were not in the awful dilemma that their brethren were in the city of_____.",
    "answer": "Zarahemla"
  },
  {
    "id": 3143,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma7:4",
    "question": "The people in the city of Gideon had given Alma2 exceedingly great joy of knowing that they were established again in the way of the_____ and in his righteousness.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 3144,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:5",
    "question": "Alma2 had much afflictions and sorrow because of the condition the people of Zarahemla were in.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3145,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:7",
    "question": "Alma2 went and declared the word of God to the people of the city Gideon and told them of many things to come.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3146,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma7:7",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people of many things to come, but the thing that was more important than any other, was that the time was not to far distant that the_____ would live and come among his people.",
    "answer": "Redeemer"
  },
  {
    "id": 3147,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:8",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that he did not mean that the Redeemer would come among them at the time of his dwelling in the mortal tabernacle; because the Spirit had not made it know unto him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3148,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma7:8",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people of the city of Gideon that he did know that the Lord God has power to do all things which are according to his_____.",
    "answer": "Word",
    "options": ["Word", "Prophets", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3149,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma7:9",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people in Gideon that the Spirit had said to cry unto them and repent, and prepare the_____ of the Lord, and walk in his paths which are straight.",
    "answer": "Way",
    "options": ["Road", "Way", "Path"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3150,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:9",
    "question": "Alma2 did not tell the people in Gideon that the Lord, the Son of God; would soon come to the earth.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3151,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma7:10",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people of the city of Gideon that the Son of God would be born in what land? which was the land of their forefathers. ",
    "answer": "Jerusalem"
  },
  {
    "id": 3152,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma7:10",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the name of the mother of the Son of God would be named what?",
    "answer": "Mary"
  },
  {
    "id": 3153,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma7:10",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people of the city of Gideon that Mary would be a virgin and a chosen vessel, who shall be overshadowed and conceive by the power of the Holy_____, and bring forth a son, even the Son of God.",
    "answer": "Ghost"
  },
  {
    "id": 3154,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:11",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the Son of God would go forth, suffering pains and afflictions and temptations of every kind.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3155,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:11",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the Son of God’s would suffer that the word might be fulfilled which said that he would take upon him the pains and the sickness of his people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3156,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma7:12",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the Son of God would take upon him death, that he may loose the_____ of death which bind his people.",
    "answer": "Bands"
  },
  {
    "id": 3157,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma7:12",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the Son of God would take upon him the infirmaties of his people, that his bowels may be filled with mercy, according to the_____.",
    "answer": "Flesh",
    "options": ["Body", "Flesh", "Spirit"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3158,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:12",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the Son of God would suffer all things that he may know according to the flesh how to succor his people according to their infirmities.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3159,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma7:13",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the_____ knows all things; nevertheless to Son of God would suffer according to the flesh that he might take upon him the sins of his people.",
    "answer": "Spirit",
    "options": ["Spirit", "Satan", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3160,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:13",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that the Son of God would take upon himself the sins of his people; that he may blot out their transgressions according to the power of his deliverance; and that this was his testimony.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3161,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:14",
    "question": "Alma2 did not tell the people in the city of Gideon that they must repent and be born again or they could not inherit the kingdom of heaven.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3162,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma7:14",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people to come and be_____ unto repentance; that they may be washed from their sins, and to have faith on the Lamb of God, who will take away the sins of the world.",
    "answer": "Baptized"
  },
  {
    "id": 3163,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:14",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the Son of God is not mighty to save and to cleanse his people from all unrighteousness.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3164,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma7:15",
    "question": "Alma2told the people to come forth, and show God that they were willing to repent of their sins and enter into a_____ with him to keep his commandments, and witness it unto him by going into the waters of baptism.",
    "answer": "Covenant",
    "options": ["Pact", "Oath", "Covenant"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3165,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma7:16",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that those that were baptize and keep the commandments of God would have_____ life, according to the testimony of the Holy Spirit, which testified unto him.",
    "answer": "Eternal"
  },
  {
    "id": 3166,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:19",
    "question": "Alma2 said I perceive that you are in the paths of righteousness",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3167,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:20",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Nephites that the Lord never varies from that which he has said; neither does he turn from the right to the left, or from that which is right to that which is wrong.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3168,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "20,21",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the course of the Lord is one eternal_____ and he does not dwell in unholy temples.   Round-",
    "answer": "Alma7:"
  },
  {
    "id": 3169,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:21",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the Lord can enter anything that is filthy and anything that is unclean can also be received into the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3170,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:21",
    "question": "Alma2 said “and it shall be at the last day, that he who is filthy shall remain in his filthiness",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3171,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma7:22",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people many things so that he could awaken them to a sense of their_____ to God; that they may walk blameless before him, and walk in his holy order after they had received him.",
    "answer": "Duty",
    "options": ["Right", "Duty", "Acceptance"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3172,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma7:23",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people to be humble and be submissive and gentle; easy to be entreated; full of patience and long-suffering; being_____ in all things.",
    "answer": "Temperate"
  },
  {
    "id": 3173,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma7:23",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Nephites to be diligent in keeping the commandments of God at all times; asking for whatsoever things that they stand in need of, both spiritual and_____.",
    "answer": "Temporal"
  },
  {
    "id": 3174,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:23",
    "question": "Alma2 tells us that we should always return thanks to God for whatsoever things we receive from him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3175,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma7:24",
    "question": "Alma2 says that we should have faith, hope, and_____, and then we will always abound in good works.",
    "answer": "Charity"
  },
  {
    "id": 3176,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:25",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people in Gideon that there have been holy prophets since the world began.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3177,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma7:27",
    "question": "Alma2 wished that the people Gideon would have the_____ of God rest upon them and their houses, lands, and all they possess, according to their faith and good works.",
    "answer": "Peace",
    "options": ["Spirit", "Peace", "Heart"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3178,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma8:1",
    "question": "All the things that Alma2 taught the people in the city of Gideon are written down for the record.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3179,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma8:1",
    "question": "After Alma2 taught the people in Gideon he returned home to his own_____ in the city of Zarahemla to rest himself from the labors which he had performed.",
    "answer": "House"
  },
  {
    "id": 3180,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma8:3",
    "question": "Alma2 began to teach the people in the land of Melek which was on the west of the river_____ and on the west by the borders of the wilderness. ",
    "answer": "Sidon"
  },
  {
    "id": 3181,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma8:6",
    "question": "After Alma2 finished his work at the land of Melek, he departed, and traveled for_____ days and came upon the city which was called Ammonihah.",
    "answer": "Three",
    "options": ["Two", "Three", "Four"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3182,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma8:7",
    "question": "It was the custom of the_____ to call their lands, and their cities, and their villages after the name of him who first possessed them; and so it was with the land of Ammonihah.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3183,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma8:9",
    "question": "Because_____ had gotten a great hold upon the hearts of the people of the city of Ammonihah they would not hearken unto the words of Alma.",
    "answer": ["Devil", "Satan", "Adversary"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3184,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma8:10",
    "question": "Alma2 labored much in the spirit,_____ with God in mighty prayer; that he would pour out his Spirit upon the people who were in the city of Ammonihah.",
    "answer": "Wrestling",
    "options": ["Tangling", "Fighting", "Wrestling"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3185,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma8:11",
    "question": "The people in the city of Ammonihah recognized Alma and knew that he was a high priest over the church.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3186,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma8:11",
    "question": "Because the people recognized Alma2 they would not believe in what they thought were foolish traditions in the church.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3187,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma8:12.",
    "question": "The people of Ammonihah knew that Alma had delivered his judgment-seat over to_____; therefore they said that he had no power over them.",
    "answer": "Nephihah"
  },
  {
    "id": 3188,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma8:13",
    "question": "The people of the city of Ammonihah withstood all of Alma2’s words and reviled him, and spit on him, and caused that he should be_____ out from their city.",
    "answer": "Cast"
  },
  {
    "id": 3189,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma8:14",
    "question": "Alma2 was being weighed down with sorrow, wading through much tribulation and anguish of the soul, because of the wickedness of the people who were in the city of Ammonihah.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3190,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma8:14",
    "question": "While Alma2 was journeying toward the city of Aaron an_____ of the Lord appeared unto him and commanded that he return to the city of Ammonihah.",
    "answer": "Angel",
    "options": ["Messenger", "Follower", "Angel"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3191,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma8:16",
    "question": "Alma2 was told by the angel of the Lord to preach to the people of Ammonihah that if they did not repent, he would destroy them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3192,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma8:17",
    "question": "The Lord said that the people of Ammonihah were studying at this time that they may destroy the_____ of the people.",
    "answer": "Liberty",
    "options": ["Liberty", "Welfare", "Laws"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3193,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma8:17",
    "question": "The people of Ammonihah were destroying the laws which were contrary to the statues, and judgments, and commandments which he had given unto his people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3194,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma8:18",
    "question": "When Alma2 went unto the city of Ammonihah for the second time, he entered the same way he did the first time.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3195,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma8:19",
    "question": "When Alma2 entered Ammonihah the second time he was hungry and asked a man:  Will you give a humble_____ of God something to eat?",
    "answer": "Servant"
  },
  {
    "id": 3196,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma8:20",
    "question": "The man that fed Alma2 was a_____ and knew that Alma2 was a holy prophet of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Nephite",
    "options": ["Lamanite", "Zoramite", "Nephite"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3197,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma8:20",
    "question": "The man that fed Alma2 knew who he was because an angel of the Lord had told him in a_____; and he knew that Alma would be a blessing unto him and his household.",
    "answer": "Vision",
    "options": ["Text Message", "Vision", "Hallucination"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3198,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma8:21, 22",
    "question": "What was the name of the man that fed Alma2 bread and meat, and he was filled?",
    "answer": "Amulek"
  },
  {
    "id": 3199,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma8:24",
    "question": "Alma2 told Amulek that he was the high priest over the church and that he was called to preach the word of God to the people of Ammonihah, but they would not receive him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3200,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma8:26",
    "question": "Alma2 told_____ that he was blessed for taken him in and feeding him because he was hungry and had fasted for many days.",
    "answer": "Amulek"
  },
  {
    "id": 3201,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma8:27",
    "question": "Alma2 only tarried with Amulek for one day before he began to preach the people of the city of Ammonihah.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3202,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma8:28",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people of Ammonihah did wax more gross in their iniquities.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3203,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma8:30",
    "question": "Alma2 and Amulek went forth among the people of Ammonihah to declare the words of God unto them; and they were filled with the Holy_____.",
    "answer": "Ghost"
  },
  {
    "id": 3204,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma8:31",
    "question": "The Lord gave Alma2 and Amulek much power that they could not be confined in_____; neither was it possible that any man could slay them.",
    "answer": "Dungeons",
    "options": ["Dungeons", "Cages", "Jails"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3205,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma8:31",
    "question": "Alma2 and Amulek did not exercise their power until they were bound in bands and cast into prison so that the Lord might show forth his power in them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3206,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Check the end of chapter 8",
    "question": "Chapters 9 though 14 in the Book of Alma comprise the words and teachings inclusively that were delivered to the people who were in the land of Ammonihah.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3207,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma9:3",
    "question": "Alma2 taught the people of_____ that the earth should pass away; and they did not believe his words and did not understand what he meant.",
    "answer": "Ammonihah"
  },
  {
    "id": 3208,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma9:4",
    "question": "Alma2 prophesied to the people in the city of Ammonihah that the city would be destroyed in one day and they did not believe him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3209,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma9:5",
    "question": "The people of Ammonihah did not know_____ and that he could do such marvelous works because they were a hard-hearted and stiffnecked people.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 3210,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma9:7",
    "question": "The people of the city of Ammonihah tried to lay their hands on Alma but could not.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3211,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma9:8",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people of Ammonihah that they were a wicked and perverse generation and how quickly had they forgotten the traditions of their_____ and the commandments of God.",
    "answer": "Fathers"
  },
  {
    "id": 3212,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma9:11",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people in the city of Ammonihah that if it wasn’t for the Lord’s_____ power, and his mercy and long-suffering towards them, they would have been cut off from the face of the earth.",
    "answer": "Matchless"
  },
  {
    "id": 3213,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma9:12",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that the Lord had commanded them to repent or they could nowise inherit the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3214,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma9:12",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that if they did not repent he would visit them in his anger, and in his fierce_____ he will not turn away.",
    "answer": "Anger",
    "options": ["Temper", "Anger", "Moment"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3215,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma9:14",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that the words of the Lord were verified when he said that Lamanites had been cut off from the presence of the Lord when they started with their transgressions.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3216,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma9:16",
    "question": "Because the Lord has made many promises to the_____ he will be merciful unto them and prolong their existence in the land.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Ismaelites", "Ammonites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3217,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma9:17",
    "question": "Alma2 said that at some period of time the Lamanites will be brought to believe in the word of the Lord, and he will be merciful unto all who call in his name.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3218,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma9:19",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that the Lord would not suffer that they should live in their iniquities to destroy his_____.",
    "answer": "People"
  },
  {
    "id": 3219,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma9:20",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the people of_____ were highly favored of the Lord and were favored above every other nation, kindred, tongue, or people.",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 3220,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma9:21",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Nephites had not been visited by the Spirit of God; having conversed with angels, and have been spoken unto by the voice of the Lord.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3221,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma9:23",
    "question": "Alma2 said that if the Nephites should transgress contrary to the light and knowledge which they do have, it would be far more tolerable for the_____ than for them.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["Ismaelites", "Lamanites", "Ammonites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3222,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma9:24",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people of the city of Ammonihah that the promises of the Lord were extended to the Lamanites, but they were not unto them if they transgressed.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3223,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma9:26",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that the Son of God would come in not so distant days in all his glory; and his glory would be full of grace, equity, truth, and full of patience.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3224,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma9:30,31",
    "question": "Because Alma2 told the people in the city of Ammonihah that they were in a fallen state and a hard-hearted and stiffnecked people, they were angry with him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3225,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma9:34",
    "question": "Amulek also began to preach to the people who were in the land of_____.",
    "answer": "Ammonihah"
  },
  {
    "id": 3226,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10-2",
    "question": "Amulek was the son of_____, who was the son of Ishmael, who was a descendent of Aminadi.",
    "answer": "Giddonah"
  },
  {
    "id": 3227,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma10:2",
    "question": "Amulek was a descendent of Aminadi.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3228,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10:2",
    "question": "What is the name of the prophet who interpreted the writing which was upon the wall of the temple, which was written by the finger of God?",
    "answer": "Aminadi"
  },
  {
    "id": 3229,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10:3",
    "question": "Aminadi was a descendent of Nephi, who was the son of Lehi, who came out of the land of_____.",
    "answer": "Jerusalem"
  },
  {
    "id": 3230,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10:3",
    "question": "Lehi was a descendent of Manasseh, who was the son of_____ who was sold into Egypt by the hands of his brethren.",
    "answer": "Joseph"
  },
  {
    "id": 3231,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma10-4",
    "question": "Amulek told the people that he was a man of no small reputation among those that knew him; and had many relatives and friends, and had acquired many riches by his industry.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3232,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10:5",
    "question": "Amulek said that he had known and seen the mysteries and marvelous power of the_____.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 3233,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma10:6",
    "question": "Amulek told the people of Ammonihah that he was called many times but did not hear because he had hardened his_____.",
    "answer": "Heart",
    "options": ["Soul", "Heart", "Spirit"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3234,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10:7",
    "question": "As Amulek was traveling to see a beloved relative of his, an_____ of the Lord told him to return to his own house; because he would feed a prophet of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Angel"
  },
  {
    "id": 3235,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma10:8",
    "question": "Amulek did not obey the angel of the Lord when he was told to return to his house and feed a prophet of the Lord.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3236,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "9,10",
    "question": "Amulek believed that_____ was a holy man because an angel of the Lord had told him so and knew that the things that the he had said were true.  Alma-",
    "answer": "Alma10:"
  },
  {
    "id": 3237,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma10:10,11",
    "question": "Amulek told the people that the Lord had blessed him and his family and his kinsfolk while Alma2 had dwelled in his house.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3238,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma10:13",
    "question": "Some of the people of Ammonihah tried to question Alma2 and Amulek to try to catch them in their words; that they might witness against them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3239,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10:13",
    "question": "The people of_____ wanted to question Alma2 and Amulek to try to catch them lying so that they could be slain or cast them into prison.",
    "answer": "Ammonihah- "
  },
  {
    "id": 3240,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10:14",
    "question": "What was the profession of the men that tried to destroy and catch Alma2 and Amulek in their words?",
    "answer": "Lawyers"
  },
  {
    "id": 3241,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma10:16",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the lawyers began to question Amulek that thereby they might make him_____ his words, or contradict the words which he spoke.",
    "answer": "Cross",
    "options": ["Eat", "Stumble", "Cross"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3242,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10:17",
    "question": "The lawyers of the city in Ammonihah did not know that_____ knew of their designs and could also read their thoughts.",
    "answer": "Amulek"
  },
  {
    "id": 3243,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma10:17",
    "question": "Amulek did not call the lawyers of the city of Ammonihah hypocrites.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3244,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10:17",
    "question": "Amulek said that the lawyers of Ammonihah were laying the foundation of the_____; because they were laying traps and snares to catch the holy ones of God.",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },
  {
    "id": 3245,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10:19",
    "question": "Amulek made a reference to King_____ when he told the people that he had said if the time should come that the people chose iniquity, they would be ripe for destruction.",
    "answer": "Mosiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 3246,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma10:22",
    "question": "Amulek told the people that if it was not for the_____ of the righteous, who were in the land; the Lord would have visited them with utter destruction.",
    "answer": "Prayers",
    "options": ["Fastings", "Gifts", "Prayers"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3247,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10:23",
    "question": "Amulek told the people of Ammonihah that if they did not repent the Lord would visit them in his anger and be smitten by famine, pestilence, and by the_____.",
    "answer": "Sword"
  },
  {
    "id": 3248,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma10:24",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people of Ammonihah were angrier with Amulek because of the words that he had told them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3249,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma10:24",
    "question": "The people of Ammonihah said that Amulek had reviled against their laws which were just, and also to their wise lawyers who they had selected.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3250,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10:25",
    "question": "Amulek told the people why they had let_____ get such a hold upon their hearts and yielded themselves to him that he may have power over them.",
    "answer": "Satan"
  },
  {
    "id": 3251,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10:31",
    "question": "What was the name of the lawyer who had accused Amulek and Alma2 the most of breaking their laws?",
    "answer": "Zeezrom"
  },
  {
    "id": 3252,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma10:32",
    "question": "The lawyers’ objective was to get gain; and they got gain according to their employment.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3253,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:1",
    "question": "It was the law of King Mosiah that every man who was a judge of the law, or those who were appointed to be judges should receive wages according to their labors.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3254,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:2",
    "question": "If a man owed another man and he would not pay that which he owed, it was his right to complain to the judge of the land.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3255,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma11:2",
    "question": "If a man did not pay his debts he would be stripped, or be cast out from the land among the people as a thief and a_____.",
    "answer": "Robber",
    "options": ["Bad Guy", "Robber", "Scoundrel"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3256,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:3",
    "question": "According to the Nephite way of coins and measures; a senine of gold for a day is equal to a senum of silver for a day.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3257,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma11:4",
    "question": "The_____ did not value their coins after the manner of the Jews who were at Jerusalem; neither did they measure after the manner of the Jews.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3258,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:20",
    "question": "The lawyers of Ammonihah would stir the people to riotings, and all manner of wickedness, that they might be employed by the people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3259,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:20",
    "question": "There were no such things as law suits among the Nephites during the time of Amulek and Alma2.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3260,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma11:21",
    "question": "Zeezrom was an expert in the devices of the_____; that he might destroy the things which were good.",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },
  {
    "id": 3261,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma11:22",
    "question": "_____ began to question Amulek; and Amulek told him that he would not say anything that was contrary to the Spirit of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Zeezrom"
  },
  {
    "id": 3262,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma11:22",
    "question": "Zeezrom tried to bribe_____ with six onties of silver to deny the existence of a Supreme Being.",
    "answer": "Amulek"
  },
  {
    "id": 3263,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:24",
    "question": "Zeezrom did not know that God existed.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3264,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma11:26,28",
    "question": "Zeezrom asked Amulek if there was a true and living_____; and if only one existed.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 3265,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma11:31",
    "question": "Amulek told Zeezrom that he believed there was a God because and an_____ of the Lord had told him.",
    "answer": "Angel"
  },
  {
    "id": 3266,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:34",
    "question": "Zeezrom asked Amulek if God would save his people in their sins.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3267,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma11:34",
    "question": "Amulek told_____ that God could not save his people in their sins because he would be denying his word.",
    "answer": "Zeezrom"
  },
  {
    "id": 3268,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:35",
    "question": "Zeezrom accused Amulek of having the authority to command God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3269,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma11:39",
    "question": "Amulek told Zeezrom that the Son of God was the very Eternal_____ of heaven and of earth, and of all things that exist.",
    "answer": "Father"
  },
  {
    "id": 3270,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma11:39",
    "question": "Amulek also told Zeezrom that the Eternal Father was the beginning and the end, the first and the_____.",
    "answer": "Last"
  },
  {
    "id": 3271,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:40",
    "question": "Amulek said that those who believe in the Son of God are they that shall have eternal life and salvation comes to no one else.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3272,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:41",
    "question": "Amulek told Zeezrom that those that are wicked remain as though there had been no redemption made.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3273,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:41",
    "question": "Amulek told Zeezrom that the day will come when the wicked shall rise from the dead and stand before God, and be judged according to their works.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3274,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma11:42",
    "question": "Amulek said that the death of our bodies is called_____ death; and the death of Christ shall loose the bands of this temporal death and all shall be raised from this temporal death.",
    "answer": "Temporal"
  },
  {
    "id": 3275,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma11:43",
    "question": "Amulek told Zeezrom that the_____ and the body shall be reunited again in its perfect form; both limb and joint shall be restored to its proper frame.",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },
  {
    "id": 3276,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:43",
    "question": "Amulek tells us that we shall be brought to stand before God, knowing all the things we each know, and have a recollection of all our guilt.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3277,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma11:44",
    "question": "Amulek said that the restoration shall come to all, both young and old, both male and female, both the wicked and the righteous, and both_____ and free.",
    "answer": "Bond"
  },
  {
    "id": 3278,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:44",
    "question": "Amulek said that not every single person will be brought before the bar of Christ the Son, and God the Father, and the Holy Spirit, which is one Eternal God to be judged according to their works.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3279,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:45",
    "question": "Amulek spoke to Zeezrom concerning the death of the mortal body, and also concerning the resurrection.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3280,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma11:46",
    "question": "When Amulek finished with his words the people began to be astonished, and also_____ began to tremble.",
    "answer": "Zeezrom"
  },
  {
    "id": 3281,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:46",
    "question": "Once Amulek finished answering the questions that Zeezrom had put before him and also finished speaking to him, Alma2 chose not to write anymore of his words.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3282,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:1",
    "question": "When Alma2 saw that the words of_____ had silenced Zeezrom, he began to speak unto him and testified of his words.",
    "answer": "Amulek"
  },
  {
    "id": 3283,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma12:5.6",
    "question": "Alma2 told Zeezrom that the Adversary and exercised his power in him and had laid a snare to catch the people; and subject them to his will.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3284,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:6",
    "question": "The adversary wanted to encircle_____ and the people with his chains, that he might chain them down to everlasting destruction, according to the power of his captivity.",
    "answer": "Zeezrom"
  },
  {
    "id": 3285,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:7",
    "question": "When Alma2 had spoken his words to Zeezrom, he began to tremble more exceedingly because he had become more convinced of the power of_____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 3286,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma12:7",
    "question": "Zeezrom had become convinced that Alma2 and Amulek knew the thoughts and intents of his heart; because the Lord had given power unto them that they might know these things according to the spirit of prophecy.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3287,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:8",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Zeezrom began to inquire of_____ and Amulek diligently, that he might know more concerning the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 3288,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma12:9",
    "question": "Alma2 told Zeezrom that it is given unto many to know of the_____ of God, but they are laid under a strict command.",
    "answer": "Mysteries",
    "options": ["Mysteries", "Thoughts", "Ideas"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3289,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:9",
    "question": "The mysteries of God are imparted only according to the portion of his word which he grants to the children of men, according to the heed and_____ which they give unto him.",
    "answer": "Diligence"
  },
  {
    "id": 3290,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma12:10",
    "question": "The more we harden are hearts; the less portion of the mysteries of God we will receive.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3291,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma12:10",
    "question": "Those that do not harden their hearts; to him is given a greater_____ of the word, until it is given unto him to know all the mysteries of God.",
    "answer": "Portion",
    "options": ["Helping", "Portion", "Abundance"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3292,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma12:11",
    "question": "According to Alma2, the chains of hell mean:  To those that is given the lesser portion of the word until they know nothing concerning his mysteries; and then they are taken captive by the devil, and led by his will down to destruction.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3293,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:14",
    "question": "Alma2 told Zeezrom that our words will condemn us, all our works will condemn us; and our_____, and we shall not be found spotless.",
    "answer": "Thoughts"
  },
  {
    "id": 3294,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma12:14",
    "question": "Alma2 said that because of all the things that will condemn us; we will be happy and glad if we could command the rocks and the_____ to fall upon us to hide us from his presence.",
    "answer": "Mountains",
    "options": ["Hills", "Volcanoes", "Mountains"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3295,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma12:15",
    "question": "Alma2 said that we cannot hide from the Lord but must come forth and stand before him in his glory, power, might, majesty, and dominion and acknowledge that his judgments are just.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3296,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma12:15",
    "question": "Alma2 said that we must also acknowledge that God is just in all his works.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3297,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma12:15",
    "question": "Alma2 said that God is merciful unto the children of men, and that he has all the power to save every man that believes in his name and brings repentance unto him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3298,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:16",
    "question": "Alma2 said the second death is spiritual death, then is the time that whosoever died in his sins, as to temporal death, shall also die a spiritual death; and shall die as to things pertaining unto_____.",
    "answer": "Righteousness"
  },
  {
    "id": 3299,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:17",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the lake of fire and brimstone ascends up forever and ever; and then is the time comes that they shall be chained down to an everlasting destruction, according to the power and captivity of_____.",
    "answer": "Satan"
  },
  {
    "id": 3300,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma12:19",
    "question": "When Alma2 had finished and made an end to his speaking the people began to be more astonished.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3301,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:20",
    "question": "What was the name of the man who was a chief ruler over the people in the city of Ammonihah who began to question Alma2?",
    "answer": "Antionah"
  },
  {
    "id": 3302,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma12:20",
    "question": "Antionah asked Alma2 what he meant when he said that man should rise from the dead and be changed from his mortal to an immortal state that the soul can never die.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3303,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma12:21",
    "question": "At what direction in the Garden of Eden did God place cherubim and a flaming sword that so that Adam and Eve would not enter and partake of the tree of life, and live forever.",
    "answer": "East",
    "options": ["West", "East", "South"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3304,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:22",
    "question": "Alma2 told Antionah that_____ did fall by the partaking of the forbidden fruit, according to the word of God; and by his fall, all mankind became a lost and fallen people.",
    "answer": "Adam"
  },
  {
    "id": 3305,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:23",
    "question": "Alma2 said that if Adam had partaken of the fruit of the_____ of life at that time, there would have been no death to man and the Lord’s word would have been void.",
    "answer": "Tree"
  },
  {
    "id": 3306,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:24",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the time that is granted unto man to prepare to meet God is called a_____ state.",
    "answer": "Probationary"
  },
  {
    "id": 3307,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma-12:26",
    "question": "Alma2 said that if our first parents could have gone forth and partaken of the tree of life they would have been miserable forever, having no preparatory state.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3308,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma12:27",
    "question": "Alma2 said that it was appointed unto men that they must die; and after death, they must come to be_____.",
    "answer": "Judged",
    "options": ["Knighted", "Crowned", "Judged"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3309,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma12:28",
    "question": "After God appointed that these things should come unto men, he saw that it was expedient that man should know concerning the things which he had appointed unto them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3310,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:29",
    "question": "Alma2 said that God sent_____ to converse with men, who cause men to behold his glory.",
    "answer": "Angels"
  },
  {
    "id": 3311,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:30",
    "question": "Alma2 said that God conversed with men, and made it know unto them the plan of_____, which had been prepared from the foundation of the world.",
    "answer": "Redemption"
  },
  {
    "id": 3312,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:31",
    "question": "Men first transgressed the first commandments as to things which were temporal, and becoming as Gods, knowing good from_____.",
    "answer": "Evil"
  },
  {
    "id": 3313,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:31",
    "question": "By becoming like Gods, men placed themselves in a state to act, or be placed in a state to act according to their wills and pleasures, whether to do evil or to do_____.",
    "answer": "Good"
  },
  {
    "id": 3314,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:33",
    "question": "Alma2 said that God did call all men, in the name of his Son saying:  If you will repent, and harden not your hearts, then will I have mercy upon you, through mine Only Begotten_____.",
    "answer": "Son"
  },
  {
    "id": 3315,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma12:34",
    "question": "Alma2 said that those who repent and harden not their hearts shall have the claim to mercy though the Only Begotten Son, unto a remission of his_____; and these shall enter into the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": "Sins",
    "options": ["Deeds", "Bad Deeds", "Sins"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3316,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma12:36",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Nephites if they hardened their hearts; their iniquity would provoke the Lord to send his wrath upon them in the first provocation.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3317,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma12:36",
    "question": "The first provocation can also mean to describe things that are temporal.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3318,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma12:37",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted the Nephites to also remember the Lord’s second commandments which he had given them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3319,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma13:1",
    "question": "Alma2 told his brethren to remember that the Lord God ordained_____, after his holy order, which was after the order of his Son, to teach them unto the people.",
    "answer": "Priests",
    "options": ["Priests", "Lawyers", "Judges"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3320,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma13:3",
    "question": "Alma2 said that that the priests of the Lord were called and prepared from the_____ of the world according to the foreknowledge of God.",
    "answer": "Foundation"
  },
  {
    "id": 3321,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma13:4",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the Lord’s priests were called to this holy calling on account of their_____, while others would reject the Spirit of God on account of the hardness of their hearts and blindness of their minds.",
    "answer": "Faith",
    "options": ["Riches", "Intelligence", "Faith"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3322,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:6",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the high priesthood was not a holy calling but more of a calling of a status symbol.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3323,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:7",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that the high priesthood was called after the order of his Son, which order was from the foundation of the world; or in other words, being without beginning of days or end of years.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3324,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma13:7",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the high priesthood was prepared from eternity to all_____, according to God’s foreknowledge of all things.",
    "answer": "Eternity"
  },
  {
    "id": 3325,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:8",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the priests were ordained after this manner:  Being called with a holy calling, and ordained with a holy ordinance, and taking upon them the high priesthood of the holy order, which has no beginning or end.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3326,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma13:9",
    "question": "Alma2 said that brethren that are called become high priest forever, after the order of the_____, the Only Begotten of the Father, who is without beginning of days or ends of years.",
    "answer": "Son"
  },
  {
    "id": 3327,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma13:10",
    "question": "Alma2 said that those that were ordained became high priest of God; and it was on account of their faith and repentance, and their righteousness before God, choosing to repent and work righteousness rather than to_____.",
    "answer": "Perish"
  },
  {
    "id": 3328,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma13:11",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the high priesthood was called after this holy order, and were sanctified, and their garments were washed white through the_____ of the Lamb of God. ",
    "answer": "Blood"
  },
  {
    "id": 3329,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:12",
    "question": "Alma 2said that those whose garments were made white became pure and spotless before God, and could not look upon sin except it was with abhorrence.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3330,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:12",
    "question": "Alma2 said there were many, an exceedingly great many who were made pure and entered into the rest of the Lord their God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3331,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:14",
    "question": "Alma2 said that Melchizedek the high priest was special and that he was a high priest after another holy order.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3332,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma13:15",
    "question": "Alma2 said that their father Abraham paid one-tenth part of all that he possessed to what high priest?",
    "answer": "Melchizedek"
  },
  {
    "id": 3333,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma13:17",
    "question": "What was the land called that Melchizedek was a king over?",
    "answer": "Salem",
    "options": ["Waters Of Mormon", "Salem", "Ammonihah"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3334,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:17",
    "question": "The people in the land of Salem had waxed strong in iniquity and abominations and had all gone astray; they were full of all manner of wickedness.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3335,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma13:18",
    "question": "Because_____ had exercised mighty faith and preached to the people about repentance, they did repent; and he did establish peace in the land in all his days.",
    "answer": "Melchidezek"
  },
  {
    "id": 3336,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:18",
    "question": "Another name for Melchizedek was the prince of peace, because he had established peace once again in the land of Salem; and he did reign under his father",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3337,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:18",
    "question": "In the Book of Mormon and in the Book of Alma, it is written by Mormon the name of the father of Melchizedek.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3338,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma13:19",
    "question": "There were many before_____, and also there were many afterwards, but none were greater; therefore, of him they have more particularly made mention.",
    "answer": "Melchizedek"
  },
  {
    "id": 3339,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:21",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when Alma2 had said these words unto them, he stretched forth his hand unto them and cried with a mighty voice, saying:  Now is the time to repent for the day of salvation draws near.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3340,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:22",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the voice of the Lord, by the mouth of his angels, declare unto all nations that they may have glad tidings of great joy.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3341,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma13:22",
    "question": "Alma2 said the voice of the Lord, by the mouth of his angels, declare and sound these glad tidings among all his people, even to them that are scattered abroad upon the face of the_____.",
    "answer": "Earth"
  },
  {
    "id": 3342,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:23",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the angels declare glad tidings of great joy and that they are made known unto us in plain terms; that we may understand, that we cannot err.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3343,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma13:24",
    "question": "Alma2 said that angels are declaring things for the purpose of preparing the hearts of the_____ of men to receive the word of the Lord at the time of his coming.",
    "answer": "Children"
  },
  {
    "id": 3344,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:25",
    "question": "Alma2 wished that the only Begotten Son of God would come in his day; nevertheless, he said that he would rejoice sooner or later.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3345,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:25",
    "question": "Alma2 said he knew when the only Begotten Son of God would come unto the children of men.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3346,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma13:26",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the coming of the Lord would be made known unto just and_____ men, by the mouth of angels, at the time of his coming.",
    "answer": "Holy"
  },
  {
    "id": 3347,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:26",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the just and holy men would let the people know of the coming of the Lord so that the words of their fathers would be fulfilled, according to that which they have spoken concerning him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3348,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma13:27",
    "question": "Alma2 told his brethren that he wished from the inner most part of his heart and with great anxiety even unto pain; that they would hearken to his words, and cast off their sins, and not_____ the day of their repentance.",
    "answer": "Procrastinate"
  },
  {
    "id": 3349,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma13:28",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people to humble themselves before the Lord, and call on his holy name, and watch and_____ continually, that they may not be tempted above that which they could bear.",
    "answer": "Pray"
  },
  {
    "id": 3350,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma13:29",
    "question": "Alma2 also told his brethren to have faith in the Lord; having a hope that they would receive_____ life; having the love of God always in their hearts, that they may be lifted up at the last day and enter into his rest.",
    "answer": "Eternal",
    "options": ["Gifts", "Long", "Eternal"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3351,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:31",
    "question": "All the words that Alma2 spoke to the people are written in the Book of Alma.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3352,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma14:1,2",
    "question": "After Alma2 had finished speaking to the people; many of them believed in his words and repented; but the most part of them desired to destroy Alma and Amulek.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3353,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma14:3",
    "question": "The people were angry with Alma2 and Amulek because they had testified so plainly against their_____, and they sought to put them away privily.",
    "answer": "Wickedness",
    "options": ["Lustfulness", "Ignorance", "Wickedness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3354,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma14:4",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people took Alma2 and Amulek and bound them with strong_____, and took them before the chief judge of the land.",
    "answer": "Cords",
    "options": ["Wires", "Cords", "Duct Tape"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3355,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma14:5",
    "question": "The people went forth and witnessed against Alma2 and_____; testifying that they had reviled against the law, and their lawyers and judges of the land.",
    "answer": "Amulek"
  },
  {
    "id": 3356,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma14:6",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Zeezrom was not astonished by the words that had been spoken by the people.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3357,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma14:6",
    "question": "Zeezrom knew concerning the blindness of the minds of the people which he had caused by his lying words; and his soul began to be harrowed up under a consciousness of his own guilt.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3358,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma14:7",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____ began to cry unto the people, saying:  Behold, I am guilty, and Alma2 and Amulek are spotless before God.",
    "answer": "Zeezrom"
  },
  {
    "id": 3359,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma14:7",
    "question": "The people cast Zeezrom out from among them and spit on him; and sent men to cast_____ unto all those that believed in his words and also the words of Alma2 and Amulek.",
    "answer": "Stones",
    "options": ["Arrows", "Rocks", "Stones"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3360,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma14:8",
    "question": "The people that believe in the words of Alma2 and Amulek were cast into the fire, and also brought forth their records which contained the Holy Scriptures, that they might also be burned and destroyed by fire.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3361,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma14:10",
    "question": "Amulek wanted to stretch forth his hands and exercise the power of_____ which was in him and Alma2 and save the people from the flames.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 3362,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma14:11",
    "question": "Alma2 told Amulek that the Spirit constrained him not to save the people because the Lord received them unto himself and that the blood of the innocent would stand as a witness against them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3363,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma14:14",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the chief judge of the land came and stood before Alma2 and Amulek as they were bound and smote them with his_____ upon their cheeks.",
    "answer": "Hand",
    "options": ["Whip", "Hand", "Cane"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3364,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "14-17",
    "question": "How many times did the chief judge of the land smack Alma2 and Amulek on their cheeks?",
    "answer": "1",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3365,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma14:16",
    "question": "The chief judge of the land that hit Alma2 and Amulek on the cheek was of the order and faith of_____ who slew Gideon.",
    "answer": "Nehor"
  },
  {
    "id": 3366,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma14:18",
    "question": "Many judges and lawyers and priest came to question Alma2 and Amulek when then were cast into prison for_____ days.",
    "answer": "Three",
    "options": ["Two", "Three", "Four"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3367,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma14:18-20",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma2 and Amulek answered all the questions that were put before them by the judges, lawyers, and priests.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3368,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma14:21",
    "question": "Many people did come gnashing their teeth and_____ on Alma and Amulek.",
    "answer": "Spitting",
    "options": ["Swearing", "Spitting", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3369,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma14:22",
    "question": "The people withheld food and water and took Alma2’s and Amulek’s clothes; and they were also bound with strong cords and confined in prison.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3370,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma14:25",
    "question": "The chief judge and all the judges, lawyers, priests, and teachers that had questioned Alma2 and Amulek before came forth and asked them to deliver themselves if they had the power of_____. ",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 3371,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma14:26",
    "question": "Alma2 and Amulek rose and stood upon their feet and asked the Lord to give them strength according to the faith which is in Christ for deliverance.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3372,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma14:26",
    "question": "Alma2 and Amulek broke the cords with which they were bound; and when the people saw this, they began to flee, for the fear of_____ had come upon them.",
    "answer": "Destruction",
    "options": ["Destruction", "Death", "Stupidity"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3373,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma14:27",
    "question": "And it came to pass that so great was their fear that the people fell first to the earth then stood up and ran out of the prison.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3374,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma14:27",
    "question": "The earth shook mightily, and the walls of the prison fell on the people and they were slain by the fall thereof.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3375,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma14:28",
    "question": "Alma2 and_____ came forth out of the prison and were not hurt because the Lord had granted unto them power, according to their faith which was in Christ.",
    "answer": "Amulek"
  },
  {
    "id": 3376,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma14:29",
    "question": "Many multitudes of people came to see what had happened because of the great noise the walls of the prison had made; and when they saw Alma2 and Amulek come out of prison unharmed, they fled.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3377,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma15:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma2 and Amulek were not commanded to leave the city of Ammonihah.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3378,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma15:1",
    "question": "When Alma2 and Amulek departed the city of Ammonihah they went to the land of Sidom and found all the people that had been cast out and stoned, because they believed in the words of_____.",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 3379,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma15:3",
    "question": "Who lay sick in the land of Sidom with a burning fever, which was caused by the great tribulations of his mind on account of his wickedness?",
    "answer": "Zeezrom"
  },
  {
    "id": 3380,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma15:3",
    "question": "Zeezrom supposed that Alma2 and Amulek were dead because of his iniquity.  And because this great sin and his other sins, did harrow up his mind until it became exceedingly sore.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3381,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma15:3",
    "question": "Zeezrom’s mind did not to began to be scorched with a burning heat because of the sins he had committed.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3382,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma15:9-10",
    "question": "Alma2 healed Zeezrom because he believed in all his words and had faith which was in Christ.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3383,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma15:11",
    "question": "When Alma2 healed Zeezrom he leaped upon his feet and began to walk; and this was done to the great astonishment of all the people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3384,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "12-13",
    "question": "Zeezrom was baptized by_____ and afterward, he began to preach the word of God in the land of Sidom.  Alma-",
    "answer": "Alma15:"
  },
  {
    "id": 3385,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma15:13",
    "question": "Alma2 did not establish a church in the land of Sidom.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3386,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma15:15",
    "question": "The people that were in the land of Ammonihah remained a stiffnecked people and did not repent of their_____.",
    "answer": "Sins",
    "options": ["Sins", "Wrong Doings", "Bad Mouthing"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3387,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma15:15",
    "question": "The people that were in Ammonihah credited the power of Alma2 and Amulek to the_____; for they were of the profession of Nehor, and did not believe in the repentance of their sins.",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },
  {
    "id": 3388,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "15:16",
    "question": "How many people of Amulek's household were converted to the gospel?____",
    "answer": "1",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3389,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma15:16",
    "question": "Amulek was rejected by his own_____ and his relatives and also those that were once his friends; for believing in the word of God.",
    "answer": "Father"
  },
  {
    "id": 3390,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma15:18",
    "question": "Alma2 took Amulek to his own house and administered unto him in his tribulations, and strengthened him in the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3391,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma17:2",
    "question": "The_____ came upon the borders of Zarahemla and the city of Ammonihah and began to slay the people and destroy the city.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Ishmaelites", "Zoramites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3392,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:3",
    "question": "And it came to pass that before the_____ could raise a sufficient army the Lamanites destroyed the people of the city of Ammonihah and also took some people captive into the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3393,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma16:5",
    "question": "Who was the chief captain of the Nephite army during the time that Alma2 and Amulek were among the Nephites?",
    "answer": "Zoram"
  },
  {
    "id": 3394,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma16:5",
    "question": "Zoram had two sons and their names were Lehi and Aha.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3395,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma16:5",
    "question": "Zoram knew that_____ had the spirit of ",
    "answer": "prophecy."
  },
  {
    "id": 3396,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma16:5",
    "question": "Zoram went unto Alma and desired of him to tell them where they should go in the wilderness to search for the Nephites that had been taken captive by the_____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3397,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma16:6",
    "question": "Alma did not inquire of the Lord to let him know where the Lamanites had taken their brethren captive.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3398,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma16:8",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Nephites and Zoram and his sons were able to free their brethren from the Lamanites; and not a soul was lost and they returned to posses their own land.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3399,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma16:9",
    "question": "The people of the city of Ammonihah said that God could not destroy their city because of its_____.",
    "answer": "Greatness",
    "options": ["Majesty", "Size", "Greatness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3400,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma16:10",
    "question": "The city of Ammonihah was left desolate in one day; and the carcasses of the dead were mangled by_____ and wild beasts of the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Dogs",
    "options": ["Dogs", "Coyotes", "Lions"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3401,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma16:11",
    "question": "Because of the scent of the dead bodies that were in the city of_____; the people did not go in the land of Ammonihah for many years.",
    "answer": "Ammonihah"
  },
  {
    "id": 3402,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma16:11",
    "question": "Another name for the land of Ammonihah is the Desolation of Nehors.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3403,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma16:11",
    "question": "The land of Ammonihah was called the Desolation of Nehors because the people were of the profession of_____.",
    "answer": "Nehor"
  },
  {
    "id": 3404,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma16:12",
    "question": "After destruction of Ammonihah there was peace was again among the Nephites and Lamanites for the space of_____ years.",
    "answer": "3",
    "options": ["2", "3", "4"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3405,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma16:13",
    "question": "Alma2 and Amulek went forth preaching repentance to the people in their temples, and their sanctuaries, and in their_____.",
    "answer": "Synagogues"
  },
  {
    "id": 3406,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma16:13",
    "question": "The Nephites worshipped the Lord in all their places that were built after the manner of what tribe of people?",
    "answer": "Jews"
  },
  {
    "id": 3407,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma16:14",
    "question": "Alma2 and Amulek preached the word of God without any respect of persons continually.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3408,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma16:16",
    "question": "There was no inequality among the people; the Lord did pour out his_____ on all the face of the land to prepare the minds of the children of men.",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },
  {
    "id": 3409,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma16:19",
    "question": "The priests taught the coming about the coming of Son of God, his sufferings and death, and also the_____ of the dead.",
    "answer": "Resurrection"
  },
  {
    "id": 3410,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma16:20",
    "question": "Many people inquired concerning the place where the Son of God should come; and they were taught that he would appear unto them after his resurrection.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3411,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma16:21",
    "question": "Because the people were taught that the Son of God would visit them after his resurrection they did not receive the teachings with joy and gladness",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3412,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Beginning of Alma17",
    "question": "Chapters 17 though 26 in the Book of Alma contain the account of the sons of King Mosiah inclusively.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3413,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:1",
    "question": "When Alma2 was journeying from the land of Gideon towards the land of Manti he met the sons’ of_____ journeying towards the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": "Mosiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 3414,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:2",
    "question": "The sons of Mosiah were with Alma2 at the time the_____ first appeared unto him.",
    "answer": "Angel"
  },
  {
    "id": 3415,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma17:2",
    "question": "Alma2 did rejoice exceedingly when he saw his brethren and was even more joyous when he learned that they were still his brethren in the Lord; and had waxed strong in the knowledge of the truth.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3416,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:2",
    "question": "The sons of Mosiah were men of sound_____ and they had searched the scriptures diligently, that they might know the word of God.",
    "answer": "Understanding"
  },
  {
    "id": 3417,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:3",
    "question": "The sons of Mosiah had given themselves to much prayer, and fasting; therefore they had the spirit of prophecy and the spirit of_____.",
    "answer": "Revelation"
  },
  {
    "id": 3418,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:3",
    "question": "The sons of Mosiah taught with great power and_____ of God.",
    "answer": "Authority"
  },
  {
    "id": 3419,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma17:4",
    "question": "For how many years had the sons of Mosiah been teaching the Lamanites the word of God?",
    "answer": "14",
    "options": ["14", "15", "16"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3420,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:5",
    "question": "The sons of Mosiah had many afflictions and suffered much, both in body and in mind, such as_____, thirst and fatigue, and also much labor in the spirit.",
    "answer": "Hungar"
  },
  {
    "id": 3421,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:6",
    "question": "The sons of Mosiah had refused the kingdom of their father called King_____, in the first year of the reign of judges.",
    "answer": "Mosiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 3422,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:7",
    "question": "The sons of Mosiah departed out of the land of Zarahemla, and took their_____., spears, bows, arrows, and slings for the purpose of providing food for themselves in the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Swords"
  },
  {
    "id": 3423,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma17:8",
    "question": "The sons of Mosiah did not take anyone else but themselves to preach to word of God unto the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3424,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma17:9",
    "question": "The sons of Mosiah fasted and prayed much that the Lord would grant unto them a_____ of his Spirit.",
    "answer": "Portion",
    "options": ["Large Amount", "Small Amount", "Portion"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3425,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:9",
    "question": "The sons of Mosiah were desirous to be_____ in the hands of God in bringing the Lamanites to the knowledge of the truth and baseness of the traditions of their fathers which was not correct.",
    "answer": "Instuments"
  },
  {
    "id": 3426,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma17:11",
    "question": "The Lord said unto the sons of Mosiah to establish his word and be patient in long-suffering and afflictions.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3427,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:11",
    "question": "The reason the Lord wanted the sons of Mosiah to be patient and long-suffering was so they could be_____ examples unto him and be an instrument in his hands in bringing many souls unto the salvation.",
    "answer": "Good"
  },
  {
    "id": 3428,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma17:12",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the_____ of the sons of Mosiah, and also those that were with them received courage to go forth unto the Lamanites to declare the word of God.",
    "answer": "Hearts",
    "options": ["Hearts", "Bodies", "Heads"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3429,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma17:13",
    "question": "When the sons of Mosiah arrived at the borders of the land of the Lamanites they separated themselves from one another.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3430,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:14",
    "question": "The hearts of the Lamanites were set upon riches, or upon gold and silver, and precious stones; but they did not want to labor for these things with their own_____.",
    "answer": "Hands"
  },
  {
    "id": 3431,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma17:15",
    "question": "The Lamanites were a very indolent people, and many of them worshipped_____, however the promises of the Lord were extended unto them on the condition of repentance.",
    "answer": "Idols",
    "options": ["Statues", "Idols", "Horses"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3432,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:18",
    "question": "Which of the sons of Mosiah was the chief among them? Administering unto them and departed from them to teach the Lamanites on his own. ",
    "answer": "Ammon"
  },
  {
    "id": 3433,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:19",
    "question": "Ammon went to the land of Ishmael, which was called after the sons’ of_____; who also became Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Ishmael"
  },
  {
    "id": 3434,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma17:20",
    "question": "When Ammon entered the land of Ishmael, the Lamanites took him and bound him which was their custom to bind all Nephites that fell into their hands.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3435,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:21",
    "question": "The Lamanites took Ammon and carried him before the king who was over the land of Ismael; and his name was_____; and he was a descendant of Ishmael.",
    "answer": "Lamoni"
  },
  {
    "id": 3436,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma17:22-23",
    "question": "King Lamoni asked Ammon if he desired to live in the land among the Lamanites and Ammon said no.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3437,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:24",
    "question": "King Lamoni caused that the bands on Ammon to be loosed wanted Ammon to marry one of his_____.",
    "answer": "Daughters"
  },
  {
    "id": 3438,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma17:25",
    "question": "Ammon became a_____ to King Lamoni and was sent to watch over his flocks.",
    "answer": "Servant",
    "options": ["Servant", "Shepherd", "Slave"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3439,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "26-27",
    "question": "How many days had Ammon been a servant unto King Lamoni when some Lamanites came and scattered his flock?",
    "answer": "2",
    "options": ["2", "3", "4"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3440,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:26",
    "question": "What was the name of the place of water where all the Lamanites took their flocks for water?",
    "answer": "Sebus"
  },
  {
    "id": 3441,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma17:28-29",
    "question": "The servants of King Lamoni began to murmur and cry because they said that he would kill them for allowing other Lamanites to scatter his flock.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3442,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma17:29",
    "question": "Ammon wanted to show forth his power to his fellow servants in restoring the king’s flock so that he might lead them to believe in his_____.",
    "answer": "Words",
    "options": ["Babblings", "Speeches", "Words"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3443,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma17:32",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Ammon led the search with the servants to find the flocks of King Lamoni and did gather them together again to the place of Sebus for water.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3444,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:34",
    "question": "The same men that had scattered the_____ of King Lamoni came a second time to scatter them again, and Ammon went to contend with them.",
    "answer": "Flocks"
  },
  {
    "id": 3445,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma17:35",
    "question": "The men did not fear Ammon because they thought that one of them could slay him according to their pleasure.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3446,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:35",
    "question": "The men that had scattered King Lamoni’s flock did not know that the Lord had promised King_____ that he would deliver his sons out of their hands.",
    "answer": "Mosiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 3447,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma17:35",
    "question": "The men that contended with Ammon did not know anything concerning the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3448,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma17:35",
    "question": "The men that contended with Ammon delighted in the destruction of their brethren; and this was the cause or purpose for scattering the flocks of King Lamoni.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3449,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:36",
    "question": "What was the choice of weapon that Ammon used the first time to slay the men who had scattered the kings’ flocks?",
    "answer": "stones"
  },
  {
    "id": 3450,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma17:36",
    "question": "The men were angry with Ammon because he had slain their brethren so they came after him with their_____ to slay him because they could not hit him with their stones.",
    "answer": "Clubs",
    "options": ["Bats", "Clubs", "Swords"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3451,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma17:37",
    "question": "Ammon did not cut the arms of every man that tried to kill him with the edge of his sword.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3452,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma17:38",
    "question": "How many men did Ammon kill with his sling and stones?",
    "answer": "6",
    "options": ["6", "7", "8"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3453,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma17:39",
    "question": "Ammon returned the flocks of Kings Lamoni to his pasture and then went unto the king carrying the_____ which he had smitten off by the sword as a testimony of the things which they had done.",
    "answer": "Arms",
    "options": ["Legs", "Heads", "Arms"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3454,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:1",
    "question": "King Lamoni caused that his servants should stand before him and to testify of the things which they had seen at the waters of Sebus.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3455,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma18:2",
    "question": "King Lamoni thought Ammon was the_____Spirit.",
    "answer": "Great",
    "options": ["Good", "Bad", "Great"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3456,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:3",
    "question": "The servants of King Lamoni did not know if Ammon was a man or the Great Spirit; but they did know that he could not be slain.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3457,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:4",
    "question": "Because of the things which he had done; King Lamoni thought the Ammon was the Great_____.",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },
  {
    "id": 3458,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma18:4",
    "question": "King Lamoni thought that the Great Spirit had come down to spare the lives of his servants and it was the Great Spirit that had been spoken by their_____.",
    "answer": "Fathers",
    "options": ["Mothers", "Brothers", "Fathers"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3459,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "5-6",
    "question": "King_____ was taught by his father that there was a Great Spirit; and feared that it had come down because he had slain so many of his servants for letting the Lamanites scatter his flocks.  Lamoni-",
    "answer": "Alma18:"
  },
  {
    "id": 3460,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma18:8",
    "question": "Ammon was preparing the king’s horse’s and_____ when King Lamoni asked his servants saying:  Where is this man that has such great power?",
    "answer": "Chariots",
    "options": ["Hair", "Supper", "Chariots"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3461,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:8",
    "question": "Ammon was preparing the king’s horses and chariots when King Lamoni asked his servants saying:  Where is this man that has such great power?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3462,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma18:10",
    "question": "King Lamoni said that there had not been any servant among all his servants that has been so_____ as Ammon; because he remembered to execute all his commandments.",
    "answer": "Faithful",
    "options": ["Nice", "Faithful", "Honest"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3463,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:12",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when Ammon had finished preparing the horse’s and_____ of King Lamoni; he returned to the king and saw that his countenance had change.",
    "answer": "Chariots"
  },
  {
    "id": 3464,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:13",
    "question": "What was the other name that one of the servants of King Lamoni called Ammon by?",
    "answer": "Rabbanah"
  },
  {
    "id": 3465,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:13",
    "question": "The word Rabbanah interpreted means powerful or great king.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3466,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:13",
    "question": "The word Rabbanah only appears written in the Book of Alma.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3467,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:14",
    "question": "When Ammon turned himself to King Lamoni and asked what he desired of him and the king did not answer him for one hour.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3468,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:16",
    "question": "Because Ammon was filled with the Spirit of God; he could perceived the thoughts of King_____.",
    "answer": "Lamoni"
  },
  {
    "id": 3469,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:17",
    "question": "Ammon told King Lamoni that he was just a man and his servant; and told him that he would do anything which the king desired as long as it was right.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3470,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:18",
    "question": "King Lamoni marveled because_____ could discern his thoughts and asked:  Who art you? Are you the Great Spirit who knows all things? ",
    "answer": "Ammon"
  },
  {
    "id": 3471,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:19",
    "question": "Ammon told King Lamoni that he was the Great Spirit.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3472,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:20",
    "question": "King Lamoni told Ammon that he could speak boldly, and tell him by what power had he slew the_____of his brethren that had scattered his flocks.",
    "answer": "Arms"
  },
  {
    "id": 3473,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma18:21",
    "question": "King Lamoni told Ammon if he told him concerning these things that he would give him anything which he desired and that he knew that he was more powerful than his_____.",
    "answer": "Armies",
    "options": ["Battalions", "Navy Seals", "Armies"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3474,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma18:22",
    "question": "Because Ammon was wise and_____, he asked King Lamoni if he would hearken unto his words and tell him by what power he had done the things that he did.",
    "answer": "Harmless",
    "options": ["Large", "Harmless", "Charismatic"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3475,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:23",
    "question": "King Lamoni told Ammon that he would not believe in his words.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3476,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "24-25",
    "question": "King Lamoni did not know what Ammon meant when he asked him if he believed that there was a_____.  God-",
    "answer": "Alma18:"
  },
  {
    "id": 3477,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:24-25",
    "question": "King Lamoni did not know what Ammon meant when he asked him if he believed that there was a God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3478,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:26-29",
    "question": "King Lamoni believed that Great Spirit or God had created all things which were in the_____; but did not know concerning the heavens.",
    "answer": "Earth"
  },
  {
    "id": 3479,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:30",
    "question": "Ammon told King Lamoni that the heavens’ was the place where God dwelled with all his holy_____.",
    "answer": "Angels"
  },
  {
    "id": 3480,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:31-32",
    "question": "King Lamoni asked Ammon if heaven was above the earth; and Ammon told him yes and that God looks down upon all the children of men.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3481,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:32",
    "question": "Ammon told King Lamoni that God knows all the thoughts and intents of the heart; because his_____ had created all the children of men from the beginning.",
    "answer": "Hand"
  },
  {
    "id": 3482,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:33",
    "question": "King Lamoni asked Ammon if he was sent from God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3483,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:34",
    "question": "Ammon told King Lamoni that God was just a man; and he had created all men in his own_____.",
    "answer": "Image"
  },
  {
    "id": 3484,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:34",
    "question": "Ammon told King Lamoni that he was called by the Lord’s Holy Spirit to teach God’s things unto his people, that they may be brought to the knowledge of that which is_____and true.",
    "answer": "Just"
  },
  {
    "id": 3485,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:35",
    "question": "Ammon told King Lamoni that a portion of the Spirit of God dwelled in him and give him knowledge, and also power according to his_____ and desires which are in God.",
    "answer": "Faith"
  },
  {
    "id": 3486,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:36",
    "question": "After Ammon had finished with his words he began to tell King Lamoni of the creation of the world, and also the creation of father_____.",
    "answer": "Adam"
  },
  {
    "id": 3487,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:36",
    "question": "Ammon also told the king about the fall of man, and rehearsed and laid before him the records and the holy_____ of the people which had been spoken by the prophets.",
    "answer": "Scriptures"
  },
  {
    "id": 3488,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:36",
    "question": "Ammon however, did not tell King Lamoni from the time that Lehi their father had left Jerusalem.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3489,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:37",
    "question": "Alma also rehearsed unto the king and his servants all the journeyings of their fathers in the wilderness, and all the suffering with hunger and thirst, and their travel, etc.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3490,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:38",
    "question": "Ammon also rehearsed unto the kings and his servants concerning the rebellions of_____ and Lemuel and the sons of Ishmael.",
    "answer": "Laman"
  },
  {
    "id": 3491,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:38",
    "question": "Ammon expounded to King Lamoni and his servants all the records and scriptures from the time Lehi left_____ down to the present time.",
    "answer": "Jerusalem"
  },
  {
    "id": 3492,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:39",
    "question": "Ammon also expounded unto them the plan of redemption, which was prepared from the foundation of the world; and also concerning the coming of _____, and all the works of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 3493,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:40",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when Ammon had finished with his words King Lamoni did not believe his words.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3494,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:41",
    "question": "King Lamoni began to cry unto the Lord, to have mercy on him and his people liked he had upon the people of Nephi.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3495,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:42",
    "question": "When King Lamoni had finished crying to the Lord for mercy he fell to the earth and if he were_____.",
    "answer": "Dead"
  },
  {
    "id": 3496,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:43",
    "question": "And it came to pass that his servants carried King Lamoni unto his wife, and laid him upon a bed; and he laid there as if he were dead for the space of two days and two_____.",
    "answer": "Nights"
  },
  {
    "id": 3497,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:43",
    "question": "King Lamoni’s wife and his sons, and his daughters mourned over him, after the manner of the_____, greatly lamenting his loss.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3498,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma19:2",
    "question": "King Lamoni’s wife heard of the fame of_____ and sent for him.",
    "answer": "Ammon"
  },
  {
    "id": 3499,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma19:5",
    "question": "The queen desired of Ammon to go to see her husband because some people had said that King Lamoni was dead and that he stunk but she said that her husband did not stink.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3500,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma19:6",
    "question": "Ammon knew that King Lamoni was under the power of God; he knew that the dark_____ of unbelief was being cast away from his mind.",
    "answer": "Veil",
    "options": ["Cloud", "Dream", "Veil"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3501,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma19:6",
    "question": "Ammon also knew that King Lamoni was experiencing a light which did light up his mind, which was the light of the Glory of God, which was a marvelous light of goodness.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3502,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma19:6",
    "question": "Ammon knew that King Lamoni had the of everlasting life lighted up his soul and that he had overcome his_____ frame, and he was carried away in God.",
    "answer": "Natural",
    "options": ["Weakened", "Natural", "Spiritual"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3503,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma19:7",
    "question": "Ammon did not know that King Lamoni had passed away.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3504,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma19:8",
    "question": "Ammon told the queen that King Lamoni was not dead; but slept in_____, and that tomorrow he would rise again; therefore not to bury him.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 3505,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "9-10",
    "question": "The wife of King Lamoni believed all the words of_____; and because of her exceeding faith she would be blessed.  Ammon-",
    "answer": "Alma19:"
  },
  {
    "id": 3506,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma19:12",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Ammon was wrong about his prediction, and King Lamoni did not arise when Ammon said he would.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3507,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma19:13",
    "question": "King Lamoni told his wife that he had seen his_____; and that he shall come forth, and be born of a woman, and he would redeem all mankind who believe in his name.",
    "answer": "Redeemer",
    "options": ["Forefathers", "Father", "Redeemer"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3508,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma19:14",
    "question": "King Lamoni’s heart was swollen with joy and he snaked to the ground and so did the queen because they had been overpowered by the Spirit.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3509,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma19:15",
    "question": "The servants of King Lamoni who testified to him about the great power of Ammon began to cry unto God because the fear of the Lord had come upon them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3510,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma19:16",
    "question": "All the servants of King Lamoni called on the name of the Lord until they all had fallen to the ground.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3511,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma19:16",
    "question": "What was the name of the servant of King Lamoni that had been converted unto the Lord for many years, on account of a remarkable vision of her father?",
    "answer": "Abish"
  },
  {
    "id": 3512,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma19:16",
    "question": "Of what tribe was Abish?",
    "answer": "Lamanite",
    "options": ["Nephite", "Lamanite", "Ishmaelite"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3513,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma19:17",
    "question": "Abish let everyone of the servants of King Lamoni know that she had been converted to the Lord.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3514,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma19:17",
    "question": "Abish wanted to tell the people of what happened among them so she ran from house to_____, making it known unto the people.",
    "answer": "House"
  },
  {
    "id": 3515,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma19:18",
    "question": "The multitude began to assemble themselves together and beheld the king, and the queen, and Ammon, and their servants lay_____ upon the earth.",
    "answer": "Prostrate",
    "options": ["Still", "Quietly", "Prostrate"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3516,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma19:19",
    "question": "The people began to murmur among themselves; some saying that it was a great evil that had come upon the king and his house because he had let a_____ remain in the land.",
    "answer": "Nephite",
    "options": ["Lamanite", "Nephite", "Zoramite"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3517,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma19:20",
    "question": "Some of the people rebuked the king saying that he had brought this evil upon his house, because he had slew his servants who had had their flocks scattered at the waters of_____.",
    "answer": "Sebus"
  },
  {
    "id": 3518,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma19:22",
    "question": "One who was among the people was exceedingly angry with_____ because he had killed his brother and he went forth to slay Ammon; and as he lifted his sword to kill Ammon, he fell dead.",
    "answer": "Ammon"
  },
  {
    "id": 3519,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma19:24",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the multitude did not dare to touch Ammon, and began to marvel again among themselves what could be the cause of the great power that Ammon had and what all these things could mean.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3520,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma19:25",
    "question": "And it came to pass that there were many among the people who said Ammon was the Great_____, and others said he was sent by the Great Spirit.",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },
  {
    "id": 3521,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma19:26",
    "question": "Some of the people said that Ammon was a_____, who had been sent from the Nephites to torment them.",
    "answer": "Monster",
    "options": ["Monster", "Devil", "Neither A Or B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3522,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma19:27",
    "question": "And there were some who said that Ammon was sent by the Great Spirit to afflict them because of their iniquities.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3523,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "29-28",
    "question": "Abish took the_____ by the hand; and as soon as she touched her hand she stood up and thanked Jesus for saving her from an awful hell.  Queen-",
    "answer": "Alma19:"
  },
  {
    "id": 3524,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma19:30",
    "question": "The queen did not clasp her hands, being filled with joy, speaking many words which were not understood.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3525,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "29,30",
    "question": "Who took King Lamoni by the hand and he stood upon his feet?  Abish-Alma19:",
    "answer": "16,"
  },
  {
    "id": 3526,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma19:31",
    "question": "When King Lamoni saw the contention among his people he went forth and began to rebuke them, and to teach them the words which he had heard from_____.",
    "answer": "Ammon"
  },
  {
    "id": 3527,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma19:31-32",
    "question": "Many of the people were converted by the words of King Lamoni but there were many among them who would not hear his words; therefore they went on their way.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3528,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma29:33",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Ammon stood up and began to administer unto the people, and also did all the servants of King Lamoni; they declared that their hearts had been changed; and they had no more desire to do_____.",
    "answer": "Evil"
  },
  {
    "id": 3529,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma19:34",
    "question": "Many of the people of Lord began to declare to the people that they had seen_____ and had conversed with them; and they had told them the things of God, and his righteousness.",
    "answer": "Angels",
    "options": ["Devils", "Angels", "Dragons"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3530,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma19:36",
    "question": "And the work of the Lord did commence among the_____ and he began to pour his Spirit upon them; and we see that his arm is extended to all people who will repent and believe in his name.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3531,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma20:1",
    "question": "King Lamoni2 desired that Ammon would go with him to the land of Nephi, that he might show him unto his_____.",
    "answer": "Father",
    "options": ["Brother", "Mother", "Father"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3532,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma20:2",
    "question": "Who told Ammon not to go to the land of Nephi?",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 3533,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma20:2",
    "question": "The Lord told Ammon not to go to the land of Nephi because who would seek his life?  King ",
    "answer": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 3534,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma20:2",
    "question": "Ammon’s was told by the Lord that his brother’s Aaron, Muloki, and Ammah were in prison in the land of_____; and that he should go there.",
    "answer": "Middoni"
  },
  {
    "id": 3535,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma20:4",
    "question": "Who told Ammon that the king of the land of Middoni was his friend, and that he would go with him to flatter him and he would cast his brethren from prison?  Lamoni ",
    "answer": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 3536,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma20:6",
    "question": "When King Lamoni2 heard the words of Ammon he caused that his servants prepare his horses and his_____ for the trip.",
    "answer": "Chariots"
  },
  {
    "id": 3537,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma20:8",
    "question": "When Ammon and King Lamoni2 where on their journey they came across King Lamoni1 who was king over all the land.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3538,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma20:10",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 asked his son King Lamon2 why and where was he going with Ammon who was a_____?",
    "answer": "Nephite",
    "options": ["Bad Person", "Lamanite", "Nephite"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3539,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma-20:9,12",
    "question": "King Lamoni2 told King Lamoni1 that he was tarrying in his own kingdom; and that was the reason he did not go to the feast his father had prepared for his sons.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3540,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma20:13",
    "question": "King Lamon2 was not astonished because King Lamon1 was angry with him.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3541,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma20:13",
    "question": "King Lamon1 told his son that Ammon was the son of liar, and had robbed their fathers by their cunning and their lyings; and had deceived them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3542,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma20:14",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 told his son to slay among with his_____ and not to go to the land of Middoni but to go to the land or Ishmael.",
    "answer": "Sword"
  },
  {
    "id": 3543,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma20:15",
    "question": "King Lamoni2 told King Lamoni1 that he would slay Ammon and go to the land of Ishmael.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3544,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma20:15",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 knew that Ammon and his brethren were just men and holy_____ of the true God.",
    "answer": "Prophets"
  },
  {
    "id": 3545,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma20:16",
    "question": "Because of the words that King Lamoni1 had told him, his father was angry with him and drew his sword to slay him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3546,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma20:17",
    "question": "Ammon stood before King Lamoni1 and told him that he should not slay his son because he was an innocent man and had _____of his sins.",
    "answer": "Repented"
  },
  {
    "id": 3547,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma20:20",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 stretched forth his hand to slay Ammon.  But Ammon withstood his blows, and cut the_____ of the king.",
    "answer": "Arm",
    "options": ["Leg", "Arm", "Head"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3548,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma20:21",
    "question": "King Lamon1 saw that he could not slay Ammon and began to plead with Ammon to spare his life.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3549,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma20:22",
    "question": "Ammon told King Lamon1 that he would_____ him if he did not release his brethren from prison.",
    "answer": "Slay",
    "options": ["Slay", "Spare", "Free"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3550,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma20:23",
    "question": "King Lamon1 told Ammon that he would grant him anything that he would ask of him even half of his_____.",
    "answer": "Kingdom"
  },
  {
    "id": 3551,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma20:26",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 saw that Ammon had know desire to slay him and a great_____ for his son, and he was astonished.",
    "answer": "Love",
    "options": ["Likeness", "Fondness", "Love"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3552,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma20:26",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 said that he would not grant unto his son his kingdom again and that he would continue to govern him.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3553,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma20:28",
    "question": "Because of his hardened heart King Lamoni1 did not release Ammon’s brethren from prison.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3554,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma20:29",
    "question": "When Ammon and King Lamoni2 were journeying toward the land of Middoni they met his brethren and they were exceedingly_____ because they saw that they were naked.",
    "answer": "Sorrowful",
    "options": ["Joyous", "Sorrowful", "Mad"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3555,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma20:29",
    "question": "Ammon’s brothers had suffered hunger, thirst, and all kinds of afflictions; nevertheless they were_____ in all their sufferings.",
    "answer": "Patient"
  },
  {
    "id": 3556,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma20:30",
    "question": "It was their lot that Ammon’s brothers had fallen into the hands of a more hardened and a more stiffnecked Lamanites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3557,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma21:1",
    "question": "Ammon and his brethren separated themselves again and Aaron took his journey towards the land that was called Jerusalem by the_____; calling it after the land of their fathers.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3558,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma21:2",
    "question": "The Lamanites and Amalekites and the people of Amulon had built a great city which was called_____.",
    "answer": "Jerusalem"
  },
  {
    "id": 3559,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma21:4",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Aaron came upon the city of Jerusalem and first began to preach to the Amulonites.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3560,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma21:4",
    "question": "Many of the Amalekites and Amulonites built_____ after the order of the Nehors.",
    "answer": "Synagogues",
    "options": ["Houses", "Barns", "Synagogues"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3561,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma21:5",
    "question": "When Aaron entered into a synagogue and began to preach unto them; there arose an Amalekite and began to contend with him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3562,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma21:8",
    "question": "The _____ that contended with Aaron did not believe that Aaron knew of things to come and knew of the things he had spoken of.",
    "answer": "Amalekite"
  },
  {
    "id": 3563,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma21:9",
    "question": "Aaron began to open the_____ unto the people concerning the coming of Christ and also concerning the resurrection of the dead.",
    "answer": "Scriptures"
  },
  {
    "id": 3564,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma21:9",
    "question": "Aaron told the people that there could be no redemption for mankind save it was through the death and sufferings of Christ, and the atonement of his_____.",
    "answer": "Blood",
    "options": ["Heart", "Blood", "Body"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3565,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma21:10",
    "question": "The people began to be angry with Aaron and started to mock him; and they would not hear his words so he left their synagogue.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3566,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma21:11",
    "question": "Aaron came upon the land which was called Ani-Anti and came upon his brother Muloki and also Ammah and his brethren contending with the people about the word of_____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 3567,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma21:13",
    "question": "Aaron and a certain number of his brethren were taken and cast into prison and the remainder of them fled to the land of Middoni and the regions surrounding it.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3568,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "16-17",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Aaron and his brethren were blessed by the Lord and brought many of the_____ and Lamanites to the knowledge of the truth.   Amalekites-",
    "answer": "Alma21:"
  },
  {
    "id": 3569,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma21:17",
    "question": "Because of Aaron and his brethren many of the people were brought to the convincing of their sins, and of the traditions of their fathers, which were not correct.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3570,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma21:18",
    "question": "Ammon and King Lamoni2 returned from the land of Middoni to the land of Ishmael, which was the land of their_____.",
    "answer": "Inheritance",
    "options": ["Joy", "Hardship", "Inheritance"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3571,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma21:19",
    "question": "King Lamoni2 wanted Ammon to serve him and be his servant.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3572,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma21:21",
    "question": "King Lamoni2 caused that there should be synagogues built in the land of Ismael and declared unto those that were under his reign that they were a_____ people.",
    "answer": "Free",
    "options": ["Righteous", "Free", "Unrighteous"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3573,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma21:22",
    "question": "King Lamoni2 also declared unto the people that they had to liberty of worshiping the Lord their _____ according to their desires.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 3574,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma21:23",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Ammon did preach unto the people of King Lamoni2 all things pertaining to righteousness; and they were zealous in keeping the commandments of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3575,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:1",
    "question": "During the time when Ammon was teaching the people of King Lamoni2; Aaron and his brethren departed from the land of Middoni and were led by the_____ to the land of Nephi.",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },
  {
    "id": 3576,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma22:2",
    "question": "Ammon and his brethren went unto the king’s_____ and bowed himself before the king.",
    "answer": "Palace",
    "options": ["Throne", "House", "Palace"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3577,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma22:3",
    "question": "Ammon and his brethren desired that King Lamon1 would spare their lives and they would become his servants.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3578,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma22:3",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 was pleased with Aaron and his brethren and desired them to become his servants.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3579,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma22:3",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 insisted that Aaron administer unto him because he was troubled of the generosity and the_____ of the words of Ammon.",
    "answer": "Greatness",
    "options": ["Kindness", "Greatness", "Truthfulness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3580,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:3",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 did not want to know why Ammon had not come to the land of Middoni with_____ and his brethren.",
    "answer": "Aaron"
  },
  {
    "id": 3581,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma22:4",
    "question": "Who told King Lamoni1 that Ammon had been called by the Spirit of the Lord to go to the land of Ishmael to teach the people?",
    "answer": "Aaron",
    "options": ["Muloki", "Ammah", "Aaron"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3582,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma22:5",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 was troubled because Aaron had told him concerning the Spirit of the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3583,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma22:7",
    "question": "Aaron was not pleased with King Lamoni1 because he did not believe in God.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3584,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:10",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 asked Aaron if God was the Great Spirit who had created all things both in heaven and in_____.",
    "answer": "Earth"
  },
  {
    "id": 3585,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma22:11",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 believed that the Great Spirit created all things and desired to know more concerning all the things that Aaron had said.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3586,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma22:13",
    "question": "Aaron did not start to teach King Lamoni1 about the creation of Adam and reading the scriptures unto the king.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3587,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:12",
    "question": "Aaron told the king how God created man after his own_____, and that God gave him commandments, and that because of transgression, man had fallen.",
    "answer": "Image"
  },
  {
    "id": 3588,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:14",
    "question": "Aaron told King Lamoni1 since man had fallen he could not merit anything of himself; but the sufferings and death of_____ atoned for their sins, though faith and repentance, etc.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 3589,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:15",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 asked Aaron what was required of him to have_____ life.",
    "answer": "Eternal"
  },
  {
    "id": 3590,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma22:15",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 also asked Aaron what he should do to be born of God, having his wicked spirit rooted out of his_____, and receive the Spirit, that he may be filled with joy.",
    "answer": "Breast",
    "options": ["Breast", "Body", "Chest"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3591,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma22:15",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 did not want to be cast off at the last day and said that he would forsake his_____, that he may receive great joy.",
    "answer": "Kingdom",
    "options": ["Wife", "Children", "Kingdom"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3592,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma22:16",
    "question": "Aaron told King Lamoni1 that he needed to bow himself before God and repent of all of his sins and call on his name in faith, believing that he would receive the_____ which he desired.",
    "answer": "Hope",
    "options": ["Hope", "Answer", "Revelation"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3593,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma22:17",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when Aaron had said these words, King Lamoni1 did not bow down before the Lord, upon hid knees; and lay prostrate himself upon the earth.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3594,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma22:18",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 told God that he would give away all his_____ to know him, and that he may be raised from the dead, and be saved at the last day.",
    "answer": "Sins",
    "options": ["Fortune", "Sins", "Kingdoms"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3595,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:19",
    "question": "The servants of King Lamoni1 ran and told the_____ all that had happened unto the king.",
    "answer": "Queen"
  },
  {
    "id": 3596,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma22:19",
    "question": "The queen was angry with Aaron and his brethren because she thought that they had been the cause of his fall, and commanded that her servants take and slay them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3597,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma22:21",
    "question": "The queen saw that the servants were afraid to lay their hands upon Aaron and his brethren and she began to fear exceedingly, lest there should some_____ come upon her.",
    "answer": "Evil",
    "options": ["Curse", "Evil", "Omen"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3598,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:22",
    "question": "Because Aaron saw that there should be a great contention and disturbance among the people; he put forth his hand and raised King _____ from the earth.",
    "answer": "Lamoni1"
  },
  {
    "id": 3599,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:23",
    "question": "When the queen and many of the servants saw what_____ had done they marveled and began to fear.  And King Lamoni1 stood forth, and began to minister unto them.",
    "answer": "Aaron"
  },
  {
    "id": 3600,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma22:23",
    "question": "Because of the ministering of King Lamoni1,all of his household was converted unto the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3601,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma22:25",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 administered unto his people and they were pacified towards Aaron and those who were with him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3602,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:27",
    "question": "The land of Zarahemla was divided by a_____ strip of wilderness, which ran from the sea east, and to the sea west.",
    "answer": "Narrow"
  },
  {
    "id": 3603,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:27",
    "question": "The narrow strip of wilderness divided the_____ and the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3604,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma22:28",
    "question": "The Lamanites that were more idled lived in the wilderness and lived west of the land of Nephi.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3605,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma22:28",
    "question": "The more _____of the Lamanites lived in the wilderness, and dwelt in tents; and they were spread through the wilderness on the west of the land of Nephi.",
    "answer": "Idle",
    "options": ["Idle", "Stiffnecked", "Ferocious"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3606,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:29",
    "question": "The Nephites were nearly surrounded by the_____; nevertheless they had taken possession of all the northern parts of the land bordering on the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3607,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:30",
    "question": "The land the Nephites called Bountiful bordered upon the land which they called_____; which was so far northward that it came into the land which been peopled, and been destroyed.",
    "answer": "Desolation"
  },
  {
    "id": 3608,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:31",
    "question": "The land northward was called Desolation and the land southward was called_____.",
    "answer": "Bountiful"
  },
  {
    "id": 3609,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma22:31",
    "question": "The land that was called Bountiful was filled with all manner of wild animals of every kind, and part of them had come from the land northward for_____.",
    "answer": "Food",
    "options": ["Water", "Refuge", "Food"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3610,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma22:32",
    "question": "How long did it take a Nephite to cross from the line Bountiful to the land of Desolation?",
    "answer": "One Day And A Half",
    "options": [
      "One Day And A Half",
      "Two Days And A Half",
      "Three Days And A Half"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 3611,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:32",
    "question": "The land of Nephi and the land of Zarahemla were nearly surrounded by_____; and there was a small neck of land between the land northward and the land southward.",
    "answer": "Water"
  },
  {
    "id": 3612,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma22:34",
    "question": "At the end of chapter 22 Mormon returns us again to the account of Ammon and Aaron, Omner and Himni, and their brethren.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3613,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma23:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the king of the Lamanites sent a proclamation among all his people, that they should not lay their hands upon Ammon and his ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3614,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma23:1",
    "question": "The proclamation the king of the Lamanites sent out among his people said that Ammon and his brethren would not go forth preaching the word of God",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3615,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma23:2",
    "question": "The king sent a decree among his people that they should let Ammon and his brethren into their houses, and also in their temples, and their_____.",
    "answer": "Sanctuaries"
  },
  {
    "id": 3616,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma23:3",
    "question": "Because King Lamoni1 and his household had been converted; he sent his proclamation throughout the land unto his people, that the word of_____ might have no obstruction.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 3617,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma23:3",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 wanted to convince all his people that they were all brethren, and that they ought not to murder, plunder, steal, nor commit adultery, nor to commit any manner of_____.",
    "answer": "Wickedness"
  },
  {
    "id": 3618,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma23:5",
    "question": "Because of the preaching of Aaron and his brethren; _____ were brought to the knowledge of the Lord, and taught to believe in the traditions of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Thousands",
    "options": ["Hundreds", "Thousands", "Millions"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3619,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma23:5",
    "question": "Thousands of_____ were taught the records and prophecies which were handed down even to the present time.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3620,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma23:6",
    "question": "Many Lamanites were brought to the knowledge of the truth, through the preaching of Ammon and his brethren, according to the spirit of revelation, and the power of God working miracles in them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3621,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma23:6",
    "question": "And as sure as the Lord lives, many of the Lamanites that were taught the word of God by Ammon and his brethren fell away from the church.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3622,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "-Alma23:7",
    "question": "Many of the Lamanites became a righteous people and put down their weapons of rebellion and did not fight against God anymore, neither against any of their brethren.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3623,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma23:14",
    "question": "Only_____ of the Amalekites were converted unto the church of God by Ammon and his brethren.",
    "answer": "1",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3624,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma23:14",
    "question": "Ammon and his brethren were able to convert many of the Amulonites unto the church of God.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3625,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma23:16",
    "question": "Because the king desired to have a name to distinguish themselves from their brethren; they consulted with Aaron and many of his priests concerning the name they should take upon themselves.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3626,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma23:17",
    "question": "The name that the people took upon themselves was Anti-_____; and they were no longer called Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 3627,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma23:17 & Alma27:26",
    "question": "The Anti-Nephi-Lehies were also known by what other name?",
    "answer": "Ammonites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3628,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma23:18",
    "question": "The Anti-Nephi-Lehies became a very_____ people; and they were friendly with the Nephites and the curse of God did no more follow them.",
    "answer": "Industrious",
    "options": ["Idolatrous", "Industrious", "Lazy"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3629,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people who were not converted to the church and had not take upon the name of Anti-Nephi-Lehies were stirred up by the Amulonites and_____ to anger against their brethren.",
    "answer": "Amalekites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3630,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma24:2",
    "question": "The people began to rebel against their king and took up arms against the people of Anti-Nephi-Lehi.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3631,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:3",
    "question": "The king conferred the_____ upon his son, and he was called Anti-Lehi-Nephi.",
    "answer": "Kingdom"
  },
  {
    "id": 3632,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:5",
    "question": "Ammon and his brethren wanted to have a council meeting with King Lamoni2 and his brother Anti-Nephi-_____.",
    "answer": "Lehi"
  },
  {
    "id": 3633,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma24:6",
    "question": "There was not one soul among all the people that had been converted unto the Lord that would take up arms against their brethren; and they would also not make preparations of war.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3634,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:8",
    "question": "King_____ thank his great God that he had given him and his people a portion of his Spirit to soften their hearts, that they were able to have opened a correspondence with their brethren the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Lamoni"
  },
  {
    "id": 3635,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:10",
    "question": "King Lamoni2 told the people and thanked his great_____, for forgiving them of their many sins and murders which they had committed, and had taken away the guilt from their hearts, through the Merits of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 3636,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma24:12",
    "question": "King Lamoni2 said to the people since God had taken away their stains, their_____ had become bright, and not to stain them no more with the blood of their brethren.",
    "answer": "Swords",
    "options": ["Hearts", "Sins", "Swords"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3637,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:14",
    "question": "King Lamoni2 said that God loved their souls as well as their children; therefore, in his mercy he had visited them by his angels that the plan of_____ might be made known unto them as well as future generations.",
    "answer": "Salvation"
  },
  {
    "id": 3638,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma24:15",
    "question": "King Lamoni2 told the people to hide their swords that they may remain bright as a_____ to their God at the last day, that they would not stain them again with the blood of their brethren.",
    "answer": "Testimony",
    "options": ["Witness", "Testimony", "Pledge"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3639,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:16",
    "question": "King Lamoni2 told the people to hide their swords and_____ them deep in the earth, that they may be kept bright; and if their brethren did destroy them, they would go to their God and be saved.",
    "answer": "Bury"
  },
  {
    "id": 3640,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:17",
    "question": "The people took their swords and all the weapons of war which were used for the shedding of man’s_____, and did bury them up deep in the earth.",
    "answer": "Blood"
  },
  {
    "id": 3641,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma24:18",
    "question": "By burying their weapons of war the people were vouching and covenanting with God that they would give up their own lives.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3642,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma24:18",
    "question": "The people that were converted unto the Lord said that they would spend their days in idleness and would not labor abundantly with their hands.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3643,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:20",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites came up to the land of Nephi with the purpose of destroying the king, and to place another in his stead, and to destroy the people of Anti-Nephi-_____ out of the land.",
    "answer": "Lehi"
  },
  {
    "id": 3644,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma24:21",
    "question": "The Anti-Nephi-Lehi's prostrated themselves before the Lamanites upon the earth; and they were in this attitude and position when the Lamanites fell upon them and began to slay them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3645,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:24",
    "question": "The_____ slew a thousand and five of the Anti-Nephi-Lehi's before they quit slaying them because their hearts were swollen; and repented to the Lord for the things which they had done.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3646,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma24:27",
    "question": "Of all the Anti-Nephi-Lehi's that were slain, there was not a wicked man among them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3647,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:27",
    "question": "More than a thousand of the Anti-Nephi-Lehi's were brought to the knowledge of the truth; and thus we see that the____ works in many ways to the salvation of his people.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 3648,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:28",
    "question": "The greatest number of those of the Lamanites who slew so many of their brethren were_____ and Amulonites, and they were of the order of the Nehors.",
    "answer": "Amalekites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3649,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:29",
    "question": "Many of the Anti-Nephi-Lehi's were actual descendants of_____ and Lemuel.",
    "answer": "Laman"
  },
  {
    "id": 3650,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma24:30",
    "question": "Mormon reminds us that once a people have been enlightened by the Spirit of God, and have had a great knowledge of things pertaining to righteousness, and fall away and transgress, they become more hardened.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3651,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:30",
    "question": "Mormon writes that people who have been enlightened by the Spirit of_____ and have a great knowledge of things pertaining to righteousness, and have fallen away and transgress; their state becomes worse than though they have never known the things of God.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 3652,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma25:1",
    "question": "The Lamanites were angry with themselves because they had slain their brethren the Anti-Nephi-Lehi's and swore vengeance upon the_____.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3653,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma25:2",
    "question": "The Lamanites took their armies and went over to the land of Zarahemla, and fell upon the people who were in the land of_____, and destroyed them.",
    "answer": "Ammonihah"
  },
  {
    "id": 3654,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma25:4",
    "question": "And among the Lamanites who were slain were almost all the seed of_____ and his brethren who was the leader of the priests of King Noah.",
    "answer": "Amulon"
  },
  {
    "id": 3655,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma25:7",
    "question": "The rest of the priest of King Noah fled into the east wilderness and having usurped the power and authority of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3656,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma25:5",
    "question": "The priest of King Noah caused that many of the Lamanites should perish by_____ because of their belief in the Lord.",
    "answer": "Fire",
    "options": ["Hanging", "Firing Squad", "Fire"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3657,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma25:7",
    "question": "The rulers who were the remnant of the children of Amulon caused that they should be put to death; all those that believed in the things of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3658,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma25:8",
    "question": "The_____ began to hunt the seed of Amulon and his brethren and began to slay them; and they fled into the east wilderness.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3659,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma25:9",
    "question": "The words of_____ were brought to pass, which he said concerning the seed of the priests who caused that he should suffer death by fire.",
    "answer": "Abinadi"
  },
  {
    "id": 3660,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma25:10",
    "question": "Abinadi had said to the priests of King Noah:  What you shall do unto me shall be a_____ of things to come.",
    "answer": "Type"
  },
  {
    "id": 3661,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma25:11",
    "question": "Abinadi was the first that suffered death by fire because of his belief in God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3662,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma25:11",
    "question": "Abinadi is considered to be the first martyr in the Book of Mormon by many Book of Mormon scholars.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3663,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma25:12",
    "question": "The words of_____ were verified what he told the priests of King Noah because their seed had been driven and hunted and smitten by the Lamanites. ",
    "answer": "Abinadi"
  },
  {
    "id": 3664,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma25:13",
    "question": "And it came to pass that many of the Lamanites came over to dwell in the land of Ishmael and Nephi, and did join themselves to the people of God, who were the people of Anti-Nephi-Lehi.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3665,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma25:14",
    "question": "Some of the Lamanites did bury their weapons of war and began to be a righteous people, and they did walk in the ways of the_____, and did observe to keep his commandments and his statutes.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 3666,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma25:15",
    "question": "The Lamanites did keep the Law of_____; because it had not yet been fulfilled.",
    "answer": "Mosess"
  },
  {
    "id": 3667,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma25:15",
    "question": "Some of the Lamanites did not look forward to the coming of Christ, considering that the Lawords of Mosmones was a type of his coming.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3668,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma25:16",
    "question": "The Lamanites did not suppose that_____ came by the Lawords of Mosmones; but the lawords of Mosmones did serve to strengthen their faith in Christ; and thus they did retain a hope through faith.",
    "answer": "Salvation",
    "options": ["Riches", "Salvation", "Favoritism"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3669,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma25:17",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Ammon, Aaron, Omner, and Himni, and their brethren did not rejoice exceedingly, for the success they had had among the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3670,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:2",
    "question": "Ammon told his brethren that they had had great success because of the_____ the Lord had bestowed upon them.",
    "answer": "Blessings"
  },
  {
    "id": 3671,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma26:3",
    "question": "Ammon told his brethren that the Lamanites were in darkness, yea, even in the darkest_____, but now many of them were brought to behold the marvelous light of God!",
    "answer": "Abyss",
    "options": ["Abyss", "Canyon", "Hole"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3672,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:3",
    "question": "Ammon also told his brethren that they had become_____ in the hands of God to bring about this great work among the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Instruments"
  },
  {
    "id": 3673,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:5",
    "question": "Ammon said the field was ripe and they thrust what farm tool into the field and did reap with their might, and day long in laboring?",
    "answer": "Sickle"
  },
  {
    "id": 3674,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma26:6",
    "question": "Ammon told his brethren that the storm cannot penetrate them; neither shall they be driven with fierce winds whithersoever the enemy desires to carry them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3675,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma26:10",
    "question": "Which one of Ammon’s brothers rebuked him and accused him of boasting?",
    "answer": "Aaron",
    "options": ["Himni", "Aaron", "Omner"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3676,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:11",
    "question": "Ammon told his brother Aaron that he did not boast in his own strength, neither in his own wisdom; but that his heart was full of joy and would rejoice in his_____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 3677,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma26:12",
    "question": "Ammon told his brother that he knew he was nothing; therefore he would not boast of himself, but that he would boast of his God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3678,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:12",
    "question": "Ammon told Aaron that in the strength of whom could he do all things?",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 3679,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma26:14",
    "question": "Ammon said they had reason to praise God forever, because the Lord was the Most High God, and loosed our brethren from the chains of_____.",
    "answer": "Hell",
    "options": ["Death", "Misery", "Hell"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3680,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:15",
    "question": "Ammon said to Aaron the Lord had encircled them with the matchless bounty of his_____; and they had been instruments in his hands of doing his great and marvelous work.",
    "answer": "Love"
  },
  {
    "id": 3681,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma26:16",
    "question": "Ammon wanted his brethren to glory in the Lord; and said that who could glory in the Lord too much.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3682,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma26:16",
    "question": "Ammon said he could not say the_____ part of which he felt about God.",
    "answer": "Smallest",
    "options": ["Biggest", "Smallest", "Largest"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3683,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:20",
    "question": "Ammon said that the Lord did not exercise his justice upon him and his brethren when they went about trying to destroy his_____.",
    "answer": "Church"
  },
  {
    "id": 3684,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma26:20",
    "question": "Ammon said that the Lord did not exercise his justice upon him and his brethren when they went about trying to destroy his church.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3685,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma26:20",
    "question": "Ammon said the Lord in his great mercy had brought them over the everlasting gulf of death and misery, even to the salvation of their souls.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3686,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma26:21",
    "question": "Ammon said that there is no_____ man that can know the things of God save it be those that have a feeling of expressing humbleness or regretful pain or sorrow for his sins.",
    "answer": "Natural",
    "options": ["Natural", "Strong", "Rich"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3687,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:22",
    "question": "Ammon told his brethren that those who repent and exercise faith and bring forth good works and prays continually without ceasing—unto such is given to know the_____of God.",
    "answer": "Mysteries"
  },
  {
    "id": 3688,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma26:22",
    "question": "Ammon said that those who is given the mysteries of God; also can be given to reveal things which never have been revealed.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3689,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma26:26",
    "question": "Ammon reminded his beloved brethren, that they came into the wilderness not with the intent to destroy their brethren, but with the intent that perhaps they might save some of their souls.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3690,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma26:27",
    "question": "Ammon said when their hearts were depressed, and were about to turn back, the Lord had comforted them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3691,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma26:27",
    "question": "The Lord told Ammon and his brethren to go among the Lamanites, and bear with patience your afflictions; and I will give you_____.",
    "answer": "Success",
    "options": ["Money", "Success", "Gold"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3692,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:28",
    "question": "Ammon said that they had gone from house to house, relying upon the mercies of the world—not upon the mercies of the world alone but upon the____ of God.",
    "answer": "Mercies"
  },
  {
    "id": 3693,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma26:29",
    "question": "Ammon told his brethren that they had been delivered through the power and_____ of God.",
    "answer": "Wisdom",
    "options": ["Goodness", "Wisdom", "Skill"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3694,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:30",
    "question": "Ammon said that they had suffered all manner of afflictions, that perhaps they might be the means of saving some few_____.",
    "answer": "Souls"
  },
  {
    "id": 3695,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma26:31",
    "question": "Ammon said they could witness of the sincerity of the brethren they had saved because of their love towards their brethren and towards them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3696,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:33",
    "question": "Ammon and his brethren knew that the Lamanites that had been slain had gone to their God because of their love and of their hatred towards_____.",
    "answer": "Sin"
  },
  {
    "id": 3697,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma26:35",
    "question": "Ammon said that there have never been men born that had so great reason to rejoice as him and his_____ since the world began.",
    "answer": "Brethren",
    "options": ["Wives", "Sons", "Brethren"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3698,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:35",
    "question": "Ammon said that God has all power, all wisdom, and all understanding; he comprehends all things, and he is a merciful Being, even unto salvation, to those who will_____ and believe in his name.",
    "answer": "Repent"
  },
  {
    "id": 3699,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:36",
    "question": "Ammon boasted in the name of his God, who had been mindful of the Lamanites, who are a branch of the tree of_____, and had been lost from its body in a strange land.",
    "answer": "Israel"
  },
  {
    "id": 3700,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:37",
    "question": "Ammon reminded his brethren that God is mindful of every people, whatsoever land they may be; and numbers his people, and his_____ of mercy are over all the earth.",
    "answer": "Bowels"
  },
  {
    "id": 3701,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma27:2",
    "question": "The_____ were angry because of their losses in war and they saw that they could not seek revenge from the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Amalekites",
    "options": ["Amalekites", "Amulonites", "Zoramites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3702,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma27:2",
    "question": "The Amalekites began to stir up the people in anger against their brethren, the people of Anti-Nephi-Lehi.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3703,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma27:3",
    "question": "The Anti-Nephi-Lehi's again refused to take up their arms, and they suffered themselves to be slain according to the desires of their enemies.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3704,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma27:4",
    "question": "Ammon and his_____ saw this great work of destruction and they were moved with compassion.",
    "answer": "Brethren"
  },
  {
    "id": 3705,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma27:5",
    "question": "Ammon wanted to gather the Anti-Nephi-Lehi's and go down to the land of Zarahemla of their brethren; the_____, and flee out of the hands of their enemies, that they may not be destroyed.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3706,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma27:7",
    "question": "Who did Ammon inquired of to see if he would say to him to go down to Zarahemla among the Nephites? ",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 3707,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma27:9",
    "question": "Who established the laws in Zarahemla that said there should be no slaves among the land?",
    "answer": "King Mosiah2",
    "options": ["King Noah", "King Mosiah2", "King Benjamin"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3708,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma27:12",
    "question": "When Ammon inquired of the Lord he told him not to go to the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3709,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma27:12",
    "question": "Who did the Lord say to Ammon had a great hold on the hearts of the Amalekites, who do stir up the Lamanites to anger against their brethren? ",
    "answer": "Satan"
  },
  {
    "id": 3710,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma27:13",
    "question": "When Ammon finished inquiring of the Lord he did not go and tell the kings all the words which the Lord had said unto him.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3711,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma27:16",
    "question": "And it came to pass that as Ammon was going forth into the land of Zarahemla, he and his brethren met_____, and it was a joyful meeting.",
    "answer": "Younger"
  },
  {
    "id": 3712,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma27:17",
    "question": "Ammon was so joyous when he met Alma the Younger that he fell to the ground.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3713,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma27:18",
    "question": "Mormon writes that Ammon’s joy can none receive save it be the truly penitent and humble seeker of happiness.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3714,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma27:19",
    "question": "Ammon was accompanied by his brethren which were Aaron, Omner, and _____.",
    "answer": "Himni"
  },
  {
    "id": 3715,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma27:20",
    "question": "Alma the Younger took Ammon and his brethren to his own_____; and they went and told the chief judge all the things that had happened unto them in the land of Nephi.",
    "answer": "House",
    "options": ["Inn", "House", "Farm House"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3716,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma27:21",
    "question": "Alma the Younger sent a proclamation throughout all the land, desiring the_____ of the people concerning the admitting their brethren, who were the people of Anti-Nephi-Lehis.",
    "answer": "Voice",
    "options": ["Vote", "Hearts", "Voice"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3717,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma27:22",
    "question": "And it came to pass the voice of the people came saying:”We will give up the land of_____ unto our brethren for an inheritance”.",
    "answer": "Jershon"
  },
  {
    "id": 3718,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma27:24",
    "question": "The Nephites said that they would set of their armies between the land of Jershon and the land of Nephi to protect the Anti-Nephi-Lehi's.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3719,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma27:25,26",
    "question": "Ammon and Alma the Younger related to the Anti-Nephi-Lehi's the conditions of the Nephites and they were not joyous and did not agree to the terms.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3720,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma27:26 & Alma57:6",
    "question": "What is the name that the Nephites gave to the people of Ammon who were known for their zeal towards God?",
    "answer": "Ammonites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3721,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma27:27",
    "question": "The Anti-Nephi-Lehi's became among the people of Nephi, and also numbered among the people who were of the church of God",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3722,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma27:27",
    "question": "The Anti-Nephi-Lehi's were distinguished for their_____ towards God.",
    "answer": "Zeal",
    "options": ["Love", "Zeal", "Red Mark On Their Foreheads"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3723,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma27:27",
    "question": "The Anti-Nephi-Lehi's were perfectly honest and upright in all things; and they were firm in the faith of_____, even unto the end.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 3724,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma27:28",
    "question": "The Anti-Nephi-Lehi's looked upon shedding the_____of their brethren with the greatest abhorrence.",
    "answer": "Blood"
  },
  {
    "id": 3725,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma27:28",
    "question": "The Anti-Nephi-Lehi's never did look upon death with any degree of terror, for their hope and views of Christ and the resurrection; therefore, death was swallowed up to them by the victory of Christ over it.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3726,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma27:30",
    "question": "Because of their beliefs the Anti-Nephi-Lehi's were a zealous and beloved people, and a highly_____ people of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Favored",
    "options": ["Looked Upon", "Motivated", "Favored"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3727,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma28:1",
    "question": "It came to pass that the Ammonites were established in the land of Jershon and also established a_____.",
    "answer": "Church",
    "options": ["Fraternity", "Club", "Church"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3728,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "2,7",
    "question": "During the fifteenth year of the reign of the judges over the people of Nephi; the most tremendous_____ occurred in Nephites history.",
    "answer": "War",
    "options": ["War", "Confrontation", "Battle"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3729,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma28:2-3",
    "question": "During this time in Nephites history the most tremendous battle between the Nephites and Lamanites occurred in which tens of thousands of Lamanites were slaughtered and also of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3730,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma28:4",
    "question": "Because of the tremendous battle between the Lamanites and Nephites; there was a great mourning and lamentation heard throughout all the land, among all the people of_____.",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 3731,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma28:10",
    "question": "From the first year to the fifteenth years of the reign of the_____ it had brought to pass the destruction of many thousands of lives, and also has brought to pass an awful scene of bloodshed.",
    "answer": "Judges"
  },
  {
    "id": 3732,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma28:11",
    "question": "The bodies of many thousands were moldering in heaps upon the face of the_____.",
    "answer": "Earth"
  },
  {
    "id": 3733,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma28:12",
    "question": "The Nephites had hope and rejoiced and even know according to the promises of the Lord, that those that died are raised to dwell at the_____ hand of God, in a state of never-ending happiness.",
    "answer": "Right"
  },
  {
    "id": 3734,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma28:13",
    "question": "Mormon writes to us that the inequality of man comes about because of sin and transgression, and the power of the_____.",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },
  {
    "id": 3735,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma28:13",
    "question": "The inequality of man comes about because of sin and transgression and the power of the devil; which comes by the cunning plans which he devises to ensnare the hearts of men.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3736,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "13,14",
    "question": "Mormon says that there is a great call of diligence of men to labor in the_____ of the Lord because of the power of the devil.",
    "answer": "Workshop",
    "options": ["Workshop", "Vineyard", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3737,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma28:14",
    "question": "Mormon writes that there is a great reason of sorrow, and also rejoicing-sorrow because of death and destruction among men, and joy because of the light of_____ unto life.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 3738,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma29:1",
    "question": "Alma2 wished that he was an_____, and could go forth and speak with the trump of God, with a voice to shake the earth, and cry repentance unto every people!",
    "answer": "Angel"
  },
  {
    "id": 3739,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma29:2",
    "question": "Alma2 said that he would declare unto every soul, as with the voice of_____, repentance and the plan of redemption; that they should repent and come unto God.",
    "answer": "Thunder",
    "options": ["Thunder", "Clarity", "Electricity"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3740,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma29:2",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted to declare to the people with the voice of thunder to come unto repentance that there might not be more sorrow upon all the face of the earth.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3741,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma29:3",
    "question": "Alma2 said that he should not be content with the things which the Lord had allotted unto him.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3742,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma29:4",
    "question": "Alma2 testified that he knew that the Lord grants unto men according to their_____, whether it should be unto death or unto life.",
    "answer": "Desire",
    "options": ["Wishes", "Desire", "Likes"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3743,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma29:4",
    "question": "Alma2 also knew that the Lord allots unto men according to their_____, whether they should be unto salvation or unto destruction.",
    "answer": "Wills"
  },
  {
    "id": 3744,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma29:5",
    "question": "Alma2 testified that he knew the choice of good and_____ has come before all men, and he that knows not good from evil is blameless.",
    "answer": "Evil"
  },
  {
    "id": 3745,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma29:5",
    "question": "Alma2 testified that he knew the choice of good and evil has come before all men, and he that knows not good from evil is blameless.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3746,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma29:5",
    "question": "Alma2 knew to him it is given according to his desires, whether he desires good or evil, life or death, joy or remorse of conscience.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3747,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma29:6,7",
    "question": "Because of all the things he knew; Alma2 wondered why he desired to be an angel, and desired more than to perform the work to which he had been called.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3748,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma29:8",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Lord does grant unto all nations, of their own nation and_____, to teach his word, and in his wisdom he sees to it that they should have all they need.",
    "answer": "Tongue",
    "options": ["Tongue", "Tribe", "Company"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3749,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma29:8",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Lord does counsel in wisdom, according to that which is_____ and true.",
    "answer": "Just"
  },
  {
    "id": 3750,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma29:9",
    "question": "Alma2 knew what the Lord had commanded of him and gloried in it.  He did not_____ of himself, but did glory in that which the Lord had commanded of him. ",
    "answer": "Gloried"
  },
  {
    "id": 3751,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma29:9",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted to be an_____ in the hands of God and to bring some soul to repentance; and this was his joy.",
    "answer": "Instrument"
  },
  {
    "id": 3752,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma29:10",
    "question": "Alma2 said that when he saw many of his brethren truly penitent; and coming to the Lord their God, then his soul was filled with_____.",
    "answer": "Joy",
    "options": ["Gladness", "Mercy", "Joy"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3753,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma29:10",
    "question": "Alma2 said when he saw many of his brethren coming to the Lord their God; then he does remember what the Lord has done for him, even that he has heard his_____.",
    "answer": "Prayers"
  },
  {
    "id": 3754,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma29:10",
    "question": "Alma2 said he could not recall when the Lord his God stretched his merciful arm which he extended towards him.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3755,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma29:11",
    "question": "Alma2 remembered the captivity of his_____; and he surely did know that the Lord did deliver them out of bondage, and by this he established his church.",
    "answer": "Fathers"
  },
  {
    "id": 3756,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma29:11",
    "question": "Alma2 also knew that the Lord God, the God of_____, the God of Isaac, and the God of Jacob, did deliver them out of bondage.",
    "answer": "Abraham"
  },
  {
    "id": 3757,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma29:12",
    "question": "Alma2 said that he had always remembered the captivity of his fathers; and that the same God who delivered them out of the hands of the_____ did deliver them out of bondage.",
    "answer": "Egyptians"
  },
  {
    "id": 3758,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma2913",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the same God did establish his church among them and that the same God had called him by a_____ calling.",
    "answer": "Holy",
    "options": ["Precious", "Holy", "Sacred"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3759,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma29:13",
    "question": "Alma2 said that God had called him to a holy calling to preach the word unto this people, and had given him much success, in which his joy was full.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3760,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma29:14",
    "question": "Alma2 said his joy had been more full because of the success of his brethren, who have been up to the land of Nephi preaching the word of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3761,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma29:15",
    "question": "Alma2 said that his brethren have labored exceedingly preaching the word of God, and have brought much_____; and how great shall be their reward!",
    "answer": "Fruit",
    "options": ["Success", "Fruit", "Vegetables"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3762,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma29:17",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted God to grant unto his brethren, that they may sit down in the_____ of God; and also al those who are the fruit of their labors that they may go no more out, but that they may praise him forever.",
    "answer": "Kingdom",
    "options": ["Kingdom", "Throne", "Seat"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3763,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma29:17",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted God that he would grant unto him that it may be done according to his words, even as he had spoken it. Amen",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3764,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:2",
    "question": "And it came to pass that after the tremendous battle; the dead of the Lamanites and Nephites were not numbered because of the greatness of their numbers.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3765,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:2",
    "question": "But it came to pass that after they had buried their dead, and also after the days of fasting, and mourning, and_____, there began to be continual peace throughout all the land.",
    "answer": "Prayer"
  },
  {
    "id": 3766,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:3",
    "question": "The Nephites did observe to keep the commandments of the Lord; and they were not strict in observing the ordinances of God; according to the Lawords of Mosmones.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3767,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:3",
    "question": "The Nephites were taught to keep the Law of_____ until it should be fulfilled.",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },
  {
    "id": 3768,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:6",
    "question": "In the latter end of the seventeenth year of the reign of the judges; there came a man into the land of_____, and he was an Anti-Christ.",
    "answer": "Zarahemla"
  },
  {
    "id": 3769,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:6",
    "question": "In what Book of Mormon book; do we find the words “Anti-Christ” first mentioned? ",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 3770,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:6",
    "question": "The man who was an Anti-Christ began to preach unto the people against the prophecies which had been spoken by the prophets, concerning the coming of_____.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 3771,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:7",
    "question": "There was no law among the Nephites against a man’s belief; for it was strictly contrary to the commands of God that there should be a law which should bring men on to unequal grounds.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3772,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:8",
    "question": "For thus says the scriptures: “Choose ye this day, whom ye will_____”.",
    "answer": "Serve"
  },
  {
    "id": 3773,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:9",
    "question": "If a man desired to serve God, it was his_____; or rather, if he believed in God it was his privilege to serve him; but if he did not believe in God there was no law to punish him.",
    "answer": "Privilege",
    "options": ["Right", "Liberty", "Privilege"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3774,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:10",
    "question": "According to Nephite law if a man murdered another man he was punished and put to_____.",
    "answer": "Death"
  },
  {
    "id": 3775,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:10",
    "question": "People were not punished for robbing, stealing, and committing adultery and for all this wickedness and they were not punished but a fine was imposed on them.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3776,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:11",
    "question": "The Nephites had a law that a man would be punished for his beliefs.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3777,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:11",
    "question": "For the Nephites there was a law that men should be judged according to their_____.  And there was no law against a man’s belief, but a man was punished only for the crimes which he had done.",
    "answer": "Crimes"
  },
  {
    "id": 3778,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:12",
    "question": "What was the name of the Anti-Christ that came into the land of Zarahemla preaching that there should be no Christ?_____",
    "answer": "Korihor"
  },
  {
    "id": 3779,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:13",
    "question": "Korihor told the people of_____ that they were bound down under a foolish and vain hope and yoked themselves with such foolish things, and that no man could know of anything which is to come.",
    "answer": "Zarahemla"
  },
  {
    "id": 3780,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:13",
    "question": "Korihor told the Nephites that only a just and holy prophet of the Lord could know of anything which is to come.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3781,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:14",
    "question": "Korihor said the things the people called prophecies, which they said are handed down by the holy prophets, were foolish_____ of their fathers.",
    "answer": "Traditions"
  },
  {
    "id": 3782,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:15",
    "question": "Korihor told the Nephites that they could not know of things which they could not see; therefore they cannot know that there shall be a_____.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 3783,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:16",
    "question": "Korihor told the people that when they looked forward and said they saw a remission of their sins; it was the effect of a frenzied_____.",
    "answer": "Mind",
    "options": ["Thought", "Mind", "Head"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3784,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:16",
    "question": "Korihor told the Nephites that the derangement of their minds came because of the traditions of their fathers, which led them away into a belief of things which were not so.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3785,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:17",
    "question": "Korihor said many more false things unto the people, telling them that there could be no_____ made for the sins of men, but every man fared in this life according to the management of the creature.",
    "answer": "Atonement"
  },
  {
    "id": 3786,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:17",
    "question": "Korihor told the Nephites that every man prospered according to his_____, and that every man conquered according to his strength; and whatsoever a man did was no crime.",
    "answer": "Genius",
    "options": ["Know How", "Brain", "Genius"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3787,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:18",
    "question": "Because of his preaching Korihor led the hearts of many Nephites away, causing them to lift up their heads in their wickedness.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3788,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:18",
    "question": "Korihor led many women, and also men, to commit_____telling them that when a man was dead, that was the end thereof.",
    "answer": "Whoredoms",
    "options": ["Robberies", "Whoredoms", "Murders"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3789,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:19 & 27:26",
    "question": "Korihor also went to the land of Jershon to preach false things among the_____ who were the people of Ammon, who were once the people of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Ammonites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3790,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:20",
    "question": "The people of Ammon were more wise than many of the Nephites; and they took_____ and bound him and carried him before Ammon, who was a high priest over the people.",
    "answer": "Korihor"
  },
  {
    "id": 3791,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:19,21",
    "question": "Who caused that Korihor should be carried out of the land of Jershon?",
    "answer": "Ammon"
  },
  {
    "id": 3792,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:21",
    "question": "Korihor than went to the land of Gideon, and began to preach to them also; and here he did have much success.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3793,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:21,23",
    "question": "The people in the land of Gideon took Korihor and bound and carried him before the high priest whose name was_____.",
    "answer": "Giddonah"
  },
  {
    "id": 3794,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:21 & 23:16",
    "question": "And Korihor was also taken before the chief judge over the land whose was name_____.",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 3795,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:22",
    "question": "Giddonah asked_____ why he went about perverting the ways of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Korihor"
  },
  {
    "id": 3796,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:22",
    "question": "Giddonah the high priest did not ask Korihor why he went about the land of Gideon perverting the ways of the Lord.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3797,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:22",
    "question": "Giddonah asked Korihor why he taught the people that there should be no_____, and interrupting their rejoicings; and why he spoke against all the prophecies of the holy prophets.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 3798,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:23",
    "question": "Korihor told Giddonah and Alma2 that he taught the things he did because he did not teach the foolish_____of their fathers.",
    "answer": "Traditions"
  },
  {
    "id": 3799,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:23",
    "question": "Korihor told Giddonah and Alma2 that he did not teach the people to bind themselves down under the foolish ordinances and performances which are laid down by ancient priests.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3800,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:23",
    "question": "Korihor also told Giddonah and Alma2 that the ancient_____ taught what they did to the people to usurp power and authority over them.",
    "answer": "Priests",
    "options": ["Prophets", "Priests", "Elders"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3801,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:23",
    "question": "Korihor told Giddonah and Alma2 that the ancient_____ taught things to keep the people in ignorance, that they may not lift there heads, but be brought down according to their words.",
    "answer": "Priests",
    "options": ["Prophets", "Priests", "Elders"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3802,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:24",
    "question": "Korihor said to Giddonah and Alma2 that the people were not a_____ people, but a people that were in bondage.",
    "answer": "Free"
  },
  {
    "id": 3803,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:24",
    "question": "Giddonah and Alma2 taught the people that the ancient prophecies were true but Korihor said that they were not_____.",
    "answer": "True"
  },
  {
    "id": 3804,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:25",
    "question": "Korihor accused Giddonah and Alma2 of saying the Nephites were a guilty and a fallen people because of the transgressions of their parents. But he said that a child is not guilty because of his parents.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3805,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:27",
    "question": "Korihor said that Giddonah and Alma2 taught according to their own desires; and to keep the people down, even as if they were in bondage, that they may_____ themselves with the labors of their hands.",
    "answer": "Glut",
    "options": ["Glut", "Fill", "Stuff"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3806,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:27",
    "question": "Korihor told Giddonah and Alma2 that the people did not dare to look up with boldness, and that they did not_____ to enjoy their rights and privileges.",
    "answer": "Dare"
  },
  {
    "id": 3807,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:28",
    "question": "Korihor said that the people did not dare to make use of that which is their own because they might offend their_____.",
    "answer": "Priests",
    "options": ["Gods", "Elders", "Priests"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3808,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:28",
    "question": "Korihor said that if the people did not do what Giddonah and Alma2 said according to their words, they might offend some unknown being, who they said is_____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 3809,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:28",
    "question": "Korihor said that God is a being who never has been_____ or known, who never was or will never ever be.",
    "answer": "Seen"
  },
  {
    "id": 3810,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:29",
    "question": "Giddonah and Alma2 saw the hardness of the heart of_____, and that he would revile even against God, they would not make any reply to his words.",
    "answer": "Korihor"
  },
  {
    "id": 3811,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:29",
    "question": "Giddonah and the high_____ caused that Korihor should be bound; and they delivered him up to the hands of the officers, and sent him to the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": "Priest"
  },
  {
    "id": 3812,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:29",
    "question": "Giddonah and the high priest caused that Korihor be brought before_____, and the chief judge who was governor over all the land.",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 3813,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:30",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Korihor was brought before Alma2 the chief judge, and he did go on in the same manner as he had done in the land of_____.",
    "answer": "Gideon",
    "options": ["Nephi", "Jershon", "Gideon"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3814,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:30",
    "question": "Because of the words that_____ had said, he was a blasphemous person. ",
    "answer": "Korihor"
  },
  {
    "id": 3815,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:31",
    "question": "Korihor did rise up in great swelling words before Alma2, and did revile against the priests and teachers, accusing them of leading away the people after the silly_____ of their fathers.",
    "answer": "Traditions"
  },
  {
    "id": 3816,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:32",
    "question": "Alma2 told Korihor that he knew that they did not glut themselves upon the labors of the people.  And that he had labored from the commencement of the reign of judges, with his own_____.",
    "answer": "Hands"
  },
  {
    "id": 3817,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma11:5",
    "question": "Alma2 told Korihor that he had never received so much as even one_____; which was a monetary unit used by the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Seon",
    "options": ["Seon", "Senine", "Limnah"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3818,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:33",
    "question": "Alma2 told Korihor that he had never received so much as even one senine but that his brethren were the only ones to receive compensation.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3819,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:34",
    "question": "Alma2 said to Korihor that the only thing he and his brethren received for their labors in the church was to declare the truth, and have rejoicings in the joy of their people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3820,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:35",
    "question": "Alma2 told Korihor that it was not possible that he and his brethren had deceived the people because their teachings had caused great joy in their_____.",
    "answer": "Hearts",
    "options": ["Hearts", "Heads", "Bodies"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3821,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:38",
    "question": "At the time that Alma2 first asked Korihor if he believed there was a God he said yes.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3822,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:39",
    "question": "Alma2 testified to Korihor that he knew there was a God and that_____ shall come.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 3823,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:40",
    "question": "Alma2 told Korihor that the only evidence he had that there is no God and that Christ will not come was only his_____.",
    "answer": "Word",
    "options": ["Bible", "Beliefs", "Word"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3824,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:42",
    "question": "Alma2 said that Korihor knew there was a God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3825,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:42",
    "question": "Alma2 said that Korihor was possessed with a_____ spirit, and that he had put of the Spirit of God and that it had no place in him.",
    "answer": "Lying",
    "options": ["Good", "Bad", "Lying"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3826,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:42",
    "question": "Who did Alma2 say had power over Korihor?_____",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },
  {
    "id": 3827,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:42",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the devil had power over Korihor and carried him about; working devices that he may destroy the_____ of God.",
    "answer": "Children"
  },
  {
    "id": 3828,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:43",
    "question": "Korihor wanted Alma2 to show him a_____, that he may be convinced that there was a God; and show unto him that he has power, and then he would be convinced of the truth in Alma2’s words.",
    "answer": "Sign"
  },
  {
    "id": 3829,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:44",
    "question": "Alma2 told Korihor that he already has signs that there was a God and not to_____ God.",
    "answer": "Tempt",
    "options": ["Question", "Tempt", "Deny"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3830,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:44",
    "question": "Alma2 said that these things proved there was a God:  His personal testimony and also the testimonies of his brethren",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3831,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:44",
    "question": "The testimony of all the holy prophets.  The scriptures and even the earth, and all things that are upon the face of it; prove that there is a God",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3832,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:44",
    "question": "Alma2 told Korihor that also these things denoted that there is a God:  The motion of the earth and also all the planets which move in their regular form do witness that there is a Supreme_____.",
    "answer": "Creator"
  },
  {
    "id": 3833,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:44",
    "question": "Alma2 told Korihor that there is a Supreme Creator.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3834,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:44",
    "question": "Alma2 testified to Korihor about the motion of planets.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3835,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:45",
    "question": "Even after all the things Alma2 showed to Korihor that proved there was a God, he said he would still deny there was a God unless showed him a_____.",
    "answer": "Sign"
  },
  {
    "id": 3836,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:46",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma2 was grieved because of the_____ of the heart of Korihor, and that he still resisted the spirit of the truth, that his soul may be destroyed.",
    "answer": "Hardness",
    "options": ["Stupidity", "Hatred", "Hardness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3837,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:47",
    "question": "Alma2 said that it was better that the soul of Korihor should be lost than he may and should have the means of bringing many_____ down to destruction.",
    "answer": "Souls"
  },
  {
    "id": 3838,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:47",
    "question": "Alma2 said that Korihor used lying words and flattering words to make the people believe that there was no God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3839,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:47",
    "question": "Alma2 told Korihor that if he denied again that there was no God, that God would smite him and that he would become_____.",
    "answer": "Dumb",
    "options": ["Crazy", "Sick", "Dumb"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3840,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:47",
    "question": "Alma2 told Korihor that he would become dumb and would never open his mouth again and deceive the Nephites anymore.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3841,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "45,48",
    "question": "How many times did Korihor deny that there was a God?",
    "answer": "1",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3842,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:48",
    "question": "Korihor said that he did not deny the existence of a_____, but that he did not believe that there was a God.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 3843,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:48",
    "question": "Korihor told Almsa2 that he did not know that there is a God; and except he showed him a sign, he would not believe.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3844,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:49",
    "question": "Alma2 told Korihor that he would give him a sign, that he would be struck dumb, according to his words; and he said that in the name of God he would be struck dumb and no more have utterance.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3845,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:50",
    "question": "When Alma2 said the words which he said, Korihor was struck_____, that he could not have utterance, according to the words of Alma2.",
    "answer": "Dumb"
  },
  {
    "id": 3846,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:51",
    "question": "What person put forth his hand and wrote unto Korihor these words: Art thou convinced of the power of God?",
    "answer": "The Chief Judge",
    "options": ["Alma2", "Ammon", "The Chief Judge"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3847,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:52",
    "question": "Korihor did not write back to the chief judge and did not confess that he knew that he was dumb and could not speak.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3848,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:52",
    "question": "Korihor wrote that he knew that it was the power of_____ that brought upon him the inability to speak.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 3849,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:52",
    "question": "Korihor wrote that he knew that there was a God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3850,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:53",
    "question": "Who did Korihor say had deceived him?_____ ",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },
  {
    "id": 3851,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:53",
    "question": "Korihor wrote that the devil had appeared unto him in the form of an_____.",
    "answer": "Angel",
    "options": ["Dove", "Angel", "Serpent"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3852,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:53",
    "question": "The devil told Korihor to go and reclaim the people, because they had gone astray after an unknown_____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 3853,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:53",
    "question": "The devil did not tell Korihor that there was no God.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3854,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:53",
    "question": "Who taught Korihor all the words which he should say unto the people?",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },
  {
    "id": 3855,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:53",
    "question": "Korihor taught the words that he did and had much success with them because they were_____ unto the carnal mind.",
    "answer": "Pleasing",
    "options": ["Intelligent", "Challenging", "Pleasing"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3856,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:53",
    "question": "Korihor said that because the words were pleasing unto the carnal mind he started to believe that they were actually true.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3857,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:53",
    "question": "Korihor confessed that he did not know why such a curse was put on him.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3858,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:54",
    "question": "Who did Korihor wished that would pray to God on his behalf to take away the curse from him?",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 3859,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:55",
    "question": "Alma2 said that it was up to_____ to take away the curse from Korihor.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 3860,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:56",
    "question": "After Alma2 prayed unto the Lord; the curse was taken away from Korihor.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3861,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:56",
    "question": "Korihor was cast out and went about from house to house_____ for his food.",
    "answer": "Begging"
  },
  {
    "id": 3862,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:57",
    "question": "The knowledge of what had happened to Korihor was published throughout all the land in a_____.",
    "answer": "Proclamation",
    "options": ["Text Message", "Proclamation", "Newspaper"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3863,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:57",
    "question": "What person sent the proclamation throughout all the land of what had happened to Korihor?",
    "answer": "Chief Judge",
    "options": ["Alma2", "Chief Judge", "King Lamoni2"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3864,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:57",
    "question": "The chief judge declared unto those that had believed in the words of_____ that they must speedily repent, or the same judgments would come upon them.",
    "answer": "Korihor"
  },
  {
    "id": 3865,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:58",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people were all convinced of the_____ of Korihor.",
    "answer": "Wickedness",
    "options": ["Wickedness", "Deceiving", "Evilness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3866,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:59",
    "question": "What was the name of the people that Korihor went about begging for food and was run upon and trodden down?",
    "answer": "Zoramites",
    "options": ["Nephites", "Lamanites", "Zoramites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3867,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:59",
    "question": "Korihor was able to live a long and normal life because he repented of his sins.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3868,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:60",
    "question": "Mormon wrote that we can see for ourselves that the devil will not support his_____ at the last day, but does speedily drag them down to hell.",
    "answer": "Children"
  },
  {
    "id": 3869,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:1",
    "question": "Who was leading the Zoramites to bow down to dumb idols?_____ ",
    "answer": "Zoram"
  },
  {
    "id": 3870,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:2",
    "question": "Because of the iniquity of the Zoramites it caused great sorrow to Alma2.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3871,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:2",
    "question": "The Zoramites had not separated themselves from the Nephites.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3872,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma31:2",
    "question": "The_____ had separated themselves from the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Zoramites",
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Zoramites", "Ammonites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3873,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma31:3",
    "question": "The land where the Zoramites had gathered together was called_____.",
    "answer": "Antionum",
    "options": ["Jershon", "Manti", "Antionum"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3874,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:4",
    "question": "The Nephites were concerned greatly because they thought that the Zoramites would enter a correspondence with the_____ which would cause a great loss to them.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3875,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:15",
    "question": "Mormon wrote that the word of God has more power on the effect of the mind of the people than the sword.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3876,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:5",
    "question": "According to Mormon; which has more power on the effect of the mind of the people-the sword or the word of God?",
    "answer": "word"
  },
  {
    "id": 3877,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:7",
    "question": "Alma2 had three sons; but only took two of them to preach the word of God to the Zoramites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3878,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:7",
    "question": "What is the name of the eldest son of Alma2 the Younger?",
    "answer": "Helaman"
  },
  {
    "id": 3879,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:8",
    "question": "Because the_____ were dissenters from the Nephites; therefore they had had the word of God preached unto them.",
    "answer": "Zoramites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3880,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:9",
    "question": "The Zoramites would not observe to keep the commandments of God, and his statutes, according to the Law of_____.",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },
  {
    "id": 3881,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:10",
    "question": "The Zoramites would not observe the performances of the church; to continue to pray daily in order that they might not enter into temptation.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3882,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:11",
    "question": "Mormon writes that one of the best ways to ward off the temptations of the devil is to pray and be in supplication to God daily.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3883,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:11",
    "question": "By doing the things which they were doing; the Zoramites were perverting the ways of the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3884,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:11",
    "question": "By not doing what they were supposed to do according to the church; the_____ were perverting the ways of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Zoramites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3885,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma31:12",
    "question": "To the astonishment of Alma2 and his brethren, the Zoramites had built_____, and they would gather themselves together on one day of the week; which they called the day of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Synagogues",
    "options": ["Synagogues", "Houses", "Chapels"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3886,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:12",
    "question": "The manner in which the Zoramites worshipped the Lord was not new to Alma2 and his brethren.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3887,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:13",
    "question": "The Zoramites had a place built up in the center of their synagogue, a place for standing, which was high above the head and it would only allow one person at a time to worship.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3888,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:15",
    "question": "The Zoramites believed that God was a holy God and a spirit and that God would be a spirit forever.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3889,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:16",
    "question": "The Zoramites believed that the Nephites believed in traditions which were handed down by the childishness of their fathers.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3890,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma31:16",
    "question": "What tribe of people believed that they were elected to be the chosen children of God?",
    "answer": "Zoramites",
    "options": ["Zoramites", "Nephites", "Lamanites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3891,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma31:16",
    "question": "The Zoramites believed that they were elected to be the_____ children of God.",
    "answer": "Holy",
    "options": ["Chosen", "Holy", "Preferred"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3892,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma31:16",
    "question": "The Zoramites believed that God had made it known unto them that there would be no_____.",
    "answer": "Christ",
    "options": ["Death", "Christ", "Hell"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3893,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:17",
    "question": "The Zoramites believed that God was the same yesterday, today and_____; and had elected them to be saved.",
    "answer": "Forever"
  },
  {
    "id": 3894,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:19",
    "question": "When Alma2 and his brethren and his sons had heard the prayers of the Zoramites; they were astonished beyond measure.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3895,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:20",
    "question": "Every Zoramites that went up to pray on the stand did not offer the same prayer.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3896,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:21",
    "question": "Another name for the holy stand in which the Zoramites offered their prayers is called_____.",
    "answer": "Rameumptom"
  },
  {
    "id": 3897,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma31:21",
    "question": "The word “Rameumptom” only appears how many times in the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "1",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3898,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:21",
    "question": "The word “Rameumpton” only appears once in the Book of Mormon.  Name the book in which it appears.",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 3899,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:23",
    "question": "After the Zoramites finished offering the self-same prayer unto God, they returned to their homes, never speaking of their God again until they had assembled themselves together again.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3900,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:23",
    "question": "After the Zoramites finished offerings their prayers unto God; they would return home and talked to each other about speaking of God.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3901,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:24",
    "question": "When Alma2 saw how the_____ offered their prayers he was sadden because he saw that they were a wicked and a perverse people.",
    "answer": "Zoramites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3902,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:24",
    "question": "Alma2 also saw that the Zoramites hearts were set upon_____, and upon silver, and upon all manner of fine goods.",
    "answer": "Gold"
  },
  {
    "id": 3903,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma31:25",
    "question": "Alma2 also saw the Zoramites_____ were lifted up unto great boasting of their pride.",
    "answer": "Hearts",
    "options": ["Heads", "Hearts", "Voices"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3904,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:26",
    "question": "Alma2 wondered how long the Lord would suffer that he and his servants would dwell below in the flesh, to behold such gross wickedness among the children of men.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3905,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma31:28",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Zoramites were puffed up with their costly apparel, and their ringlets, and their bracelets, and their ornaments of_____.",
    "answer": "Gold",
    "options": ["Silver", "Platinum", "Gold"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3906,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma31:29",
    "question": "The Zoramites said that God had made it known to them that there shall be no_____.",
    "answer": "Christ",
    "options": ["Sabbath Day", "Christ", "Evil"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3907,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma31:30",
    "question": "Alma2 asked the Lord to give him_____ that he may be able to bear his infirmities because of the wickedness of the Zoramites.",
    "answer": "Strength",
    "options": ["Patience", "Longsuffering", "Strength"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3908,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:31",
    "question": "Alma2’s heart was exceedingly sorrowful because of the Zoramites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3909,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:31",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted strength from the Lord so that he could suffer with patience the afflictions which would come upon him because of the iniquity of the_____.",
    "answer": "Zoramites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3910,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:32",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted the Lord to comfort his_____ and give him success; and also those of his fellow laborers who were with him.",
    "answer": "Soul"
  },
  {
    "id": 3911,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:34",
    "question": "Alma2 asked the Lord to grant unto them that they might have success in bringing the Zoramites again unto_____.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 3912,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:35",
    "question": "Alma2 did not tell the Lord that the souls of the Zoramites were precious and that they were also their brethren.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3913,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:36",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma2 finished with his prayer and clapped his_____ upon all of them who were with him. And behold, they were filled with the Holy Spirit.",
    "answer": "Hands"
  },
  {
    "id": 3914,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:37",
    "question": "After Alma2 finished with his prayer and clapped his hands; he and his brethren separated themselves one from another, taking no thought for themselves’ what they should eat, drink, or put on.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3915,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:38",
    "question": "Who provided for Alma2 and his brethren that they would not get hungry or thirst?",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 3916,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma31:38",
    "question": "The Lord also gave Alma2 and his brethren strength that they should suffer no manner of_____.",
    "answer": "Afflictions",
    "options": ["Afflictions", "Sickness", "Death"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3917,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma31:38",
    "question": "The Lord granted unto Alma2 all that he had asked for because he had prayed in_____.",
    "answer": "Faith",
    "options": ["Private", "Faith", "Church"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3918,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:1",
    "question": "Alma2 and his brethren preached to the Zoramites in their synagogues, and in their houses, and in their streets.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3919,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma32:2",
    "question": "When Alma2 and his brother went among the Zoramites to preach the word of God; they had success in what class of people?",
    "answer": "Poor",
    "options": ["Rich", "Middle Income", "Poor"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3920,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma32:2",
    "question": "The poor class of people; were cast out of the synagogues because of the_____ of their apparel.",
    "answer": "Coarseness",
    "options": ["Costliness", "Ugliness", "Coarseness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3921,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:3",
    "question": "The poor class of people; were permitted to enter into the synagogues to worship God.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3922,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:3",
    "question": "The poor class of people; were esteemed as filthy and dross and they were poor as to the things of the_____.",
    "answer": "World"
  },
  {
    "id": 3923,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:3",
    "question": "The poor class of people; were also poor in heart.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3924,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:4",
    "question": "What is the name of the hill where Alma2 was teaching and speaking to the poor class of people of the Zoramites?",
    "answer": "Onidah"
  },
  {
    "id": 3925,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma32:5",
    "question": "The poor class of the Zoramites; were despised of all men but more especially by the_____.",
    "answer": "Priests",
    "options": ["Teachers", "Priests", "Elders"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3926,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:5",
    "question": "The poor class of the people of the Zoramites had labored abundantly to build the_____ with their own hands.",
    "answer": "Synagogues"
  },
  {
    "id": 3927,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:5",
    "question": "One of the Zoramites who was foremost among the crowd of people asked Alma2 where they should go to worship the word of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3928,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma32:6",
    "question": "Alma2 beheld with great_____ because he knew that the people were truly humbled because of their afflictions.",
    "answer": "Joy",
    "options": ["Joy", "Sorrow", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3929,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:6,7",
    "question": "Alma2 stretched forth his hand and blessed those who were truly penitent among the crowd.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3930,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:9",
    "question": "The poor class of the Zoramites said that they could not worship God because they had been cast out of their_____.",
    "answer": "Synagogues"
  },
  {
    "id": 3931,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:10",
    "question": "Alma2 asked the Zoramites if they thought that they could only worship God in their synagogues.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3932,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma32:12",
    "question": "Alma2 thought that it was well that the poor class of people had been cast out of their synagogues because it made them_____.",
    "answer": "Humble",
    "options": ["Nicer", "Humble", "Poorer"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3933,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:12",
    "question": "Alma2 said that it was necessary for the poor class of people to learn wisdom; and that they are brought to a lowliness of heart because it made them humble.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3934,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma32:12",
    "question": "The poor class of the Zoramites; were despised because of their exceeding_____.",
    "answer": "Poverty",
    "options": ["Poverty", "Number", "Dirtiness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3935,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:13",
    "question": "Alma2 told the poor class of the Zoramites that they were blessed because they were compelled to be_____.",
    "answer": "Humble"
  },
  {
    "id": 3936,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:15",
    "question": "Alma2 said that those who truly humble themselves and repent of their sins, and_____ to the end, the same shall be blessed.",
    "answer": "Endure"
  },
  {
    "id": 3937,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:16",
    "question": "Blessed are they who_____ themselves without being compelled to be humble.",
    "answer": "Humble"
  },
  {
    "id": 3938,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma32:16",
    "question": "Blessed is he who believes in the word of God, and is_____ without stubbornness of heart.",
    "answer": "Baptized",
    "options": ["Truly", "Baptized", "Willingly"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3939,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:17",
    "question": "Alma2 says that there are many who say:  If you will show unto us a sign from heaven, then we shall know of a surety; then we shall believe.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3940,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:18",
    "question": "Alma2 said that if we need to be shown a sign in order to believe, we have true faith.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3941,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:21",
    "question": "Alma2 said that_____ is not to have a perfect knowledge of things.",
    "answer": "Faith"
  },
  {
    "id": 3942,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma32:21",
    "question": "If we have faith we hope for things which are not seen, which are_____.",
    "answer": "True",
    "options": ["True", "False", "Unreal"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3943,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:22",
    "question": "Alma2 said that we should remember that_____ is merciful unto all who believe on his name; therefore he desires in the first place, that we should believe even on his word.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 3944,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:23",
    "question": "By whom does the Lord impart his words to give unto men and women also?",
    "answer": "Angels"
  },
  {
    "id": 3945,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma32:23",
    "question": "Alma2 says that_____ children do have words given unto them many times which confound the wise and learned.",
    "answer": "Little",
    "options": ["Many", "Big", "Little"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3946,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma32:24",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites that he did not mean to judge them only according to that which is_____.",
    "answer": "True",
    "options": ["Right", "True", "Righteous"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3947,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:25",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites that he truly believed that there were some among them who were really humbled and not compelled to be made to be so.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3948,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma32:27",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites to awake and arouse their faculties, even to an experiment upon his_____.",
    "answer": "Words",
    "options": ["Teachings", "Words", "Neither A Or B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3949,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:28",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted the Zoramites to compare his word unto a_____.",
    "answer": "Seed"
  },
  {
    "id": 3950,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:28",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted the Zoramites to plant a true or good seed unto their_____.",
    "answer": "Hearts"
  },
  {
    "id": 3951,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:28",
    "question": "If the seed that we plant unto our hearts is a good seed and we do not resist the Spirit of the Lord, it will begin to swell within our breasts.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3952,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:28",
    "question": "If the seed that we have planted in our hearts is a good seed; we must say that it is a good seed because it is beginning to enlarge our souls.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3953,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:28",
    "question": "A good seed will begin to enlighten our understanding, and will be delicious unto us.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3954,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma32:31",
    "question": "Alma2 said that every good seed will bring forth unto its own_____.",
    "answer": "Likeness",
    "options": ["Tree", "Fruit", "Likeness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3955,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:32",
    "question": "Alma2 said if a seed grows it is good, but if it does not grow, behold it is not good, therefore it is_____ away.",
    "answer": "Cast"
  },
  {
    "id": 3956,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:33",
    "question": "Alma2 said that if we try his experiment and plant the seed, and it swells and sprouts and begins to grow, we must know that the seed is good.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3957,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:34",
    "question": "Alma2 tells us that our knowledge is perfect of the seed only but that our_____ is dormant.",
    "answer": "Faith"
  },
  {
    "id": 3958,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:35",
    "question": "Alma2 writes that whatsoever is light is_____, because it is discernible, therefore we must know that it is good.",
    "answer": "Good"
  },
  {
    "id": 3959,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:37",
    "question": "Alma2 writes that in order for the seed to get roots and grow up into a tree and bring forth fruit we must nourish it with great care that it may grow up and bring forth fruit unto us.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3960,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:38",
    "question": "Alma2 said if we neglect the tree and take no thought for its nourishment it will not get any root and when the heat of the_____ comes and scorches it; it will wither away and we will pluck it up and cast it out.",
    "answer": "Sun"
  },
  {
    "id": 3961,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:39",
    "question": "Alma2 tells us that if the seed that we plant does not grow up and bear fruit; it is not because the seed was no good but it was because are ground was barren, therefore we cannot have the fruit thereof.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3962,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:40",
    "question": "Alma2 writes that if we do not nourish the word, looking forward with an eye of faith to the fruit thereof, we can never pluck of the fruit of the tree of_____.",
    "answer": "Life"
  },
  {
    "id": 3963,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:41",
    "question": "Alma2 writes that if we nourish the word, nourish the tree as it begins to grow by our faith with great diligence and patience, looking forward to the fruit thereof, it shall take root; springing up unto everlasting life.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3964,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:42",
    "question": "Alma2 tells us that because of our diligence and our faith and our patience with the word in nourishing it, we shall pluck the fruit thereof.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3965,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma32:42",
    "question": "The fruit of the Tree of Life is most precious, which is sweet above all that is_____.",
    "answer": "Sweet",
    "options": ["Good", "Sweet", "Rich"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3966,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:42",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the fruit of the tree of everlasting life is white above all that is_____ and pure above all that is pure.  And we shall feast upon this fruit even until we are filled.",
    "answer": "White"
  },
  {
    "id": 3967,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:42",
    "question": "Alma2 writes that we shall never_____ neither shall we never thirst if we partake of the tree of everlasting life.",
    "answer": "Hunger"
  },
  {
    "id": 3968,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:43",
    "question": "Alma2 said that after we nourish the word/tree we shall reap the rewards of our faith, and our_____, and patience, and long-suffering, waiting for the tree to bring forth fruit unto us.",
    "answer": "Diligence"
  },
  {
    "id": 3969,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:1",
    "question": "After Alma2 finished speaking to the Zoramites they desired to know whether they should believe in one_____.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["God", "Person", "Faith"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3970,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:1",
    "question": "The Zoramites desired and asked Alma2 how they might obtain this fruit of which he had spoken, or how they should plant the seed, or the word of which he had spoken.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3971,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:1",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites that the seed or word of which he had spoken of must be planted in their_____.",
    "answer": "Hearts",
    "options": ["Heads", "Chest", "Hearts"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3972,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:1",
    "question": "The Zoramites did not desire to know in what manner they should begin to exercise their faith.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3973,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:2",
    "question": "The Zoramites told Alma2 that they could not worship their God because they had been cast out of their_____.",
    "answer": "Synagogues",
    "options": ["Synagogues", "Houses", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3974,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:2",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites that they should search the_____ to find out where and how they could worship their God.",
    "answer": "Scriptures",
    "options": ["Book Of Mormon", "Scriptures", "Pearl Of Great Price"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3975,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:2",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites that if they had searched the scriptures concerning where and how they could worship their God they did not understand them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3976,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:3",
    "question": "What prophet of old times did Alma2 refer to and told the Zoramites had spoken concerning prayer or worship?",
    "answer": "Zenos",
    "options": ["Moses", "Nephi", "Zenos"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3977,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:4",
    "question": "What prophet of old times did Alma2 say had prayed in the wilderness and the Lord had heard his prayer.",
    "answer": "Zenos",
    "options": ["Zenos", "Zenock", "Zeus"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3978,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma33:5",
    "question": "Alma2 said the prophet_____ of old times had cried unto the Lord in his field and the Lord had heard his prayer?",
    "answer": "Zenos"
  },
  {
    "id": 3979,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:6",
    "question": "When Zenos the prophet of old times had cried unto the Lord in his_____ the Lord did hear his prayer.",
    "answer": "House",
    "options": ["Barn", "Shed", "House"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3980,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:7",
    "question": "What particular place in his house did the prophet Zenos pray unto the Lord and he did hear his prayer?",
    "answer": "Closet",
    "options": ["Bathroom", "Closet", "Living Room"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3981,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:8",
    "question": "The Lord is merciful unto us when we cry unto him to be heard of him and not of men, and he will hear our prayers.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3982,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:9",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the Lord had not been merciful unto him when he had prayed unto him in the midst of his congregations.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3983,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:10",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the Lord had also heard his prayers when he had been cast out and despised by his_____.",
    "answer": "Enemies",
    "options": ["People", "Enemies", "Friends"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3984,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:10",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Lord was angry with his enemies and did visit them in his anger with speedy destruction.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3985,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:11",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the Lord had heard his prayers because of his afflictions and sincerity.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3986,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:11",
    "question": "Alma2 prayed unto the Lord in all his afflictions because in the Lord was his joy; and he had turned his judgments away from him, because of_____.",
    "answer": "Jesus Christ",
    "options": ["Sincerity Of His Prayers", "Constant Praying", "Jesus Christ"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3987,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:12",
    "question": "Alma2 asked the Zoramites if they believed in the scriptures which had been written by the prophets of old times.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3988,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma33:13",
    "question": "What prophet of old times did Alma2 tell the Zoramites had written and said that the Lord had turned away his judgments because of his beloved son Jesus Christ?_____ ",
    "answer": "Zenos"
  },
  {
    "id": 3989,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma33:14",
    "question": "Alma2 told the_____ if they had read the scriptures, how was it possible that could they disbelieve in the Son of God.",
    "answer": "Zoramites"
  },
  {
    "id": 3990,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:15",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites that the prophet Zenos and also the prophet_____ of old times had spoken of the things concerning the Son of God.",
    "answer": "Zenock",
    "options": ["Nephi", "Moses", "Zenock"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3991,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:16",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites that the Lord was _____ with them because they could not understand his mercies which he had bestowed upon them because of his son Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "Angry",
    "options": ["Upset", "Angry", "Mad"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3992,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "15,17",
    "question": "What second prophet of old did Alma2 say had testified of the Son of God and because the people would not understand his words; they stoned him to death?  Zenock",
    "answer": "Alma33:"
  },
  {
    "id": 3993,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:18",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites that Zenos and Zenock were the only prophets that had spoken and testified of the things concerning the Son of God.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3994,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma33:19",
    "question": "What prophet did Alma2 say raised a type of Jesus Christ in the wilderness, that whosoever would look upon it might live?",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },
  {
    "id": 3995,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:19",
    "question": "Alma2 said that Moses raised a type of Jesus Christ in the wilderness and many of them did look and lived",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 3996,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:20",
    "question": "Alma2 said that a lot of the people understood the meaning of the type of Jesus Christ that Moses had raised up in the wilderness.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 3997,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma33:20",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites that many of the Israelites did not understand the type of Jesus Christ that_____ had raised up because the hardness of their hearts.",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },
  {
    "id": 3998,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:20",
    "question": "Alma2 said that many of the Israelites would not look upon the type of Jesus Christ Moses had raised up because they were_____.",
    "answer": "Harden",
    "options": ["Stuck Up", "Harden", "Sick"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3999,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma33:20",
    "question": "Alma2 told the_____that they were many who were so hardened that they would not look, therefore they perished.",
    "answer": "Zoramites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4000,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:20",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites the reason they would not look was because they did not believe that it would_____ them.",
    "answer": "Heal",
    "options": ["Heal", "Save", "Cleanse"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4001,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma33:21",
    "question": "Alma2 desired that the Zoramites could be healed by merely casting about their eyes unto the_____ that they might be healed.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 4002,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:21",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people to behold quickly their eyes unto the Son of God and not hardened their hearts and be slothful.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4003,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:22",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that wo would come upon them in they would not cast their eyes unto the Son of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4004,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma33:22",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites the Son of God would come to redeem his people, and that he shall suffer and die and_____ for their sins.",
    "answer": "Atone"
  },
  {
    "id": 4005,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma33:22",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people the Son of God would also rise again from the dead, which shall bring to pass the_____, and that all men shall stand before him.",
    "answer": "Resurrection"
  },
  {
    "id": 4006,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma33:22",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites the Lord would bring to pass the resurrection; that all men shall stand before him, to be judged at the last and judgment_____, according to their works.",
    "answer": "Day"
  },
  {
    "id": 4007,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:23",
    "question": "Alma2 desired that the Zoramites would plant the word in their hearts, and as it begins to swell that they would nourish if by their_____.",
    "answer": "Faith",
    "options": ["Belief", "Faith", "Sincerity"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4008,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:23",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites that he desired that God would grant unto them that their burdens might be heavy and awful.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4009,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma33:23",
    "question": "Alma2 desired that the Zoramites burdens may be light through the joy of the Son of_____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 4010,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:23",
    "question": "Alma2 desired the Zoramites would believe in the word of God and could do anything if they were willing.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4011,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:1",
    "question": "After Alma2 finished speaking to the Zoramites; he sat down on the ground and who arose and began to speak to them?",
    "answer": "Amulek",
    "options": ["King Noah", "King Limhi2", "Amulek"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4012,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:1",
    "question": "Amulek told the Zoramites that it was impossible that they should be ignorant of the things which have been spoken by Alma2 concerning the coming of Christ.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4013,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:2",
    "question": "Who did Amulek say was the taught by Alma2 and himself that would be the father of Jesus Christ?",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 4014,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:2",
    "question": "Amulek told the_____ that he knew the things concerning Christ were taught unto them bountifully before their dissension from among them.",
    "answer": "Zoramites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4015,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:3",
    "question": "The Zoramites desired of_____, the beloved brother of Amulek; that he should make known unto them what they should do because of their afflictions.",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 4016,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:3",
    "question": "Amulek told the people that Alma2 had exhorted them to have faith and patience in their afflictions.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4017,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:4",
    "question": "Amulek told the Zoramites that they should have so much_____ as even to plant the word in their hearts, that they may try the experiment of its goodness.",
    "answer": "Faith",
    "options": ["Desire", "Faith", "Knowledge"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4018,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:5",
    "question": "Amulek told the Zoramites he knew that the great question in their minds was whether the word be in the Son of God, or whether there shall be no_____.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 4019,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:6",
    "question": "Amulek said who had proved unto the Zoramites in many instances, that the word is in Christ unto salvation?",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 4020,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:7",
    "question": "What three prophets of old times did Amulek say Alma2 had appealed unto; to prove to the Zoramites that the things concerning Christ were true?  Zenos, and Zenock, and_____.",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },
  {
    "id": 4021,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:8",
    "question": "Amulek did not testify to the Zoramites that the things he said concerning Jesus Christ were true.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4022,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:8",
    "question": "Amulek testified unto the Zoramites that he knew Jesus Christ would come among the children of men, to take upon him the transgressions of his people, and shall atone for the sins of the world.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4023,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:8",
    "question": "Amulek testified to the Zoramites that the Lord God himself had spoken of the things concerning Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4024,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:9",
    "question": "Amulek said it was expedient that an_____ should be made; for according to the great plan of the Eternal God.",
    "answer": "Atonement"
  },
  {
    "id": 4025,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:9",
    "question": "Amulek said that mankind would unavoidably_____ if there was no atonement made by Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "Perish",
    "options": ["Get Burned", "Be Sent To Hell", "Perish"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4026,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:10",
    "question": "Amulek said that there should be a great and_____ sacrifice; not a sacrifice of man, neither of beast, neither of any manner of fowl.",
    "answer": "Last"
  },
  {
    "id": 4027,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:10",
    "question": "Amulek testified that there should be a great and last sacrifice; not a sacrifice of man, neither of beast, neither of any manner of fowl.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4028,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:10",
    "question": "Amulek said that it was expedient that the sacrifice of Jesus Christ must be an infinite and_____ sacrifice.",
    "answer": "Eternal"
  },
  {
    "id": 4029,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:11",
    "question": "Amulek said that a man could sacrifice his own blood which shall atone for the sins of another.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4030,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:13",
    "question": "Amulek told the Zoramites that there should be a stop to the shedding of blood; then shall the Law of_____ be fulfilled.",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },
  {
    "id": 4031,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:13",
    "question": "After the great and last sacrifice; Amulek said that every jot and _____, and none shall have passed away.",
    "answer": "Tittle"
  },
  {
    "id": 4032,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:14",
    "question": "Amulek said that the meaning of the law was to point to the great and last sacrifice.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4033,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:14",
    "question": "Amulek said that the great and last sacrifice will be the Son of_____, infinite and eternal.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 4034,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:15",
    "question": "The intent of this last sacrifice is to bring about the bowels of mercy which overpowers justice, and brings about means unto men that they may have faith unto repentance.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4035,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:16",
    "question": "And_____ can satisfy the demands of justice, and encircles them in the arms of safety.",
    "answer": "Mercy",
    "options": ["Mercy", "Repentance", "Money"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4036,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:16",
    "question": "Amulek said that those who exercise no faith unto repentance are exposed to the whole law of the demands of justice.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4037,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:16",
    "question": "The great and eternal plan of redemption is brought about unto those that have no faith unto repentance.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4038,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:17",
    "question": "Amulek wished that his brethren would begin to exercise their faith unto_____.",
    "answer": "Repentance"
  },
  {
    "id": 4039,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:17",
    "question": "Amulek wanted his brethren to begin to call upon Jesus Christ, that he would have_____ upon them.",
    "answer": "Mercy",
    "options": ["Pity", "Mercy", "Compassion"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4040,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "16,18",
    "question": "Who did Amulek say “is mighty to save”?",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["Nephi", "Moses"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4041,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "20,21",
    "question": "Amulek told his brethren to cry unto the Lord in their fields, over all of their flocks and in their_____.",
    "answer": "Yards",
    "options": ["Yards", "Barns", "Houses"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4042,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:21",
    "question": "Amulek told his brethren to cry unto the Lord how many times during the day.",
    "answer": "3",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4043,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:22",
    "question": "Amulek said that his brethren should not cry unto the Lord against the power of their enemies.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4044,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:23",
    "question": "Who did Amulek say is “an enemy to all righteousness”? ",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },
  {
    "id": 4045,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:24",
    "question": "Amulek did not tell his brethren to cry unto the Lord over the crops of their fields, that they may prosper in them.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4046,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:26",
    "question": "Amulek told the Zoramites to pour out their souls in their_____, their secret places, and in their wilderness.",
    "answer": "Closets"
  },
  {
    "id": 4047,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:27",
    "question": "We should let our hearts be full, and drawn out in prayer unto the Lord continually for our welfare, and also for the welfare of those who are_____ us.",
    "answer": "Around",
    "options": ["Behind", "Around", "Beneath"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4048,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:28",
    "question": "After we have prayed continually for the welfare of others it is okay to turn away the needy and the naked.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4049,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:28",
    "question": "Amulek said that we should visit the sick and_____, and impart of our substance, if we have, to those who stand in need of it.",
    "answer": "Afflicted"
  },
  {
    "id": 4050,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:28",
    "question": "Amulek said that if we do not do any of these things (visit the sick/help the needy/impart of our substance) our prayers are in vain, and avails us nothing, and we are hypocrites who deny the faith.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4051,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:28",
    "question": "Amulek said if we do not cry unto the Lord and do other good things; our_____ are in vain, and avails us nothing, and we are hypocrites who deny the faith.",
    "answer": "Prayers"
  },
  {
    "id": 4052,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:29",
    "question": "If we are not charitable, Amulek said we are dross, which_____ do cast out,",
    "answer": "Refiners",
    "options": [
      "(it Being Of No Worth) And Is Trodden Under The Foot Of Men.   Woodsmiths",
      "Metallurgist",
      "Refiners"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 4053,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:30",
    "question": "Amulek told the Zoramites that they had received many witnesses, seeing that the holy_____ testify of these things.",
    "answer": "Scriptures"
  },
  {
    "id": 4054,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:30",
    "question": "Amulek told the Zoramites that after they had received so many witnesses, they should come forth and bring fruit unto_____.",
    "answer": "Repentance",
    "options": ["Repentance", "Him", "Jesus Christ"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4055,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:31",
    "question": "Amulek wished that the_____ would come forth and harden not their hearts any longer.",
    "answer": "Zoramites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4056,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:13",
    "question": "Amulek did not wish that the Zoramites would come forth and not harden their hearts any longer.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4057,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:31",
    "question": "Amulek told the Zoramites that tomorrow would be the time which would become the day of their salvation.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4058,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:31",
    "question": "Amulek told the Zoramites that if they harden not their_____, immediately shall the great plan or redemption would be brought about unto them.",
    "answer": "Hearts"
  },
  {
    "id": 4059,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:31",
    "question": "For behold, this_____ is the time for men to prepare to meet God.",
    "answer": "Life"
  },
  {
    "id": 4060,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:32",
    "question": "Behold the day of this life is the day for men to perform their_____.",
    "answer": "Labors",
    "options": ["Jobs", "Acts Of Charity", "Labors"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4061,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:33",
    "question": "Amulek beseeched the Zoramites that they would not_____ the day of their repentance until the end.",
    "answer": "Procastinate"
  },
  {
    "id": 4062,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:33",
    "question": "Amulek said that this day of life is given to us to prepare for_____.",
    "answer": "Life",
    "options": ["Charitable Work", "Life", "The Olympics"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4063,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:33",
    "question": "For behold, if we do not improve our time while in this_____, then comes the night of darkness. ",
    "answer": "Life"
  },
  {
    "id": 4064,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:33",
    "question": "According to Amulek, we can perform our labors in the night of darkness.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4065,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:34",
    "question": "Amulek said that at the end of this life we cannot say, that I will repent, that I will return to my_____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 4066,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:34",
    "question": "The same_____ which does possess our bodies at the time that we go out of this life, that same spirit will have power to possess our bodies in the eternal world.",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },
  {
    "id": 4067,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:34",
    "question": "Amulek said the same spirit which possesses our bodies at the time that we go out of this life, that same spirit will have the power to possess our bodies in the eternal world.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4068,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:35",
    "question": "Amulek said if we have procrastinated the day of our repentance even until death, behold, we have become subjected unto the spirit of the_____.",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },
  {
    "id": 4069,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:35",
    "question": "If the Spirit of the Lord has withdrawn from us, and has no place in us, the devil has all power over us.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4070,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:35",
    "question": "The final state of the wicked is when the devil has all power over them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4071,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:36",
    "question": "Amulek testified that the things he knew were true because the Lord has said that he cannot dwell in_____ temples.",
    "answer": "Unholy"
  },
  {
    "id": 4072,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:36",
    "question": "Amulek said that the Spirit of the Lord can only dwell in_____ of the righteous.",
    "answer": "Hearts",
    "options": ["Bodies", "Hearts", "Heads"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4073,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:36",
    "question": "The Lord has said that the righteous shall sit down in his_____, to go out no more. ",
    "answer": "Kingdom"
  },
  {
    "id": 4074,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:36",
    "question": "Our garments are made_____ through the blood of the Lamb.",
    "answer": "White"
  },
  {
    "id": 4075,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:37",
    "question": "Amulek said that we should remember his testimony, and that we should work on our salvation with fear before God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4076,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:37",
    "question": "Amulek told the Zoramites that it was all right if they denied the coming of Christ, as long as they had repented and gain a testimony of him.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4077,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:38",
    "question": "Amulek told the Zoramites that they should not contend any more against the_____ Ghost.",
    "answer": "Holy"
  },
  {
    "id": 4078,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:38",
    "question": "Amulek told the Zoramites that they should receive the Holy Ghost, and take upon them the name of_____.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 4079,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:38",
    "question": "Amulek testified that we should humble ourselves even to the dust, and worship_____, in whatsoever place that we may be in, in spirit and in truth.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 4080,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:38",
    "question": "Amulek said that we should live in thanksgiving daily, for the many mercies and blessings which the Lord does bestow upon us.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4081,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:39",
    "question": "Amulek exhorts us that we should be watchful unto prayer continually, that we may not be led away by the temptation of the_____.",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },
  {
    "id": 4082,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:39",
    "question": "Amulek exhorts us pray continually, that the devil may not overpower us and that we may not become his_____ at the last day.",
    "answer": "Subjects",
    "options": ["People", "Subjects", "Beings"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4083,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:39",
    "question": "Amulek testified that if we become the subjects of the Devil, he will reward us with good things at the last day.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4084,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:40",
    "question": "Amulek exhorted his brethren to have patience and should bear all manner of their afflictions; that they would not revile against those who had cast them out of their sanctuaries.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4085,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:40",
    "question": "The people that Amulek testified to were cast out of their sanctuaries because of their exceeding_____.",
    "answer": "Poverty",
    "options": ["Smell", "Riches", "Poverty"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4086,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:41",
    "question": "Amulek testified to the Zoramites to have patience and bear their afflictions with a firm_____ that they shall one day rest from all of their afflictions.",
    "answer": "Hope",
    "options": ["Testimony", "Hope", "Faith"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4087,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma35:1",
    "question": "After Amulek had finished testifying to the Zoramites, they withdrew themselves from the multitude and came over into the land of_____.",
    "answer": "Jershon",
    "options": ["Waters Of Mormon", "Zarahemla", "Jershon"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4088,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma35:2",
    "question": "The more part of the Zoramites consulted together concerning the words which had preached unto them, and were angry.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4089,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma35:3",
    "question": "The Zoramites were angry with the words that had been preached unto them because it did destroy their craft, and they would not hearken unto the words.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4090,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma35:6",
    "question": "The Zoramites consulted one with another and found out the minds of all the people, and those that were in favor of the words which had been spoken by_____ and his brethren were cast out.",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 4091,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma35:7",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma2 and his brethren did minister to those that were cast out.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4092,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma35:8",
    "question": "The people of the Zoramites did not get angry with the people of Ammon who were in Jershon, because of their beliefs.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4093,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma35:8",
    "question": "During the time that Alma2 and Amulek and their brethren testified of the word or God, the chief ruler of the Zoramites was a very wicked man.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4094,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma35:9",
    "question": "The people of Ammon were afraid of the chief ruler of the _____ because he breathed out many threatenings against them.",
    "answer": "Zoramites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4095,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma35:9",
    "question": "The poor people of the Zoramite’s who had been cast out, were nourished and clothed and given lands unto their inheritance by what people?",
    "answer": "Ammon"
  },
  {
    "id": 4096,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma35:9",
    "question": "The people of Ammon did not administer to the wants of the people of the Zoramites who had been cast out.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4097,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma35:10",
    "question": "The Zoramites became angry with the people of Ammon because of the things they were doing for the poor and began to stir up what people to also be angry with them?",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4098,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma35:11",
    "question": "And the Zoramites and the Lamanites began to make preparations for war against the people of_____, and also against the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Ammon"
  },
  {
    "id": 4099,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma35:13",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people of Ammon departed out of the land of Jershon, and came over into the land of_____.",
    "answer": "Melek",
    "options": ["Melek", "Mormon", "Zarahemla"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4100,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma35:14",
    "question": "And Alma2, and Ammon, and their brethren, and also the two sons of Alma returned to the land of_____.",
    "answer": "Zarahemla",
    "options": ["Melek", "Mormon", "Zarahemla"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4101,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma35:14",
    "question": "Alma2, Ammon, and his brethren; became_____ in the hands of God of bringing many of the Zoramites unto repentance.",
    "answer": "Instruments"
  },
  {
    "id": 4102,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma35:15",
    "question": "Alma2 was not sadden or grieved because of the iniquity of his people.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4103,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma35:15",
    "question": "Alma2 and his brethren declared the word of God unto all the people in every city.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4104,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma35:15",
    "question": "Alma2 began to see that the hearts of the people began to wax hard, and that they began to be offended because of the strictness of the_____ of God.",
    "answer": "Word"
  },
  {
    "id": 4105,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma35:16",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____ caused his sons should be gathered together, that he might give unto them every one his charge, separately.",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 4106,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma35:16",
    "question": "Alma2 gave charge to each of his sons concerning the things pertaining unto righteousness.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4107,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma35:16",
    "question": "The charge that Alma2 gave to each of his sons pertaining to righteousness, have been recorded; and we have a copy of them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4108,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:1,37:1,38:1,39:1-42:31",
    "question": "The charge that Alma2 gave to each of his sons pertaining to righteousness; have been recorded in the Book of Jacob.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4109,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:1",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to give ear to his words; that inasmuch as he shall keep the commandments of_____ he shall prosper in the land.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 4110,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:2",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted Helaman to remember the captivity of their fathers.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4111,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma36:2",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that no one else but God could deliver their fathers from captivity and _____.",
    "answer": "Bondage",
    "options": ["Prison", "Bondage", "Jails"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4112,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:3",
    "question": "Helaman was in his mid 30’s when Alma2 gave his commandments to him.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4113,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma36:3",
    "question": "Alma2 testified to Helaman that he knew that whosoever shall put their trust in God shall be supported in their_____.",
    "answer": "Trials",
    "options": ["Trials", "Life", "Homes"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4114,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:3",
    "question": "If we put are trust in God; we will be supported by him in our trials, troubles, and in our afflictions.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4115,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:3",
    "question": "Alma2 testified unto _____ that if we must put our trust in God we shall be lifted up at the last day.",
    "answer": "Helaman"
  },
  {
    "id": 4116,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:4",
    "question": "Alma2 testified unto Helaman that he knew the things he knew because of his spiritual mind, not of the carnal mind but, of_____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 4117,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma36:5",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that he knew the things of God because a holy_____ had made these things known to him.",
    "answer": "Angel",
    "options": ["Man", "Ghost", "Angel"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4118,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:5",
    "question": "Alma2 testified unto Helaman that he was unworthy to receive the things of God told to him by an angel.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4119,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:6",
    "question": "Seeking to destroy the church of God; Alma2 went with the_____ of Mosiah.",
    "answer": "Sons"
  },
  {
    "id": 4120,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:6",
    "question": "Who or what stopped Alma2 and the sons of Mosiah from destroying the church of God?",
    "answer": "Angel"
  },
  {
    "id": 4121,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:7",
    "question": "The holy angel spoke to Alma2 and the sons of Mosiah with a voice of_____, and the whole earth did tremble beneath their feet.",
    "answer": "Thunder"
  },
  {
    "id": 4122,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:7",
    "question": "Alma2 and the sons of Mosiah fell to the earth because the fear of the Lord came upon them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4123,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:8",
    "question": "Who did the angel of the Lord tell to arise and stand up first, Alma2 or the sons of Mosiah? ",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 4124,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:8",
    "question": "Alma2 did not arise and stand up as he was commanded by the angel of the Lord.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4125,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:9",
    "question": "The angel of the Lord told Alma2 that he would be destroyed if he continued to destroy the church of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4126,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma36:10",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma2 fell to the earth for how many days and how many nights?",
    "answer": "3",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4127,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:10",
    "question": "When_____ fell to the earth he could not open his mouth and could not use his limbs.",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 4128,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:10",
    "question": "When Alma2 fell to the earth he could not open his mouth and could not use his limbs.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4129,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:11",
    "question": "Alma2 heard all the words of the Lord which were spoken to him by his holy angel.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4130,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma36:11",
    "question": "Immediately upon hearing the words of the holy angel; Alma2 was struck with such great fear and amazement, that he fell to the_____ and did not hear anymore of his words.",
    "options": ["Ground", "Earth"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4131,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma36:12",
    "question": "Alma2’s was racked with eternal_____, for his soul was harrowed up to the greatest degree and racked with all his sins.",
    "answer": "Torment",
    "options": ["Torment", "Punishment", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4132,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:13",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that he could not remember all his sins and iniquities.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4133,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:13",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that not only could he remember all his sins and iniquities for which he was tormented with the pains of_____.",
    "answer": "Hell"
  },
  {
    "id": 4134,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:13",
    "question": "Alma2 testified unto Helaman that he could not understand why he was being punished because he had not rebelled against God and had kept his holy commandments.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4135,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:14",
    "question": "Alma2 testified unto Helaman that he had led many of the Lord’s_____ away unto destruction.",
    "answer": "Children"
  },
  {
    "id": 4136,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma36:14",
    "question": "Alma2 said that so great had been his iniquities, that the very thought of coming into the presence of God did rack his soul with inexpressible_____.",
    "answer": "Horror",
    "options": ["Fear", "Horror", "Gladness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4137,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:15",
    "question": "Alma2 thought that he could be banished and become extinct both_____ and body for the things he had done to by leading the children of the Lord away from him.",
    "answer": "Soul"
  },
  {
    "id": 4138,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:15",
    "question": "Alma2 wished that he would not be brought to stand in the presence of God, to be judged of his deeds.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4139,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma36:16",
    "question": "For how many days and nights was Alma2’s soul racked with the pains of a damned soul?",
    "answer": "3",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4140,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma36:17",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma2 was racked with torment, while he was harrowed up by the memory of his many_____.",
    "answer": "Sins",
    "options": ["Deeds", "Sins", "Thoughts"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4141,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:17",
    "question": "Alma2 remembered that his father had prophesied to the people concerning the coming of Jesus Christ, a_____ of God.",
    "answer": "Son"
  },
  {
    "id": 4142,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma36:17",
    "question": "Alma2 remembered that his father had prophesied that Jesus Christ would come; to_____ for the sins of the world.",
    "answer": "Atone",
    "options": ["Atone", "Be Punished", "Bleed"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4143,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:18",
    "question": "Alma2 cried within his heart: O Jesus, the Son of God, have mercy on me.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4144,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:18",
    "question": "Alma2 was caught in his mind in the gall of bitterness and was encircled about by the everlasting chains of_____.",
    "answer": "Death"
  },
  {
    "id": 4145,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "19,18",
    "question": "The Lord had _____ on Alma2 that he could no longer remember the memory of his sins.",
    "answer": "Compassion",
    "options": ["Compassion", "Love", "Mercy"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4146,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:20",
    "question": "Alma2 was filled with joy and with a marvelous light that his joy was the same as filled with the joy as exceeding as was his pain.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4147,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:20",
    "question": "Alma2 told _____ that there could be nothing so exquisite and so bitter as were his pains.",
    "answer": "Helaman"
  },
  {
    "id": 4148,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:21",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that on the other hand, there could be nothing so exquisite and sweet as was his joy.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4149,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:22",
    "question": "Alma2 thought that he saw God sitting upon his throne as did Lehi in his vision.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4150,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:22",
    "question": "Alma2 saw God sitting upon his throne, surrounded with numberless concourses of_____, in singing and praising their God.",
    "answer": "Angels"
  },
  {
    "id": 4151,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:22",
    "question": "Alma2’s soul did not want to be where God and his angels were.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4152,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:23",
    "question": "Alma2’s limbs did receive their strength again, and he stood on his feet, and did manifest unto the people that he had been born of_____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 4153,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:24",
    "question": "From the time that Alma2 was born again of God; he had not labored without ceasing, that he might brings souls unto repentance",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4154,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:24",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted his people to taste of the exceeding_____ of which he tasted; that they might also be filled with the Holy Ghost.",
    "answer": "Joy"
  },
  {
    "id": 4155,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma36:25",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that the Lord does give him exceeding great joy in the fruit of his_____.",
    "answer": "Labors",
    "options": ["Loins", "Fields", "Labors"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4156,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:26",
    "question": "Alma2 said that many people had also been born of God and have tasted the same as he has tasted.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4157,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:26",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that many people have been born of God and have seen eye to_____ as he had seen.",
    "answer": "Eye"
  },
  {
    "id": 4158,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:26",
    "question": "The knowledge that Alma2 had of God was of_____; and not of man.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 4159,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:27",
    "question": "Alma2 said that God had not supported him when he was under trials and troubles of every kind.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4160,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:27",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that God had delivered him from_____, and from bonds, and from death.",
    "answer": "Prison"
  },
  {
    "id": 4161,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "27,26",
    "question": "Alma2 said that he puts his_____ in God, and he will still deliver him from his many trials and troubles.",
    "answer": "Love",
    "options": ["Love", "Trust", "Whole Soul"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4162,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:28",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that he knew that God would raise him up at the_____ day, to dwell in his glory.",
    "answer": "Last"
  },
  {
    "id": 4163,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:28",
    "question": "Alma2 said that he would not always praise God for delivering him from his trials and troubles.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4164,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:28",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that he knew that God had brought their fathers out of_____, and that he had swallowed up the Egyptians in the Red Sea.",
    "answer": "Egypt"
  },
  {
    "id": 4165,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:28",
    "question": "What is the name of the body of water that the Lord swallowed up the Egyptians in?",
    "answer": "Red"
  },
  {
    "id": 4166,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma36:28",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that he knew the Lord had delivered their fathers from bondage and_____ from time to time.",
    "answer": "Captivity",
    "options": ["Prison", "Captivity", "Jail"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4167,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:29",
    "question": "Alma2 said that God had brought their fathers out of the land of_____; by his everlasting power.",
    "answer": "Jerusalem"
  },
  {
    "id": 4168,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:29",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to retain in his memory and remembrance the captivity of their fathers even as he has done.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4169,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:30",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted Helaman to know that inasmuch as he would keep the commandments of God; he would prosper in the land.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4170,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:30",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted Helaman to know that inasmuch as he would not keep the_____ of God; he would be cut off from his presence.",
    "answer": "Commandments"
  },
  {
    "id": 4171,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:30",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that all things come to pass according to the word of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4172,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:1",
    "question": "What son did Alma2 entrust with the records of the Nephites?",
    "answer": "Helaman"
  },
  {
    "id": 4173,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:2",
    "question": "Alma2 did not command Helaman to keep a record of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4174,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:2",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to keep a record of the Nephites on the Plates of_____, and keep all those things sacred, as he had done.",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 4175,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:2",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that the Nephite records are kept for a_____ purpose.",
    "answer": "Wise",
    "options": ["Wise", "Not So Wise", "Important"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4176,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:3",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the plates of what metal contain all the engravings which have the records of the Holy Scriptures upon them?",
    "answer": "Brass",
    "options": ["Copper", "Brass", "Gold"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4177,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:3",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that the plates of brass contain the genealogy of their forefathers, even from the beginning",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4178,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:4",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that it had been prophesied by their fathers that a record should be kept and handed down from one_____ to another.",
    "answer": "Generation",
    "options": ["People", "Generation", "Tribe"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4179,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:4",
    "question": "Who did Alma2 say would preserve the records of the Nephites?",
    "answer": ["lord", "god"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4180,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:4",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that their records would go forth to every nation, kindred, _____, and people.",
    "answer": "Tongue"
  },
  {
    "id": 4181,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:4",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that the records would go forth to the world and that every people would know the mysteries contained upon them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4182,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:5",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the Plates of Nephi would retain their_____; and also all the plates which contain Holy Scripture.",
    "answer": "Brightness"
  },
  {
    "id": 4183,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:6",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that by_____ and simple things are great things brought to pass.",
    "answer": "Small"
  },
  {
    "id": 4184,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:6",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that by small and simple things are great things brought to pass; and small means in many instances_____ the wise. ",
    "answer": "Confoud"
  },
  {
    "id": 4185,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:7",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Lord God does work by small means to bring about his great and_____ purposes.",
    "answer": "Eternal",
    "options": ["Small", "Eternal", "Unimportant"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4186,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:7",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that by very small means the Lord does confound the wise and brings about the salvation of many_____.",
    "answer": "Souls",
    "options": ["Bodies", "Souls", "People"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4187,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:8",
    "question": "Alma2 said it is wisdom in God that many things should be preserved.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4188,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:8",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the records have enlarged the memory of the people and convinced them of the error of their ways, and brought them to the knowledge of____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 4189,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:8",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman the records have brought many people of the error of their ways and to the knowledge of God; unto the salvation of many souls.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4190,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:9",
    "question": "Alma2 said that if it was not for the things in the records, _____ he and his brethren could not convince so many thousands of the Lamanites of the error of their traditions.",
    "answer": "Ammon"
  },
  {
    "id": 4191,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:9",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman the records and their words brought many_____ unto repentance and brought them to the knowledge of the Lord their God.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4192,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:9",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the records and their words had not brought the Lamanites to rejoice in Jesus Christ their redeemer.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4193,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:10",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that many of their brethren, the Nephites, were beginning to harden their hearts in sin and iniquities.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4194,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:12",
    "question": "Alma2 said the records were preserved for a_____ purpose, which purpose is known unto God.",
    "answer": "Wise",
    "options": ["Good", "Wise", "Unknown"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4195,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:12",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Lord does counsel in wisdom over all his works, and his paths are unknown.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4196,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:12",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Lords paths are straight and his course is one_____ round.",
    "answer": "Eternal"
  },
  {
    "id": 4197,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:12",
    "question": "What prophet of the Lord is the first person to say that the Lord’s course is “one eternal round”?_____-Alma2/Alma the ",
    "answer": "Younger"
  },
  {
    "id": 4198,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:13",
    "question": "Alma2 reminded Helaman to remember how strict the commandments of God are.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4199,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:14",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted_____ to remember that God had entrusted him with the sacred records, which he has kept sacred, and also which he will keep and preserve them for a wise purpose.",
    "answer": "Helaman"
  },
  {
    "id": 4200,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:14",
    "question": "Alma2 said one of the purposes of the sacred records was so that God could show forth his power unto future generations.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4201,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:15",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman by the_____ prophecy, that if he transgressed the commandments of God, the things which are sacred would be taken away from him by the power of God.",
    "answer": "Spirit",
    "options": ["Spirit", "Gift", "Tongue"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4202,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:15",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman by the spirit of prophecy, that if he transgressed the commandments of God, he would be delivered up unto Satan.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4203,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:16",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that he must not appeal unto the Lord for all things whatsoever he must do with the sacred records.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4204,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:16",
    "question": "Alma2 said to Helaman that if he kept the commandments of God concerning the sacred records, no power on earth or_____ could take them away from him.",
    "answer": "Hell"
  },
  {
    "id": 4205,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:16",
    "question": "Alma2 said that God is powerful to the fulfilling of all his words.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4206,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:17",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that God would fulfil all his_____ which he shall make unto him.",
    "answer": "Promises",
    "options": ["Deeds", "Promises", "Tasks"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4207,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:17",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that God had fulfilled all his promises which he had made unto their fathers.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4208,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:19",
    "question": "Alma2 said one of the purposes of the sacred records had been fulfilled, even to the restoration of many thousands of the_____ to the knowledge of the truth of the word of God.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4209,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:19",
    "question": "Alma2 said God would show forth his power to future generations of the Lamanites; therefore the sacred records will be preserved.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4210,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:20",
    "question": "Alma2 commanded_____ to be diligent in fulfilling all his words, and to be diligent in keeping the commandments of God as they are written.",
    "answer": "Helaman"
  },
  {
    "id": 4211,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:21",
    "question": "Alma2 did not speak unto Helaman concerning the twenty-four plates that were in his possession.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4212,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:21",
    "question": "The twenty-four plates contain mysteries and works of darkness, or the_____ works of those people who had been destroyed.",
    "answer": "Secret",
    "options": ["Good", "Bad", "Secret"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4213,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:21",
    "question": "Alma2 said the twenty-four plates mysteries would be manifested unto his people, the_____.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4214,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:21",
    "question": "The twenty-four plates contain the murders, and robbings, and the plunderings, and all the wickedness and abominations, of the people the Lord had destroyed.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4215,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:21,Mos8:8,Ether1:1",
    "question": "The twenty-four plates contain the record of the Jaredites which the Lord had destroyed because of their wickedness and abominations.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4216,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:21",
    "question": "Alma2 commanded_____ to preserve the interpreters.",
    "answer": "Helaman"
  },
  {
    "id": 4217,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:22",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Lord saw that his people began to work in_____, and work secret murders and abominations.",
    "answer": "Darkness",
    "options": ["Daylight", "Darkness", "Sundays"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4218,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:22",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman the Lord had said the people needed to repent are they would be destroyed from the face of the_____.",
    "answer": "Earth",
    "options": ["Moon", "Americas", "Earth"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4219,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:23",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the Lord would prepare unto his servant Gazelem, a stone, which shall shine forth in darkness unto light.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4220,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos8:14",
    "question": "Gazelem is another name for which one of these prophets of the Lord?",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["Nephi", "Mosiah", "Lehi"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4221,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:23",
    "question": "Alma2 said the stone would show those that serve the Lord the secret works of their brethren; their works of_____, and their wickedness and abominations.",
    "answer": "Darkness"
  },
  {
    "id": 4222,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:24",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman the interpreters were prepared that the word of God might be fulfilled.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4223,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "37:38",
    "question": "Another name that we can use to describe the Interpreters is a ball or director and the fathers of Alma2 and Helaman called it the_____.  Liahona-Alma37:",
    "answer": "24,"
  },
  {
    "id": 4224,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:25",
    "question": "The Lord said the interpreters would bring to light all the secrets and abominations, unto every nation that shall hereafter possess the land.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4225,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "26-27",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that Jaredites were destroyed because they did not_____; therefore the word of the Lord had been fulfilled.",
    "answer": "Care",
    "options": ["Care", "Repent", "Pray"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4226,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:26",
    "question": "Alma2 said the secret abominations of the Jaredites had been brought out of_____ and made known unto them.",
    "answer": "Darkness",
    "options": ["Their Closets", "Obscurity", "Darkness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4227,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:27",
    "question": "Alma2 commanded Helaman to retain all the oaths, covenants, and agreements and all the signs and the wonders of the Jaredites from the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4228,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:27",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that if the Nephites were to get a hold of the secret oaths and covenants of the Jaredites they would fall into darkness also and be_____.",
    "answer": "Destroyed",
    "options": ["Destroyed", "Rewarded", "Resurrected"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4229,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:28",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that there was not a curse upon the land; that destruction would not come upon all those workers of darkness.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4230,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:28",
    "question": "Alma2 said when the workers of darkness were fully_____, they would be destroyed by the power of God.",
    "answer": "Ripe"
  },
  {
    "id": 4231,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:28",
    "question": "Alma2 desired that the Nephites would not be destroyed by the power of the Lord.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4232,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:29",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to keep the secrets plans of their oaths and their covenants of the Jaredites from the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4233,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:29",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to only let the Nephites know of the wickedness and murders and the_____ of the Jaredites.",
    "answer": "Abominations"
  },
  {
    "id": 4234,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:29",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to teach the Nephites to abhor such wickedness and murders and abominations of the Jaredites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4235,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:29",
    "question": "Helaman was to teach the_____ that the Jaredites were destroyed on account of their wickedness and abominations and their murders.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4236,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:30",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Jaredites had murdered all the_____ of the Lord who came among them to declare unto them concerning their iniquities.",
    "answer": "Prophets"
  },
  {
    "id": 4237,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:30",
    "question": "Alma2 never mentions that the blood of the prophets who had been murdered by the Jaredites; did not cry unto the Lord their God for vengeance.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4238,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:30",
    "question": "Alma2 said the judgments of_____ did come upon those workers of darkness and secret combinations.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 4239,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:31",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman the land was cursed forever and ever unto those workers of darkness and secret_____, even unto destruction, except they repent before they are fully ripe.",
    "answer": "Combinations"
  },
  {
    "id": 4240,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:31,21-23,29",
    "question": "Alma2 never uses the word Jaredites to Helaman to refer to the people who have been destroyed because of their works of darkness and secret combinations to.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4241,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:32",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted Helaman to remember the words which he had spoken unto him; and not trust the secret plans unto the_____.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4242,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:32",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to teach the Nephites an everlasting hatred against sin and_____.",
    "answer": "Iniquity",
    "options": ["Cleanliness", "Murders", "Iniquity"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4243,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:33",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to preach unto the Nephites repentance, and faith on the Lord Jesus_____.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 4244,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:33",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to teach the Nephites to_____ themselves and to be meek and lowly in heart.",
    "answer": "Humble"
  },
  {
    "id": 4245,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:33",
    "question": "Helaman was to teach the Nephites to withstand every temptation of the_____, with their faith on the Lord Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },
  {
    "id": 4246,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:34",
    "question": "Alma2 told_____ to teach the Nephites to never be weary of good works, but to be meek and lowly in heart; for such shall find rest in their souls.",
    "answer": "Helaman"
  },
  {
    "id": 4247,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:35",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to remember to learn_____ in his youth and to learn to keep the commandments of God in his youth.",
    "answer": "Wisdom",
    "options": ["Knowledge", "Wisdom", "Everything"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4248,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:36",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to cry unto_____ for all of his support; and to let all his doings be unto the Lord.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 4249,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:36",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to let his thoughts be directed unto the Lord; and to let his_____ of his heart be placed upon the Lord forever.",
    "answer": "Afflictions",
    "options": ["Afflictions", "Sorrows", "Pains"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4250,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:37",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to_____ with the Lord in all his doings and he would direct him in all things which are good.",
    "answer": "Counsel",
    "options": ["Wrestle", "Counsel", "Pray"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4251,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:37",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to counsel with the Lord when he lies down in the_____ to lie down unto the Lord; that he may watch over him in his sleep.",
    "answer": "Night",
    "options": ["Couch", "Day", "Night"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4252,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:37",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to let his_____ be full of thanks unto God every time he wakes up in the morning.",
    "answer": "Heart",
    "options": ["Belly", "Chest", "Heart"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4253,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:37",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that if he always gave thanks unto the Lord and did the right things he would not be lifted at the last day.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4254,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:38",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that their fathers called a ball or director a_____, which is, being interpreted, a compass.",
    "answer": "Liahona"
  },
  {
    "id": 4255,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:38",
    "question": "How many times does the word “Liahona” appear in the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "3",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4256,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:38",
    "question": "The word “Liahona” only appears in what book of the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 4257,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:38",
    "question": "According to Alma2, who did he say made or prepared the compass?",
    "answer": ["lord", "god"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4258,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:39",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that know man can work and make such a thing as the Liahona of so curious_____.",
    "answer": "Workmanship",
    "options": ["Engravings", "Workmanship", "Metal"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4259,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:39",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that the Liahona was prepared to show unto their fathers the course which they should travel in the_____.",
    "answer": "Wilderness"
  },
  {
    "id": 4260,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:40",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Liahona worked for their fathers according to their_____ in God.",
    "answer": "Faith"
  },
  {
    "id": 4261,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:40",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman the faith their fathers had in God would caused the_____ to point the way they should travel in the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Spindles",
    "options": ["Spindles", "Arrows", "Missiles"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4262,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:40",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman their fathers had the miracle of the Liahona and many other_____ wrought by the power of God, day by day.",
    "answer": "Miracles"
  },
  {
    "id": 4263,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:41",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman because the miracles were worked by_____ means it did show unto their fathers marvelous works.",
    "answer": "Small",
    "options": ["Large", "Small", "Huge"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4264,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:41",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman their fathers were slothful, and forgot to exercise their_____ and diligence and then those marvelous works ceased.",
    "answer": "Faith"
  },
  {
    "id": 4265,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:41",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman because of the slothfulness of their fathers, and because they did not exercise their faith in the Lord; their fathers did not progress in their_____.",
    "answer": "Journey",
    "options": ["Journey", "Way", "Direction"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4266,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:42",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that their fathers tarried in the wilderness, or did not travel a direct course.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4267,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:42",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman their fathers were afflicted with hunger and thirst, because of their_____.",
    "answer": "Transgressions",
    "options": ["Wrong Doings", "Transgressions", "Wickedness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4268,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:43",
    "question": "Alma2 said that his fathers were slothful to give heed to the_____ and that is why they did not prosper and was an example of things which were temporal.",
    "answer": "Compass",
    "options": ["Lord", "Gospel", "Compass"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4269,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:43",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman their fathers did not prosper in temporal and_____ things because they did not give heed to the compass which was prepare by the Lord.",
    "answer": "Spiritual"
  },
  {
    "id": 4270,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:44",
    "question": "Alma2 said it is easy to give heed to the word of Christ, which will point to you a straight course to eternal bliss.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4271,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:44",
    "question": "Alma2 said it is not easy to give heed to the word of Jesus Christ because the Liahona will not always point to a straight course to eternal bliss.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4272,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:45",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the director/Liahona is a type of thing or an example of following Jesus_____.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 4273,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:45",
    "question": "Alma2 said if we follow Jesus Christ he will carry us beyond the vale of sorrow into a far better land or course of promise.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4274,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:46",
    "question": "Alma2 cautioned Helaman to not be slothful because of the easiness of the way like it was for their fathers; that if they would look they might live.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4275,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:46",
    "question": "Alma2 told_____ the way is prepared by the Lord, even so it is with us; and if we will look we may live forever.",
    "answer": "Helaman"
  },
  {
    "id": 4276,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:47",
    "question": "And told Helaman to take care of the sacred things he had been entrusted with and to see that he looks to God and live.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4277,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:47",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to go and declare the word of the Lord unto his people and to be_____.",
    "answer": "Sober",
    "options": ["Gentle", "Thoughtful", "Sober"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4278,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:47",
    "question": "Which one of his three sons did Alma2 command to go and declare the word of the Lord unto the Nephites?",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["Helaman", "Shiblon", "Corianton"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4279,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma38:15",
    "question": "Which one of his three sons did Alma2 command to go and teach the word of the Lord unto the Nephites?",
    "answer": "Shiblon",
    "options": ["Helaman", "Shiblon", "Corianton"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4280,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma42:31",
    "question": "Which one of his three sons did Alma2 command to go and preach the word of the Lord unto the Nephites?",
    "answer": "Corianton",
    "options": ["Helaman", "Shiblon", "Corianton"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4281,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "37:1",
    "question": "What is the name of Alma2 the Youngers’ second son?  Shiblon-Alma38:",
    "answer": "1,"
  },
  {
    "id": 4282,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma39:1",
    "question": "What is the name of Alma2 the Youngers’ youngest son? ",
    "answer": "Corianton"
  },
  {
    "id": 4283,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma38:1",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon that inasmuch as he would keep the commandments of God he would prosper in the land.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4284,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma38:1",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon if he would not keep the commandments of God he would be cast off from his presence.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4285,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma38:2",
    "question": "Alma2 had great joy in_____ because of the steadiness and faithfulness he had in God.",
    "answer": "Shiblon",
    "options": ["Helaman", "Shiblon", "Corianton"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4286,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:2",
    "question": "Alma2 said_____ had commenced in his youth to look to the Lord their God.",
    "answer": "Shiblon"
  },
  {
    "id": 4287,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:2",
    "question": "Alma2 hope Shiblon would continue in keeping the commandments of the Lord; and said blessed is he that endureth to the_____.",
    "answer": "End"
  },
  {
    "id": 4288,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:3",
    "question": "Alma2 had great joy in Shiblon because of his faithfulness, diligence, patience, and long-_____ among the people of the Zoramites.",
    "answer": "Suffering"
  },
  {
    "id": 4289,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma38:4",
    "question": "Alma2 said he knew Shiblon had been bonded by the_____.",
    "answer": "Zoramites",
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Zoramites", "Amulekites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4290,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:4",
    "question": "Which one of Alma2’s son was stoned by the Zoramites because he preached the word of the Lord to them?",
    "answer": "Sbilon"
  },
  {
    "id": 4291,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:4",
    "question": "Alma2 said Shiblon was able to bear all his sufferings with patience because the_____ was with him.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 4292,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma38:4",
    "question": "Alma2 said he and Shiblon knew that the Lord had delivered him from the Zoramites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4293,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma38:5",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon to remember to keep his_____ in the Lord and he would deliver him out of his trials.",
    "answer": "Trust",
    "options": ["Prayers", "Trust", "Faith"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4294,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma38:5",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon to trust in the Lord and he would deliver him from his trials, troubles, and his_____.",
    "answer": "Afflictions",
    "options": ["Unworthiness", "Cleanliness", "Afflictions"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4295,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma38:5",
    "question": "Who did Alma2 say would be lifted up in the last day if he would keep his trust in the Lord?",
    "answer": "Shiblon",
    "options": ["Helaman", "Shiblon", "Corianton"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4296,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma38:6",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Spirit of God was the one that made all things known unto him and not his own wisdom.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4297,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:6",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon if he had not been born of_____ he would had not been able to know the things of God.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 4298,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:7",
    "question": "Who did Alma2 say had been sent by God to declare unto him to stop the work of destruction among his people?",
    "answer": "Angel"
  },
  {
    "id": 4299,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma38:7",
    "question": "Alma2 said he had seen an angel face to_____ and had spoken to him.",
    "answer": "Face",
    "options": ["Head", "Face", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4300,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma38:7",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon that the voice of the angel that had spoken to him was like_____, and it shook the whole earth.",
    "answer": "Thunder",
    "options": ["Fire", "Thunder", "A Ghetto Blaster"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4301,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma38:37",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon that the angel that had spoken to him face to face was a female.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4302,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:8",
    "question": "Alma2 said that he did not receive a remission of his_____ until he cried out unto the Lord Jesus Christ for mercy.",
    "answer": "Sins"
  },
  {
    "id": 4303,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma38:8",
    "question": "Alma2 cried unto the Lord for a remission of his sins and did find peace unto his_____.",
    "answer": "Soul",
    "options": ["Soul", "Mind", "Body"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4304,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma38:9",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon of his experience with the angel so that he would learn wisdom.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4305,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma38:9",
    "question": "Alma2 said that there is no other way or_____ whereby man can be saved, only in and through Christ.",
    "answer": "Means",
    "options": ["Direction", "Means", "Path"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4306,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:9",
    "question": "Alma2 said that Jesus Christ is the_____ and the light of the world.",
    "answer": "Life"
  },
  {
    "id": 4307,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma38:9",
    "question": "Alma2 said that Jesus Christ is the word of truth and righteousness.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4308,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:10",
    "question": "Alma2 told_____ even as he had begun to teach the word of the Lord; that he should continue to do so.",
    "answer": "Shiblon"
  },
  {
    "id": 4309,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:10",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon to be_____ and temperate in all things.",
    "answer": "Diligent"
  },
  {
    "id": 4310,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:11",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon not to be lifted up unto pride and to not_____ in his own wisdom, nor of his own strength.",
    "answer": "Boast"
  },
  {
    "id": 4311,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:12",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon to use_____, but not overbearance; and to also bridle all his passions and be filled with love.",
    "answer": "Boldness"
  },
  {
    "id": 4312,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma38:12",
    "question": "Alma2 did not tell Shiblon to see that he refrain from idleness.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4313,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:13",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon not to pray like what group of people that wanted to be seen and heard of men?",
    "answer": "Zoramites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4314,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma38:13",
    "question": "The Zoramites prayed to be heard of men and to be praised for their_____.",
    "answer": "Wisdom",
    "options": ["Looks", "Apparel", "Wisdom"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4315,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma38:14",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon that the Zoramites would pray and say:  O God, I thank thee that we are_____ than our brethren.",
    "answer": "Better",
    "options": ["Taller", "Better", "Worst"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4316,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:14",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon to pray and ask for his forgiveness in his _____, and to remember his brethren in mercy.",
    "answer": "Unworthiness"
  },
  {
    "id": 4317,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma38:14",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon that he did not have to acknowledge his unworthiness before God at all times.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4318,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma38:15",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon that may the Lord bless his_____, and receive him at the last day into his kingdom, to sit in peace.",
    "answer": "Soul",
    "options": ["Body", "Soul", "Heart"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4319,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma38:15",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon to go and teach the word of the Lord unto the Nephites and to be sober.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4320,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:10",
    "question": "Corianton was around his mid twenties when Alma2 gave him his charge.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4321,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma39:1",
    "question": "Alma2 told_____ that he had more to say to him that he did to Shiblon.",
    "answer": "Corianton"
  },
  {
    "id": 4322,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:1",
    "question": "Alma2 gave more counsel to Coriantion than any other of his sons.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4323,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:1",
    "question": "Alma2 said Corianton did not observe the steadiness, faithfulness and diligence in keeping the commandments of God like his brother Shiblon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4324,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:1",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that Shiblon did not set a good example for him; in keeping the commandments of the Lord.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4325,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma39:2",
    "question": "Alma2 said Corianton did not give so much heed unto his_____ as did his brother Shiblon, among the Zoramites.",
    "options": ["Apparel", "Looks"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4326,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma39:2",
    "question": "Who did Alma2 say went about boasting in his own strength and wisdom?",
    "answer": "Corianton"
  },
  {
    "id": 4327,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:3",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that it was grievous to him because he forsaken the ministry of the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4328,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma39:3",
    "question": "What was the name of the harlot that Corianton went after among the borders of the Lamanites?",
    "answer": "Isabel"
  },
  {
    "id": 4329,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma39:3",
    "question": "The harlot Isabel was from the land of_____.",
    "answer": "Siron",
    "options": ["Waters Of Mormon", "Many Waters", "Siron"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4330,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma39:4",
    "question": "Alma2 told_____ that Isabel had stolen away the hearts of many men; but that it was not an excuse for him to go after her.",
    "answer": "Corianton"
  },
  {
    "id": 4331,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:4",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that he should have tended to the ministry wherewith he was entrusted to.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4332,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:5, 9,11",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton the things or the lust of his eyes was an abomination in the sight of the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4333,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:5",
    "question": "According to Alma2; the lust of our eyes, is above all sins except of the shedding of innocent blood and denying the Holy Ghost.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4334,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma39:6",
    "question": "Alma2 said if we deny the_____ Ghost once it has had a place in us, and we know that we deny it, it is a sin which is unpardonable.",
    "answer": "Holy"
  },
  {
    "id": 4335,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma39:6",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that whosoever murders against the light and_____ of God, it is not easy for him to obtain forgiveness.",
    "answer": "Knowledge",
    "options": ["Knowledge", "Wisdom", "Truth"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4336,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:7",
    "question": "Alma2 did not tell Corianton that he wished that he would not be guilty of such a crime as denying the Holy Ghost.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4337,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma39:7",
    "question": "Alma2 told_____ that he did not wish to dwell upon his crimes, to harrow up his soul, if it were not for his own good.",
    "answer": "Corianton"
  },
  {
    "id": 4338,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:8",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that he could hide his crimes from God if he was very cleaver and sneaky.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4339,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma39:8",
    "question": "Alma2 said that if we do not repent, our sins will stand against us as a_____ against us at the last day.",
    "answer": "Testimony"
  },
  {
    "id": 4340,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma39:9",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton to repent and forsake his sins, and not to go anymore after the_____ of his eyes.",
    "answer": "Lusts",
    "options": ["Pleasure", "Eye Candy", "Lusts"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4341,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma39:9",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton to cross himself in all things; and if he did not, he could not inherit the_____ of God. ",
    "answer": "Kingdom"
  },
  {
    "id": 4342,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:10",
    "question": "Alma2 did not command Corianton to take it upon himself to counsel with his older brothers in his undertakings.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4343,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:10",
    "question": "Because he was in his youth; Alma2 told Corianton that he stood in need of nourishing from his elder brothers.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4344,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:10",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that he did not have to always give heed to the counsel of his older brothers.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4345,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma39:11",
    "question": "Alma2 counseled Corianton against being led away by any vain and _____ things.",
    "answer": "Foolish",
    "options": ["Precious", "Foolish", "Pretty"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4346,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma39:11",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton to not let his heart be led away by the_____ again after those wicked harlots.",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },
  {
    "id": 4347,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma39:11",
    "question": "Alma2 said Corianton had brought great iniquity among the_____ because when they saw his conduct they would not believe in his words.",
    "answer": "Zoramites",
    "options": ["Zoramites", "Lamanites", "Amulekites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4348,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:12",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton the Spirit of the Lord had commanded him to tell his children to do good because they could lead away the hearts of many people unto destruction.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4349,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:12",
    "question": "Alma2 commanded Corianton in the fear of the Lord that he should not refrain from his iniquities.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4350,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma39:13",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that he should turn to the Lord with all his mind, might, and _____.",
    "answer": "Strength"
  },
  {
    "id": 4351,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:13",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton to turn to the Lord and use his mind, might, and strength; and not lead away the hearts of anymore of the people unto iniquity.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4352,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma39:13",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton to acknowledge his_____ and the wrong which he had done unto the people.",
    "answer": "Faults",
    "options": ["Strength", "Wisdom And", "Faults"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4353,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma39:12",
    "question": "Alma2 commanded Corianton not to seek after riches and the_____ things of the world.",
    "answer": "Vain",
    "options": ["Pretty", "Vain", "Better"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4354,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:14",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that the riches and vain things of this world could not be carried away with him when he died.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4355,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma39:15",
    "question": "Alma2 spoke to Corianton about the coming of Christ; and that he would surely come to declare_____ tidings of salvation unto his people.",
    "answer": "Glad",
    "options": ["Glad", "Sad", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4356,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:16",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that he was called to the ministry to declare glad tidings among his people and to prepare their minds for salvation.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4357,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:16",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton he was called to the ministry to prepare the minds of the people to prepare their children to hear the gospel at the time of Jesus Christ’s coming.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4358,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:17",
    "question": "According to Alma2; Corianton felt comfortable or at ease about the things pertaining to the coming of Christ.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4359,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma39:17",
    "question": "Corianton wondered why the things pertaining to the coming of Jesus _____were being known unto him so long before his actual coming.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 4360,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:17",
    "question": "Corianton did not wonder why the things pertaining to the coming of Jesus Christ were being made known unto him so long before his actual coming.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4361,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma39:18",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton a_____ at this time is as precious unto God as a soul will be at the time of his coming.",
    "answer": "Soul",
    "options": ["Person", "Body", "Soul"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4362,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma39:18",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that it was necessary that the plan of_____ should be made known unto this people as well as unto their children.",
    "answer": "Redemption",
    "options": ["God", "Redemption", "The Resurrection"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4363,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma39:19",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that it was just as easy for the Lord to send his_____ to declare glad tidings now as is was for him or after the time of his coming.",
    "answer": "Angel"
  },
  {
    "id": 4364,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:1",
    "question": "Alma2 did not know that Corianton was worried concerning the resurrection of the dead.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4365,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:1",
    "question": "Alma2 perceived that Corianton was worried concerning the resurrection of the_____.",
    "answer": "Dead"
  },
  {
    "id": 4366,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:2",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that the mortal body does not put on immortality until after the coming of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4367,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:2",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that the mortal body does not put on corruption and_____ until the coming of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "Incorruption"
  },
  {
    "id": 4368,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:3",
    "question": "Alma2 said Jesus Christ brings to pass the_____ of the dead.",
    "answer": "Resurrection"
  },
  {
    "id": 4369,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:3",
    "question": "Alma2 said there are many mysteries which are kept from man and that no one knows them except God and his holy prophets.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4370,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:3",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that he had inquired diligently of the Lord that he may know concerning the resurrection of the dead.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4371,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma40:4",
    "question": "Alma2 said there is a time appointed that all shall come_____ from the dead.",
    "answer": "Forth",
    "options": ["Before", "Forth", "Among"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4372,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:4",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the time which is appointed that all shall come forth from the dead is known only to God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4373,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:5",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton it does not matter that all shall come forth at one time, or a second time or a_____ time from the dead.",
    "answer": "Third"
  },
  {
    "id": 4374,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:5",
    "question": "Alma2 said he knew that there is a time appointed that all shall rise from the_____.",
    "answer": "Dead"
  },
  {
    "id": 4375,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:6",
    "question": "Alma2 said there must be a space between the time of _____and the time of the resurrection.",
    "answer": "Death"
  },
  {
    "id": 4376,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:7",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that he had inquired of the Lord concerning what became of the_____ of men from the time of death until the time appointed for the resurrection.",
    "answer": "Souls"
  },
  {
    "id": 4377,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:8",
    "question": "Alma2 said it does not matter if there was more than one time appointed for men to rise from the dead; because all men to not die at once.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4378,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:8",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that all is one day with God, and _____ is only measured unto men.",
    "answer": "Time"
  },
  {
    "id": 4379,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:10",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton the he knew the time will come when all shall rise from the dead, and then shall they know that God knows all the times that are appointed unto man",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4380,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:11",
    "question": "Alma2 said an angel of the Lord had told him concerning the state of the_____of man between death and the resurrection.",
    "answer": "Soul"
  },
  {
    "id": 4381,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma40:11",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the spirits of all_____, as soon as they departed from this mortal body, are taken home to that God who gave them life.",
    "answer": "Men",
    "options": ["Persons", "Men", "Individuals"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4382,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:11",
    "question": "Alma2 said that only the spirits of the good are taken home to that God that gave them life.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4383,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:12",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that it shall come to pass, that the spirits of those who are_____ are received into a state of happiness.",
    "answer": "Righteous"
  },
  {
    "id": 4384,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:12",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that the state of happiness is called paradise.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4385,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:12",
    "question": "According to Alma2 paradise is a state of_____, a state of peace, where the righteous shall rest from all their troubles and from all care, and sorrow.",
    "answer": "Rest"
  },
  {
    "id": 4386,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:12",
    "question": "According to Alma2 paradise is a state of rest, a state of_____, where the righteous can rest from all their troubles and from all care, and sorrow.",
    "answer": "Peace"
  },
  {
    "id": 4387,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:13",
    "question": "And it shall come to pass that the spirits of the wicked or the evil shall be cast into outer_____.",
    "answer": "Darkness"
  },
  {
    "id": 4388,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:13",
    "question": "The spirits of the wicked and evil chose to have no part or portion of the Spirit of the_____.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 4389,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:13",
    "question": "The spirits of the wicked and evil chose evil works rather than good; therefore the spirit of the_____ did enter them, and take possession of their house.",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },
  {
    "id": 4390,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:13",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the spirits in outer darkness shall be weeping, and wailing, and_____of their teeth, because of their own iniquity.",
    "answer": "Gnashing"
  },
  {
    "id": 4391,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:13",
    "question": "Alma2 said the spirits of the wicked and evil will be led captive by the will of the Grim Reaper.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4392,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:14",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton the state of the wicked in outer darkness is awful; and are looking fearful for the fiery indignation of the wrath of God upon them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4393,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:14",
    "question": "Alma2 said the spirits of the wicked and evil remain in outer darkness and as well as the righteous in paradise, until the time of their resurrection.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4394,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:15",
    "question": "Alma2 said there are some people that have understood that the state of happiness and the state of misery of the soul; was a first resurrection.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4395,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:15",
    "question": "Alma2 did not admit to Corianton that the raising of the spirit of the soul and their consignation to happiness or misery; may be termed a resurrection.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4396,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:16",
    "question": "According to Alma2 the resurrection of all those who have been, or who are, or who shall be, down to the resurrection of Jesus Christ from the dead is called the first resurrection.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4397,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:16",
    "question": "Alma2 said that only those souls who have been born and have died before the coming of Jesus Christ are entitled to the first resurrection.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4398,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:17",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton not to suppose the first resurrection does not mean that the consignation to happiness or misery does not mean what he had spoken of.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4399,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma40:18",
    "question": "According to Alma2 the first resurrection means the reuniting of the soul with the body, of those from the days of_____ down to the resurrection of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "Adam",
    "options": ["Abraham", "Adam", "Noah"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4400,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:19",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton whether the souls and the bodies of those of whom he had spoken shall all be reunited at once, the wicked as well as the righteous, he did not say.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4401,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:29",
    "question": "Alma2 said all will come forth; and it was enough for him to know that the resurrection comes to pass before the resurrection of those who die after the resurrection of Jesus Christ",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4402,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma40:20",
    "question": "Alma2 said it was his_____, that the souls and the bodies are reunited, of the righteous, at the resurrection of Jesus Christ, and his ascension into heaven.",
    "answer": "Opinion",
    "options": ["Opinion", "Understanding", "Thoughts"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4403,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:21",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton there is a space between death and the resurrection of the body, and a state of the soul in happiness or in_____.",
    "answer": "Misery"
  },
  {
    "id": 4404,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:21",
    "question": "Alma2 said there is a time appointed by God that the dead shall come forth, and be reunited, both_____ and body, and be brought to stand before God, and be judged according to their works.",
    "answer": "Soul"
  },
  {
    "id": 4405,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:21",
    "question": "Alma2 said only the unrighteous dead that died during the time before Jesus Christ ascension into heaven; will be brought to stand before God and be judged according to their works.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4406,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:22",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton the resurrection of Jesus Christ brings about the restoration of those things of which has been spoken by the mouths of the_____.",
    "answer": "Prophets"
  },
  {
    "id": 4407,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:23",
    "question": "According to Alma2 every soul shall be restored to the body, and the body to the soul; and every limb and_____.",
    "answer": "Joint"
  },
  {
    "id": 4408,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:23",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton every soul shall be restored to the body; and that not even a _____ of the head shall not be lost; but all things shall be restored to their proper and perfect frame.",
    "answer": "Hair"
  },
  {
    "id": 4409,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:24,25",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton after the restoration the_____will shine forth in the kingdom of God; according to the things which has been spoken by the prophets of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Righteous"
  },
  {
    "id": 4410,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma40:26",
    "question": "Alma2 said an awful death will come upon the wicked; for they die as to things pertaining to things of_____.",
    "answer": "Righteousness",
    "options": ["The Good", "Righteousness", "Cleanliness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4411,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:26",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that no_____ thing can inherit the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": "Unclean"
  },
  {
    "id": 4412,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:26",
    "question": "Alma2 said unclean things and the wicked are cast out of the kingdom of God, and consigned to partake of the fruits of their_____or their works.",
    "answer": "Labors"
  },
  {
    "id": 4413,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma40:26",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that the wicked are cast out of the kingdom of God and they drink the dregs of a_____cup.",
    "answer": "Bitter",
    "options": ["Bad", "Large", "Bitter"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4414,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma41:1",
    "question": "Alma2 said he had more to say about the restoration because some people had wrested (twisted) the scriptures, and have gone astray because of this thing.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4415,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma41:1",
    "question": "Alma2 knew_____was worried and concerned about the restoration of things which had been spoken by the mouths to the prophets of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Corianton"
  },
  {
    "id": 4416,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma41:2",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that the plan of the_____is requisite with the justice of God.",
    "answer": "Restoration"
  },
  {
    "id": 4417,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma41:2",
    "question": "Alma2 said it is requisite that all things should be restored to their proper order and it was also requisite and just; according to the power and resurrection of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4418,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma41:2",
    "question": "According to the power and resurrection of Jesus Christ; the soul of man should be restored to its body, and that every part of the_____should be restored to itself.",
    "answer": "Body"
  },
  {
    "id": 4419,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma41:3",
    "question": "Alma2 said it is requisite with the_____of God that men should be judged according to their works.",
    "answer": "Justice",
    "options": ["Laws", "Justice", "Meaning"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4420,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma41:3",
    "question": "Alma2 said if your works were good in this life, and the desires of your hearts were good, then you should also, at the last day, be restored unto that which is good.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4421,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma41:4",
    "question": "Alma2 said if your works were evil in this life, then evil will be restored unto you.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4422,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma41:4",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton all things shall be restored to their proper order, every thing to its natural frame-mortality raised to immortality, corruption to_____.",
    "answer": "Incorruption"
  },
  {
    "id": 4423,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma41:4",
    "question": "Alma2 said all of us will be raised to endless happiness to inherit the kingdom of God, or to_____misery to inherit the kingdom of the devil, the one on one hand, the other on the other. ",
    "answer": "Endless"
  },
  {
    "id": 4424,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma41:14",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that all of us will be raised to endless happiness to inherit the kingdom of God, or to endless misery to inherit the kingdom of the_____.",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },
  {
    "id": 4425,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma41:5",
    "question": "Alma2 said if we desired to do evil all day long, even so shall we have evil rewarded unto us when the night comes.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4426,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma41:6",
    "question": "According to Alma2; if we have repented of our sins, and desired righteousness until the end of our days, even so shall we be rewarded unto_____.",
    "answer": "Righteousness"
  },
  {
    "id": 4427,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma41:7",
    "question": "If we are righteous until the end of our days; we are redeemed of the Lord and are taken out, and we are delivered out from the endless night of_____.",
    "answer": "Darkness",
    "options": ["Darkness", "Misery", "Woes"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4428,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma41:7",
    "question": "Alma2 said we either stand or fall; for behold, we are our own judges, whether to do good or to do_____.",
    "answer": "Evil"
  },
  {
    "id": 4429,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma41:8",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the decrees of God are alterable for our own good.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4430,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma41:8",
    "question": "Alma2 said the decrees of God are unalterable; therefore, the way is prepared that whosoever will; may_____therein and be saved.",
    "answer": "Walk",
    "options": ["Walk", "Run", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4431,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma41:9",
    "question": "Alma2 told_____not to risk more offenses against God upon the points of doctrine, which had caused him to commit sin. ",
    "answer": "Coriantion"
  },
  {
    "id": 4432,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma41:10",
    "question": "Alma told Corianton not to suppose he would be restored from sin to happiness because of the things which he had spoken to him concerning the restoration.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4433,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma41:10",
    "question": "What person did Alma2 say “wickedness never was happiness” to?",
    "answer": "Corianton",
    "options": ["Helaman", "Shiblon", "Corianton"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4434,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma41:11",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that all men are in a state of nature or carnal state, and are in the gall of bitterness and in the bonds of iniquity without God in the world.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4435,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma41:11",
    "question": "If we are of a carnal state and in the bonds of iniquity, we are without God in the world; therefore, we are in a state contrary to the nature of happiness.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4436,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma41:13",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton the meaning of the word restoration is to bring back again evil for_____, carnal for carnal, or devilish for devilish.",
    "answer": "Evil"
  },
  {
    "id": 4437,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma41:13",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton the meaning of the word restoration is to bring back good for that which is good; righteous for that which is unrighteous.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4438,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma41:14",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton to see that he was merciful unto his brethren; to deal justly, judged righteously, and do good_____.",
    "answer": "Continually",
    "options": ["Always", "Once In Awhile", "Continually"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4439,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma41:15",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton the things which he did send out shall return unto him again, and be_____.",
    "answer": "Restored",
    "options": ["Restored", "Given Back", "Taken Away"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4440,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma41:15",
    "question": "Alma2 said the word_____more fully condem’s the sinner, and justifies him not at all.",
    "answer": "Restoration",
    "options": ["Damnation", "Restoration", "Wickedness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4441,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:1",
    "question": "Alma2 knew Corianton was worried because of the things which he could not understand-which is concerning the justice of God in the punishment of the sinner.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4442,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:1",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton he knew he supposed that it is an injustice that the sinner should be consigned to a state of misery.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4443,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:2",
    "question": "Alma2 did not relate to Corianton the story of Adam and Eve our first parents.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4444,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:2",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton the Lord God sent out our first parents forth from the garden of_____, to till the ground, from where they were taken.",
    "answer": "Eden"
  },
  {
    "id": 4445,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:2",
    "question": "Alma2 said God drew out the man, and he placed at the west end of the Garden of Eden, and placed a thing which was called Cherubim.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4446,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:2",
    "question": "Alma2 said God drew out the man, and he placed at the east end of the Garden of Eden, _____, and a flaming sword which turned every way, to keep Adam away from the Tree of Life.",
    "answer": "Cherubim"
  },
  {
    "id": 4447,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:3",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that the man had become as God, knowing good and_____; because he had partaken of the fruit.",
    "answer": "Evil"
  },
  {
    "id": 4448,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:3",
    "question": "Alma2 said if the man had partaken of the_____of Life, he would have lived forever.",
    "answer": "Tree"
  },
  {
    "id": 4449,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:2-3",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton the purpose God had placed Cherubim and a flaming sword in front of the Tree of Life was to keep Adam from partaking of it.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4450,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:3",
    "question": "Alma2 said if Adam would have partaken of the Tree of Life, he would have lived forever.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4451,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:4",
    "question": "There was a time granted unto man to repent, a______time, a time to repent and serve God.",
    "answer": "Probationary"
  },
  {
    "id": 4452,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma42:5",
    "question": "If_____ would have put forth his hand immediately, and partaken of the tree of life, he would have lived forever, according to the word of God.",
    "answer": "Mike",
    "options": ["Mike", "John"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4453,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:5",
    "question": "If Adam would have partaken of the Tree of Life, he would have lived forever, having no space for repentance, and the word of God would have been void.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4454,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:5",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton if Adam would have partaken of the Tree of Life, the word of God would have been void, and the great plan of_____would have been frustrated.",
    "answer": "Salvation"
  },
  {
    "id": 4455,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:6",
    "question": "Alma2 said there was appointed unto man to_____; therefore, as they were cut off from the Tree of Life they should be cut off from the face of the earth.",
    "answer": "Die"
  },
  {
    "id": 4456,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma42:6",
    "question": "Alma2 said man became lost forever, and they became a_____man.",
    "answer": "Fallen",
    "options": ["Sinful", "Fallen", "Wicked"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4457,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:7",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that our first parents were cut off both temporally and_____from the presence of the Lord; and they became subjects to follow after their own will.",
    "answer": "Spiritually"
  },
  {
    "id": 4458,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:8",
    "question": "It was not expedient that man should be reclaimed from this temporal death, for that would destroy the great plan of_____.",
    "answer": "Happiness"
  },
  {
    "id": 4459,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:9",
    "question": "The fall had brought upon all mankind a spiritual death as well as a_____death, and they were cut off from the presence of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Temporal"
  },
  {
    "id": 4460,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:9",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that it was not necessary that mankind should not be reclaimed from this spiritual death that he had been speaking about.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4461,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:10",
    "question": "Because we have become carnal, sensual, by nature; Alma2 said this probationary state that we are in is for us to prepare; or it is our preparatory state.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4462,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:11",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton to remember that if it was not for the plan of_____, as soon as we would die, our souls would be miserable, being cut off from the presence of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Redemption"
  },
  {
    "id": 4463,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:12",
    "question": "Alma2 said if it were not for the plan of redemption; there was no means to reclaim men from this fallen state, which man brought upon himself because of his own disobedience.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4464,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:13",
    "question": "According to the justice of God, the plan of redemption could not be brought about, only on conditions of repentance of men in this_____state.",
    "answer": "Probationary"
  },
  {
    "id": 4465,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:13",
    "question": "The words “probationary state” can also be used to describe this “preparatory state” that we are now living in.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4466,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:13",
    "question": "According to Alma2 if there was not a preparatory state the plan of redemption or the conditions thereof; mercy could not take effect except is should destroy the work of justice.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4467,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:13",
    "question": "The work of justice could not be destroyed; if so God would cease to be_____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 4468,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma42:14",
    "question": "Because all mankind were fallen, and they were in the grasp of justice; yea, the_____of God, it consigned mankind forever to be cut off from his presence.",
    "answer": "Justice",
    "options": ["Justice", "Conditions", "Hands"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4469,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:15",
    "question": "The plan of mercy could not be brought about except an_____should be made; therefore God himself has atoned for the sins of the world, to bring about the plan of mercy.",
    "answer": "Atonement"
  },
  {
    "id": 4470,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:15",
    "question": "Alma2 said God himself has brought about the plan of mercy, to appease the demands of justice; that God might be a perfect, just_____, and a merciful God also.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 4471,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:16",
    "question": "Repentance could not come unto men except there was a punishment, which also was eternal as the life of the soul should be.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4472,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma42:16",
    "question": "There is a punishment which also is eternal as the life of the soul should be, affixed opposite to the plan of_____, which was as eternal also as the life of the soul.",
    "answer": "Happiness",
    "options": ["Misery", "Happiness", "Hell"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4473,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:18",
    "question": "There is not a punishment affixed, and a just law given, which brought remorse of conscience unto man.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4474,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:20",
    "question": "If there was no law given against sin; men would not be afraid to_____.",
    "answer": "Sin"
  },
  {
    "id": 4475,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:21",
    "question": "If there was no law given unto men, if men sinned what could justice do, or mercy either, for they would have no claim upon the creature.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4476,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:22",
    "question": "There is a_____given, and a punishment affixed, and a repentance granted; which repentance mercy claims; otherwise, justice claims the creature and executes the law, and the law inflicts the punishment.",
    "answer": "Law"
  },
  {
    "id": 4477,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:22",
    "question": "If there was no law given or punishment for sin, the works of justice would be destroyed, and God would cease to be_____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 4478,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:23",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that God sometimes ceases to be God and is not fair and just.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4479,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:23",
    "question": "Mercy claims the penitent, and mercy comes because of the atonement; and the atonement brings to pass the resurrection of the_____.",
    "answer": "Dead"
  },
  {
    "id": 4480,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:23",
    "question": "Alma2 said the resurrection of the dead brings men back into the presence of_____; and thus they are restored into his presence, to be judged according to their works.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 4481,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:23",
    "question": "Alma2 said that men are judged according to their works, according to the law and not according to justice.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4482,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma42:24",
    "question": "Justice exercises all his demands, and also mercy claims all which is her own; and thus, none but the truly_____are saved.",
    "answer": "Penitent",
    "options": ["Penitent", "Sorry", "Forgiving"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4483,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:25",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton not to suppose mercy can rob justice, if that was the case, God would cease to be God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4484,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma42:26",
    "question": "God brings about his great and_____purposes, which were prepared from the foundation of the world.",
    "answer": "Eternal",
    "options": ["Beautiful", "Just", "Eternal"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4485,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:26",
    "question": "God brings about his great and eternal purposes, which were prepared from the_____of the world.",
    "answer": "Foundation"
  },
  {
    "id": 4486,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:26",
    "question": "Because of God’s great and eternal purposes; there comes the salvation and the redemption of men, and also their destruction and_____.",
    "answer": "Misery",
    "options": ["Fall", "Misery", "Damnation"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4487,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:27",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that anyone can come and partake of the waters of life freely.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4488,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:27",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that anyone and everyone should come and partake of the waters of life freely because God has made it a commandment.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4489,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma42:27",
    "question": "Alma2 said no one is compelled to come and partake of the waters of life freely; but in the last day it shall be restored unto him according to his_____.",
    "answer": "Deeds",
    "options": ["Wealth", "Deeds", "Fortune"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4490,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:28",
    "question": "If we desire to do evil, and have not repented in our days, behold, _____shall be done unto us, according to the restoration of God.",
    "answer": "Evil"
  },
  {
    "id": 4491,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:29,1",
    "question": "Alma2 desired Corianton to not be troubled by so many things in his mind, but to only let his sins trouble him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4492,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:29",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton to only be troubled by his sins, which shall bring him down to repentance.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4493,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:30",
    "question": "Alma2 desired_____not to deny the justice of God no more, and not endeavor to excuse himself in the least point because of his sins, by denying the justice of God.",
    "answer": "Corianton"
  },
  {
    "id": 4494,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma42:30",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton to let the justice of God and his mercy and his long-suffering; have a full sway in his_____; and let it bring him down to the dust in humility.",
    "answer": "Heart",
    "options": ["Belly", "Heart", "Bosom"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4495,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma42:31",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that he was called of God to_____the word unto the people.",
    "answer": "Preach",
    "options": ["Prophesy", "Preach", "Explain"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4496,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:31",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton to declare the word of God with truth and soberness, that he may bring souls unto repentance, that the great plan of mercy may have claim upon them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4497,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma42:31",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton may God grant unto him even according to his_____.",
    "answer": "Words",
    "options": ["Wishes", "Words", "Deeds"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4498,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:31",
    "question": "Out of his three sons, Alma2 counseled Corianton the most.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4499,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma21:31",
    "question": "Because_____ was the most wayward son of Alma2; he counseled him the most.",
    "answer": "Corianton"
  },
  {
    "id": 4500,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:1",
    "question": "Alma2 and his sons went forth among the people of Zarahemla to declare the word of God unto the people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4501,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:2",
    "question": "Alma2 and his sons preached the word of God, and the truth, according to the spirit of prophecy and_____.",
    "answer": "Revelation"
  },
  {
    "id": 4502,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:2",
    "question": "Alma2 and his sons preached the word of God after the_____order of God by which they were called.",
    "answer": "Holy",
    "options": ["Sacred", "Holy", "Chosen"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4503,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:4",
    "question": "And it came to pass that in the days that Alma2 and his sons preached the word of God unto the Zoramites, the Zoramites became_____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Amulekites", "Nephites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4504,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:4",
    "question": "In the eighteenth year of the reign of the_____, the Lamanites gathered together their armies in the land of Jershon to make war with the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Judges"
  },
  {
    "id": 4505,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:5",
    "question": "What was the name of the leader of the Lamanites who came into the land of the Zoramites to make war with the Nephites?",
    "answer": "Zerahemnah",
    "options": ["Moroni", "Zerahemnah", "Teancum"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4506,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:6",
    "question": "What tribe of people did Zerahemnah appoint as chief captains over the Lamanites because of their wicked and murderous disposition?",
    "answer": "Amalekites",
    "options": ["Amalekites", "Amulekites", "Ammonites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4507,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:7",
    "question": "Zerahemnah appointed Amalekites as chief captains of the Lamanites in order to preserve their hatred towards the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4508,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:7",
    "question": "Zerahemnah did not appoint Amalekites as chief captains so that he might bring them into subjection to the accomplishment of his designs.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4509,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:8",
    "question": "Zerahemnah purposes and designs were to stir up the_____to anger against the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Amulekites", "Ammonites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4510,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:8",
    "question": "Zerahemnah’s designs were to usurp great power over the Amulekites, and also that he might grain power over the_____by bringing them into bondage.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4511,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:9",
    "question": "The Nephites designs or purposes were to support their lands, houses, wives, and their_____.",
    "answer": "Children",
    "options": ["Barns", "Children", "Property"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4512,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:9",
    "question": "The Nephites wanted to preserve all the things they possessed from the hands of their_____.",
    "answer": "Enemies",
    "options": ["Enemies", "Opposing Forces", "Neighbors"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4513,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:9",
    "question": "The Nephites wanted to preserve their rights, privileges, and also their_____, that they might worship God according to their desires. ",
    "answer": "Liberty"
  },
  {
    "id": 4514,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:9",
    "question": "The Nephites did not want to preserve their rights, privileges, and also their liberty, that they might worship God according to their desires.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4515,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:10",
    "question": "The Nephites knew that if they should fall into the hands of the_____ and worship God in spirit and in truth, the Lamanites would destroy them.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4516,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:11",
    "question": "The Nephites did not know the extreme hatred of the Lamanites towards their brethren, who were the Anti-Nephi-Lehi’s",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4517,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:11",
    "question": "Another name for the people of_____; is the Anti-Nephi-Lehi’s.",
    "answer": "Ammon"
  },
  {
    "id": 4518,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:11,56:6",
    "question": "The Anti-Nephi-Lehi’s had entered into a covenant with the Lord that they would not shed the blood of their brethren; and they would not break it.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4519,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:11",
    "question": "If the people of Ammon should fall into the hands of the_____ they would be destroyed.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4520,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:12",
    "question": "The Nephites would not allow the Anti-Nephi-Lehi’s to be destroyed; therefore they gave them_____for their inheritance.",
    "answer": "Lands",
    "options": ["Precious Things", "Gold", "Lands"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4521,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:13",
    "question": "The people of_____did give the Nephites a large portion of their substance to support the armies of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Ammon"
  },
  {
    "id": 4522,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:13",
    "question": "Because the Anti-Nephi-Lehi’s would not take up arms against their brethren; the Nephites were compelled, alone, to withstand against the Lamanites by themselves.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4523,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:13",
    "question": "During the time of the eighteenth year of the reign of the judges, the Lamanites consisted of people who were descendants of Laman and Lemuel, and the sons of Ismael.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4524,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:13",
    "question": "The Lamanites also consisted from those who were dissented from the Nephites; who were Amalekites, Zoramites, and the descendants of the priests’ of_____.",
    "answer": "Noah"
  },
  {
    "id": 4525,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:14",
    "question": "The Lamanites and those descendants of people were as numerous, nearly, as were the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4526,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:14",
    "question": "The Nephites were not obligated to contend with their brethren, even unto bloodshed.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4527,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:15",
    "question": "And it came to pass the armies of the Lamanites gathered together in the land of Antionum, and the armies of the _____were prepared to go to battle and meet them in the land of Jershon.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4528,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:16",
    "question": "In what Book of Mormon book is Moroni; the chief captain of the Nephite armies first mentioned?",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 4529,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:16",
    "question": "The words “Captain Moroni” never appear in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4530,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:16",
    "question": "Moroni was the only chief captain of the Nephite armies.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4531,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:17",
    "question": "Moroni took command only of the Nephites armies and not of the government of their wars.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4532,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:17",
    "question": "Moroni was only_____years old when he took command of the armies of the Nephites and of their government of their wars.",
    "answer": "25",
    "options": ["25", "26", "27"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4533,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:17",
    "question": "Moroni was in his mid-thirties when he took command of the armies of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4534,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:18",
    "question": "Moroni and his people were armed with swords, and with cimeters, and all manner of_____of war.",
    "answer": "Weapons"
  },
  {
    "id": 4535,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:19",
    "question": "Moroni had prepared his people with breastplates and arm-shields, and also shields to defend their hands, and they were also dressed with thick clothing.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4536,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:20",
    "question": "The army of_____ was not prepared with any such things as was the armies of Moroni; they had only their swords, cimeters, their bows and their arrows.",
    "answer": "Zerahemnah"
  },
  {
    "id": 4537,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:20",
    "question": "The armies of Zerahemnah also had their stones and slings; and they were naked, save it were a skin which was girded about their loins.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4538,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:20",
    "question": "All the armies of Zerahemnah were naked except for the skins that were girded about their loins; but the Zoramites and the Amalekites were not.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4539,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:21",
    "question": "Because Zerahemnah’s armies were not armed with breastplates, neither with shields they were exceedingly afraid of the armies of the_____ because of their armor.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4540,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:21",
    "question": "Even though the armies of Zerahemnah were more numerous than the armies of the Nephites; they were exceedingly afraid because of how well Nephites were prepared for war.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4541,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:22",
    "question": "Zerahemnah and his armies came unto the land of Manti to try to take possession of it and supposed that_____and his armies would not know where they had gone.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4542,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:23",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni sent_____into the wilderness to watch the camp of the armies of Zerahemnah.",
    "answer": "Spies",
    "options": ["Women", "Spies", "Investigators"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4543,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:23",
    "question": "Because Moroni knew concerning the prophecies of_____; he sent certain men unto him to inquire of the Lord where they should go to defend themselves against the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 4544,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:24",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma2 informed the men of_____ where they should go to defend themselves and those messengers went and delivered the message unto him.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4545,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:2",
    "question": "Moroni caused that all the people in that quarter of the land of Manti should gather themselves together to do battle against the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4546,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:26",
    "question": "Moroni and the Nephites were prepared to defend their lands, country, rights, and their liberties against the time of the coming of the_____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4547,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:27",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni caused that his army should be secreted in the valley which was near the bank of the river_____.",
    "answer": "Sidon"
  },
  {
    "id": 4548,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:28",
    "question": "Moroni did not place spies about the land that he might know when the camp of the Lamanites should come upon them.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4549,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:29",
    "question": "Moroni was always oblivious to the intention of the Lamanites against his army and the Nephites.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4550,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:29",
    "question": "The_____wanted to destroy the Nephites, or to subject them and bring them into bondage that they might establish a kingdom unto themselves over all the land.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4551,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:30",
    "question": "Moroni knew that it was only the desire of the Nephites to preserve their lands, their liberty, and their church.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4552,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:30",
    "question": "In what Book of Mormon book is the word “Stratagem” first used?",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 4553,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:30",
    "question": "Moroni though it was no sin that he should defend the_____by stratagem; therefore, he found out by his spies which course the Lamanites were taking.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4554,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:30&Refer to Origin of the Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Alma2 is not the only person to use the word “Stratagem” in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4555,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:30",
    "question": "The word “Stratagem” is only used in what Book of Mormon book? ",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 4556,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "62:35",
    "question": "The word Stratagem is used how many times in the book of Alma?",
    "answer": "1",
    "options": ["1", "5", "7"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4557,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:31",
    "question": "The name of the hill in which Moroni concealed a part of his army to do battle with the Lamanites was called what?",
    "answer": "Riplah",
    "options": ["Cumorah", "Riplah", "Ramah"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4558,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:35",
    "question": "The army of the Nephites which was concealed on the south of the hill Riplah was led by a man whose name was Lehi.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4559,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:37",
    "question": "The work of death commenced on both sides of the armies, but it was more dreadful on the part of the_____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4560,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:37",
    "question": "Because of the Lamanites nakedness they were exposed to the heavy blows of the Nephites with their swords and their cimeters, which brought death almost at every_____.",
    "answer": "Stroke",
    "options": ["Blow", "Stroke", "Swing"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4561,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:38",
    "question": "Because of the way the Nephites were dressed they were shielded from the vital parts of their body from the strokes of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4562,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:39",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the_____became frightened, because of the great destruction among them; and they began to flee towards the river Sidon.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4563,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:43",
    "question": "Before their fight with the army of Moroni; the Lamanites had never been known to fight with such exceeding great strength and courage, not even from the beginning of their days.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4564,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:44",
    "question": "The armies of the Lamanites were inspired to fight with great strength and courage because their leaders and chief captains were_____and Amalekites.",
    "answer": "Zoramites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4565,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:44",
    "question": "The armies of the Lamanites were also inspired to fight with great strength and courage because of_____who was their chief captain and commander.",
    "answer": "Zerahemnah"
  },
  {
    "id": 4566,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:44",
    "question": "The Lamanites did fight like_____against the armies of Moroni.",
    "answer": "Dragons",
    "options": ["Animals", "Dogs", "Dragons"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4567,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:44",
    "question": "Many of the Nephites were slain by the hands of the Lamanites and their strokes did pierce many of their breastplates, and their arms.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4568,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:45",
    "question": "The Nephites were inspired by a better cause, for they were not fighting for a monarchy neither for power; but they were fighting for their homes and their liberties.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4569,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:45",
    "question": "The_____were also fighting for their wives and their children, and for their rites of worship and their church.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4570,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:46",
    "question": "The Nephites fought and were doing that which they felt was the duty which they owed to their_____.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["Countrymen", "Fathers", "God"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4571,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:46",
    "question": "The Lord had said unto the_____, that; “Inasmuch as you are not guilty of the first offense, neither the second, you shall not suffer yourselves to be slain by the hands of your enemies”.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4572,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:47",
    "question": "The Lord did not say unto the Nephites to defend their families even unto bloodshed.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4573,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:47",
    "question": "The Nephites contended with the_____, to defend themselves, and their families, and their religion.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4574,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:48",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when the men of_____saw the fierceness and the anger of the Lamanites, they were about to shrink and flee from them.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4575,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:48",
    "question": "Moroni perceived the thoughts of his men and sent forth and inspired them with these thoughts-the thoughts of their lands, their liberty, and their freedom from_____.",
    "answer": "Bondage",
    "options": ["Bondage", "Worship", "Work"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4576,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:49",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the men of Moroni turned upon the Lamanites, and they cried with several voices unto the Lord their God.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4577,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:49",
    "question": "The men of Captain Moroni cried with one voice unto the Lord their God for their liberty and their freedom from bondage.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4578,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:50",
    "question": "The men of Moroni began to stand against the Lamanites with power; and in that selfsame hour that they cried unto the Lord for their freedom, the_____ began to flee before them.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4579,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:51",
    "question": "During this time in the history of the Nephites; the Lamanites were more numerous, by more than double the number of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4580,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:53",
    "question": "When Zerahemnah saw that his armies were encircled by the armies of_____; he and his armies were struck with terror.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4581,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:54",
    "question": "When Moroni saw that_____and his armies were struck with terror; he commanded his men that they should stop shedding their blood.",
    "answer": "Zerahemnah"
  },
  {
    "id": 4582,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma44:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass Moroni said unto Zerahemnah that he and his armies did not desire to be men of_____, and you know that you are in our hands.",
    "answer": "Blood",
    "options": ["War", "Blood", "No Mercy"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4583,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma44:2",
    "question": "Moroni and his armies did not come to battle against the Lamanites that they might shed their blood for power neither did he desire to bring anyone to the yoke of bondage.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4584,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma44:2",
    "question": "Moroni told Zerahemnah he knew they were angry with the Nephites because of their_____.",
    "answer": "Religion",
    "options": ["Riches", "Skin Color", "Religion"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4585,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma44:3",
    "question": "Moroni told Zerahemnah that the Lord was with them; and had delivered the_____into their hands.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["Ammonites", "Lamanites", "Amulekites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4586,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma44:3",
    "question": "Moroni told Zerahemnah that the Lord had delivered them into their hands because of their religion and their faith in_____.",
    "answer": "Christ",
    "options": ["Christ", "Holy Ghost", "Nephi"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4587,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma44:3",
    "question": "Moroni told Zerahemnah to recognize that he and his armies could not destroy their faith in Christ.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4588,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma44:4",
    "question": "Moroni said because they had true faith in God; God will support, and keep, and preserve them, so long as they are faithful unto him, and unto their faith, and their religion.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4589,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma44:4",
    "question": "Moroni said the Lord will never suffer that they shall be destroyed except they should fall in transgression and deny their_____.",
    "answer": "Faith",
    "options": ["Idols", "Faith", "God"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4590,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "5,6",
    "question": "Moroni commanded_____ in the name of that all-powerful God, to deliver up their weapons of war.  Zerahemnah-",
    "answer": "Alma44:"
  },
  {
    "id": 4591,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma44:5",
    "question": "Moroni commanded Zerahemnah in the name of that all-powerful God, who had strengthened their arms that they could have gained power of him and his armies.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4592,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma44:5",
    "question": "Moroni told Zerahemnah that because they had maintained the sacred word of God, they owed all of their_____; and all that was most near and dear unto them.",
    "answer": "Happiness",
    "options": ["Trust", "Happiness", "Misery"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4593,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma44:6",
    "question": "Moroni commanded_____by all of his desires which he had for life that he would deliver up his weapons of war unto him and his armies.",
    "answer": "Zerahemnah"
  },
  {
    "id": 4594,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma44:6",
    "question": "Moroni told Zerahemnah if he would deliver up his arms unto him he would not seek his blood, but would spare his life and the life of his armies.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4595,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma44:8",
    "question": "Zerahemnah told_____he and his armies would deliver up their weapons of war unto him but would not suffer themselves to take an oath of not warring with them again.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4596,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma44:8",
    "question": "Zerahemnah told Moroni he and his armies would deliver up their weapons of war unto him but would not suffer themselves to take an oath of not warring with them again.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4597,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma44:8",
    "question": "The reason Zerahemnah told Moroni he and his armies would not take an oath of not coming to war with them again is because he knew he and his armies would break it.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4598,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma44:8",
    "question": "Zerahemnah told Moroni to take his and his armies weapons of war and to let them depart into the_____; otherwise they would retain their weapons and perish or conquer.",
    "answer": "Wilderness",
    "options": ["Forest", "Wilderness", "Waters Of Mormon"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4599,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma44:9",
    "question": "Zerahemnah told Moroni that even though they were of his faith, they believed that God had not delivered them up unto the hands of Moroni and his armies.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4600,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma44:19",
    "question": "Zerahemnah believed that is was the cunning of_____that had preserved them from their swords and also their breastplates.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4601,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma44:10",
    "question": "After Zerahemnah had finished speaking; Moroni returned unto him his weapons of war, which he had received, and said: “Behold, we will end the_____”.",
    "answer": "Conflict",
    "options": ["Fight", "Conflict", "Battle"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4602,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma44:11",
    "question": "Moroni told Zerahemnah that he would not let him leave unless he took an oath or he would spill his_____, or shall submit to the conditions which he had proposed.",
    "answer": "Blood",
    "options": ["Guts", "Blood", "Neither A Or B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4603,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma44:12",
    "question": "Zerahemnah retained his sword and was angry with Moroni, and he rushed forward to try to kill Moroni; but as he raised his_____, one of Moroni’s soldiers smote it to the ground.",
    "answer": "Sword"
  },
  {
    "id": 4604,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma44:12",
    "question": "One of Moroni’s soldiers broke Zerahemnah’s sword and took of his_____and it fell to the earth. And Zerahemnah withdrew from before them into the midst of his soldiers.",
    "answer": "Scalp"
  },
  {
    "id": 4605,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma44:13",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the soldier who had smote off the scalp of Zerahemnah, took up the scalp from off the ground by the hair, and put it upon the point of his sword and raised it up",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4606,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma44:14",
    "question": "The soldier raised his sword and said even as this scalp has fallen to the earth, so shall you fall to the earth except you will deliver up your weapons of war and depart with a_____of peace.",
    "answer": "Covenant",
    "options": ["Compromise", "Covenant", "Treaty"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4607,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma44:15",
    "question": "There were many or Zerahemnah’s armies who heard the words of the soldier and were struck with fear and came forward and delivered up their weapons unto the feet of_____.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4608,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma44:15",
    "question": "Those that delivered up their weapons of war unto Moroni were not allowed to depart into the wilderness but were taken prisoners by Moroni and his armies.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4609,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma44:16",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____was exceedingly wroth, and he did stir up the remainder of his soldiers to anger, to contend more powerfully against the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Zerahemnah"
  },
  {
    "id": 4610,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma44:17",
    "question": "Moroni was angry because of the stubbornness of Zerahemnah and the Lamanites; therefore he commanded his people that they should fall upon them and slay them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4611,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma44:18",
    "question": "Because of the_____naked skins and their bare heads were exposed to the sharp swords of the Nephites; they were pierced and smitten, and did fall exceedingly fast before the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4612,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma44:18",
    "question": "The prophecy the soldier of Moroni had prophesied concerning the fall and defeat of the armies of Zerahemnah did not come to pass.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4613,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma44:19",
    "question": "When Zerahemnah saw that they were all about to be destroyed, he cried mightily unto_____, promising that he would covenant unto him and his armies.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4614,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma44:19",
    "question": "Because of the covenant Zerahemnah had made with him, Moroni caused that the work of death should cease again among the people.  And he took the weapons of war from the_____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4615,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma44:20",
    "question": "Because of the covenant Zerahemnah had made with Moroni and his armies they were allowed to depart into the wilderness.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4616,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma44:21",
    "question": "Because the number of dead among the Lamanites and_____ was so great; their dead were not numbered.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4617,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma44:22",
    "question": "What is the name of the river that the dead among the Lamanites and Nephites were cast into, and they have gone forth and are buried in the depths of the sea.",
    "answer": "Sidon",
    "options": ["Snake", "Mississippi", "Sidon"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4618,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma44:24",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the eighteenth year of the reign of the judges over the people of Nephi ended; and also the record of_____, which was written upon the plates of Nephi.",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 4619,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45-62",
    "question": "Chapters 45-62 comprise the account of the people of Nephi, and their wars and dissentions, in the days of Helaman, according to the record of Helaman, which he kept in his days",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4620,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma45:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass the people of_____were exceedingly rejoiced, because the Lord had again delivered them out of the hands of their enemies.",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 4621,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:1",
    "question": "The Nephites did not give thanks to the Lord because he had delivered them from the hands of the Nephites but made human sacrifices unto him instead.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4622,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:1",
    "question": "The Nephites did fast much and pray much, and they did worship God with exceedingly great joy because he had delivered them out of the hands of their enemies.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4623,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma45:2",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma2 came into his eldest son_____; and asked him if he believed the words which he had spoken unto him concerning the records which had been kept.",
    "answer": "Helaman"
  },
  {
    "id": 4624,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:3",
    "question": "Helaman did not believe in the words which had been spoken unto him by Alma2; concerning that which had been spoken in the records which had been kept.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4625,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "4,5",
    "question": "Alma2 asked Helaman if he believed in Jesus_____, who shall come; and he said he believed in all the words which had been spoken unto him by Alma2.  Christ-",
    "answer": "Alma45:"
  },
  {
    "id": 4626,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "6,7",
    "question": "Alma2 asked Helaman if he would keep his commandments, and he said he would with all his_____.",
    "answer": "Mind",
    "options": ["Mind", "Heart", "Body"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4627,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:8",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that he was blessed and that the Lord shall prosper him in the promise land.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4628,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:9",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that he had a_____to tell him; but was not allowed to tell the people until it has been fulfilled; and to write the words which he should say.",
    "answer": "Prophecy",
    "options": ["Secret", "Prophecy", "Story"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4629,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:10",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that because he had the spirit of_____he could prophecy unto him.",
    "answer": "Revelation",
    "options": ["God", "Holy Ghost", "Revelation"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4630,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:10",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that the Nephites were going to dwindle in the Lord 400 years from the time that Jesus Christ would manifest himself unto them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4631,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:10",
    "question": "How many years did Alma2 tell Helaman the Nephites would start to dwindle in unbelief after Jesus Christ would manifest himself unto them?",
    "answer": "4 Hundred",
    "options": ["2 Hundred", "3 Hundred", "4 Hundred"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4632,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:11",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Nephites would see wars and pestilences, famines and bloodshed, even until the people of_____shall become extinct.",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["Moses", "Nephi", "Lehi"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4633,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma45:12",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Nephites would suffer because they would dwindle in unbelief in the word of God and fall into works of_____.",
    "answer": "Darkness"
  },
  {
    "id": 4634,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:12",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman the Nephites would suffer because they would also do all manner of iniquities and lasciviousness.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4635,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:12",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Nephites would sin against so great light and_____.",
    "answer": "Knowledge",
    "options": ["Truth", "Knowledge", "Smarts"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4636,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:12",
    "question": "How many generations did Alma2 tell Helaman shall not all pass away before the great iniquity of the Nephites would come?",
    "answer": "4",
    "options": ["3", "4", "5"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4637,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:13",
    "question": "Alma2 said when the great day would come of the suffering of the people; the seed of those who are now numbered among the people of Nephi would no longer be numbered.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4638,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:14",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that those few who would survive the great and dreadful day would be numbered among what tribe of people?",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["Nephites", "Lamanites", "Israelites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4639,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:14",
    "question": "Alma2 said that a few would survive the great and dreadful day and would be called the_____of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Disciples",
    "options": ["Children", "Chosen", "Disciples"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4640,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:14",
    "question": "Alma2 said the disciples of the Lord would be pursued and killed by the Lamanites until they would also become extinct.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4641,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:14",
    "question": "Alma2 said the disciples of the Lord would be killed because of the iniquity of the people and because his_____would be fulfilled.",
    "answer": "Prophecy",
    "options": ["Revelation", "Prophecy", "Storytelling"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4642,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:15",
    "question": "And it came to pass that after Alma2 had spoken to Helaman he blessed him and his other sons; and he also blessed the_____for the righteous sake.",
    "answer": "Earth",
    "options": ["Earth", "Ground", "Heavens"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4643,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma45:16",
    "question": "The Lord cursed the land unto every nation, kindred, tongue, and every_____, when they are fully ripe and fall into wickedness. ",
    "answer": "People"
  },
  {
    "id": 4644,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:16",
    "question": "Alma2 said the cursing and the blessing of God upon the land, is because he cannot look upon sin with the least degree of_____.",
    "answer": "Allowance",
    "options": ["Allowance", "Tolerance", "Admittance"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4645,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:17",
    "question": "After Alma2 said these things unto Helaman, he blessed the church and all those who should stand fast in the faith from that time forward.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4646,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:18",
    "question": "What was the name of the land which Alma2 departed to after he blessed his sons and all of those who would stand fast in the faith of the church?",
    "answer": "Zarahemla",
    "options": ["Manti", "Zarahemla", "Nephi"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4647,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:18",
    "question": "After Alma2 departed into the land of Zarahemla he was heard preaching unto the Nephites in the land of Melek.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4648,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:18",
    "question": "After Alma2 departed into the land of Zarahemla he was never heard of anymore.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4649,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:18",
    "question": "In the Book of Ether we are told by Mormon about the burial and the death of Alma2 theYounger.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4650,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:19",
    "question": "Mormon tells us that Alma2 the Younger was a_____man; and that if was said among the people of the church that he was taken up by the Spirit.",
    "answer": "Righteous",
    "options": ["Righteous", "Holy", "Unrighteous"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4651,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma45:19",
    "question": "Mormon tell us that Alma2 the Younger was a righteous man and taken up by the Spirit, or buried by the Lord, even as what other prophet old times?_____",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },
  {
    "id": 4652,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:19",
    "question": "We suppose that the Lord took Alma2 the Younger unto himself and received him in the Spirit; therefore, for this cause we know nothing concerning his_____and burial.",
    "answer": "Death",
    "options": ["Death", "Body", "Life"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4653,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:20",
    "question": "And it came to pass that in the beginning of the 19th year of the reign of the judges, Helaman went forth among the people to declare the word of the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4654,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma45:21",
    "question": "Because the_____ had many little dissensions and disturbances among themselves; it became expedient that the word of the God should be declared among them.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4655,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma45:23",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Helaman and his brethren appointed_____and teachers over the churches.",
    "answer": "Priests"
  },
  {
    "id": 4656,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:23",
    "question": "Because there arose a dissension among the Lamanites, they would not give heed to the words of Helaman and his brethren.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4657,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:24",
    "question": "The people grew proud, being lifted up in the pride of their_____, because of their exceeding great riches.",
    "answer": "Hearts",
    "options": ["Skins", "Eyes", "Hearts"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4658,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma45:24",
    "question": "The people grew proud and rich in there own eyes, and would not give heed to_____and his brothers’ words, and walk uprightly before God.",
    "answer": "Helaman"
  },
  {
    "id": 4659,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:1,2",
    "question": "And it came to pass that those that would not hearken unto Helaman and his brethren were gathered together to battle and they were exceedingly wroth with the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4660,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:3",
    "question": "The leader of the Lamanites was a large and strong man; and his name was_____.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah",
    "options": ["Teancum", "Helorum", "Amalickiah"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4661,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:25",
    "question": "Amalickiah was not a Nephite by birth; but was a descendant of Ismael.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4662,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:4",
    "question": "The Lamanite leader Amalickiah was desirous to be a_____over the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "King",
    "options": ["King", "Chief", "Commander"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4663,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:4",
    "question": "Amalickiah and those that desired that he should be their king were greater than the lower judges of the land, and they were seeking for_____.",
    "answer": "Power",
    "options": ["Riches", "Power", "Jewels"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4664,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:5",
    "question": "Amalickiah led the people by flattering them, and said if he were made king he would make them_____over the people.",
    "answer": "Rulers",
    "options": ["Kings", "Rulers", "Justices"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4665,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:6",
    "question": "Amalickiah led many of the Lord’s children away from the Lord by creating dissensions among the people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4666,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:6",
    "question": "During the time of Amalickiah there were not many high priests among the land preaching the word of God.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4667,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:7",
    "question": "there were many people who belonged to the church who believed in the flattering words of_____.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 4668,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:7",
    "question": "Because the Lord had delivered them from the Lamanites the_____had great rejoicings.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4669,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:8",
    "question": "Mormon tells us that when we forget the Lord our God, we are quick to do iniquity, and we are left to be led by_____.",
    "answer": ["Satan", "devil", "Adversary", "evil"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4670,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:9",
    "question": "Mormon writes that we can see the great wickedness one very wicked man can cause to take place among the children of men.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4671,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:10",
    "question": "Amalickiah was a man of cunning devices and a man of many_____words; that he led away the hearts of many people to do wicked things.",
    "answer": "Flattering",
    "options": ["Smart", "Flattering", "Cunning"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4672,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:10",
    "question": "Amalickiah and his people seeked to destroy the church of God, and to destroy the foundation of_____which God had granted unto them.",
    "answer": "Liberty",
    "options": ["Liberty", "Equal Rights", "Justice"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4673,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:10",
    "question": "The foundation of liberty was granted unto the people and was also blessing from God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4674,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:11",
    "question": "And it came to pass when_____who was the chief commander of the armies of the Nephites, had heard of the dissensions, he was angry with Amalickiah.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4675,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:12",
    "question": "On what type of clothing did Moroni write the words: In memory of our God?",
    "answer": "Coat"
  },
  {
    "id": 4676,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:12",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote inspiring words on his coat and fastened it upon the end of a_____.",
    "answer": "Pole",
    "options": ["Stick", "2 X 4", "Pole"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4677,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:13",
    "question": "Captain Moroni fastened on his head-plate, and his_____-plate, and his shields, and girded on his armor about his loins.",
    "answer": "Breast",
    "options": ["Arm", "Leg", "Breast"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4678,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:13",
    "question": "Captain Moroni took the pole which he had fastened to his coat and bowed himself to the earth and called it what name? ",
    "answer": "Liberty"
  },
  {
    "id": 4679,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:13",
    "question": "Captain Moroni did not pray mightily unto his God for the blessings of liberty to rest upon his brethren.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4680,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:13",
    "question": "Captain Moroni prayed for liberty for his brethren as long as there should be a band of_____remain to posses the land.",
    "answer": "Christians",
    "options": ["Nephites", "Lamanites", "Christians"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4681,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:14",
    "question": "The true believers of Christ were called what name by those who did not belong to the church?",
    "answer": "Christians"
  },
  {
    "id": 4682,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:15",
    "question": "The true believers in Christ took upon them, gladly, the name of Christ, or Christians, because of their belief in Christ who should come.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4683,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:16",
    "question": "Captain Moroni prayed that the cause of the_____; and that the freedom of the land might be favored.",
    "answer": "Christians"
  },
  {
    "id": 4684,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:17",
    "question": "And it came to pass Captain Moroni poured out his soul to God, and named all the land which was south of the land Desolation; a chosen land, and the land of liberty.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4685,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:18",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said the Christians were_____; because they took upon themselves the name of Christ.",
    "answer": "Despised",
    "options": ["Disowned", "Despised", "Likeable"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4686,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:19",
    "question": "When Captain Moroni had finished with his words, he went forth among the people, waving the rent part of his garment in the air.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4687,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:20",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told those who would help maintain the title of Liberty upon the land; to come forth and enter into a_____with the Lord.",
    "answer": "Covenant"
  },
  {
    "id": 4688,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:20",
    "question": "The people covenanted with the Lord that they would help maintain their_____, and their religion, that the Lord God may bless them.",
    "answer": "Rights"
  },
  {
    "id": 4689,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:212",
    "question": "The people came running together with their armor girded about their loins, rending their garments in token or as a covenant.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4690,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:21",
    "question": "The people covenanted that they would not forsake their God; or, and if they should fall into transgression; the Lord would rend them even as they had rent their_____.",
    "answer": "Garments",
    "options": ["Swords", "Axes", "Garments"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4691,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:22",
    "question": "After the people had covenanted with the Lord; they cast their garments upon the_____of Moroni, that if they should fall into transgression, the Lord would cast them upon the feet of their enemies.",
    "answer": "Feet"
  },
  {
    "id": 4692,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:23",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told his people they were a remnant of the seed of what people?",
    "answer": "Jacob",
    "options": ["Jacob", "Laman", "Lemuel"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4693,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:23",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told his people they were a remnant of the seed of_____, whose coat was rent by his brethren into many pieces.",
    "answer": "Joseph"
  },
  {
    "id": 4694,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:23",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told the people to remember to keep the commandments of God, or their garments should be rent by their brethren, and cast into prison, sold, or be slain.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4695,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:24",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told the Nephites to preserve their liberty as a remnant of_____; and remember his words before his death.",
    "answer": "Joseph"
  },
  {
    "id": 4696,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:24",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said Joseph saw that a part of the remnant of his coat was preserved and had not decayed.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4697,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:24",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said Joseph said that even as a remnant of his coat was preserved by the hand of the Lord; so shall the remainder of his seed shall perish, even as the remnant of his garment.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4698,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:25",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that Jacob felt no sorrow that part of his seed would perish while part of his seed would be preserved.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4699,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:25",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that Jacob was joyful because of his part of his son’s seed would be taken up unto_____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 4700,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:27",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told the Nephites who knew what part of Joseph seed would perish and which would be taken up unto the Lord, unless they shall stand fast in the faith of_____. ",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "id": 4701,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:28",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when Captain Moroni had finished with his words; he gathered together all the people who were desirous to maintain their liberty, to stand against_____.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 4702,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:28",
    "question": "Those Nephites who had dissented and were with Amalickiah were called_____.",
    "answer": "Amalickiahites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4703,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:29",
    "question": "The_____were more numerous than the Amalickiahites, and Amalickiah feared them; therefore, he took his people with him and departed into the land of Nephi.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4704,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:30",
    "question": "Captain Moroni knew that_____would stir up the Lamanites to anger against him and his people and to do battle with them, so that he could gain his purposes.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 4705,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:31",
    "question": "Because of the things Amalickiah was doing; Captain Moroni thought it was expedient that he should take his armies, and enter into a_____to keep the peace.",
    "answer": "Covenant",
    "options": ["Treaty", "Alliance", "Covenant"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4706,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:31",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain_____took his army and marched out into the wilderness, to cut off the course of Amalickiah in the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4707,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:33",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Amalickiah fled with a small part of his army and the rest were delivered up into Captain Moroni and were taken back to the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4708,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:34",
    "question": "Captain Moroni was appointed by the_____judges and the voice of the people, therefore; he had power over the armies of the Nephites to establish power and exercise authority over them.",
    "answer": "Chief"
  },
  {
    "id": 4709,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:35",
    "question": "Captain Moroni gave the Amalickiahites prisoners the choice to enter a covenant to support the cause of freedom or to be put to death.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4710,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:35",
    "question": "And a lot of Captain Moroni’s prisoners denied to enter a covenant to support the cause of freedom and were put to death.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4711,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:36",
    "question": "And it came to pass Captain Moroni caused the title of_____to be hoisted upon every tower which was in all the land that was possessed by the Nephites ",
    "answer": "Liberty"
  },
  {
    "id": 4712,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:36",
    "question": "Captain Moroni planted the standard of liberty among the_____.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Amalickiahites", "Nephites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4713,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:38",
    "question": "And it came to pass the Nephites had peace in the land once again and_____and the high priests did also maintain order in the church.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["Amalickiah", "Helaman", "Zoram"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4714,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:39",
    "question": "And it came to pass that many who died, firmly believed that their souls were redeemed by the Lord Jesus Christ; thus they went out of the world rejoicing.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4715,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:40",
    "question": "There were some of the Nephites who died with_____, which at some seasons of the year were very frequent in the land.",
    "answer": "Fevers",
    "options": ["Boils", "Fevers", "Leprosy"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4716,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:40",
    "question": "The Lord had prepared excellent qualities of many plants and roots which were provided to remove the cause of_____.",
    "answer": "Disease",
    "options": ["Malaria", "Disease", "Spells"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4717,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:40",
    "question": "Many men were subjected to diseases because of the nature of the_____.",
    "answer": "Climate",
    "options": ["Climate", "Earth", "Sun"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4718,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:41",
    "question": "There were many of the Nephites who died of old age; and those who died in the faith of Jesus Christ are happy with him, as we must suppose.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4719,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma47:1",
    "question": "Amalickiah stirred up the Lamanites against the people of Nephi, that the king of the Lamanites sent a_____throughout the land.",
    "answer": "Proclamation",
    "options": ["Newsflash", "Text Message", "Proclamation"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4720,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma47:1",
    "question": "The proclamation that the king of the Lamanites sent throughout his land was for the Lamanites to gather themselves to do battle against the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4721,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:2",
    "question": "The Lamanites were afraid to go to battle against the_____, and it came to pass that they would not obey the commandments of the king.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4722,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:3",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the king of the Lamanites gave_____the command of that part of his army which was obedient unto his commands.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 4723,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma47:4",
    "question": "Amalickiah was a subtle man to do evil, therefore he laid the plan in his_____to dethrone the king of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Heart",
    "options": ["Head", "Heart", "Chest"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4724,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma47:5",
    "question": "Amalickiah sought to gain the favor of those who were not obedient to the king of Lamanites and they were in a place called Onidah.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4725,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:6",
    "question": "The Lamanites who were afraid to go to battle against the Nephites had appointed a man to be a king and a leader over them; so that they would not be subjected to go against the_____.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4726,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma47:8",
    "question": "Amalickiah’s intention was to gain favor with the armies of the Lamanites, that he might place himself at their head and dethrone the king and take possession of the_____.",
    "answer": "Kingdom",
    "options": ["Land", "Kingdom", "Palace"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4727,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma47:10",
    "question": "And it came to pass when the night came Amalickiah sent a_____embassy into the mountain where the leader of the disenchanted Lamanites were.",
    "answer": "Secret",
    "options": ["Secret", "Delegation", "Proclamation"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4728,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:10",
    "question": "The name of the leader of the disenchanted Lamanites was called_____, and Amalickiah wanted him to come down from the mountain so that he could speak to him. ",
    "answer": "Lehonti"
  },
  {
    "id": 4729,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma47:11",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Lehonti came down from the mountain to speak with Amalickiah.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4730,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma47:11",
    "question": "Amalickiah sent a message",
    "answer": "3",
    "options": [
      "(1st Time) How Many Times For Lehonti To Come Down From The Mountain So That He Could Speak To Him?  1",
      "2",
      "3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 4731,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:12",
    "question": "Because Lehonti would not come down from the mountain; _____went up the mountain to speak with Lehonti.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 4732,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma47:13",
    "question": "Amalickiah did not betray his own army so that he could become 2nd in command of a larger Lamanite army by delivering his army to Lehonti.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4733,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:14",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____came down with his men and surrounded the men of Amalickiah.",
    "answer": "Lehonti"
  },
  {
    "id": 4734,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma47:15",
    "question": "Amalickiah’s men pleaded with him that he would not let the Lamanite armies destroy them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4735,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:16",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____delivered his men contrary to the commands of the king so that he could accomplish his designs in dethroning the king.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 4736,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma47:17",
    "question": "It was not the custom among the Lamanites if their chief leader was killed, to appoint the second leader to be their chief leader.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4737,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:18",
    "question": "And it came to pass Amalickiah had one of his servant administer_____by small amounts to Lehonti, that he died.",
    "answer": "Poison"
  },
  {
    "id": 4738,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:19",
    "question": "When Lehonti died; the_____appointed Amalickiah to be their leader and their chief commander.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4739,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:20",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Amalickiah marched with his armies to the land of Nephi, to the city of_____, which was the chief city. ",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 4740,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma47:21",
    "question": "And the king came out to meet him with his guards, for he supposed that Amalickiah had fulfilled his commands.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4741,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma47:22",
    "question": "As the king came out to meet him, Amalickiah caused that his_____bowed themselves before the king, as if to reverence him because of his greatness.",
    "answer": "Servants",
    "options": ["Boys", "Servants", "Body Guards"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4742,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:23",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the king put forth his hand to raise them, as was the custom with the_____, as a token of peace, which custom they had taken from the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4743,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:24",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when the king raised his hands, a servant of_____stabbed him in the heart and he fell to the earth.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 4744,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma47:25,26",
    "question": "After the king fell to the ground his servants fled and the servants of Amalickiah said it was his servant that had stabbed the king.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4745,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:27",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Amalickiah commanded that his armies should march forth and see what had happened to the_____.",
    "answer": "King"
  },
  {
    "id": 4746,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma47:27",
    "question": "Amalickiah pretended to be angry, and said: “Whosoever loved the king, let him go forth, and pursue his servants that they may be slain”.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4747,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:29",
    "question": "The servants of the king were frightened and fled into the wilderness, and came over into the land of Zarahemla and joined the people of_____.",
    "answer": "Ammon"
  },
  {
    "id": 4748,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:30",
    "question": "The army which pursued the servants of the king returned empty handed; and thus_____, by his fraud, gained the hearts of the people.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 4749,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma47:32",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the queen, when she had heard that the king was slain—sent a message to Amalickiah desiring him to spare the city of Nephi and also the people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4750,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma47:33",
    "question": "The queen desired that Amalickiah would come and see her and also wanted him to bring_____with him to testify concerning the death of the king.",
    "answer": "Witnesses",
    "options": ["Men", "Guards", "Witnesses"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4751,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:34",
    "question": "Amalickiah took the same servant that had killed the king and all others that were with him at the time and testified to the_____ that it was the king’s own servants that had killed him. ",
    "answer": "Queen"
  },
  {
    "id": 4752,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma47:34",
    "question": "After Amalickiah and his servants testified of how the king had been killed the queen was not satisfied with their testimonies.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4753,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:35",
    "question": "Amalickiah sought the favor of the_____, and took her unto him to marry her and make her his wife.",
    "answer": "Queen"
  },
  {
    "id": 4754,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma47:35",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Amalickiah by his fraud, and by the assistance of his cunning servants, obtained the_____.",
    "answer": "Kingdom",
    "options": ["Empire", "Kingdom", "Land"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4755,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:35",
    "question": "Amalickiah was made king throughout all the land, among all the people of the_____, who consisted of Lemuelites, Ishmalites, and all the dissenters of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4756,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma47:36",
    "question": "The Nephites who had dissented had been instructed in the same knowledge of the Lord became more hardened, wild, and ferocious than the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4757,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:36",
    "question": "The Nephites who had dissented to the Lamanites began drinking in the traditions of the Lamanites; giving way to indolence; entirely forgetting the_____ their God.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 4758,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma48:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that as soon as Amalickiah became the king of the Lamanites he began to appoint people to speak unto the Nephites from their towers.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4759,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma48:2",
    "question": "Amalickiah inspired the hearts of the Lamanites against the Nephites because he sought to_____over all the land.",
    "answer": "Reign",
    "options": ["Have Control", "Reign", "Ownership"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4760,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:2",
    "question": "Amalickiah wanted to reign over all the people that were in the land; both the_____and the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4761,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma48:3",
    "question": "Amalickiah accomplished his design, for he had hardened the hearts of the Lamanites and_____their minds, and stirred them up to anger against the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Blinded",
    "options": ["Close", "Opened", "Blinded"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4762,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:4",
    "question": "Amalickiah was determined because of the greatness of the number of his people, to overpower the_____and bring them into bondage.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4763,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma48:5",
    "question": "Amalickiah appointed_____as chief captains of his armies, because they were more acquainted with the strength of the Nephites, and they knew the weakest parts of their cities.",
    "answer": "Zoramites",
    "options": ["Zoramites", "Lemuelites", "Ishmaelites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4764,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:7",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Amalickiah was obtaining his power by fraud and deceit; _____on the other hand, had been preparing the minds of the people to be faithful unto the Lord.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4765,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma48:8",
    "question": "Captain Moroni had the Nephites erecting small forts, building walls of stones, all around their borders of lands and their cities.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4766,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma48:9",
    "question": "Captain Moroni place a greater amount of_____around the weakest parts of their cities.",
    "answer": "Men",
    "options": ["Forts", "Walls", "Men"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4767,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma48:9",
    "question": "Captain Moroni did not strengthen and fortify his armies and cities which were possessed by the Nephites.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4768,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:10",
    "question": "Captain Moroni made preparations to support the liberties of the Nephites; that they might maintain that which was called by their enemies the cause of the_____.",
    "answer": "Christians"
  },
  {
    "id": 4769,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma48:11",
    "question": "Captain Moroni was not a very strong and mighty man.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4770,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:11",
    "question": "Captain Moroni was a strong and mighty man; he was a man of a_____understanding; a man whose soul did have joy in the liberty and the freedom of his country.",
    "answer": "Perfect"
  },
  {
    "id": 4771,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:11",
    "question": "Captain Moroni did also have joy because he wanted his brethren to be free from_____and slavery.",
    "answer": "Bondage"
  },
  {
    "id": 4772,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma48:12",
    "question": "Moroni’s_____did swell with thanksgiving to his God, for the many privileges and blessings which he bestowed upon his people.",
    "answer": "Heart",
    "options": ["Head", "Heart", "Chest"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4773,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma48:12",
    "question": "Captain Moroni did not labor exceedingly for the welfare and safety of his people.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4774,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:13",
    "question": "Captain Moroni was a man whose was firm in the_____of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "Faith"
  },
  {
    "id": 4775,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma48:13",
    "question": "Captain Moroni did not ever swear an oath to defend his people from their enemies.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4776,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma48:13",
    "question": "Captain Moroni had sworn an oath to defend his people, his rights, and his country, and his religion, even to the loss of_____from their enemies.",
    "answer": "Blood",
    "options": ["Arms", "Legs", "Blood"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4777,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma48:14",
    "question": "The Nephites were not taught to defend themselves against their enemies, even to the shedding of blood if it were necessary.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4778,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:14",
    "question": "The Nephites were taught to never give an offense, and never to raise the_____except it were to preserve their lives.",
    "answer": "Sword"
  },
  {
    "id": 4779,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:15",
    "question": "The Nephites had faith in their_____that he would prosper them in the land if they were faithful in keeping his commandments.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 4780,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma48:15",
    "question": "The Nephites had faith in their God that he would prosper them in the land and to warn them to flee from their enemies, to prepare them for war, according to their danger",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4781,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:16",
    "question": "The Nephites had faith in God that he would make it know unto them where they should go to defend themselves against their_____.",
    "answer": "Enemies"
  },
  {
    "id": 4782,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:16",
    "question": "Captain_____had faith in the Lord that he would deliver them from their enemies; and his heart did glory in it; not in the shedding of blood but in doing good.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4783,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma48:16",
    "question": "Captain Moroni did have joy in preserving his people and keeping the_____of God and resisting iniquity.",
    "answer": "Commandments",
    "options": ["Statues", "Commandments", "Constitution"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4784,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:17",
    "question": "Verily I say unto you, if all men had been, and were, and ever would be, like unto Moroni, behold the very powers of_____would have been shaken forever.",
    "answer": "Hell"
  },
  {
    "id": 4785,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:17",
    "question": "Mormon writes and tells us if we were more like Captain Moroni; the_____would never have power over the hearts of the children of men.",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },
  {
    "id": 4786,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:18",
    "question": "Behold_____; was a man like unto Ammon, the son of Mosiah, and even the other sons of Mosiah, and also Alma and his sons, for they were all men of God.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4787,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma48:19",
    "question": "Helaman and his brethren were no less serviceable unto the people than was Captain Moroni; for they did preach the word of God, and did baptize many.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4788,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:20",
    "question": "The Nephites did humble themselves because of the words of the Lord, insomuch that they were highly favored of the_____; and did not have a war for the space of four years. ",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 4789,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:23",
    "question": "The Nephites were sorry to take up arms against the Lamanites, because they did not delight in the shedding of_____.",
    "answer": "Blood"
  },
  {
    "id": 4790,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "23-24",
    "question": "The Nephites would not suffer that their wives and children should be massacred by the barbarous cruelty of the_____; who were once their brethren.  Lamanites-",
    "answer": "Alma48:"
  },
  {
    "id": 4791,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma48:24",
    "question": "Captain Moroni’s Nephites were sorrowful because of those who had dissented from their church, and had left them and had gone to destroy them by joining the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4792,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:25",
    "question": "Captain Moroni’s people could not bear that their brethren should rejoice over the_____of the Nephites as long as there were any who should keep the commandment of God.",
    "answer": "Blood"
  },
  {
    "id": 4793,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:1,2",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites were approaching towards the land of Ammonihah; and Captain Moroni had rebuilt the city and stationed and army there.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4794,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma49:3",
    "question": "The Lamanites though that the city of_____ would be an easy target to destroy because they had destroyed it once before.",
    "answer": "Ammonihah",
    "options": ["Nephi", "Lehi", "Ammonihah"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4795,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma48:3",
    "question": "The Lamanites had destroyed the city of Ammonihah once before because of the iniquity of the people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4796,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma49:4",
    "question": "The Nephites had dug a ridge of _____around the city of Ammonihah and it was so high that the Lamanites’ stones and arrows could not have any effect on them.",
    "answer": "Earth",
    "options": ["Rocks", "Stones", "Earth"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4797,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:5",
    "question": "The chief captains of the Lamanites were not astonished exceedingly because of the wisdom of the Nephites in preparing the places of security.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4798,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma49:6",
    "question": "The_____supposed that they could overcome the Nephite cities because of the greatness of their numbers.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4799,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:6",
    "question": "The Lamanites prepared themselves with garments of skins, which were very thick garments to cover their nakedness.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4800,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma49:7",
    "question": "The_____supposed that they could easily overpower the Nephites and subject them to the yoke of bondage, or slay and massacre them according to their pleasure.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4801,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma49:8",
    "question": "The Nephites were very well prepared for battle against the Lamanites because of the instructions of Captain_____.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4802,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:9",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites; or Amalickiahites were exceedingly astonished at the manner the Nephites had prepared themselves.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4803,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma49:10",
    "question": "King_____did not come down from the mountain to the head of his army because he did not care for the blood of the people.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 4804,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma49:12",
    "question": "Because of the fortifications of the Nephite city of Ammonihah, the Lamanites retreated into the_____ and marched towards the land of Noah.",
    "answer": "Wilderness"
  },
  {
    "id": 4805,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:13",
    "question": "The chief captains of the Lamanites came forward and took an oath that they would destroy the people of the city of Noah.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4806,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:14",
    "question": "The city of Noah had been a weak city before; but to the astonishment of the Lamanites; because of the means of Captain Moroni, the city of Noah was even stronger than the city of Ammonihah",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4807,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma49:15",
    "question": "It was according to the desires of Captain_____ that the Lamanites were afraid of the city of Noah because it had been the weakest part of the land of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4808,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma49:16",
    "question": "Captain Moroni appointed_____to be the chief captain of the city of Noah and he was the same person who fought with the Lamanites in the valley on the east of the river Sidon.",
    "answer": "Lehi"
  },
  {
    "id": 4809,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma49:17",
    "question": "The Lamanites feared the chief captain Lehi, exceedingly; nevertheless their chief captains had sworn with an_____to attack the city.",
    "answer": "Oath"
  },
  {
    "id": 4810,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:18",
    "question": "The only way the Lamanites could enter the city of Lehi was through the entrance; because Captain Moroni had his men dug a deep ditch all away around it.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4811,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma49:20",
    "question": "A group of the_____men of the Nephites were prepared to defend the city of Noah with their swords and with their slings.",
    "answer": "Strongest",
    "options": ["Strongest", "Weakest", "Smartest"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4812,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma49:21",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the captains of the Lamanites fought with the_____before the place of the entrance of the city of Noah.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4813,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:22",
    "question": "The Lamanites began to dig down the banks of the city of Noah in order to obtain a pass to the Nephite armies.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4814,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma49:22",
    "question": "Instead of filling up their ditches by pulling down the banks of earth, they were filled up in a measure with the dead and_____bodies of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Wounded",
    "options": ["Hurt", "Wounded", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4815,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:23",
    "question": "The Nephites did not get an opportunity to slay all of the chief captains of the Lamanites because some of them fled.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4816,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma49:23",
    "question": "More than a_____of the Lamanites were slain during the battle for the city of Noah; and there was not a single soul of the Nephites slain.",
    "answer": "Thousand",
    "options": ["Hundred", "Thousand", "Ton"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4817,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma49:24",
    "question": "There were about_____men of the Nephites’ army who were wounded during the battle of the city of Noah.",
    "answer": "50",
    "options": ["50", "60", "70"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4818,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:24",
    "question": "The 50 wounded men of the Nephites’ army were wounded in the legs but their wounds were not severe.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4819,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma49:25",
    "question": "And it came to pass, that when the Lamanites saw that all of their_____captains were killed; they fled into the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Chief"
  },
  {
    "id": 4820,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma49:25",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites returned to the land of Nephi, to inform their king, _____, who was a Nephite by birth, concerning their great loss.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 4821,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:26",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Amalickiah was exceedingly angry with his people, because he could not obtain his desires to bring the Nephites to the yoke of bondage.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4822,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:27",
    "question": "Amalickiah was exceedingly wroth but he did not curse God neither Moroni.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4823,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma49:27",
    "question": "Amalickiah swore with an oath that he would drink the_____of Captain Moroni.",
    "answer": "Blood"
  },
  {
    "id": 4824,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma49:27",
    "question": "Amalickiah was angry with Captain Moroni because he had kept the commandments of God in preparing for the_____of his people.",
    "answer": "Safety",
    "options": ["Good", "Safety", "Battle"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4825,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma49:28",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Nephites thank the Lord their God, because of his_____power in delivering them from the hands of their enemies.",
    "answer": "Matchless"
  },
  {
    "id": 4826,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma49:30",
    "question": "The Nephites had exceeding great prosperity in the_____because of their heed and diligence in the word of God.",
    "answer": "&&&",
    "options": ["Land", "Church", "Synagogues"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4827,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:30",
    "question": "The word of the Lord was declared unto the Nephites by Helaman, Shiblon, Corianton, and Ammon and his brethren.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4828,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain_____did not stop making preparations for war, or to defend his people against the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4829,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:2",
    "question": "Captain Moroni caused that the Nephites dig heaps of earth all around their cities in the land and had timbers of the height of a_____, all around their cities.",
    "answer": "Man",
    "options": ["Woman", "Man", "Sasquatch"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4830,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:3",
    "question": "Captain Moroni caused that upon these works of timbers there should be a frame of pickets built upon the timbers.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4831,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:4",
    "question": "Captain Moroni caused_____to be erected that overlooked those works of pickets.",
    "answer": "Towers"
  },
  {
    "id": 4832,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:4",
    "question": "Captain Moroni caused the Nephites to build places of security to be built upon those towers, that the stones of the_____could not hurt them.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4833,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:6",
    "question": "Captain Moroni did not prepare strongholds against the coming of the enemies of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4834,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:7",
    "question": "Captain Moroni caused that his armies should go forth into the east wilderness and drove all the_____that were there, into their own lands.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4835,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:8",
    "question": "The land of_____did run in a straight course from the east sea to the west.",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["Mormon", "Amalickiah", "Nephi"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4836,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:9",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni caused that the inhabitants who were in the land of_____go forth into the east wilderness and possess the land.",
    "answer": "Zarahemla"
  },
  {
    "id": 4837,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:11",
    "question": "Captain Moroni cut off all the strongholds of the Lamanites in the east wilderness and also in the west by erecting fortifications.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4838,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:11",
    "question": "The_____possessed all of the land northward, and even all the land which was northward of the land of Bountiful, according to there pleasure.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4839,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:12",
    "question": "The armies of Captain Moroni did not increase daily because of the assurance of protection which his works did bring forth unto the Nephites.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4840,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:13",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Nephites began the foundation of a city, and they called the name of the city_____and it was by the east sea.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4841,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:14",
    "question": "The Nephites also began to build a city between the city of Moroni and the city of Aaron and named it Nephihah.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4842,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:15",
    "question": "And the Nephites began to build many cities on the north, one in particular manner which they called_____which was in the north.",
    "answer": "Lehi",
    "options": ["Lehi", "Nephi", "Lamuel."]
  },
  {
    "id": 4843,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:17,18",
    "question": "The twenty and first year of the reign of the judges over the people of Nephi was exceedingly prosperous and they did multiply and were strong in the land.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4844,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:19",
    "question": "Mormon writes that we can see how merciful and just are all the dealings of the Lord, to the fulfilling of all of his_____unto the children of men.",
    "answer": "Words"
  },
  {
    "id": 4845,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:19,20",
    "question": "The Lord’s words were verified when he spoke unto Lehi that his seed would be blessed inasmuch as they shall keep his_____.",
    "answer": "Commandment"
  },
  {
    "id": 4846,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:21",
    "question": "The Nephites were quarreling and had contentions among themselves, which brought upon them their wars and their destructions.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4847,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:21",
    "question": "Because the_____were murdering, plundering.and doing other abominations among themselves; it brought upon them their wars and destructions.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4848,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:22",
    "question": "Those who did not keep the commandments were consigned to bondage, or to perish by the_____, or to dwindle in unbelief, and mingle with the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Sword"
  },
  {
    "id": 4849,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:23",
    "question": "During the days of Captain Moroni there have never been such a happier people; even since the days of Nephi.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4850,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:25",
    "question": "And it came to pass that there was a contention among the_____concerning the land of Lehi and the land of Morianton.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Nephites", "Ishmaelites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4851,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:26",
    "question": "The Nephites who possessed the land of Morianton did not claim a part of the land of Lehi.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4852,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:26",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people in the land of Morianton took up arms against their brethren, and they were determined by the_____to slay them.",
    "answer": "Sword",
    "options": ["Sword", "Knife", "Gun"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4853,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:27",
    "question": "The Nephites in the land of Lehi fled to the camp of Captain_____, and appealed unto him to assist them; for behold they were not in the wrong.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4854,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:28",
    "question": "The Nephites in the land of Morianton were led by a man named_____.",
    "answer": "Morianton",
    "options": ["Amalickiah", "Teancum", "Morianton"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4855,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:29",
    "question": "Because Morianton and his people were afraid of Captain Moroni’s army, they fled to a land that was northward, which was covered with large bodies of_____.",
    "answer": "Water",
    "options": ["Rivers", "Water", "Snakes"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4856,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:29",
    "question": "Morianton and his people did not want to take possession of the land northward which was covered with large bodies of water.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4857,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:30",
    "question": "Morianton was a man of great_____, therefore he was angry with one of his maid servants, and he fell upon her and beat her a lot.",
    "answer": "Passion",
    "options": ["Strength", "Passion", "Moxie"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4858,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:31",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the maid servant that was beaten by Morianton came over to the camp of Captain_____.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4859,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:31",
    "question": "Mormon never writes the name of the maid servant that was beaten by Morianton in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4860,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:31",
    "question": "The maid servant that was beaten by Morianton told Captain Moroni all things concerning Morianton and his intentions to flee into the land_____.",
    "answer": "Northward",
    "options": ["Westward", "Southward", "Northward"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4861,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:32",
    "question": "Captain Moroni was concerned that the people who were in the land of Bountiful would hearken to the words of Morianton and unite with his people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4862,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:32",
    "question": "Captain Moroni sent an army to cut off the people of Morianton and to stop their flight into the land northward.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4863,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:32",
    "question": "If the people of Morianton would unite with the people of the land of Bountiful it would not lay a foundation for serious consequences among the people of Nephi.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4864,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:32",
    "question": "By the uniting of the people of Morianton and the people of Bountiful it would lead to the overthrow of the liberty of the people of _____.",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 4865,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:34",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the army of Captain Moroni cut off the peoples’ flight by the borders of the land called _____.",
    "answer": "Desolation",
    "options": ["Isolation", "Desolation", "Probation"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4866,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:34",
    "question": "The land of Desolation was by the narrow pass which led by the sea on the west and on the east.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4867,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:35",
    "question": "The army that Captain Moroni sent to cut off the peoples’ flight into the land northward was led by a man named_____.",
    "answer": "Teancum",
    "options": ["Teancum", "Gadianton", "Gideon"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4868,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "alma50:35",
    "question": "The people of Morianton were very stubborn because of his wickedness and his flattering words.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4869,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:35",
    "question": "And it came to pass that a battle commenced between both of the armies and Morianton was slain by_____.",
    "answer": "Teancum"
  },
  {
    "id": 4870,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:36",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people of Morianton were taken prisoners, and returned to the camp of Captain_____where they coveted to keep the peace.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4871,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:37",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Nephihah, who was the chief judge of the land died, having filled the judgment-seat with a perfect uprightness before God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4872,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:37-4:16,17",
    "question": "The chief judge Nephihah succeeded was what other chief judge of the land of Zarahemla?",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 4873,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:38",
    "question": "Nephihah did not refuse Alma1 when he was asked to take possession of the sacred records and those things which were in the hands of Alma1.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4874,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:39",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Nephihah went the way of the earth and his son_____was appointed to fill the judgment-seat.",
    "answer": "Pahoran",
    "options": ["Pahoran", "Ammoron", "Jacob"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4875,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:39",
    "question": "Pahoran took an oath and sacred ordinance to judge_____, and to keep the peace, and the freedom of the people.",
    "answer": "Righteously",
    "options": ["Wrongly", "Badly", "Righteously"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4876,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:39",
    "question": "Pahoran took and oath to grant unto the people their sacred privileges to worship the Lord their ____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 4877,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:30",
    "question": "Pahoran the chief judge did not take an oath to support and maintain the cause of God all his days, and to bring the wicked to justice according to their crime.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4878,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:2",
    "question": "And it came to pass that in the 25th year of the reign of the_____, there began to be a contention among the people concerning the chief judge Pahoran.",
    "answer": "Judge"
  },
  {
    "id": 4879,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:2",
    "question": "In the beginning of Pahoran’s reign there was a part of the people who desired that a few particular points of the_____should be altered.",
    "answer": "Law",
    "options": ["Doctrine", "Gospel", "Law"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4880,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:3",
    "question": "Pahoran hearkened unto the voice of the people and let some of the Nephite laws to be changed.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4881,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:4",
    "question": "Pahoran would not let some of the people to alter their laws so they became angry with him and desired that he no longer be the chief_____.",
    "answer": "Judge"
  },
  {
    "id": 4882,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:4",
    "question": "There arose a warm dispute among the people concerning the altering of the laws of the Nephites; but not into bloodshed.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4883,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:5",
    "question": "Those that desired that Pahoran should be dethroned from the judgment-seat were called_____.",
    "answer": "Kingmen",
    "options": ["Freemen", "Kingmen", "Knights Templar"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4884,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:5",
    "question": "The king-men desired that the law should be altered in a manner to overthrow the free government and to establish a king over the land.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4885,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:6",
    "question": "Those that were desirous that Pahoran should remain chief judge over the land took it upon themselves the name of_____.",
    "answer": "Freemen",
    "options": ["Rightmen", "Freemen", "Wing-men"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4886,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:6",
    "question": "The_____ had sworn or covenanted to maintain their rights and the privileges of their religion by a free government.",
    "answer": "Freemen"
  },
  {
    "id": 4887,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:7",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the matter of their contention was settled by the voice of the people and it was in the favor of the_____.",
    "answer": "Freemen",
    "options": ["Kingmen", "Freemen", "Free Lancers"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4888,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:7",
    "question": "Because Pahoran retained the judgment-seat his brethren rejoiced and also many of the people of liberty.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4889,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:7",
    "question": "Because of the victory of the voice of the people; the king-men did not dare oppose the law and were obliged to maintain the cause of_____.",
    "answer": "Freedom",
    "options": ["Freedom", "Liberty", "God"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4890,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:8",
    "question": "Those who were in favor of kings were those of high birth, and they sought to be_____.",
    "answer": "Kings"
  },
  {
    "id": 4891,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:8",
    "question": "The king-men sought to be kings over the land and they were supported by those who sought power and authority of the people.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4892,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:9",
    "question": "During the time of the king-men and freemen it was a critical time for the_____because Amalickiah was gathering together soldiers to fight with them.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Nephites", "Zoramites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4893,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:11",
    "question": "Amalickiah and his armies were not as great as they once were; nevertheless, he feared not to come down to the land of_____.",
    "answer": "Zarahemla",
    "options": ["Zarahemla", "Mormon", "Waters Of Mormon"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4894,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:12",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____the chief captain of the Lamanite armies did come down at the head of his armies.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 4895,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:13",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when the king-men heard that the Lamanites were coming down to battle against the Nephites, they were glad in their_____.",
    "answer": "Hearts",
    "options": ["Heads", "Hearts", "Brains"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4896,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:13",
    "question": "The_____refused to take up arms against the Lamanites because they were angry with the chief judge, and also with the people of liberty.",
    "answer": "King"
  },
  {
    "id": 4897,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:13",
    "question": "The king-men liked their chief judge Pahoran so much that they were more than glad to take up arms in defense of their country.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4898,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:14",
    "question": "Captain Moroni was exceedingly wroth with the people whom he had labored with so much diligence to preserve.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4899,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:14",
    "question": "Captain Moroni was exceedingly wroth at the people that his_____ was filled with anger against them.",
    "answer": "Soul",
    "options": ["Heart", "Soul", "Chest"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4900,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:15",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni sent a_____, with the voice of the people, unto the governor of the land.",
    "answer": "Petition",
    "options": ["Declaration", "Petition", "Text Message"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4901,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:15",
    "question": "Captain Moroni’s petition would give him power to compel those dissenters to defend their country or to put them to death.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4902,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:16",
    "question": "Contentions and_____among the Nephites had been a cause of all their destruction.",
    "answer": "Dissensions"
  },
  {
    "id": 4903,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:16",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain_____was granted according to the petition of the voice of the people.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4904,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:17",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni commanded that his army should go against those king-men, to pull down their pride and nobility and level them with the earth.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4905,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18,19",
    "question": "Captain Moroni’s army defeated the king-men with the sword and those that were not slain in battle were taken prisoners.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4906,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:19",
    "question": "And it came to pass that there was_____thousand of those dissenters who were hewn down with the sword.",
    "answer": "Four",
    "options": ["Two", "Three", "Four"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4907,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:19",
    "question": "Those dissenters who were taken prisoners were not given trials right away because of the time period the Nephites were in with the armies of Amalickiah.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4908,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:20",
    "question": "The remainder of the dissenters were compelled to hoist and yield the title of_____upon their towers, and in their cities, and to take up arms in defense of their country.",
    "answer": "Liberty"
  },
  {
    "id": 4909,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:21",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni put an end to the king-men and their pride in professing their_____.",
    "answer": "Nobility",
    "options": ["Freedom", "Nobility", "Rights"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4910,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:21",
    "question": "The dissenters were brought down to humble themselves like unto their brethren, and to fight valiantly for their freedom from bondage.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4911,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:22",
    "question": "And it came to pass that while Captain Moroni was taking care of the affairs of the_____and subjecting them to peace and civilization, the Lamanites came down to the land of Moroni.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4912,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:23",
    "question": "Amalickiah defeated the armies of Captain Moroni in the city of Moroni because they were not sufficiently strong and were driven from it.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4913,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:24",
    "question": "And those who were not driven out of the city of Moroni fled to the city of Nephihah, and also the people of the city of Lehi gathered themselves together to battle.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4914,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:25",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____the chief Lamanite commander would not suffer his armies to go against the people of the city of Nephihah.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 4915,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:26",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Amalickiah took possession of all of the Nephite cities that were on the east borders by the seashore.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4916,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:27",
    "question": "And thus the Lamanites obtained, by the cunning of_____, so many cities by their numberless hosts which were strongly fortified after the manner of the fortifications of Moroni.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 4917,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:28",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the armies of Amalickiah marched to the borders of the land Bountiful, driving the_____before them and slaying many.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4918,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:29",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the armies of Amalickiah were met with the army of_____; who was the same person who had slain Morianton in battle.",
    "answer": "Teancum"
  },
  {
    "id": 4919,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:30",
    "question": "Amalickiah was marching forth with army that he might take possession of the land of Bountiful and also the land northward.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4920,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:31",
    "question": "Amalickiah was met with a disappointment by being repulsed by_____and his men because they were great warriors.",
    "answer": "Teancum"
  },
  {
    "id": 4921,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:31",
    "question": "Teancum men did exceed the_____in their strength and in their skill of war, insomuch that they did gain advantage over the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["Zoramites", "Nephites", "Lamanites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4922,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:32",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when the night came Teancum and his _____went out in the night to the camp of Amalickiah.",
    "answer": "Servant",
    "options": ["Maid", "Servant", "Assistant"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4923,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:33",
    "question": "Amalickiah and his men were overcome with sleep because of their fatigue; which was caused by the labors and_____of the day.",
    "answer": "Heat",
    "options": ["Heat", "Humidity", "Partying"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4924,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:34",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Teancum went privily into the tent of Amalickiah and put a_____into his heart; and did cause the death of him immediately that he did not awake his servants.",
    "answer": "Javelin"
  },
  {
    "id": 4925,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:34",
    "question": "What kind of weapon of war did Teancum use to slay king Amalickiah?",
    "answer": "Javelin",
    "options": ["Sword", "Spear", "Javelin"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4926,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma62:36",
    "question": "It is interesting to note that the word “javelin” only appears how many times in the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "1",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4927,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:35",
    "question": "And_____returned to his own camp and his men were asleep, and he awoke them and told them all the things which he had done.",
    "answer": "Teancum"
  },
  {
    "id": 4928,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:37",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the 25th year of the reign of the judges over the people came to pass and so did the days of Amalickiah.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4929,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:35,51:34,62:36",
    "question": "Teancum is known not only for being a great Nephite warrior but also because he killed three prominent Lamanite leaders which were; Morianton, Amalickiah, and Ammoron.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4930,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma52:2",
    "question": "When the Lamanites awoke and saw that Amalickiah was dead they abandoned their design in marching into the land northward, and retreated into the city of Mulek.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4931,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:3",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the brother of Amalickiah was appointed king over the Lamanites and his name was_____.",
    "answer": "Ammoron"
  },
  {
    "id": 4932,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma52:4",
    "question": "Ammoron did command that his people should maintain those cities which they had taken by the shedding of much_____.",
    "answer": "Blood",
    "options": ["Sweat", "Blood", "Skin"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4933,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:5",
    "question": "Because of the numerous Lamanite armies Teancum thought it was not expedient that he should attempt to attack_____and his men in their forts.",
    "answer": "Ammoron"
  },
  {
    "id": 4934,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:7",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Teancum kept preparing himself and his army for war until Captain_____sent a large number of men to strengthen his army.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4935,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:8",
    "question": "Captain Moroni sent orders unto_____that he should retain all the prisoners who fell into his hands as a ransom for those whom the Lamanites had taken prisoner.",
    "answer": "Teancum"
  },
  {
    "id": 4936,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma52:10",
    "question": "Captain Moroni did not send orders unto Teancum that he should be faithful in maintaining the land Bountiful and should not seek every opportunity to scourge the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4937,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma52:10",
    "question": "Captain Moroni sent orders unto Teancum that he might take again by_____or some other way those cities which had been taken out of their hands.",
    "answer": "Stratagem",
    "options": ["Stratagem", "Cunning Or (c) Bribery"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4938,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:12",
    "question": "King Ammoron had departed out of the land of Zarahemla, and had made it known unto the_____concerning the death of his brother.",
    "answer": "Queen"
  },
  {
    "id": 4939,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma52:13",
    "question": "Ammoron endeavored to harass the Nephites in every border which they possessed and to draw away a part of their forces.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4940,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:16",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni sent orders unto_____that he should make an attack upon the city of Mulek and retake it if it were possible.",
    "answer": "Teancum"
  },
  {
    "id": 4941,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma52:17",
    "question": "Teancum made preparations to attack the city of Mulek but because it was well fortified he abandon his designs and returned to the city of Bountiful.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4942,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma52:19",
    "question": "Captain Moroni and Teancum and many of the chief captains of the Nephites held a council of_____.",
    "answer": "War",
    "options": ["Thanksgiving", "War", "Peace"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4943,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma52:19",
    "question": "The council of war that Captain Moroni and Teancum held was so they could by some means flatter the Lamanites out of their strongholds and come to battle against them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4944,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma52:20",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Captain Moroni and his council sent embassies to the army of the Lamanites which protected the city of Mulek; and his name was Jacob.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4945,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:20",
    "question": "Jacob was the leader of the Lamanites who protected the city of Mulek and he was a_____and would not come out with his army to meet the Nephites upon the plains.",
    "answer": "Zoramite"
  },
  {
    "id": 4946,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma52:21",
    "question": "Captain Moroni had high hopes that Jacob the Zoramite would meet them upon the plains which were fair grounds for a battle of war.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4947,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:22",
    "question": "Captain Moroni caused that_____and a small number of his men should march down to the seashore to provide a decoy for Jacob and his men.",
    "answer": "Teancum"
  },
  {
    "id": 4948,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:24",
    "question": "The guards of the_____discovered Teancum and his men and went and told Jacob their leader, and they took courage and pursued them with vigor because of their small numbers.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4949,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:25",
    "question": "While Teancum and his men were leading the Lamanites away from the city of Mulek; Captain_____went with his army and took possession of it and slew all those who had been left to protect it.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4950,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:27",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the_____did pursue Teancum until they came near the city of Bountiful, and then they were met by Lehi and a small army.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4951,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma52:28",
    "question": "When the Lamanites saw Lehi and his army coming against them they fled in confusion; because they were worn out because of their march, and the men of Lehi were fresh.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4952,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma52:30",
    "question": "Lehi and his army were desirous that they should overtake the Lamanites until they should meet Captain Moroni and his men.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4953,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:32",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain_____commanded his men that they should fall upon Jacob and his men and give them battle until they had given up their weapons of war.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4954,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma52:33",
    "question": "Because Jacob was a Zoramite and had an unconquerable_____, he led the Lamanites forth to battle with exceeding fury against Captain Moroni.",
    "answer": "Spirit",
    "options": ["Demeanor", "Spirit", "Body"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4955,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma52:35",
    "question": "Jacob was determined to cut his way through to the city of Mulek but Captain Moroni and his men were more powerful; and they fought with exceeding fury on both sides.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4956,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:35",
    "question": "During the battle with Jacob and his men; Captain Moroni was wounded and_____was killed.",
    "answer": "Jacob"
  },
  {
    "id": 4957,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma52:36",
    "question": "Lehi and his men pressed upon the Lamanites in the rear with such fury with his strong men, that they were confused and knew not whether to go or to strike.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4958,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:37",
    "question": "Captain Moroni saw that the Lamanites were confused and said if they would deliver up their weapons of war they would forbear in shedding of their_____.",
    "answer": "Blood"
  },
  {
    "id": 4959,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:38",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the chief captains of the Lamanites who were not slain came forth and threw down their weapons of war at the feet of Captain_____.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4960,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:39",
    "question": "There were many of the Lamanites who refused to lay down their weapons of_____and they were bound and their weapons of war were taken from them.",
    "answer": "War"
  },
  {
    "id": 4961,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma52:40",
    "question": "The number of the Lamanites who were taken prisoners did not exceed the number that had been slain in battle on both sides.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4962,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanite prisoners were compelled to go forth and bury their dead and also the dead of the_____.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4963,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma53:1",
    "question": "Captain Moroni placed_____over the Lamanites while they should perform their labors.",
    "answer": "Guards",
    "options": ["Guards", "Servants", "Women"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4964,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma53:2",
    "question": "Captain Moroni went to the city of Mulek with Lehi, and took command of the city and gave it to Lehi.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4965,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:2",
    "question": "Lehi was a man who had been with Captain_____in the more part of all his battles; and he was a man like unto Moroni.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4966,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma53:2",
    "question": "Lehi and Captain Moroni rejoiced in each others safety and they were beloved by each other and also by all the people of Nephi.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4967,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma53:3",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni caused that the Lamanite prisoners should commence in laboring in digging a ditch around the land, or the city, Bountiful.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4968,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:4",
    "question": "Captain Moroni caused that the_____prisoners build a breastwork of timbers and earth to encircle the city of Bountiful to an exceeding height.",
    "answer": "Lamanite"
  },
  {
    "id": 4969,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma53:5",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the city of Bountiful became a stronghold ever after.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4970,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma53:5",
    "question": "Captain Moroni was compelled to cause the Lamanites to labor, because it was easy to guard them while they performed their labors.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4971,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:6",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni gained a victory over one of the greatest of the_____armies and also of the city of Mulek which was one of their strongholds.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4972,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:6",
    "question": "The city of Mulek was one of the strongest holds of the Lamanites in the land of_____and Captain Moroni made it a stronghold to retain his prisoners.",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 4973,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma53:7",
    "question": "Captain Moroni did employ his men in delivering their women and their children from famine and affliction, and providing_____for their armies.",
    "answer": "Food",
    "options": ["Shelter", "Food", "Rum"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4974,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:8",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the armies of the Lamanites did take possession of some of the cities of the Nephites in the absence of Captain_____.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 4975,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma53:8",
    "question": "The reason some of the cities of the Nephites were taken over was because there was dissensions among them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4976,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:9",
    "question": "Because of iniquities amongst themselves; their dissensions and intrigue among themselves placed the_____in the most dangerous circumstances.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4977,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:10",
    "question": "The intrigue of the Nephites was because the people of Ammon, who in the beginning, were_____ refused to take up arms against their brethren.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 4978,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma53:10",
    "question": "The people of Ammon had been converted unto the Lord; and they had been brought down to the land of Zarahemla, and had ever since been protected by the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4979,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:11",
    "question": "According to the_____the people of Ammon had taken they would never shed the blood of their brethren anymore; or they would perish.",
    "answer": "Oath"
  },
  {
    "id": 4980,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:11",
    "question": "The people of_____ would have suffered themselves to have fallen into the hands of their brethren, had it not been for the love which Ammon and his brethren had had for them.",
    "answer": "Ammon"
  },
  {
    "id": 4981,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma53:13",
    "question": "The people of Ammon saw the danger and the many afflictions and tribulations which the Nephites bore for them and they were moved with compassion.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4982,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:13",
    "question": "Because the people of_____were moved with compassion for the Nephites; they were desirous to take up arms in the defense of their country.",
    "answer": "Ammon"
  },
  {
    "id": 4983,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma53:14",
    "question": "The people of Ammon were overpowered by the persuasions of Helaman and his_____, and they were about to break the oath that they had made.",
    "answer": "Brethren",
    "options": ["Sisters", "Wives", "Brethren"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4984,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:15",
    "question": "Helaman feared that the people of Ammon would lose their_____if they were to break the oath they had made concerning the taking up of arms against their brethren.",
    "answer": "Souls"
  },
  {
    "id": 4985,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma53:16",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people of Ammon had many sons who had not entered into a covenant that they would not take their weapons of war to defend themselves.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4986,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:17",
    "question": "The sons of the people of_____entered into a covenant to fight for the liberty of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Ammon"
  },
  {
    "id": 4987,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:17",
    "question": "The sons of the people of Ammon entered a covenant that they never would give up their_____, but they would fight in all cases to protect the Nephites and themselves from bondage.",
    "answer": "Liberty"
  },
  {
    "id": 4988,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma53:18",
    "question": "Now behold, there were_____thousand of those young men, who entered into this covenant and took their weapons of war to defend their country.",
    "answer": "Two",
    "options": ["Two", "Three", "Four"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4989,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma53:19",
    "question": "The two thousands sons of the people of Ammon desired that_____be their leader.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["Captain Moroni", "Helaman", "Amalickiah"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4990,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma53:20",
    "question": "The two thousand young men of Helaman were all_____men, and they were exceedingly valiant in courage, and also for strength and activity.",
    "answer": "Young",
    "options": ["Tall", "Skinny", "Young"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4991,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma53:20",
    "question": "The two thousand young men of Helaman were men who were true at all times in whatsoever thing they were entrusted.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4992,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:21",
    "question": "The two thousand young men of_____were men of truth and soberness, for they had been taught to keep the commandments of God and to walk uprightly before him.",
    "answer": "Helaman"
  },
  {
    "id": 4993,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma53:21",
    "question": "The two thousand young men of Helaman were men of craftiness and cunning, who were taught to take advantage of anyone when the opportunity arose.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4994,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:22",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____did march at the head of his two thousand stripling soldiers.",
    "answer": "Helaman"
  },
  {
    "id": 4995,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:22",
    "question": "The two thousand young men of Helaman were known as the two thousand_____soldiers of Helaman.",
    "answer": "Stripling"
  },
  {
    "id": 4996,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____, king of the Lamanites sent a message unto Captain Moroni desiring to exchange prisoners.",
    "answer": "Ammoron"
  },
  {
    "id": 4997,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:2",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni was not happy and did not feel to rejoice exceedingly because of the request of king Ammoron.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 4998,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:3",
    "question": "The Lamanites had taken many women and children as prisoners, and there was not a woman neither a child among all the prisoners of Captain Moroni.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 4999,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:3",
    "question": "One of the differences between the Nephites armies and the Lamanites armies; is that the Nephites never took women or children as prisoners.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5000,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma54:3",
    "question": "Captain Moroni resolved upon a_____to obtain as many prisoners of the Nephites from the Lamanites as it were possible.",
    "answer": "Stratagem",
    "options": ["Stratagem", "Spell", "Trick"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5001,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:4",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote an_____, and sent it by the servant of Ammoron, the same servant who had brought an epistle to him.",
    "answer": "Epistle"
  },
  {
    "id": 5002,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:5",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote concerning the war that Ammoron and his brother_____had waged against the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Amilickiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 5003,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:6",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote concerning the justice of God, and the sword of his almighty wrath, except Ammoron and the Lamanites would repent.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5004,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma54:7",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told Ammoron that an awful_____awaited to receive such murderers as him and his brother.",
    "answer": "Hell",
    "options": ["Death", "Hell", "Trial"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5005,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:7",
    "question": "Captain Moroni thought that Ammoron was not capable of hearkening unto his words",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5006,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:7",
    "question": "Captain Moroni asked_____to repent and withdraw his murderous purposes, and return with his armies to their own lands.",
    "answer": "Ammoron"
  },
  {
    "id": 5007,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:8",
    "question": "Ammoron rejected the request of Captain Moroni; and he had fought against the people of the_____, and Captain Moroni knew that he would do it again.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 5008,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:9",
    "question": "Captain Moroni and his armies were not prepared to receive Ammoron and his armies except he would withdraw his purposes.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5009,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:9",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote to Ammoron the he would pull down the wrath of that_____who he had rejected upon him, even to his utter destruction.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 5010,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma54:10",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote that he and his armies would retain their cities and their lands; and would maintain their_____and the cause of their God.",
    "answer": "Cities",
    "options": ["Lands", "Cities", "Churches"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5011,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:11",
    "question": "Captain Moroni supposed that his words to Ammoron were in vain and he supposed that Ammoron was a child of_____.",
    "answer": "Hell"
  },
  {
    "id": 5012,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:11",
    "question": "Captain Moroni closed his_____to Ammoron by telling him that he would not exchange prisoners.",
    "answer": "Epistle"
  },
  {
    "id": 5013,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:11",
    "question": "Captain Moroni closed his epistle to Ammoron by telling him that he would exchange prisoners of war.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5014,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:11",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that if Ammoron would exchange a man and his wife and his children for one prisoner, he would do it.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5015,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:12",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said he would arm his women and his_____and he himself would come against Ammoron and follow him into his own land.",
    "answer": "Children"
  },
  {
    "id": 5016,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:12",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told Ammoron that he would follow him into his own land and it shall be blood for____; and he would give him battle even until he was destroyed from the face of the earth.",
    "answer": "Blood"
  },
  {
    "id": 5017,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma53:13",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told Ammoron that he was angry because he sought to murder him and his people and they had only sought to defend themselves.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5018,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:13",
    "question": "Moroni said that if_____seeked to destroy him and his people he would seek to destroy him, and would follow him into the land of their first inheritance.",
    "answer": "Ammoron"
  },
  {
    "id": 5019,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:14",
    "question": "Moroni closed his epistle to Ammoron by writing that his name was Moroni and that he was the_____of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Leader"
  },
  {
    "id": 5020,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:15",
    "question": "When Ammoron received the epistle from Moroni he was not angry.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5021,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:15",
    "question": "Ammoron was angry when he received the epistle that Moroni had written unto him; and he wrote another_____unto Moroni.",
    "answer": "Epistle"
  },
  {
    "id": 5022,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:16",
    "question": "Ammoron wrote another epistle unto Moroni informing him that he was the king of the Lamanites and was the brother of_____who he accused Moroni of murdering.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah"
  },
  {
    "id": 5023,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma54:16",
    "question": "Ammoron wrote that he would avenge the_____of Amalickiah and would come upon Moroni with his armies.",
    "answer": "Blood",
    "options": ["Name", "Blood", "Honor"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5024,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:16",
    "question": "Ammoron feared the so called threatening's of Captain Moroni.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5025,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma54:17",
    "question": "Ammoron wrote that Moroni’s fathers did wrong their brethren, insomuch that they did rob them of their right to the_____when it rightly belonged to them.",
    "answer": "Government",
    "options": ["Vote", "Government", "Kingdom"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5026,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:18",
    "question": "Ammoron told Moroni if they would lay down their weapons and subject themselves to be governed by those whom the government rightly belong to, he would stop the war.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5027,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:20",
    "question": "Ammoron did not grant Moroni to the exchange of prisoners according to the way he had requested.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5028,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma54:20",
    "question": "Ammoron gladly granted Moroni his request to the exchange of prisoners so that he could preserve his food for his men of_____.",
    "answer": "War",
    "options": ["War", "Liberty", "Beauty"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5029,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:21",
    "question": "Ammoron wrote that he would wage a war which shall be eternal, either to the subjecting the_____to their authority or to their eternal extinction.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 5030,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:21",
    "question": "Ammoron said that he knew that there was no such being as a God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5031,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:21",
    "question": "Ammoron wrote that if there was such a being as a God; they knew not, but that he had made him and his people as well as the Nephites",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5032,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma54:22",
    "question": "Ammoron said if there was such a thing as a devil and a_____; he would also send Moroni there to dwell with his brother who he had murdered.",
    "answer": "Hell",
    "options": ["Heaven", "Hell", "Bad Planet"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5033,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:23",
    "question": "Ammoron wrote to Moroni by saying that he was a descendant of_____, whom his fathers pressed and brought out of Jerusalem.",
    "answer": "Zoram"
  },
  {
    "id": 5034,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:23",
    "question": "Ammoron wrote to Moroni by saying that he was a descendant of Zoram, whom his fathers pressed and brought out of the city of_____.",
    "answer": "Jerusalem"
  },
  {
    "id": 5035,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:24",
    "question": "Ammoron said that he was a bold_____; and that this war had been waged to avenge the wrongs of the Lamanites, and to maintain and to obtain their rights to the government.",
    "answer": "Lamanite"
  },
  {
    "id": 5036,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma55:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when Captain Moroni received the latest epistle from Ammoron he was angrier than the first time.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5037,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma55:1",
    "question": "Captain Moroni was angry because he knew_____had a perfect knowledge of his fraud.",
    "answer": "Ammoron",
    "options": ["Zoram", "Amalickiah", "Ammoron"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5038,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma55:1",
    "question": "Captain Moroni knew that Ammoron did not have a just cause that had caused him to wage a war against the people of_____.",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "id": 5039,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma55:2",
    "question": "Captain Moroni would not exchange prisoners with Ammoron unless he would withdraw his purpose as he had stated previously in his_____.",
    "answer": "Epistle",
    "options": ["Letter", "Proclamation", "Epistle"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5040,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma55:2",
    "question": "Captain Moroni would not grant unto_____any more power that he had already had by uniting the forces of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Ammoron"
  },
  {
    "id": 5041,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma55:3",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said he knew where the Lamanites had his people and if Ammoron would not grant him his wishes, he would seek death among them until they would sue for peace.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5042,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma55:4",
    "question": "Captain Moroni caused that a search should be made among his men that perhaps he might find a man who was a descendant of_____ among them.",
    "answer": "Laman",
    "options": ["Laman", "Lemuel", "Nephi"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5043,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma55:5",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni found a man who was a descendant of Laman and his name was_____; and he was one of the servants of the king who was murdered by Amalickiah.",
    "answer": "Laman"
  },
  {
    "id": 5044,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma55:5",
    "question": "Laman was not a servant of the king who was murdered by Amalickiah.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5045,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma55:7",
    "question": "Captain Moroni knew the name of the city where the Lamanites had his people prisoners and he caused that Laman and a small number of his men should go to the city of Gid.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5046,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma55:8",
    "question": "Laman went and told the Lamanites who were guarding the people of Captain Moroni that he was a_____; and had escaped from them.",
    "answer": "Lamanite",
    "options": ["Lamanite", "Zoramite", "Ishmaelite"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5047,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma55:8",
    "question": "Laman told the Lamanites that not only had he escaped from the Nephites but he had also taken some of their_____.",
    "answer": "Wine",
    "options": ["Swords", "Wine", "Sacred Scriptures"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5048,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma55:9",
    "question": "The Lamanites received Laman with joy and wanted to drink from his wine because they were_____.",
    "answer": "Weary",
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Weary", "Happy"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5049,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma55:10",
    "question": "Laman told the Lamanites that they should save there_____and keep it until they went to battle and that made them more desirous to drink it.",
    "answer": "Wine"
  },
  {
    "id": 5050,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma55:12",
    "question": "Laman did not give the Lamanites a choice of when they were to drink the wine he had taken from the Nephites.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5051,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma55:13",
    "question": "And it came to pass the Lamanites drank of the wine freely; and it was_____to their taste because it was strong, having been prepared in its strength.",
    "answer": "Pleasant",
    "options": ["Pleasant", "Awful", "Bitter"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5052,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma55:14",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites did not drink of the wine and were not merry and by and by they all did not become drunk.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5053,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma55:15",
    "question": "When Laman and his men saw the Lamanites had become drunk and had fallen asleep, they returned to Captain_____and told him all the things that had happened.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 5054,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma55:16",
    "question": "Captain Moroni did not plan that the Lamanites drink of the Nephites wine so that they would become drunk and fall asleep.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5055,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma55:16",
    "question": "Captain_____prepared his men with weapons and had them give them to the prisoners that were in the city of Gid so they could fight the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 5056,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alam55:17",
    "question": "Captain Moroni had the Nephite women and children and all of those that were able to use a weapon of war armed; and this was all done in profound_____.",
    "answer": "Silence",
    "options": ["Loudness", "Silence", "Darkness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5057,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma55:18",
    "question": "Captain Moroni could have awakened the Lamanites who were drunk and slayed them; but he did not delight in murder or bloodshed.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5058,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma55:19",
    "question": "Captain Moroni delighted in the saving of his people from destruction; and for this cause he did not have the Lamanites slain, because it would bring an injustice upon him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5059,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "21,22",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni had his people surround the armies of the_____, and this was done at night, so when the Lamanites awoke they saw that they were surrounded by the Nephites.  Lamanites-",
    "answer": "Alma55:"
  },
  {
    "id": 5060,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma55:23",
    "question": "When the Lamanites saw the predicament they were in they brought their weapons of war to the feet of the Nephites and pleaded for_____.",
    "answer": "Mercy",
    "options": ["Forgiveness", "Mercy", "Repentance"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5061,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma55:24",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites who were in the city of Gid surrendered to Captain_____and those Nephites who were once prisoners joined his army and it was a great strength to it.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 5062,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma55:26",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni had the Lamanite prisoners’ labor in strengthening the fortifications of the city of Gid and Bountiful.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5063,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma55:28",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the_____began again to be victorious, and to reclaim their rights and privileges.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 5064,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma55:29,30",
    "question": "The Lamanites tried many times to encircle the Nephites with their armies and attempted to administer their wine to them to poison them or get them drunk.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5065,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma55:31",
    "question": "The Nephites were slow to remember the Lord their God in this time of affliction and could be taken in the snares of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5066,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma55:32",
    "question": "The Nephites were cautious that no poison should be administered among them; for if their wine would poison a Lamanite it would also poison a_____.",
    "answer": "Nephite"
  },
  {
    "id": 5067,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma55:33",
    "question": "The Lamanites were continually bringing new forces into the city of Morianton; and because of their labors it had made it an exceeding stronghold.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5068,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:1",
    "question": "Captain_____received an epistle from Helaman stating the affairs of the people in that quarter of the land.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 5069,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma56:2",
    "question": "Helaman referred to Captain Moroni as a dearly beloved brother of his.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5070,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma56:3",
    "question": "Helaman told Captain Moroni concerning the two thousand men whom Ammon brought down from the land of Nephi.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5071,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma56:3",
    "question": "The two thousand stripling warriors of Helaman were descendants of what son of Lehi?",
    "answer": "Laman",
    "options": ["Laman", "Lemuel", "Nephi"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5072,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma56:4",
    "question": "Helaman knew that Captain Moroni knew concerning the_____or the unbelief of the two thousand stripling warriors.",
    "answer": "Traditions",
    "options": ["Ceremonies", "Traditions", "Religion"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5073,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:5",
    "question": "Helaman wanted Captain Moroni to know that the two thousand young men have taken their weapons of war, and wanted him to be their_____.",
    "answer": "Leader"
  },
  {
    "id": 5074,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:6",
    "question": "Helaman said that the two thousand stripling warrior’s fathers’ had made a covenant that they would not take their_____of war, and take them up against their brethren to shed blood.",
    "answer": "Weapons"
  },
  {
    "id": 5075,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:8",
    "question": "Helaman would not let his stripling warriors break the covenant which they had made, supposing_____would strengthen them and himself.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 5076,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma56:9",
    "question": "Helaman told Captain Moroni that they should have joy in the fact that he had marched in front of his two thousand warriors to assist Antipus in the city of Judea.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5077,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma56:10",
    "question": "Helaman told Captain Moroni that his two thousand warriors were not worthy to be called his sons.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5078,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:11",
    "question": "Antipus’ army had been reduced by the Lamanites because their forces had slain a vast number of them; nevertheless they had died in the cause of their country and their_____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 5079,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma56:12",
    "question": "The Lamanites had retained many_____, all of whom are chief captains.",
    "answer": "Prisoners",
    "options": ["Prisoners", "Women", "Men"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5080,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:16",
    "question": "Helaman wrote to Captain Moroni and said that many Nephites were depressed in body as well as in_____.",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },
  {
    "id": 5081,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma56:16",
    "question": "Helaman said that many of the Nephite had fought valiantly by day and toiled by night to maintain their cities and had suffered great afflictions of every kind.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5082,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:18",
    "question": "The Lamanites were determined to conquer the city of Judea or die; but because Antipus had received more help they were order by_____not to come against it.",
    "answer": "Ammoron"
  },
  {
    "id": 5083,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma56:19",
    "question": "Helaman told Captain Moroni that they were not favored of the Lord because the Lamanites had come upon them in their weakest point and they had been preserved.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5084,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:22",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Nephites kept_____all around the cities that they maintained to watch the movements of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Spies"
  },
  {
    "id": 5085,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:25",
    "question": "The Lamanites did not dare to march down against the city of Zarahemla; neither did they dare cross the head of the river_____, over to the city of Nephihah.",
    "answer": "Sidon"
  },
  {
    "id": 5086,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma55:27",
    "question": "Helaman was brought many provisions from the fathers of those_____thounsand men.",
    "answer": "2",
    "options": ["2", "3", "4"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5087,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma56:28",
    "question": "Helaman received help with the aid of two thousand men from the land of Zarahemla; therefore his was prepared to fight the Lamanites with ten thousand men.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5088,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:29",
    "question": "The Lamanites began to fear_____and his army because of the many provision brought unto his army and also because his army was increasing daily.",
    "answer": "Helaman"
  },
  {
    "id": 5089,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma56:34",
    "question": "The city of Antiparah was stationed by the_____army of the Lamanites and the most numerous.",
    "answer": "Strongest",
    "options": ["Weakest", "Strongest", "Largest"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5090,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma56:35,36",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites came forth with their army against Helaman and his army and they did lead away the most powerful army of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5091,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:37",
    "question": "The Lamanites pursued Helaman and his army even though they were being pursued in the rear by the army of_____.",
    "answer": "Antipus"
  },
  {
    "id": 5092,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma56:38",
    "question": "Because Antipus could see the danger Helaman and his army were in; he speedily marched his army forward but could not overtake the Lamanites because it was nightfall.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5093,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:39",
    "question": "And it came to pass that before the dawn of the morning the_____ were pursuing Helaman and his two thousand stripling warriors.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 5094,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "41,42",
    "question": "How many times did the Lamanites stop and rest than started again in pursuit of Helaman’s army before Helaman and his army decided to go to battle against them?",
    "answer": "1",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5095,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:45",
    "question": "Helaman told Captain Moroni that he had never seen so great of courage among the_____as he had seen among his two thousand stripling warriors.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 5096,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma56:46",
    "question": "Helaman's warriors said unto him:  “_____, behold our God is with us, and he will not suffer that we should fall”.",
    "answer": "Father",
    "options": ["Daddy", "Captain", "Father"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5097,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma56:47",
    "question": "Helaman’s stripling warriors were seasoned fighters because of all the previous battles they had been through.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5098,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:47",
    "question": "Helaman’s stripling warriors did not fear_____ and they did think more upon the liberty of their fathers than they did upon their own lives.",
    "answer": "Death"
  },
  {
    "id": 5099,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:47",
    "question": "The two thousand stripling warriors had been taught by their_____, that if they did not doubt, God would deliver them.",
    "answer": "Mothers"
  },
  {
    "id": 5100,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:48",
    "question": "Helaman’s warriors rehearsed unto him the words of their mothers, saying:  “We do not doubt our_____knew it”.",
    "answer": "Mothers"
  },
  {
    "id": 5101,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:50",
    "question": "The army of Antipus would have fallen unto the Lamanites had it not been for the return and help of_____and his stripling warriors.",
    "answer": "Helaman"
  },
  {
    "id": 5102,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma56:51",
    "question": "Antipus had fallen by the sword, and many of his leaders because of their weariness of the speed of their march and the rest of his army became confused and give way into the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5103,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:52",
    "question": "The Lamanites took courage because of the fall of Antipus and started to pursue the Nephites.  And when they saw_____and his warriors they turned around and pursued them.",
    "answer": "Helaman"
  },
  {
    "id": 5104,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:54",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people of Nephi, the people of Antipus, and Helaman and his warriors surrounded the army of the_____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 5105,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:54",
    "question": "Because the Lamanite were surrounded on all sides, they were compelled to deliver up their weapons of_____and also themselves as prisoners of war.",
    "answer": "War"
  },
  {
    "id": 5106,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma56:55,56",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Helaman began to count how many of his stripling warriors had fallen by the sword that had fought with him; and to his great surprise, none had been killed.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5107,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma56:56",
    "question": "Only ten stripling warriors that had fought with Helaman had been slain in battle.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5108,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:56",
    "question": "Because of the miraculous strength and such mighty power of the stripling warriors, it caused the_____to deliver themselves up as prisoners of war.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 5109,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma57:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Helaman received an epistle from _____the king of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Ammoron"
  },
  {
    "id": 5110,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:1",
    "question": "The epistle stated that if Helaman would deliver up those prisoners of war whom he had taken, he would deliver up the city of Antiparah unto him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5111,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:2",
    "question": "Helaman sent an epistle unto Ammoron saying that he was sure that he had sufficient forces to take the city of Antiparah.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5112,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma57:3",
    "question": "Ammoron refused the_____from Helaman, and he would not exchange prisoners; therefore Helaman began to make preparations to go against the city of Antiparah.",
    "answer": "Epistle"
  },
  {
    "id": 5113,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:6",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Helaman received a supply of provisions and also an addition of six thousand men to his army.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5114,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma57:6",
    "question": "Helaman received an additional_____men of the sons of the Ammonites who had come to join their brethren; the two thousand stripling warriors of Helaman.",
    "answer": "60",
    "options": ["40", "50", "60"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5115,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma57:9",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____and his army camped around the city of Cumeni for many nights; and Lamanites attempted many times to come upon Helaman but were held back.",
    "answer": "Helaman"
  },
  {
    "id": 5116,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:10",
    "question": "Helaman and his army stole the provisions the Lamanite army were about to receive; but the Lamanites were still determined to take the city of Cumeni.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5117,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma57:12",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites began to lose all hopes of succor; therefore they yielded up the city into the hands of_____and his army.",
    "answer": "Helaman"
  },
  {
    "id": 5118,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma57:13",
    "question": "Because Helaman’s prisoners were so numerous, he was obligated to employ all his forces to keep them, or to put them to_____.",
    "answer": "Death",
    "options": ["Work", "Death", "Sing"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5119,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:14",
    "question": "The Lamanite prisoners would break out in great numbers and would fight Helaman and his army with anything they could get their hands on.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5120,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:14",
    "question": "Because of the many attempted breakouts by the Lamanites; Helaman and his army killed upwards of two thousand of them after they had surrendered themselves prisoners of war",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5121,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma57:15",
    "question": "It became expedient for Helaman and his army that they should put an end to the lives of the_____, or guard them; sword in hand, down to the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 5122,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:16",
    "question": "Because of the critical circumstances Helaman and his army were in; it became a very serious matter to determine what to do with his prisoners of war.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5123,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma57:17",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Ammoron sent to the support of the prisoners of war more provisions and also a numerous army of_____.",
    "answer": "Men"
  },
  {
    "id": 5124,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma57:19",
    "question": "Helaman and his little band of two thousand and sixty fought very desperately and they were firm before the_____, and did administer death unto all that opposed them.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 5125,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:19",
    "question": "Helaman’s army of two thousand and sixty did not obey and observe to perform every word of command with exactness.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5126,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:21",
    "question": "Helaman did not remember the words which his two thousand stripling warriors said unto him concerning what their mothers had taught them.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5127,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma57:23",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____and his army did retain the city of Cumeni and were not all destroyed by the sword, but they did suffer a great loss of men.",
    "answer": "Helaman"
  },
  {
    "id": 5128,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma57:24",
    "question": "And it came to pass that after the Lamanites had fled, Helaman immediately gave_____that his men who had been wounded should be taken from among the dead.",
    "answer": "Orders",
    "options": ["Orders", "Commands", "Gestures"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5129,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma57:25",
    "question": "And it came to pass that there were_____hundred, out of Helaman’s two thousand and sixty, who had fainted because of the loss of blood.",
    "answer": "Two",
    "options": ["Two", "Three", "Four"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5130,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma57:25",
    "question": "Two hundred out of Helaman’s two thousand and sixty, fainted because of the loss of_____.",
    "answer": "Blood"
  },
  {
    "id": 5131,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:25",
    "question": "Because of the goodness of God, and to Helaman’s astonishment, there was not one soul of them who did perish; neither was there one soul among them who had not received many wounds.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5132,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:26",
    "question": "The preservation of the stripling warriors was astonishing to Helaman’s whole army because they had been spared; while a thousand of their brethren had been slain.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5133,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma57:26",
    "question": "Helaman justly ascribe the survival of the stripling warriors to the miraculous power of_____, because of their exceeding faith in that which they had been taught to believe.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 5134,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:26",
    "question": "The stripling warriors had been taught to believe that there was a just God, and whosoever did not doubt, that they should be preserved by his marvelous power.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5135,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma57:27",
    "question": "Helaman said that the stripling warriors were young, and their minds _____; and they do put their trust in God continually.",
    "answer": "Firm",
    "options": ["Sluggish", "Firm", "Awful"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5136,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:28",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Helaman inquired of Gid concerning the prisoners whom they had started to go down to the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5137,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma57:29",
    "question": "Gid was the_____captain over the band who was appointed to guard the Lamanite prisoners of war down to the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": "Chief"
  },
  {
    "id": 5138,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:32",
    "question": "Gid told Helaman that the Lamanite prisoners of war had heard the cries of his spies and took courage, and did rise up in rebellion against him and his band.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5139,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma57:33",
    "question": "Gid told Helaman that because of the rebellion of the Lamanite prisoners; he caused that their_____should come upon them.",
    "answer": "Swords",
    "options": ["Swords", "Arrows", "Javelins"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5140,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma57:33",
    "question": "Gid told_____that the Lamanite prisoners came in one body against their swords and many were killed and the remainder of them broke through and fled from them.",
    "answer": "Helaman"
  },
  {
    "id": 5141,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:35",
    "question": "Gid told Helaman that the Lord once again had preserved him and brethren out of the hands of their enemies.  And blessed is the name of our God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5142,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma57:36",
    "question": "And it came to pass when Helaman heard the words of_____, he was filled with joy because of the goodness of God in preserving them that they might not all perish.",
    "answer": "Gid"
  },
  {
    "id": 5143,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma57:36",
    "question": "Helaman said that he had_____in God that the souls of those who have been slain have entered into the rest of their God.",
    "answer": "Trust",
    "options": ["Confidence", "Trust", "Belief"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5144,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma58:1",
    "question": "Helaman tried to trick or decoy the Lamanites away from their strongholds in the city of Manti but he could not because they remembered what he had done before to them",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5145,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma58:4",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____sent an embassy to the governor of their land, to acquaint him concerning the affairs of the land.",
    "answer": "Helaman"
  },
  {
    "id": 5146,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma58:4",
    "question": "One of the reasons Helaman sent an_____to the governor was so that they could receive provisions and strength from the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": "Embassy",
    "options": ["Embassy", "Band", "Army"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5147,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma58:6",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites were also receiving provisions for their army and would resolve by_____to destroy Helaman and his army from time to time.",
    "answer": "Stratagem"
  },
  {
    "id": 5148,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma58:7",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Helaman waited for many_____, even until they were about to perish for the want of food.",
    "answer": "Months",
    "options": ["Seasons", "Months", "Years"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5149,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma58:8",
    "question": "But it came to pass that Helaman and his people did receive food, which was guarded to them by an army of two thousand men to their assistance.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5150,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma58:9",
    "question": "Helaman knew the reason why he and his army did not receive more men and more provisions for his people.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5151,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma58:9",
    "question": "Helaman and his people were grieved and also filled with fear, lest by any means the judgments of God should come upon their land, to their overthrow and utter_____.",
    "answer": "Destruction"
  },
  {
    "id": 5152,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma58:10",
    "question": "Helaman and his people did pour out their_____in prayer to God; that he would strengthen them and deliver them out of the hands of their enemies.",
    "answer": "Souls",
    "options": ["Bodies", "Souls", "Heads"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5153,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma58:11",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lord their _____did visit the Nephites with assurances that he would deliver them.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 5154,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma58:11",
    "question": "The Lord did speak_____to Helaman and his peoples souls, and did grant unto them great faith, and did cause them that they should hope for their deliverance in him.",
    "answer": "Peace",
    "options": ["Love", "Peace", "Loudly"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5155,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma58:12",
    "question": "Helaman did take courage with his small force which he had received, and was fixed with a determination to conquer their enemies.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5156,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma58:13",
    "question": "Helaman and his army went forth with all their might against the Lamanites, who were in the city Manti; and they did pitch their_____by the wilderness side.",
    "answer": "Tents"
  },
  {
    "id": 5157,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma58:14",
    "question": "And it came to pass when the Lamanites saw that Helaman and his army were by the wilderness; they sent_____to see how large and strong his army was.",
    "answer": "Spies"
  },
  {
    "id": 5158,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma58:15",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when the Lamanites saw the Helaman and his army was not that strong, they began to make preparations of war with their numerous hosts.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5159,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma58:26",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____caused that his army should not sleep and did march to the city of Manti by night.",
    "answer": "Helaman"
  },
  {
    "id": 5160,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma58:28",
    "question": "Helaman and his army used a stratagem and did take possession of the city of Manti without the shedding of_____.",
    "answer": "Blood",
    "options": ["Skin", "Blood", "Hair"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5161,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma58:30",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites did flee out of all the quarter of the land and carried with many women and children out of the land.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5162,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma58:33",
    "question": "Helaman and his army did not trust in the Lord therefore, they did not receive any help from God and he did not granted unto them any victories.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5163,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma58:34",
    "question": "Helaman did not know why the_____government would not grant them more strength; neither did the men who came up to help him.",
    "answer": "Nephite",
    "options": ["Nephite", "Lamanite", "Zoramite"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5164,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma58:35",
    "question": "Helaman and his army did not murmur why the Nephite government would not send them more strength, but they wondered why they could not.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5165,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma58:36",
    "question": "Helaman feared that there was some_____in the government; that would not send them more assistance because he knew that the Nephites were more numerous than what they had sent.",
    "answer": "Faction",
    "options": ["Portion", "Faction", "Neither A Or B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5166,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma58:37",
    "question": "Helaman and his army put their_____in God that he would deliver them, notwithstanding the weakness of his armies.",
    "answer": "Trust",
    "options": ["Trust", "Faith", "Heart"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5167,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma58:38",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Helaman and his armies were in possession of their lands; and the_____had fled to the land of Nephi.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 5168,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma58:39",
    "question": "Helaman and his stripling warriors of the people of_____; were with him in the city of Manti.",
    "answer": "Ammon"
  },
  {
    "id": 5169,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma58:39",
    "question": "Helaman told Captain Moroni the Lord had supported his stripling warriors from falling by the_____; insomuch that not even one soul had not been slain.",
    "answer": "Sword"
  },
  {
    "id": 5170,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma58:40",
    "question": "Helaman said that his stripling warriors had received many wounds; nevertheless they stand fast in that liberty wherewith God has made them free.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5171,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma58:40",
    "question": "Helaman said his warriors were strict to remember the Lord their God from day to_____; and they do observe to keep his statutes, and his judgments, and his commandments continually.",
    "answer": "Day"
  },
  {
    "id": 5172,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma58:40",
    "question": "Helaman said his warriors’ faith is strong in the prophecies concerning that which is to come.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5173,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma58:41",
    "question": "Helaman told his beloved brother Moroni; “May the Lord our God, who has redeemed us and made us free, keep you continually in his presence”.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5174,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma58:41",
    "question": "Helaman closed his epistle to Moroni by writing that he was son of Alma2.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5175,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma59:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that after Moroni had received and read Helaman’s epistle, he was exceedingly rejoiced because of the welfare, and the exceeding success of_____.",
    "answer": "Helaman"
  },
  {
    "id": 5176,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma59:1",
    "question": "Captain Moroni was exceedingly happy that Helaman had been successful in obtaining the lands they had lost unto the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5177,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma59:2",
    "question": "Moroni let it be known among all his people in the lands round about of Helaman’s success that they might_____also.",
    "answer": "Rejoice",
    "options": ["Smile", "Rejoice", "Gossip"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5178,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma59:3",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni immediately sent an_____to Pahoran, desiring that he should cause men to be gathered together to strengthen Helaman.",
    "answer": "Epistle"
  },
  {
    "id": 5179,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma59:4",
    "question": "And it came to pass when_____had sent his epistle to the land of Zarahemla, he began again to lay a plan that he might obtain the remainder of cities which the Lamanites had taken.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 5180,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma59:5",
    "question": "And it came to pass that while Moroni was making preparations for war, the_____attacked the people of Nephihah, who were gathered together from other cities.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 5181,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma59:6",
    "question": "Those who had been compelled to flee from the land of Manti, and from other lands, had come over and joined the Lamanites in this part of the Land.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5182,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma59:7",
    "question": "The people of Nephihah were slain with an exceeding great slaughter because the Lamanites were numerous and had received strength from day to day on the orders of_____.",
    "answer": "Ammoron"
  },
  {
    "id": 5183,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma59:8",
    "question": "The Lamanites were so numerous that the people of_____were obliged to flee before them; and they came over and joined the army of Captain Moroni.",
    "answer": "Nephihah"
  },
  {
    "id": 5184,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma59:11",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites took possession of the city of Nephihah and Captain_____was exceedingly sorrowful.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 5185,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma59:11",
    "question": "Captain Moroni began to doubt, because of the wickedness of the people, whether they should not fall into the hands of their_____.",
    "answer": "Brethren",
    "options": ["Brethren", "Captors", "Adversaries"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5186,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma59:12",
    "question": "Because of the wickedness of the Nephites; their_____captains doubted and marveled also of the success of the Lamanites over them.",
    "answer": "Chief"
  },
  {
    "id": 5187,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma59:13",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain_____was angry with the government, because of their indifference concerning the freedom of their country.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 5188,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____wrote again to the governor of the land which was Pahoran; who was the chief judge in the city of Zarahemla and the land.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 5189,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma60:1",
    "question": "Captain Moroni only wrote and directed his epistle to Pahoran and not to those who had been chosen by the people to govern and manage the affairs of their war.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5190,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma60:2",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote his epistle by way of condemnation to those that were in charge of the affairs of their war.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5191,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma60:3",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote that he himself, and also his men and also Helaman and his men had suffered_____sufferings.",
    "answer": "Great",
    "options": ["Small", "Great", "A Lot Of"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5192,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:3",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote that his men and others had suffered hunger, _____, and fatigue, and all manner of afflictions of every kind.",
    "answer": "Thirst"
  },
  {
    "id": 5193,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:4",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that if hunger, thirst, and fatigue, were all that they had suffered; they would not_____neither complain.",
    "answer": "Murmur"
  },
  {
    "id": 5194,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma60:5",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that there had been a great slaughter among his people; while it might have otherwise been if the government would have rendered unto their armies sufficient strength.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5195,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:5",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that because the government had not rendered sufficient strength and_____; and had neglected them, they had suffered much.",
    "answer": "Succor"
  },
  {
    "id": 5196,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:6",
    "question": "Captain Moroni and his army desired to know the cause of this exceeding great neglect; and desired to know the cause of the government’s great_____ state towards them.",
    "answer": "Thoughtless"
  },
  {
    "id": 5197,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:7",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote to the government concerning their thoughtless stupor, while their enemies were spreading the work of_____among them.",
    "answer": "Death"
  },
  {
    "id": 5198,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:8",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote that the people had placed the people in the government there and looked up to them for protection, and placed them in a situation that they might have_____them.",
    "answer": "Succored"
  },
  {
    "id": 5199,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma60:9",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote to the government saying that they had withheld their provisions from them and many had fought and_____out their lives.",
    "answer": "Bled",
    "options": ["Taken", "Bled", "Sold"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5200,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:9",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that many Nephites had suffered greatly because of the great desire which they had for the_____of the people.",
    "answer": "Welfare"
  },
  {
    "id": 5201,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma60:10",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told his beloved brethren that they should have stirred themselves more_____for the welfare and freedom of the people.",
    "answer": "Diligently",
    "options": ["Diligently", "Often", "Frequently"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5202,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:10",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote to the government telling them that the blood of thousands of Nephites would come upon their_____for vengeance.",
    "answer": "Heads"
  },
  {
    "id": 5203,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:10",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote to the government telling them that_____had heard all the cries and sufferings of those that had been slain.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 5204,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma60:11",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote that if the government could sit upon their thrones; and think that God would deliver them because of his exceeding goodness, while they did nothing; was in vain.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5205,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:12",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote that many who had fallen by the sword were not wicked; and it was a condemnation upon those that sat in the government upon their_____.",
    "answer": "Thrones"
  },
  {
    "id": 5206,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:13",
    "question": "For the Lord suffers the_____to be slain that his justice and judgment may come upon the wicked.",
    "answer": "Righteous"
  },
  {
    "id": 5207,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma60:14",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote to the government not to suppose that those that had been slain were lost; but entered into the_____of God.",
    "answer": "Rest",
    "options": ["Mansions", "Rest", "Houses"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5208,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:14",
    "question": "Captain Moroni feared exceedingly that the_____of God would come upon this people because of the exceeding slothfulness and neglect of the government towards the people.",
    "answer": "Judgments"
  },
  {
    "id": 5209,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:15",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that if it was not for the wickedness which first commenced at the head of the people, they could have withstood their_____that they could have had no power of them.",
    "answer": "Enemies"
  },
  {
    "id": 5210,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:16",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that the_____were the cause that a war broke out among themselves; and caused much bloodshed.  King-",
    "answer": "men"
  },
  {
    "id": 5211,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma60:16",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said the king-men desired power and_____among the people; and were not true to the freedom that united them.",
    "answer": "Authority",
    "options": ["Wealth", "Authority", "Riches"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5212,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:16",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said if the people would have gone out in the strength of the_____, they would have dispersed their enemies, according to the fulfilling of his word.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 5213,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma60:17",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said the Lamanites were murdering the people and carrying their women and children captive and away, causing them to suffer all manner of afflictions.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5214,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma60:17",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said his people had suffered much because of great_____of the king-men who were seeking power and authority.",
    "answer": "Wickedness",
    "options": ["Sufferings", "Swordsmanship", "Wickedness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5215,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma60:18",
    "question": "Captain Moroni would not elaborate much concerning the king-men and those that were of the head of the government because he knew that they themselves were seeking for authority.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5216,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:20",
    "question": "Captain Moroni asked the heads of the government if they had forgotten the_____of the Lord their God.",
    "answer": "Commandments"
  },
  {
    "id": 5217,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:20",
    "question": "Captain Moroni asked the heads of the government it they had forgotten the many times the Lord had delivered them out of the hands of their_____.",
    "answer": "Enemies"
  },
  {
    "id": 5218,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma60:22",
    "question": "Captain Moroni asked the heads of the government it they supposed that they could sit upon their thrones and do nothing while tens of thousands of their brethren were being slain.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5219,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma60:23",
    "question": "Captain Moroni asked the heads of the government if they supposed that God would look upon them as_____while they sit and behold the things that were happening to the people.",
    "answer": "Guiltless",
    "options": ["Guiltless", "Thoughtless", "Useless"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5220,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma60:23",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that God would find the heads of the government guiltless while that sat upon their thrones and did nothing while their brethren were being slain.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5221,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:23",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that they should clean their inward_____first, and then the outer vessel should be cleaned also.",
    "answer": "Vessel"
  },
  {
    "id": 5222,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:24",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said the head of the government should repent and send forth food and men unto him and_____. ",
    "answer": "Helaman"
  },
  {
    "id": 5223,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:24",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that if the head of the government would not repent and help him and Helaman; they would stop contending with the_____and cleansed the inward vessel. ",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 5224,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:25,27",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told the head of the government that unless they grant unto him his_____he would personally come after them himself.",
    "answer": "Epistle"
  },
  {
    "id": 5225,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:27",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that he would stir up insurrections among the head of the government until all those that desired to usurp power and authority shall become_____.",
    "answer": "Extinct"
  },
  {
    "id": 5226,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:28",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told the head of the government that he did not fear their power neither their_____but that he did fear God.",
    "answer": "Authority"
  },
  {
    "id": 5227,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:28",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that he did take his_____to defend the cause of his country, and that it was because of the iniquity of the head of the government that they had suffered so much loss.",
    "answer": "Sword"
  },
  {
    "id": 5228,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:29",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told the head of the government that the time was at hand that the sword of_____would fall upon them and visit them even to utter destruction.",
    "answer": "Justice"
  },
  {
    "id": 5229,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma60:30",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote to the head of the government that unless they would administer relief unto them; he would smite them with the sword.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5230,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma60:31",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that the Lord would not suffer that the head of the government should wax strong in their iniquities to destroy his righteous_____.",
    "answer": "People",
    "options": ["Humans", "Men", "People"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5231,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:32",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said it was the traditions of the_____fathers' that has caused a hatred towards the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 5232,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma60:32",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said it was the traditions of the Lamanites and that their iniquity was for the love of glory and the_____things of the world.",
    "answer": "Vain",
    "options": ["Rich", "Vain", "Glorious"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5233,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:33",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that the head of the government transgressed the laws of God, and that they did know that they trampled them under their_____.",
    "answer": "Feet"
  },
  {
    "id": 5234,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:34",
    "question": "Captain Moroni was constrained, according to the covenant which he had made to keep the_____of his God. ",
    "answer": "Commandments"
  },
  {
    "id": 5235,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma60:34",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told the head of the government that they should adhere to the word of God, and send speedily unto him their provisions and their men, and also help for Helaman.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5236,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma60:35",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that the Lord would not suffer that he and his men should perish with_____.",
    "answer": "Hunger",
    "options": ["The Sword", "Hunger", "Thirst"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5237,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:36",
    "question": "Moroni told the head of the government that he was their chief captain and that he seeked not for power but to_____it down.",
    "answer": "Pull"
  },
  {
    "id": 5238,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:35",
    "question": "Moroni said that he did not seek for honor of the world, but for the glory of his_____, and the freedom and welfare of his country.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 5239,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that as soon as Captain Moroni had sent his epistle unto the chief governor, he received an epistle from_____.",
    "answer": "Pahoran"
  },
  {
    "id": 5240,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma61:1",
    "question": "Pahoran was the chief governor of the Nephites’ land.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5241,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:2",
    "question": "Pahoran told Moroni in his_____that he did not rejoice in his great afflictions, and that it grieved his soul to read about them.",
    "answer": "Epistle"
  },
  {
    "id": 5242,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma61:3",
    "question": "Pahoran told Moroni that there were those who did have joy in his afflictions.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5243,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:3",
    "question": "The people who rejoiced in the afflictions of Moroni rose up in rebellion against_____and his people who were freemen.",
    "answer": "Pahoran"
  },
  {
    "id": 5244,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma61:3",
    "question": "Pahoran told Captain Moroni in his epistle that those that had risen up in rebellion against him and his people were not very numerous, and that he could take care of them.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5245,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:4",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that those that had rebelled against him were trying to take away the_____-seat from him; and were the cause of great iniquity among the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Judgment"
  },
  {
    "id": 5246,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma61:4",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that those that rebelled against him used great_____, and have led away the hearts of many people; which was the cause of sore afflictions among them.",
    "answer": "Flattery",
    "options": ["Words", "Flattery", "Speeches"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5247,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:4",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that the kingmen withheld provisions, and have daunted the freemen; that was the reason they had not been able to help Captain_____and his army.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 5248,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:5",
    "question": "The kingmen had driven_____from the land and he had fled to the land of Gideon, with as many men as it was possible.",
    "answer": "Pahoran"
  },
  {
    "id": 5249,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma61:6",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote in his epistle to Moroni that he has sent out a_____into the land of Gideon.",
    "answer": "Proclamation",
    "options": ["Text Message", "Declaration", "Proclamation"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5250,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma61:7",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that the kingmen were defiant and were afraid to come to battle with him and his army.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5251,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:8",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that the kingmen had taken possession of the city of Zarahemla and had appointed a_____over them; and he had written unto the king of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "King"
  },
  {
    "id": 5252,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:8",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that the king of the city of Zarahemla was planning to be king over all the land after the_____would conquer all of the remaining land.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 5253,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma61:9",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that Captain Moroni had censored him in his epistle.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5254,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma61:9",
    "question": "Pahoran was not angry with the words Moroni had written in his epistle; but rejoiced in the greatness of his_____.",
    "answer": "Heart",
    "options": ["Body", "Heart", "Intelligence"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5255,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:9",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that he did not seek for_____, only to retain his judgment-seat that he may preserve the rights and liberties of the people.",
    "answer": "Power"
  },
  {
    "id": 5256,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma61:9",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote to Moroni stating that his soul stands fast in that liberty which God had made him and his people_____.",
    "answer": "Free",
    "options": ["Free", "Better", "Victorious"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5257,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma61:10",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that he and his people would resist_____, even unto the shedding of blood.",
    "answer": "Wickedness",
    "options": ["Temptations", "Riches", "Wickedness"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5258,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:11",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that they would not shed the_____of their brethren if they would not rise up in rebellion and take the sword against him and his people.",
    "answer": "Blood"
  },
  {
    "id": 5259,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:12",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that he and people would subject themselves to the yoke of_____if it was requisite with the justice of God, or if he should command them to do so.",
    "answer": "Bondage"
  },
  {
    "id": 5260,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:13",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that God had commanded him and his people that they should put their_____in him, and he would deliver them.",
    "answer": "Trust"
  },
  {
    "id": 5261,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:14",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote to Moroni in his epistle that they should resist_____, and whatsoever evil they could not resist with their words, they should resist with their swords.",
    "answer": "Evil"
  },
  {
    "id": 5262,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma61:14",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote to Moroni saying that they should resist evil, and things such as rebellions and dissensions; they should resist with their_____.",
    "answer": "Swords",
    "options": ["Mouths", "Words", "Swords"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5263,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma71:14",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that they should retain their freedom; that they may rejoice in the great privilege of their church, and in the cause of the Redeemer their God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5264,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:15",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote to Captain_____telling him to come speedily unto him with a few of his men and leave the remainder in charge of Lehi and Teancum.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 5265,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma61:15",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote to Moroni telling him to leave Lehi and Teancum in charge to have power to conduct the war in that part of the land, according to the_____of God.",
    "answer": "Will",
    "options": ["Good", "Spirit", "Will"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5266,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:15",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote in his epistle to Moroni that the Spirit of God is also the Spirit of_____which was in both of them.",
    "answer": "Freedom"
  },
  {
    "id": 5267,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma61:17",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote to Moroni that they would go speedily unto the dissenters, in the strength of their God according to the faith which was in them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5268,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma61:18",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote to Moroni that they would go forth unto Lehi and Teancum against the dissenters, and put an end to the great iniquity that was among them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5269,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:15-18, 21-62:3",
    "question": "Who was the supreme commander or the commander-in-chief of the Nephite armies?",
    "answer": "Pahoran"
  },
  {
    "id": 5270,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma61:15-18, 21",
    "question": "Captain Moroni was the supreme commander or the commander-in-chief of the Nephite armies.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5271,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:19",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote to Moroni that he did have_____in receiving his epistle; and was concerned in what they should do, whether it should be just in him and his people to go against their brethren.",
    "answer": "Joy"
  },
  {
    "id": 5272,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma61:20",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote in his epistle that Moroni had written that unless the kingmen and their people would repent; that they should go against them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5273,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:21",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote to Captain Moroni that he should see to strengthen Lehi and Teancum in the_____.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "id": 5274,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:21",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote the Captain Moroni should see to it that Lehi and Teancum and their people should not fear the_____, because God would deliver them.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 5275,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma61:21",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that God would deliver those that stood fast in that liberty wherewith God had made them_____.",
    "answer": "Free",
    "options": ["Precious", "Good", "Free"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5276,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma61:21",
    "question": "Pahoran closed his epistle to Moroni say that Moroni was his beloved_____.",
    "answer": "Brother",
    "options": ["Friend", "Brother", "Comrade"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5277,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma62:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when Moroni received the epistle from Pahoran, his heart took_____.",
    "answer": "Courage",
    "options": ["Courage", "To Beating Faster", "Sick"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5278,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:1",
    "question": "After Moroni received the epistle from Pahoran, his heart took courage, and was filled with exceeding great joy because of the faithfulness of_____.",
    "answer": "Pahoran"
  },
  {
    "id": 5279,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma62:1",
    "question": "Moroni was filled with great joy because he knew that Pahoran was not a_____to the freedom and cause of their country.",
    "answer": "Traitor",
    "options": ["Man", "Traitor", "Warrior"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5280,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:2",
    "question": "Moroni did mourn exceedingly because of the iniquity of those who had driven Pahoran from the judgment-seat.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5281,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:2",
    "question": "Moroni did not mourn exceedingly because of those who had rebelled against their country and also their God.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5282,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:3",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni took a small number of men, according to the desire of Pahoran, and gave Lehi and Teancum command over the remainder of his army.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5283,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma62:3",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni took a small number of his men and began marching towards the land of_____.",
    "answer": "Gideon",
    "options": ["Zarahemla", "Gideon", "Neither A Nor B"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5284,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:4",
    "question": "Captain Moroni raised the standard of_____in whatsoever place or land he did enter; and gained whatsoever force he could in all his march towards the land of Gideon.",
    "answer": "Liberty"
  },
  {
    "id": 5285,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma62:5",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____, did flock unto Captain Moroni’s standard of liberty, and did take up their swords in the defense of their freedom.",
    "answer": "Thousands",
    "options": ["Hundreds", "Thousands", "Millions"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5286,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma62:5",
    "question": "Thousands did flock unto Captain Moroni’s standard of liberty to defend their freedom that they might not come into_____.",
    "answer": "Bondage",
    "options": ["Slavery", "Bondage", "Prison"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5287,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:6",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni arrived in the land of Gideon and united his forces with those of_____.",
    "answer": "Pahoran"
  },
  {
    "id": 5288,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:6",
    "question": "By uniting his forces with that of Pahoran’s, the Nephites force became stronger than those of the dissenters who had driven the freemen out of the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5289,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:6",
    "question": "What is the name of the king that the kingmen appointed to be their king? ",
    "answer": "Pachus"
  },
  {
    "id": 5290,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:8",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Pahoran and his army with down to the land of Zarahemla, and_____was slain and his men were taken prisoners, and Pahoran was restored to the judgment-seat.",
    "answer": "Pachus"
  },
  {
    "id": 5291,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:9",
    "question": "The men of Pachus did not receive a trial according to the law of the Nephites; and also those king-men who had been taken and cast into prison.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5292,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:9",
    "question": "Those that received a trial and were found guilt of war crimes were executed according to the law.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5293,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:9",
    "question": "Those men of Pachus and those king-men who would not take up arms in the defense of their country; but would fight against it, were put to_____.",
    "answer": "Death"
  },
  {
    "id": 5294,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:10",
    "question": "And it became expedient that the law should be strictly observed for the safety of their country; and whosoever was found denying their freedom was speedily_____according to the law.",
    "answer": "Executed"
  },
  {
    "id": 5295,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:11",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni and Pahoran did not restore peace to the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5296,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:11",
    "question": "After Captain Moroni and Pahoran restored peace to the land of Zarahemla; they inflicted death upon all those that were not true to the cause of freedom.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5297,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:12",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni caused that an army of six-thousand men should be sent to_____, to assist him in preserving that part of the land.",
    "answer": "Helaman"
  },
  {
    "id": 5298,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:13",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni also caused that an army of six-thousand men with food should be sent to the armies of Lehi and_____to fortify the land against the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Teancum"
  },
  {
    "id": 5299,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:14",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni and Pahoran took a large body of men towards the land of Nephihah, being determined to overthrow the_____in that city.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 5300,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:15",
    "question": "Captain Moroni and Pahoran took a large body of_____of the Lamanites, and slew many of them, and took their provisions and their weapons of war.",
    "answer": "Men"
  },
  {
    "id": 5301,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:16",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni caused that the surviving Lamanites enter a_____that they would not take up their weapons of war against the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Covenant"
  },
  {
    "id": 5302,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:17",
    "question": "And after the surviving Lamanites had entered into this covenant; they were sent to dwell with the people of Ammon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5303,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma62:17",
    "question": "The surviving Lamanites that entered into the covenant of Captain Moroni were numbered about_____thousand who had not been slain.",
    "answer": "Four",
    "options": ["Two", "Three", "Four"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5304,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma62:18",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni and his armies pitched their_____in the plains of Nephihah, which was near the city of Nephihah.",
    "options": ["Sombreros", "Hats Or (c) Tents"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5305,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:19",
    "question": "Captain Moroni was not desirous that the Lamanites should come to battle with his armies among the plains of Nephihah.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5306,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:19",
    "question": "The Lamanites did not dare come up to battle against the_____because of the greatness of their numbers and because of their exceeding great courage.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 5307,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:20",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when the night came; _____went forth in the darkness of the night, to spy upon the Lamanites and also to spy in what part of the city they were in.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 5308,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma62:21",
    "question": "When Moroni spied on the Lamanites; what direction were the Lamanites camped at which was by the entrance of the city Nephihah.",
    "answer": "East",
    "options": ["North", "West", "East"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5309,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:21",
    "question": "Moroni found out that the Lamanites were not asleep and neither were they camped out in the eastern part of the city of Nephihah which was also by its entrance.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5310,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:22",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni caused that his men marched forth into the city of_____and went over the walls, and let themselves down into the city.",
    "answer": "Nephihah"
  },
  {
    "id": 5311,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:23",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni’s men used strong cords and ladders to let themselves down into the city of Nephihah; and when the morning came they were all within the walls of the city.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5312,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:24-25",
    "question": "When the Lamanites awoke and saw that they were surrounded by the Nephites; they fled out by the pass, and some were taken prisoners and others fled to the land of Moroni.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5313,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:26",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni and Pahoran obtained the possession of the city of_____without the loss of one soul; and there were many of the Lamanites who were slain.",
    "answer": "Nephihah"
  },
  {
    "id": 5314,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma62:26",
    "question": "When Moroni and Pahoran obtained the city of Nephihah, how many Nephites were slain?",
    "answer": "None",
    "options": ["None", "Two", "Three"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5315,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:27",
    "question": "And it came to pass that many of the Lamanites who were taken prisoners by Captain Moroni and Pahoran were desirous to join the people of_____and become a free people.",
    "answer": "Ammon"
  },
  {
    "id": 5316,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:28",
    "question": "All the prisoners that were desirous to join the people of Ammon were granted according to their desires.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5317,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:29",
    "question": "All the Lamanites that joined the people of Ammon did begin to labor exceedingly, tilling the ground, raising all manner of grain, and_____of every herd.",
    "answer": "Flocks"
  },
  {
    "id": 5318,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:30",
    "question": "Because Captain Moroni had taken so many Lamanite prisoners, their armies were reduced exceedingly.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5319,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:31",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni took his army from the land of Nephihah to the land of Lehi; when the_____saw that Moroni was coming against them, they fled.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 5320,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:32",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites were pursued to city to city, until they were met by Lehi and_____armies.",
    "answer": "Teancum"
  },
  {
    "id": 5321,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:33",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the armies of the Lamanites were gathered together in one body in the land of Moroni, and_____their king was also with them.",
    "answer": "Ammoron"
  },
  {
    "id": 5322,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:34",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni, Lehi and Teancum did encamp with their armies around the borders of the land of_____.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "id": 5323,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:35",
    "question": "Because of the exceeding march of both the Nephites and Lamanites; both of their armies were not weary.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5324,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:35",
    "question": "What chief captain of one of the Nephites armies was exceedingly angry with Ammoron and blamed him and his brother for the cause of the war?",
    "answer": "Teancum"
  },
  {
    "id": 5325,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:35",
    "question": "Teancum was exceedingly angry with Ammoron, and Amalickiah his brother, and blamed them for the great and lasting war between the Nephites and the_____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 5326,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma62:35",
    "question": "The exceedingly great war between the Nephites and Lamanites caused much bloodshed and much_____among the people.",
    "answer": "Famine",
    "options": ["Sickness", "Injuries", "Famine"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5327,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:36",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____went forth with a cord over the walls of the city and cast a javelin into the king’s heart and killed him.",
    "answer": "Teancum"
  },
  {
    "id": 5328,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:36",
    "question": "What was the name of one of Captain Moroni’s chief captain that put a javelin into the heart of king Ammoron and killed him?",
    "answer": "Teancum"
  },
  {
    "id": 5329,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:36",
    "question": "One of the king’s servants pursued Teancum and killed him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5330,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:35,51:3462:36",
    "question": "How many times in the Book of Mormon are we told by Mormon that Teancum slew how many kings?",
    "answer": "3",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5331,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:37",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni and Pahoran were exceedingly sorrowful when they found out the Teancum had been slain.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5332,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:37",
    "question": "Mormon writes that_____had been; a man who had fought valiantly for his country, and a true friend of liberty.",
    "answer": "Teancum"
  },
  {
    "id": 5333,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma62:37",
    "question": "Mormon writes that Teancum not only was a man that fought valiantly for his country; but had also suffered very many exceedingly great_____.",
    "answer": "Afflictions",
    "options": ["Sores", "Fevers", "Afflictions"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5334,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:38",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni marched forth with his armies towards the_____, and did slay them with a great slaughter.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 5335,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:39-40",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Nephites had wars, and bloodshed's, and famines, and afflictions, for the space of many years; and were spared because of the_____of the righteous.",
    "answer": "Prayers"
  },
  {
    "id": 5336,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:40",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Nephites had many murders, contentions, and dissentions, and all manner of_____among them; but were spared because of the prayers of the righteous.",
    "answer": "Iniquity"
  },
  {
    "id": 5337,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:40",
    "question": "Because the prayers of the righteous, the Nephites were spared of many things.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5338,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:41",
    "question": "Because of the exceeding great length of the war between the Nephites and the Lamanites many of the people had become hardened.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5339,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:41",
    "question": "Because of the exceeding great length of the war between the people; many were softened because of their afflictions, insomuch that they did humble themselves before God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5340,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:42-43",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni and Helaman, and Pahoran established peace among the people of Nephi; and Moroni yielded up the command of his armies to Moronihah.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5341,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:43",
    "question": "What was the name of the man that Captain Moroni yielded up the command of his armies to?",
    "answer": "Moronihah"
  },
  {
    "id": 5342,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:43",
    "question": "Moronihah was not a son of Captain Moroni but was the son of one of his chief captains.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5343,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:43",
    "question": "Captain Moroni retired unto his own house that he might spend the remainder of his day’s in_____.",
    "answer": "Peace"
  },
  {
    "id": 5344,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:44",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Pahoran did return to his judgment-seat, and _____did take it upon himself to preach the word of God unto the people.",
    "answer": "Helaman"
  },
  {
    "id": 5345,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:45",
    "question": "Helaman and his brethren did declare the word of God with much_____unto the convincing of many people of their wickedness, which did cause them to repent and be baptized.",
    "answer": "Power"
  },
  {
    "id": 5346,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:46-47",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the church of God was established throughout the land and regulations were made concerning the law.  And their judges and chief judger were chosen.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5347,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:48",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the_____began to prosper again in the land, and began to multiply and to wax exceedingly strong.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 5348,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:49",
    "question": "Notwithstanding their riches, or their strength, or their prosperity, the Nephites were not lifted up in the pride of their eyes.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5349,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:49",
    "question": "The Nephites began to not be lifted in the pride of their eyes; neither were they slow to remember the Lord their _____; but they did humble themselves exceedingly before him.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "id": 5350,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:50",
    "question": "The Nephites did remember how great things the Lord had done for them; delivering them from death, and from bonds, and from prisons.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5351,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:51",
    "question": "The_____did pray unto the Lord continually, insomuch that the Lord did bless them, according to his word, so that they did wax strong and prosper in the land.",
    "answer": "Nephites"
  },
  {
    "id": 5352,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:52",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Helaman died and went the way of the earth in the 35th year of the reign of the_____over the people of Nephi.",
    "answer": "Judges"
  },
  {
    "id": 5353,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma63:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Shiblon took possession of those sacred things which had been delivered unto Helaman by_____.",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 5354,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma63:2",
    "question": "Mormon wrote that_____was a just man, and did walk uprightly before God; and he did observe to do good continually.",
    "answer": "Shiblon"
  },
  {
    "id": 5355,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma63:2",
    "question": "Mormon wrote that Shiblon was not a just man, and did not keep the commandments of the Lord his God; and neither did his brother.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "id": 5356,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma63:3",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni died. And thus ended the 36th year of the reign of the judges over the people of Nephi.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5357,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma63:4",
    "question": "And it came to pass that a large company of men and their families departed out of the land of_____ into the land which was northward.",
    "answer": "Zarahemla"
  },
  {
    "id": 5358,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma63:5",
    "question": "Mormon writes that_____was an exceedingly curious man.",
    "answer": "Hagoth",
    "options": ["Helaman", "Alma", "Hagoth"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5359,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma63:5",
    "question": "Hagoth is known to us as an exceedingly curious man, and also a_____.",
    "answer": "Ship Builder",
    "options": ["Carpenter", "Ship Builder", "Great Warrior"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5360,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma63:5",
    "question": "What is the name of the ship builder that built a ship and launched it forth into the west sea?",
    "answer": "Hagoth"
  },
  {
    "id": 5361,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Narrow",
    "question": "Hagoth built himself a ship and went with many Nephites into the west sea, by the_____neck which led into the land northward.",
    "answer": "Alma63:5-6"
  },
  {
    "id": 5362,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma63:6",
    "question": "Hagoth and many Nephites did enter the ship and did sail forth with many provisions; and they took their course_____.",
    "answer": "Northward",
    "options": ["Westward", "Southward", "Northward"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5363,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma63:7",
    "question": "And the first ship that Hagoth built did return and many more people did enter into it; and they also took many provisions, and set out again to the land northward.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5364,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma63:8",
    "question": "After the second trip that many of the Nephites took to the land_____; they were never heard of again.",
    "answer": "Northward"
  },
  {
    "id": 5365,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma63:8",
    "question": "Mormon writes that he supposed that the second ship did go down in the depths of the_____and drowned.",
    "answer": "Sea",
    "options": ["River", "Sea", "Ocean"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5366,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma63:8",
    "question": "And it came to pass that another ship did sail forth and Mormon writes that where she went we do not know of.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5367,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma63:10",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Shiblon died and his younger brother_____, did go forth to the land northward to carry provisions unto the people who had gone forth into the land.",
    "answer": "Corianton"
  },
  {
    "id": 5368,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma63:10",
    "question": "It became expedient that Shiblon confer those_____things, before his death, upon the son of Helaman, who was called Helaman.",
    "answer": "Sacred"
  },
  {
    "id": 5369,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma63:11",
    "question": "Shiblon entrusted Helaman with the sacred things of the Nephites; and he was called Helaman after the name of his father.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5370,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma63:12",
    "question": "Mormon writes that the engravings which were in the possession of Helaman were written and sent forth among the children of_____ throughout the land.",
    "answer": "Men"
  },
  {
    "id": 5371,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma63:12",
    "question": "Mormon writes that the engravings were sent forth among the children of men, except those parts which had been commanded by_____; that they should not go forth.",
    "answer": "Alma"
  },
  {
    "id": 5372,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma63:13",
    "question": "Mormon writes that the sacred things were to be kept sacred, and handed down for one generation to_____.",
    "answer": "Another"
  },
  {
    "id": 5373,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma63:14",
    "question": "And it came to pass that in the 39th year of the reign of the judges; there were some dissenters who had gone forth unto the_____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites"
  },
  {
    "id": 5374,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma63:14",
    "question": "The dissenters of the Nephites went forth among the Lamanites to stir them up again to anger against the_____.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["Zoramites", "Amalickites", "Nephites"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5375,
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma63:15",
    "question": "And it came to pass that an army of Lamanites came down with a numerous army to war against the army of_____and they suffered a great loss.",
    "answer": "Moronihah"
  },
  {
    "id": 5376,
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma63:16-17",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the account of Alma, and Helaman his son, and also Shiblon, who was his son, ended in the 39th year of the reign of the judges over the people of Nephi.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "id": 5377,
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "4:12",
    "question": "The game of BOM Quest was inspired in part by the author’s _____.",
    "answer": "no",
    "options": ["Wife", "Mother", "Ether"]
  }
]
